<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> <!DOCTYPE TEI.2 PUBLIC "-//TEI P4//DTD Main DTD Driver File//EN" "http://www.tei-c.org/Guidelines/DTD/tei2.dtd" [ <!ENTITY % TEI.XML "INCLUDE"> <!ENTITY % PersProse PUBLIC "-//Perseus P4//DTD Perseus Prose//EN" "http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/DTD/1.0/PersProse.dtd" > %PersProse; <!NOTATION jpg SYSTEM "JPEG"> <!ENTITY NW_RichTimesD_022_150_001 SYSTEM "NW_RichTimesD_022_150_001.jpg" NDATA jpg> <!ENTITY NW_RichTimesD_022_150_002 SYSTEM "NW_RichTimesD_022_150_002.jpg" NDATA jpg> ]> <TEI.2 id="NW_RichTimesD_022_150"> <teiHeader type="aacr2"> <fileDesc> <titleStmt> <title type="245">The Daily Dispatch: June 24, 1862. </title> <title type="gmd">[Electronic resource] </title> <funder> Institute of Museum and Library Services National Leadership Grant </funder> <respStmt> <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> <resp>Creation of digital images: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> <resp>Conversion to Tei.2-conformant markup: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> </respStmt> </titleStmt> <extent>ca. <num value="30">XXX</num> kilobytes </extent> <publicationStmt> <publisher>University of <orgName n="Richmond Library" type="library">Richmond Library</orgName> </publisher> <pubPlace>Richmond, Virginia </pubPlace> <idno type="Url">Nw_richtimesd_022_150</idno> <availability> 
<p>&#x00A9; 2004 by the University of Richmond. </p> 
<p>Url: http://oncampus.Richmond.edu/academics/Library/digital/ </p> </availability> <date> </date> </publicationStmt> <seriesStmt> 
<p>Institute of Museum and Library Services Civil War Newspaper Project </p> </seriesStmt> <notesStmt> <note>Page images have been included from the microfilm version. </note> <note>images were scanned with a Sunrise 2000 scanner from microfilm, at 14x reduction ratio at 400 dpi Optical Resolution. Creation Software: Pixel Translations. Pixtiff version 1.135. </note> <note>Ddd note: shipped: 2005_01_21_ddd_url. </note> </notesStmt> <sourceDesc> <biblFull> <titleStmt> <title type="245">The Daily Dispatch: June 24, 1862. </title> <title type="246"><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName> </title> <respStmt> <resp> </resp> <name> </name> </respStmt> </titleStmt> <editionStmt> 
<p> </p> </editionStmt> <extent>2 pages. </extent> <publicationStmt> <publisher>by Cowardin &#x0026; Hammersley. </publisher> <pubPlace>Richmond </pubPlace> <date value="1862-06-24">June 24, 1862</date><idno type="vol">22.150</idno> </publicationStmt> <seriesStmt> <title> </title> </seriesStmt> <notesStmt> <note>microfilm. Ann Arbor, Mi : Proquest. 1 microfilm reel ; 35 mm. </note> </notesStmt> </biblFull> </sourceDesc> </fileDesc> <encodingDesc> <projectDesc> 
<p>Imls Civil War Newspaper Project. </p> </projectDesc> <editorialDecl> 
<p>the images exist as archival Tiff images, with Jpeg versions for internet access. </p> </editorialDecl> <refsDecl> <state unit="article" /> </refsDecl> <classDecl> <taxonomy id="lcsh"> <bibl> <title>Library of Congress subject Headings, </title> <edition>21st edition, 1998</edition> </bibl> </taxonomy> </classDecl> </encodingDesc> <profileDesc> <creation> <date value="1862">1862 </date> </creation> <langUsage> <language id="eng">English </language> </langUsage> 
<textClass> <keywords scheme="lcsh"> 
<list type="simple"> 
<item>Newspapers -- Virginia -- Richmond</item> </list> </keywords> </textClass> </profileDesc> <revisionDesc> <change> <date>September, 2005 </date> <respStmt> <resp>Checker </resp> <name>Grant Dickie, of the University of <orgName n="Richmond Library" type="library">Richmond Library</orgName> </name> </respStmt> 
<item>File Checked, not Corrected. Do NOT SEND TO DDD. Image Error: TIFF file mislabeled: Page 2 labeled as Page 3. </item> </change> </revisionDesc> </teiHeader> 
<text id="NW_RichTimesD_022_150T"> <front> <milestone unit="page" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="page-image"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="1"/><figure entity="NW_RichTimesD_022_150_001"> <figDesc>Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume <num value="22">22</num>, <num value="150">Number 150</num>, <ref n="page 1">page 1</ref>. </figDesc> </figure></p> </div1> <titlePage> <docTitle><titlePart type="main"> Daily Dispatch </titlePart> </docTitle> <docImprint> Vol. Xxii &mdash; no.<num value="150">150</num> <pubPlace> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Va.</placeName> </pubPlace> <date value="1862-06-24">Tuesday, June 24, 1862</date> <persName n="Price,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00001" reg="mostcommon:Price,nomatch:0"><surname>Price</surname></persName> <num value="1">one</num> Cent </docImprint> </titlePage> 
<div1 type="subscription"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName><lb/> by <persName n="Cowardin,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00002" reg="mostcommon:Cowardin,nomatch:0"><surname>Cowardin</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="Hammersley,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00003" reg="mostcommon:Hammersley,nomatch:0"><surname>Hammersley</surname></persName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="2"/>the <rs>Daily Dispatch</rs> is served to subscribers at <num value="6.25">six and A Quarter</num> Cents per Week, payable to the <name>Carrier</name> weekly.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="3"/><persName n="Price,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00004" reg="mostcommon:Price,nomatch:0"><surname>Price</surname></persName> for mailing, <measure n="4dollars" type="currency">$4</measure> a year, or <measure n="2.50dollars" type="currency">$2.50</measure> for <measure n="6months" type="date">six months</measure>, in advance.</p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="4"/>the <rs>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</rs> is issued every <dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> and <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> at <measure n="2.00dollars" type="currency">$2.00</measure>, in advance.</p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="5"/>the <rs>Weekly Dispatch</rs> is issued every <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct>, and mailed to subscribers at <measure n="1dollars" type="currency">$1</measure> per annum.</p> </div1> 
<div1 type="advertising"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="6"/> 
<table rows="4" cols="4"> 
<head rend="italics">Terms of advertising.</head> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <num value="1">1</num> day,</cell><cell><measure n="0.50dollars" type="currency">$0.50</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="5days" type="date">5 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="1.50dollars" type="currency">$1.50</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="2days" type="date">2 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="0.75dollars" type="currency">$0.75</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="5days" type="date">5 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="1.75dollars" type="currency">$1.75</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square <measure n="3days" type="date">3 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="1.00dollars" type="currency">$1.00</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="12days" type="date">12 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="3.00dollars" type="currency">$3.00</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square <measure n="4days" type="date">4 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="1.25dollars" type="currency">$1.25</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <dateStruct value="-1-"><month reg="1">1 month</month></dateStruct>,</cell><cell><measure n="5.00dollars" type="currency">$5.00</measure></cell></row> </table></p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="7"/><hi rend="italics">Larger advertisements in exact properties.</hi></p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="8"/>Advertisements published until forbid, will be charged <measure n="50cents" type="currency">50 cents</measure> per square of <num value="8">eight</num> lines for the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> insertion, and <measure n="25cents" type="currency">25 cents</measure> for each continuance</p> </div1> </front> <body> <milestone unit="column" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="morning"> 
<head><date value="1862-06-24">Tuesday morning...June 24, 1862</date></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>The <rs type="place">Lines</rs>, &#x0026;c.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="9"/>The comparative quiet and peace so long reigning at our lines have not been disturbed for the past few days by any event worthy of more than passing mention; skirmishing has been constant daily at divers points but in no instance have these encounters in <unclear></unclear> timber resulted in anything more than the capture of a few prisoners and the extinction of the enemy's hopes to advance.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="10"/>Great boldness have characterized the doings of our men in those daily adventures &mdash; some few have been rash though to penetrate the outer camps of the foe and having driven everything before them returned <unclear></unclear> trophies of every imaginable description.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="11"/>Brave and characteristic as these episodes were, they have all been discountenanced by officers, and properly so; for picket duty is dangerous enough in it self, and does not call for or need (save by orders) any of these dashing feats commendable and common on the battle field.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="12"/>But not only in the infantry arm of the service have our men proved themselves superior to the foe &mdash; the artillery have amused themselves greatly, and practiced with much accuracy and effect upon the numerous breast, field, and born works thrown up on the <rs>Federal</rs> front.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="13"/>Since <persName n="Dabney,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00005" reg="mostcommon:Dabney,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Capt.</roleName> <surname>Dabney</surname></persName>'s efforts on <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> last, with heavy pieces, which caused a indecorous stampede from Federate artillery and infantry camps it was surmised that their obnoxious presence would no longer disgrace the lovely face of the landscape on the north bank of the <placeName reg="Chickahominy, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,1122759">Chickahominy</placeName> yet, numerous and impudent as ever, they again appeared in working parties on <dateStruct><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> and <dateStruct><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct>, presenting fair scope and practice for some artillerists, who, moving deliberately to the front, near <placeName><persName n="Garnett,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00006" reg="mostcommon:Garnett,nomatch:0"><surname>Garnett</surname></persName>'s farm</placeName>, shelled the enemy from their excavations, and expedited their departure from the knolls and woods with much effect.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="14"/>Shell from our pieces could be plainly seen bursting among the enemy, and although they bravely withstood our <unclear></unclear> for some short time, expecting the arrival of <orgName type="mil" key="USArtillery">U. S. artillery</orgName>, no relief came, and they laudably imitated the race of their friends on <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> last.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="15"/>The artillery of the enemy, though admirably worked and served when not face to face with ours is handled with uncommon willness and imprecision when any of our batteries appear to dispute the ground.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="16"/>Hence little damage is usually done, and the cost or results is merely a useless expenditure of powder.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="17"/>Brisk artillery fire was maintained by the foe upon our outposts on the <placeName reg="Mechanicville, Terrebonne, Louisiana" key="tgn,2504620">Mechanicville</placeName> road yesterday, but, although the range of some half dozen shells was determined with great mathematical nicety, a few fell harmlessly, unexploded, while the fragment of another slightly wounded a negro employed upon some <num value="1">one</num> of our works.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="18"/><num value="2">Two</num> shells damaged <num value="1">one</num> of our breast works slightly, but more than this no damage was done in this quarter. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="19"/> Dense columns of smoke were ascending over the enemy's position yesterday &mdash; various reasons when assigned for this unusual spectacle, but the true cause is best known to those of our chiefs in commend.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="20"/>It would not be wise in us, perhaps, even to hazard a conjecture. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="21"/> We are informed that some of our officers, detailed on picket service, have shown themselves negligent and blameworthy, insomuch that either from carelessness or ignorance of the grounds, picket parties from different regiments have fired at each other and in <num value="1">one</num> instance with loss.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="22"/>Any <hi rend="italics">faur pas</hi> of this nature, within the immediate neighborhood of the enemy is worthy of comment and punishment.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="23"/>If the topography of the place is not known to officers encamped within gunshot, for weeks together, and useless mortality ensue from want of this requisite information, how can it be expected that these came officers will successfully handle or man&#x0153;uvre forces &mdash; If only companies &mdash; on these same grounds, should exigencies require it at any moment of night or day ? It is time such negligence should cease.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="24"/>Our loss was more than necessary at <persName n="Lines,,Yorktown,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00007" reg="default:Lines,Yorktown,,,"><foreName>Yorktown</foreName> <surname>Lines</surname></persName>, from this same cause.--Lives are too precious to be uselessly sacrificed in this manner, and any mal-administration of officers should be severely punished. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="25"/> Indications of activity and liveliness prevail in all our camps &mdash; bustle, good humor, and buoyancy it seen in every action, and marked on every feature &mdash; orderlies dash to and fro: solemn and dusty <rs type="role2">Colonels</rs>, and others, are all found at their posts, and while all is industry beyond the city, what a reproach is this to the tinselled butterflies, gandy in color and braid, lounging about at pillar and post frothy in warlike speech, but loth to manly action? </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="26"/> A few days,--nay, a few hours, perhaps,--are brought with the fates of centuries.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="27"/>Let all be men and manly in the days to come &mdash; of our noble army nought need now be said &mdash; but it is of those worthless harpies we wish to add a word &mdash; of those reprobates who inveigle the unsophisticated soldier into gambling hells, and fleece from them the last few peace of hard-earned money.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="28"/>Shall the noble youths of our gallant Southern army shed their blood freely on the battle field, and these disreputable be allowed to infect hotels, disgrace the side walk, and keep open gambling holes under the very nose of all civil and military law?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="29"/>They have cast their lines in pleasant places, but were all such marched to the <rs type="place">Lines</rs>, of which we daily speak, it would be far more profitable to morality and the public weal. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head>The substitute trade.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="30"/> A few days ago we alluded to the immense frauds and villainy being carried on in this city in buying and selling substitutes by men who make a regular business of the nefarious trade.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="31"/>Although frequently spoken of and condemned by this paper and others, the evil still continues, and, if anything, is rather on the increase.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="32"/>It should be put a stop to by the authorities, and some of the swindlers, both the men who furnish them, and the substitutes themselves, who sell their service with the deliberate intention of deserting as soon as the purchase money is safely in their pockets, summarily punished.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="33"/>Too strong terms cannot be used in condemnation of this pernicious practice.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="34"/>It has a bad influence upon the army, for it these rascals can elude the service, and desert when they please without being punished, why cannot other do the same?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="35"/>Another case has come to our knowledge.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="36"/>A few days ago a man by the name of Levasseur went to the <orgName type="regiment" key="3ALRegiment">3d Alabama regiment</orgName> and bargained to furnish a substitute for a man then in service.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="37"/>The price fixed upon was $<unclear><num value="00">00</num></unclear> the dealer in substitutes receiving <measure n="300dollars" type="currency">$300</measure> for his services.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="38"/>The man's name was <persName n="Byrnes,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00008" reg="mostcommon:Byrnes,nomatch:0"><surname>Byrnes</surname></persName> who came with a certificate from the <rs>British Consul</rs> and recommendations from others; but as soon as the bargain was concluded, the substitute absconded, returning, probably, to the person who originally brought him to be sold over to other parties.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="39"/>With in the last <measure n="3weeks" type="date">three weeks</measure> <num value="7">seven</num> men from this <num value="1">one</num> regiment alone have been purchased, all of whom have since deserted.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="40"/>Such conduct is no more or less than stealing, and it is time due check should be put upon such operations by the police.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="41"/>The <hi rend="italics">morate</hi> of such conduct is bad, and, if allowed to go on, our army will be reduced very materially. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head>Unclaimed goods.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="42"/> The sale of unclaimed goods advertised in our columns by the <orgName n="Southern Express Company" type="company">Southern Express Company</orgName> did not come off yesterday, and, indeed, another advertisement by the company showed that the sale had been postponed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="43"/>This course has been pursued, we feel satisfied, because many of the packages belong to soldiers now stationed in different parts of the <rs>Confederacy</rs> and unable to call for them at the present time.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="44"/>With a vast number of packages, of different sizes, many of them large and occupying considerable room, it will be seen that it requires a large storehouse to hold them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="45"/>All the available space at the disposal of the company is being rapidly filled, and it becomes necessary to impress that fact upon the owners of boxes now in their hands, that they may be removed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="46"/>The object of advertising the goods at sanction was to induce, if possible, the owners to remove them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="47"/>This has been done in a measure, but many still remain. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">The fight on <persName n="James,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00009" reg="mostcommon:James,nomatch:0"><surname>James</surname></persName> <num value="1" type="ordinal">1st</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="48"/>And.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="49"/> --It has been ascertained that the enemy's loss on <placeName reg="James Island, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,2418933">James Island</placeName> is much larger than at <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> reported.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="50"/>Up to <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Wednesday</day></dateStruct> <time>evening</time> <num value="251">251</num> bodies had been interred by our men and their ambulances were allowed to remove their wounded.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="51"/>The probability is that their loss in killed, wounded, and prisoners, will reach <num value="1000">one thousand</num>. </p> </div3> <milestone unit="column" n="2"/> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head>The battle on <placeName reg="James Island, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,2418933">James Island</placeName>.<lb/><hi rend="italics">brilliant Confederate victory.</hi></head> <byline>[correspondence of the <orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.]</byline> <opener> <dateline> <name type="place">Charleston,</name> <date value="1862-06-20">June 20, 1862.</date> </dateline> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="52"/>The late battle in the vicinity of this city was a far more brilliant and important affair than at <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> supposed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="53"/>The enemy were so badly beaten that they have not fired a shot from their gunboats or batteries since, though previous to the fight they kept up a constant cannonade day and right.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="54"/>Considering the number of troops engaged on our side, and the length and fierceness of the combat, the battle is <num value="1">one</num> of the most remarkable of the war. The rout of the invaders was complete.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="55"/>They abandoned their dead and fled in wild confusion to their gunboats.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="56"/>Tow of their regiments &mdash; the <orgName type="regiment" key="NY79">79th New York</orgName>, (Highlanders,) and <num value="1">one</num> from <placeName reg="Michigan" key="tgn,7007520">Michigan</placeName>, fought well.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="57"/><num value="1">One</num> company of the former penetrated as far as our breastworks, and its captain was killed while mounting them aparts.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="58"/>The enemy had <num value="5">five</num> regiments in the fight.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="59"/>Our force engaged consisted of <num value="3">three</num> companies of <orgName type="mil" key="SCArtillery">South Carolina artillery</orgName>--the <orgName n="Charleston Battalion" type="battalion">Charleston battalion</orgName>, which numbered only <num value="150">150</num> men; the <rs>Eutaw</rs> battalion, <num value="400">400</num> strong.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="60"/>and <orgName n="LA battalion"><persName n="MeEnery,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00010" reg="mostcommon:MeEnery,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>MeEnery</surname></persName>'s Louisiana battalion</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="61"/>Other regiments came to the relief of these troops; but most of the fighting was already over.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="62"/>It will be seen, therefore, that the enemy outnumbered us <num value="2">two</num> or <num value="3">three</num> to <num value="1">one</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="63"/>Their greatest loss was occasioned in attempting to storm our entrenchments, behind which <orgName n="artillery"><persName n="Lamer,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00011" reg="mostcommon:Lamer,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Lamer</surname></persName>'s artillery</orgName> was stationed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="64"/><persName n="Lamar,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00012" reg="mostcommon:Lamar,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Lamar</surname></persName> was the hero of the battle.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="65"/>He was severely wounded.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="66"/><persName n="McEnery,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00013" reg="mostcommon:McEnery,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>McEnery</surname></persName> also deserves great praise.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="67"/>He led his Louisianians fearlessly into the fight, with the watchword, <q>&#x0022;Remember <persName n="Butler,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00014" reg="mostcommon:Butler,nomatch:0"><surname>Butler</surname></persName>.&#x0022;</q> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="68"/> Every day's exploration of the surrounding woods reveals additional dead of the enemy.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="69"/>It has been ascertained that a body of the <rs>Federals</rs> attempted to cross a swamp, where many of them stuck fast in the mud and were killed and wounded by our shells.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="70"/>Finally, the tide came up and drowned both dead and wounded.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="71"/><num value="250">Two hundred and fifty</num> of the enemy have already been buried by our troops, and <num value="50">fifty</num> additional dead bodies were discovered yesterday.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="72"/>The total loss of the enemy in the battle cannot be far from-- </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="73"/> 
<table rows="11" cols="2"> 
<head></head> 
<row><cell>Killed and left on the field</cell><cell><num value="300">300</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell>Taken prisoners</cell><cell><num value="130">130</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell>Wounded and dead carried off of the field, estimated at</cell><cell><num value="700">700</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell>Total loss of the enemy</cell><cell><num value="1130">1130</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell>The Confederate loss in this glorious victory is --Killed</cell><cell><num value="48">48</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell>Wounded</cell><cell><num value="106">106</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell>Total Confederate loss</cell><cell><num value="154">154</num></cell></row> </table> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="74"/>The enemy's attack was a surprise to our troops.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="75"/>Had a competent Confederate General been on the field and some plan of action arranged, the whole of the enemy's attacking force might have been cut off. As it was the greater part of the battle was fought by the rank and file <q>&#x0022;on their own book.&#x0022;</q> We have <num value="4">four</num> Confederate <rs type="role2">Generals</rs> in this quarter, but not <num value="1">one</num> was in command.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="76"/>To the rank and file, then, be the glory given of having achieved <num value="1">one</num> of the most brilliant successes of the war. If the <orgName n="Confederate Government" type="org">Confederate Government</orgName> is looking for material for more.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="77"/><rs type="role" reg="Brigadier-General">Brigadier Generals</rs>, let promotion fall upon the lion hearted <persName n="Lamar,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00015" reg="mostcommon:Lamar,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Lamar</surname></persName>, who defended the entrenchments and the gallant and chivalrous <persName n="McEnery,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00016" reg="mostcommon:McEnery,nomatch:0"><surname>McEnery</surname></persName>, who, like <persName n="Blucher,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00017" reg="mostcommon:Blucher,nomatch:0"><surname>Blucher</surname></persName>, came into the field just in the nick of time. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="78"/> Since the battle, the enemy have been entrenching themselves silently at the lower end of <placeName reg="Juices Island">Juices Island</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="79"/>As their plan of assault has proved impracticable, it is presumed they will be contented here after to advance by regular approaches &mdash; that is. If they are permitted to do so. Prisoners state that there are <num value="9">nine</num> Federal regiments on the island, and that <persName n="Stevens,General,Isaac,I.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00018" reg="default:Stevens,Isaac,I.,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <foreName>Isaac</foreName> <foreName>I.</foreName> <surname>Stevens</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Oregon" key="tgn,7007708">Oregon</placeName>, (the <rs>Chairman</rs> of the <name>Breckinridge</name> <orgName n="National Committee" type="committee">National Committee</orgName> in the last Presidential campaign.) is in command.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="80"/>This man <persName n="Stevens,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00019" reg="nearbymention:Stevens,Isaac,I.,,"><surname>Stevens</surname></persName> processed to be an ardent pro slavery man before the war, and was here in <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName>, enjoying its hospitalities, only <measure n="2years" type="date">two years</measure> ago. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="81"/>There is much dissatisfaction here with the military authorities of the department, and a strong wish expressed for a change in the <rs type="role" reg="commanding-Officer">commanding officer</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="82"/>The <placeName reg="South Carolina" key="tgn,7007712">South Carolina</placeName> troops are anxious to defend <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName>, and will do so successfully if they are permitted to. A report that we were to have the great services of <persName n="Beauregard,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00020" reg="nearbymention:Beauregard,G.,T.,,"><surname>Beauregard</surname></persName> spread universal joy among the troops.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="83"/>If however, we cannot have <persName n="Beauregard,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00021" reg="nearbymention:Beauregard,G.,T.,,"><surname>Beauregard</surname></persName>, we would be glad to get <persName n="Huger,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00022" reg="mostcommon:Huger,nomatch:0"><surname>Huger</surname></persName>, <persName n="Magruder,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00023" reg="mostcommon:Magruder,nomatch:0"><surname>Magruder</surname></persName>, <persName n="Hill,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00024" reg="mostcommon:Hill,nomatch:0"><surname>Hill</surname></persName> of <placeName reg="North Carolina" key="tgn,7007709">N. C.</placeName>, <persName n="Whiting,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00025" reg="mostcommon:Whiting,nomatch:0"><surname>Whiting</surname></persName>, <persName n="Gregg,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00026" reg="mostcommon:Gregg,nomatch:0"><surname>Gregg</surname></persName>, <persName n="Anderson,,Joseph,R.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00027" reg="default:Anderson,Joseph,R.,,"><foreName>Joseph</foreName> <foreName>R.</foreName> <surname>Anderson</surname></persName>, or any other <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> class General.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="84"/><unclear></unclear> change of some kind is necessary to restore confidence to the troops and people. </p> <closer> <signed><placeName key="tgn,2020752" n="1.000 1" reg="palmetto, manatee, florida">Palmetto</placeName>.</signed> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Operations on the river.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="85"/> --On <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> last, <num value="2">two</num> Federal gunboats came up <placeName key="tgn,7013964;tgn,1125114" n="0.164 000000.3273	placename;tgn,7013964;Richmond, Richmond, Virginia,Richmond,Virginia,United States,North and Central America;0.164 000000.3273	placename;tgn,1125114;James River, Virginia, Virginia,Virginia,United States,North and Central America" reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia,Richmond,Virginia,United States,North and Central America;James River, Virginia, Virginia,Virginia,United States,North and Central America">James river</placeName> to the neighborhood of <placeName reg="Drury's Bluff">Drury's Bluff</placeName>, and commenced shelling the woods on the <rs>Chesterfield</rs> side.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="86"/>The boats were opened upon by <orgName n="battery"><persName n="French,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00028" reg="mostcommon:French,Harriet,,,:1"><roleName n="Captain">Capt.</roleName> <surname>French</surname></persName>'s battery</orgName>, from <placeName reg="Stafford, Virginia" key="tgn,1002913">Stafford county</placeName>, and a spirited engagement was kept up for <measure n="2hours" type="date">two hours</measure> or more.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="87"/>It is believed that the boats sustained considerable damage, for they finally gave up the contest and started off down the river.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="88"/>The only injury sustained on our side was by the bursting of a gun, which seriously wounded Wm. D <persName n="Jackson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00029" reg="mostcommon:Jackson,Stonewall,,,:1"><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>, of <persName n="Stafford,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00030" reg="mostcommon:Stafford,nomatch:0"><surname>Stafford</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="89"/> It is stated that the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs>, in considerable force, have taken possession of <placeName reg="Claremont, Sullivan, New Hampshire" key="tgn,2063314">Claremont</placeName>, the fine river plantation of <persName n="Allen,Major,William,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00031" reg="default:Allen,William,,,"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <foreName n="William">Wm.</foreName> <surname>Allen</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="90"/>Whether their object is simply plunder, or a demonstration upon some point higher up the river, time will determine. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="7"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Brown,,Neil,S.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00032" reg="default:Brown,Neil,S.,,"><foreName>Neil</foreName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <surname>Brown</surname></persName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="91"/> --The <orgName n="Knoxville Register" type="newspaper">Knoxville <hi rend="italics">Register</hi></orgName> relates an incident which followed <persName n="Brown,,Neil,S.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00033" reg="default:Brown,Neil,S.,,"><foreName>Neil</foreName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <surname>Brown</surname></persName>'s apostasy, which was calculated to bring a blush to the cheeks of the most hardened renegade.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="92"/><persName n="Brown,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00034" reg="nearbymention:Brown,Neil,S.,,"><surname>Brown</surname></persName> has <num value="3">three</num> sons; <num value="2">two</num> of them are in the <orgName n="Confederate Army" type="org">Confederate army</orgName>, and <num value="1">one</num>, a youth of about <num value="15">fifteen</num>, was at home.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="93"/>Upon hearing of his father's making a Union speech, this noble lad sought him, and hearing the confirmation from his own lips, not only expressed his indignation, but declared he could never again set foot beneath the parental roof, but would join his brothers in defence of the <rs>South</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="94"/>It is said he has kept his word. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="8"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Our cause in <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName></head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="95"/> --From an article in a late number of the <orgName n="Louisville Democrat" type="newspaper">Louisville <hi rend="italics">Democrat</hi></orgName>, it appears that the spirit of <q>&#x0022;rebellion&#x0022;</q> is yet alive in <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="96"/>A correspondent of that paper, writing from <placeName key="tgn,2037994" n="1.000 4" reg="burkesville, cumberland, kentucky">Burkesville</placeName>, <date value="05-29">May 29,</date> says: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="97"/> &#x0022;Our town is again full of Secesh, numbering about <num value="125">one hundred and twenty-five</num>, under the command of <persName n="Ferguson,,Champ,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00035" reg="default:Ferguson,Champ,,,"><foreName>Champ</foreName> <surname>Ferguson</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="98"/>It is impossible to tell what depredations they will commit on this visit, since they were shot at by <num value="5">five</num> or <num value="6">six</num> Union soldiers, who chanced to be in town at the time they came in. <persName n="Ferguson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00036" reg="nearbymention:Ferguson,Champ,,,"><surname>Ferguson</surname></persName> has placed a guard around the bank, and swears that he will clean out the whole concern &mdash; books, money, bills of exchange, and all included.&#x0022; </p> </q><bibl n="Burkesville,"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="99"/> We subjoin an extract from the <rs>Louisville</rs> <hi rend="italics">Bulletin.</hi> showing that somebody in the <rs>West</rs> is supplying the <q>&#x0022;rebels&#x0022;</q> with powder: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="100"/> The <orgName n="Cincinnati Commercial" type="newspaper">Cincinnati <hi rend="italics">Commercial</hi></orgName> says, that during the past few weeks larger quantities of gunpowder have been shipped over the <orgName n="Kentucky Central Railroad" type="railroad">Kentucky Central railroad</orgName> than during the terrible month of preparation in the early history of the rebellion, and the wonder is that it is allowed to go on unchecked.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="101"/>The Surveyor of Customs at <placeName reg="Covington, Kenton, Kentucky" key="tgn,7014762">Covington</placeName> has grown alarmed at the increased shipments of this article, and has very properly refused to allow any more to pass through without permits from the <rs type="place">Custom House</rs>, <placeName reg="Cincinnati, Hamilton, Ohio" key="tgn,7013604">Cincinnati</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="102"/>The description of powder shipped is that used for blasting, but that is the same which is used for cannon, and there can be no doubt that little individual shipments of from <num value="2">two</num> to <measure n="6kegs" type="mass">six kegs</measure> go to swell the aggregate, now large in the rebel portions of the <rs>State</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="103"/><num value="1">One</num> fact is significant, and that is that all the recent shipments have been to well-known rebel sympathizers in the interior, while staunch Union men find no trade for the article, probably because rebels would hardly apply to them for an article the use of which is so unequivocal. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="9"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Ingress,Lady,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00037" reg="mostcommon:Ingress,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lady">Ladies</roleName> <surname>Ingress</surname></persName> cotton.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="104"/> --A correspondent of the <rs>Atlanta</rs> <hi rend="italics">Confederacy,</hi> writing from <placeName key="tgn,2112877" n="1.000 541" reg="manassas, manassas, virginia">Manassas</placeName>, <placeName reg="Bartow, Georgia, United States" key="tgn,2000299">Bartow county</placeName>, Ca., <date value="06-14">June 14th,</date> says: </p> <cit><q> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="105"/> The ladies are truly a great institution.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="106"/>The sufferings of our patriot soldiers arouse all their sympathies and tender feelings, for whom they undergo fatigue and trouble scarcely to be expected of the softer sex. But when occasion makes it necessary, they can show themselves made of sterner stuff than sighs and tears.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="107"/>This was illustrated by a party of ladies at <placeName reg="Cass Depot">Cass Depot</placeName> in this county, today.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="108"/>A gentleman of <placeName key="tgn,2112877" n="1.000 541" reg="manassas, manassas, virginia">Manassas</placeName> who now and then indulges in little speculations, had a few bales of cotton at the depot, a part of which the wives of some absent soldiers said they greatly needed.--They proposed to the owner to purchase what they wanted, but as they did not wish so much as a bag, he declined to let them have it. They told him they would take it; and in compliance with promise thus made to him, they went to the depot, called for the agent as a witness of their doings, and cut the rope from <num value="1">one</num> bale, took what they needed, and marched very, quietly home with it. I believe they propose to pay the owner fair compensation. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="109"/> So you see <hi rend="italics">some</hi> of the women of <placeName key="tgn,2018528" n="1.000 2" reg="bartow, polk, florida">Bartow</placeName> are <hi rend="italics">beat</hi> on having cotton.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="110"/>I do not want this to express approval or disapproval of the act, but merely to relate the circumstance. </p> </q><bibl n="Manassas, Bartow"></bibl></cit> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="10"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Extensive hanging.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="111"/> --<num value="7">Seven</num> bridge-burners were executed near <placeName reg="Atlanta, Fulton, Georgia" key="tgn,7013331">Atlanta, Ga.</placeName>, on the <dateStruct value="--18"><day reg="18">18th inst.</day></dateStruct> Arrangements had been made for them all to be swung off at the same time, but <num value="2">two</num> of the ropes breaking the men fell to the ground instead of into eternity.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="112"/>But these <num value="2">two</num> were quickly brought to their feet, new ropes adjusted to their necks, and an end at once put to their earthly career. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="113"/> The old cotton factory in <placeName reg="Lincolnton, Lincoln, North Carolina" key="tgn,2075467">Lincolnton, N. C.</placeName>, was burned down last week, involving a loss of some <measure n="40000dollars" type="currency">$40,000</measure>. It was the property of <persName n="Childs,,L.,D.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00038" reg="default:Childs,L.,D.,,"><foreName>L.</foreName> <foreName>D.</foreName> <surname>Childs</surname></persName> and <persName n="Hoke,,W.,J.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00039" reg="default:Hoke,W.,J.,,"><foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>J.</foreName> <surname>Hoke</surname></persName>. </p> </div3> <milestone unit="column" n="3"/> 
<div3 type="article" n="12"> 
<head><orgName n="regiment"><persName n="Rates,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00040" reg="mostcommon:Rates,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Colonel</roleName> <surname>Rates</surname></persName>'s regiment</orgName> at the<lb/><rs n="Battle of Shiloh" type="battle">battle of Shiloh</rs>.</head> <byline><hi rend="italics">[from an Occasional correspondent.]</hi></byline> <opener> <dateline> <name type="place">Montgomery, Ala.,</name> <date value="1862-06-07">June 7, 1862.</date> </dateline> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="114"/> While <persName n="Beauregard,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00041" reg="nearbymention:Beauregard,G.,T.,,"><surname>Beauregard</surname></persName> and I were gaining that brilliant victory at <placeName key="tgn,7017649" n="1.000 1055" reg="corinth, alcorn, mississippi">Corinth</placeName>, without fighting or letting the enemy or our own army know anything about it, I was gathering materials for a history of the <rs n="Battle of Shiloh" type="battle">battle of Shiloh</rs> from some of the heroic actors and survivors of that bloody, brilliant day. I am not joking about <persName n="Beauregard,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00042" reg="nearbymention:Beauregard,G.,T.,,"><surname>Beauregard</surname></persName>'s <q>&#x0022;victory,&#x0022;</q> because the retreat was a great triumph, if measured by its success, and the injury and loss inflicted on the enemy, which some of them, in spite of <persName n="Halleck,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00043" reg="mostcommon:Halleck,nomatch:0"><surname>Halleck</surname></persName>'s lies, have had the grace to confess.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="115"/>We certainly <q>&#x0022;surprised&#x0022;</q> them, as well as ourselves.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="116"/>We lost some of our sick, who, in consequence of the <q>&#x0022;fall back.&#x0022;</q> of course had a <q>&#x0022;relapse. &#x0022;</q> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="117"/> But, as to <placeName reg="Shiloh, Hardin, Tennessee" key="tgn,2101495">Shiloh</placeName>, many incidents we hear daily which illustrate the undying (?) devotion of our soldiers to our holy cause, and prove how idle is the empty hope of Northern hordes to conquer by superior numbers the gallant army we oppose to them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="118"/>Let me furnish an example in a hurried recital of the brave deeds of <num value="1">one</num> regiment, which was among the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> to rush from.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="119"/><placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName> to the border of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>, where, for <measure n="10months" type="date">ten months</measure>, it labored and endured; and many of its officers endeared themselves to the people of <placeName reg="Fredericksburg, Fredericksburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013943">Fredericksburg</placeName>, and that section of our State.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="120"/>I allude to the <orgName type="regiment" key="Regiment 2">2nd regiment of <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName></orgName> <orgName type="mil" key="TNVolunteer">Tennessee Volunteers</orgName>, commanded by <persName n="Bates,Colonel,W.,B.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00044" reg="default:Bates,W.,B.,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Colonel</roleName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>B.</foreName> <surname>Bates</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="121"/>It was called a rebel regiment, tendered before <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName> had yet seceded, and in service in <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> before its members had voted in camp in favor of secession.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="122"/>A noble regiment it was &mdash; its officers and men of the flower of <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName>--gentlemen of position, wealth and character, and numbering more than <num value="1000">1,000</num> strong.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="123"/>I select it for another reason.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="124"/>After <placeName reg="East Nashville, Davidson, Tennessee" key="tgn,2308580">Nashville</placeName> had fallen and <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName> had been abandoned, it was asserted that some of the <measure n="12months" type="date">twelve months</measure> volunteers had deserted, and consequent unjust criticism was indulged in by indiscreet partisans of regiments from other States.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="125"/>Indeed the foolish were often guilty of absurd comparisons and harsh judgments upon soldiers from the several States, instead of urging each to do its duty and encouraging a noble rivalry to excel.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="126"/><q>&#x0022;Place my regiment,&#x0022; </q> said a gallant <persName n="Colonel,,Tennessee,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00045" reg="default:Colonel,Tennessee,,,"><foreName>Tennessee</foreName> <surname>Colonel</surname></persName> to <persName n="Johnston,General,Sidney,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00046" reg="default:Johnston,Sidney,,,"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <foreName>Sidney</foreName> <surname>Johnston</surname></persName>, <num value="2">two</num> evenings before the battle, <q>&#x0022;in the presence of our own noble Governor, between a Mississippi and an Alabama regiment, and I will show you that Tennessean will lead where any will dare follow. &#x0022;</q> Tersely was the promise fulfilled at <placeName reg="Shiloh, Hardin, Tennessee" key="tgn,2101495">Shiloh</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="127"/><orgName n="regiment"><persName n="Bates,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00047" reg="nearbymention:Bates,W.,B.,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Bates</surname></persName>'s regiment</orgName> was ordered to a position where a double duty was required, which I have not the military terms to explain.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="128"/>However, in obeying the order they found themselves under the fire of a battery and <num value="5">five</num> regiments of the enemy's infantry.--Undismayed these gallant Tennesseeans charge the superior force and fire upon them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="129"/>Enfiladed by the enemy's fire, <num value="1">one</num> <num value="4" type="ordinal">fourth</num> of this apparently doomed battalion fall at the very onset.--Their brave and heroic <persName n="Doak,Major,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00048" reg="mostcommon:Doak,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <surname>Doak</surname></persName> reels from his horse, and before yet a friend can reach him to catch his dying words, life had fled forever.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="130"/>I've company commanders, <num value="3">three</num> of whom died instantly, and the others prostrated by the severity of their wounds, fell at the same time,--also, <num value="4">four</num> <rs type="role2">Lieutenants</rs>, <num value="2">two</num> of whom were killed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="131"/>Then came the terrific grandeur of this scene of carnage.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="132"/>Quickly rallied by their gallant <rs type="role2">Colonel</rs>, in view of their dead and dying comrades, the survivors form a line as coolly as on dress parade.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="133"/>The <rs>Colonel</rs> appoints officers in place of the fallen.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="134"/>They follow him, and in view of the brigade which had then come to their assistance, they charge and take the battery which was hurling its tempest of fire and hail upon them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="135"/>In this charge <persName n="Bates,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00049" reg="nearbymention:Bates,W.,B.,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Bates</surname></persName> fell severely wounded, and though comrade after comrade falls around them, they pursue their deadly purpose, and drive the superior forces of the enemy before them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="136"/>Notwithstanding all this loss &mdash; <rs type="role2">Colonel</rs>, <rs type="role" n="Major">Major</rs>, half their <rs type="role2">Captains</rs>, many <rs type="role2">Lieutenants</rs>, and <num value="1">one</num>-<num value="4" type="ordinal">fourth</num> the rank and file killed and wounded &mdash; on they fought all that day and the next under command of their chivalric <persName n="Goodall,Lieutenant-Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00050" reg="mostcommon:Goodall,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lieutenant-Colonel">Lieut. Col.</roleName> <surname>Goodall</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="137"/> <num value="1">One</num> melancholy incident shows how whole families fall victims and sacrifices in this war. <persName n="Bate,Captain,Humphrey,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00051" reg="default:Bate,Humphrey,,,"><roleName n="Captain">Captain</roleName> <foreName>Humphrey</foreName> <surname>Bate</surname></persName><unclear></unclear> of <placeName reg="Sumber county">Sumber county</placeName>, was shot down in the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> charge, gallantly leading his men. <num value="4">Four</num> of his relatives were killed or wounded.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="138"/>His brother-in-law, <persName n="Tyree,Captain,Joseph,P.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00052" reg="default:Tyree,Joseph,P.,,"><roleName n="Captain">Captain</roleName> <foreName n="Joseph">Jos.</foreName> <foreName>P.</foreName> <surname>Tyree</surname></persName>, was instantly killed at his side.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="139"/>His brother, <persName n="Bates,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00053" reg="nearbymention:Bates,W.,B.,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Bates</surname></persName>, fell wounded in the leg. Side by side, upon the same couch, lay these <num value="2">two</num> brothers, <num value="1">one</num> mortally, the other dangerously wounded.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="140"/>But before the battle is over, the affecting conversation between them ceases, and the <rs>Captain</rs>'s lifeless body tells the <rs>Colonel</rs> that death has closed all communion upon earth.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="141"/>It is singular that <persName n="Doak,Major,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00054" reg="mostcommon:Doak,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major">Maj.</roleName> <surname>Doak</surname></persName>'s only brother, in another regiment was also killed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="142"/><rs type="role">Lieut.</rs> Commanding <persName n="Collins,,N.,D.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00055" reg="default:Collins,N.,D.,,"><foreName>N.</foreName> <foreName>D.</foreName> <surname>Collins</surname></persName> was wounded.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="143"/><persName n="Charlton,Lieutenant,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00056" reg="mostcommon:Charlton,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lieutenant">Lieut.</roleName> <surname>Charlton</surname></persName> lost an arm. Time fails me to record other names of officers and privates, whose conspicuous gallantry deserves honorable mention.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="144"/>Enough has been said to prove that the friends of this regiment in <placeName reg="Virginia" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> and <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName> were not mistaken in their high estimate of its courage and good conduct.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="145"/>A <rs n="Virginian" type="group">Virginian</rs>. <persName n="Akers,Lieutenant,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00057" reg="mostcommon:Akers,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lieutenant">Lieut.</roleName> <surname>Akers</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Lynchburg, Lynchburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013981">Lynchburg</placeName>, belonged to <orgName type="company" n="Company A">Co. A</orgName>.--He was reported killed, but I accidentally learned in <placeName reg="Columbus, Hickman, Kentucky" key="tgn,2038271">Columbus</placeName> form <num value="1">one</num> of our escaped surgeons that he accompanied Lieut. A. to <placeName reg="Cincinnati, Hamilton, Ohio" key="tgn,7013604">Cincinnati</placeName> as prisoner, and he was recovering from his wound and doing well <measure n="3weeks" type="date">three weeks</measure> after the fight.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="146"/>I expect to have the pleasure of communicating this to his father on my return to <placeName reg="Lynchburg, Lynchburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013981">Lynchburg</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="147"/><persName n="Bates,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00058" reg="nearbymention:Bates,W.,B.,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Bates</surname></persName>'s many friends in <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> will be pleased to learn that he has not lost his leg, and is doing well in <placeName reg="Columbus, Hickman, Kentucky" key="tgn,2038271">Columbus, Miss.</placeName>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="148"/>His abilities, as well as his services, richly entitle him to promotion. </p> <closer> <signed>L.</signed> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="13"> 
<head>The execution in New Orleans.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="149"/> The miserable hireling <persName n="Butler,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00059" reg="mostcommon:Butler,nomatch:0"><surname>Butler</surname></persName> is playing the tyrant with a high hand.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="150"/>His savage instincts are far ahead of the most ferocious native of <placeName key="tgn,1000160" n="1.000 1" reg="benin">Dahomey</placeName> or <placeName key="tgn,7016766" n="1.000 1" reg="patagonia,argentina,south america">Patagonia</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="151"/>A week or <num value="2">two</num> since, as our readers have already been informed, he had <persName n="Mumford,,William,B.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00060" reg="default:Mumford,William,B.,,"><foreName n="William">Wm.</foreName> <foreName>B.</foreName> <surname>Mumford</surname></persName> executed for tearing down the flag hoisted on the <name>Mint</name> by <persName n="Farragut,Commander,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00061" reg="mostcommon:Farragut,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Commander">Com.</roleName> <surname>Farragut</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="152"/>He died as a patriot should die &mdash; with great coolness and self possession.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="153"/>An instant before he passed into the presence of his Maker he was calm in his demeanor, and on his countenance could be found no trace of the ordeal he was passing through. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="154"/> Commenting upon the execution, the black hearted scribbler in the <hi rend="italics"><placeName key="tgn,2042638" n="1.000 1" reg="delta, louisiana">Delta</placeName></hi> has the following remarks, which we copy because it speaks the sentiments of the <rs>Nero Butler</rs>, and to show the vapid and sickening stuff now in the once eloquent Southern <hi rend="italics"><placeName key="tgn,2042638" n="1.000 1" reg="delta, louisiana">Delta</placeName>:</hi> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="155"/> <persName n="Mumford,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00062" reg="nearbymention:Mumford,William,B.,,"><surname>Mumford</surname></persName>, the ill starred youth, whose name and fate will be a terror to all who are inclined to trilled with the <rs>Government</rs> or its sacred emblems in time to come, justly received the reward of his treason and madness, in presence of <num value="1000">thousands</num> of spectators, as announced in the <hi rend="italics"><placeName key="tgn,2042638" n="1.000 1" reg="delta, louisiana">Delta</placeName> </hi> of last evening.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="156"/>So far as our knowledge extends in the matter, it is the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> instance upon record of a man being tried, found guilty, and executed for laying violent hands upon our national flag, and the lesson it conveys is a solemn, and, we trust, will prove a salutary, <num value="1">one</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="157"/><persName n="Mumford,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00063" reg="nearbymention:Mumford,William,B.,,"><surname>Mumford</surname></persName>, though standing only as a representative of parties equally guilty at heart as himself, had the misfortune to mingle a little more rashness with his treasonable intents than some of his traitor associates, and paid the penalty with his worthless life.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="158"/>It is, perhaps, of very little importance whether this individual, so depraved in his nature, so lost to all sense of patriotism and love of country, be dead or alive, and the recompense of forfeiture which he made in the sacrifice of personal existence, is in no degree a compensation for the insult which he offered a great and magnanimous people, by basely trampling their noble ensign under foot.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="159"/>And the <num value="1000">thousands</num> who witnessed the exit of this miserable person from a life he had disgraced, must have learned, if they had need of such a lesson, that it is most dangerous to set at defiance a Government that from its very nature is self protecting, and will, at all hazards, and under all circumstances, vindicate itself and avenge the insult offered its flag. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="160"/> Deluded men may have flattered themselves that because a rabble or a mob sometimes rules within the narrow limits of some important town or corporation, that there is no power under the <rs>Government</rs> sufficiently potent to arrest their mad career, when their high handed wickedness extends to a violation of symbols sacred to a great and powerful nation; but the example of yesterday must disabuse them of any such fallacy. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="161"/> The hauling down of the flag on the <name>Mint</name> was a much more cowardly act than entering the ranks, in open and armed rebellion; for the perpetrator might well flatter himself that in the absence of those who had either the will or the power to redress the insult at the instant, his escape in the melee of a mob leagued city might be relied upon.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="162"/>But in this he misjudged, and never did justice overtake a criminal more abandoned, or punish a crime more revolting to the sense of every honorable, high minded person.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="163"/>There could be no reprieve from the execution of a sentence so just; and forever after, so long as time shall continue, and the good old national flag floats over the <rs>Union</rs>, as float if will long after the present race of traitors are dead and buried, let him who would violently lay hands upon it to haul it down, count well the cost by remembering the fate of <persName n="Mumford,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00064" reg="nearbymention:Mumford,William,B.,,"><surname>Mumford</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="164"/>And least by your neglect, citizens of New Orleans, some of your children may come to the same bad end, teach them that hauling down the <rs n="American" type="group">American</rs> flag is an act of treason, and is synonymous with death. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="14"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Tod,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00065" reg="mostcommon:Tod,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Tod</surname></persName>'s wish.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="165"/> --A late number of the <orgName n="Cincinnati Commercial" type="newspaper">Cincinnati <hi rend="italics">Commercial</hi></orgName> relates the following of <persName n="Tod,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00066" reg="mostcommon:Tod,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Tod</surname></persName>, the stepmother of <persName n="Lincoln,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00067" reg="nearbymention:Lincoln,Abraham,,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Lincoln</surname></persName>: </p> <cit><q rend ="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="166"/> <rs type="role" reg="Mrs.">Mrs</rs>, <persName n="Tod,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00068" reg="mostcommon:Tod,nomatch:0"><surname>Tod</surname></persName>, resident in <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName>, was present, with a female friend, at the <rs>Horticultural Rooms</rs>, on <dateStruct><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct>, and a conversation there arose between herself and several other persons, among whom was an elderly gentleman, formerly well acquainted with the <rs>Morgan</rs> family &mdash; that of which the notorious <persName n="Morgan,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00069" reg="nearbymention:Morgan,John,,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Colonel</roleName> <surname>Morgan</surname></persName> is a limb &mdash; and the conversation turning upon <persName n="Morgan,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00070" reg="nearbymention:Morgan,John,,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Morgan</surname></persName>, abhorrence of his villainies was expressed by <num value="1">one</num> of the party, when <persName n="Tod,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00071" reg="mostcommon:Tod,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Tod</surname></persName> spoke up, vehemently <q>&#x0022;I wish there were a <num value="1000">thousand</num> like <persName n="Morgan,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00072" reg="default:Morgan,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Morgan</surname></persName>&#x0022;</q> These are her precise words, as given by a gentleman acquainted with all the parties, and to whom they were, as <num value="1">one</num> of the group above alluded to, addressed. </p> </q><bibl n="Cincinnati Commercial"></bibl></cit> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="15"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="167"/> <persName n="Vance,Colonel,Z.,B.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00073" reg="default:Vance,Z.,B.,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Colonel</roleName> <foreName>Z.</foreName> <foreName>B.</foreName> <surname>Vance</surname></persName> consents to be a candidate for the <name>Governorship</name> of <placeName reg="North Carolina" key="tgn,7007709">North Carolina</placeName>. </p> </div3> <milestone unit="column" n="4"/> 
<div3 type="article" n="16"> 
<head>An <q>&#x0022;Exposition.&#x0022;</q></head> 
<argument> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="168"/> what the <rs>Federals</rs> think of the <name>Plans</name> and purposes of the <rs>Confederates</rs>. </p> </argument> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="169"/> The following article is copied from a recent number of the <placeName reg="Shelbyville, Shelby, Kentucky" key="tgn,2041264">Shelbyville (Ky.)</placeName> <hi rend="italics">News.</hi>. Is its perusal <num value="1">one</num> cannot fail to be struck with the wisdom and sagacity of the writer, who seems to predict that more important movements may be looked for within a few days: </p> <cit><q> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="170"/> We do not desire to circulate rumors or fears that will cause excitement or increase the feeling of unrest which has taken possession of so many of our best citizens.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="171"/>But facts are developing which show that traitors are determined to carry out, as far as possible, their deliberately concocted plans to keep the seat of war from their own peculiar soil &mdash; the cotton States.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="172"/>That has been from the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> the leading object of the <rs>Southern</rs> traitors when lead the van in the traitorous attempts to overthrew the <rs>Government</rs> and break up the <rs>Union</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="173"/>Foiled in their earlier attempts to carry out this darling object, new plans were recently formed, and all the energies of the traitors are expected to carry these plans into operation &mdash; partially, if not thoroughly.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="174"/>The measures recently adopted by the traitors, and which they are endeavoring to carry out, may be stated thus: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="175"/> <num value="1">1</num>. Withdraw all the forces from the <rs>Virginia</rs> and <placeName reg="North Carolina" key="tgn,7007709">North Carolina</placeName> coasts, and concentrate them at some central point in <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="176"/>These forces to form <num value="1">one</num> wing of the <orgName n="Confederate Army" type="org">Confederate army</orgName>, to be placed under the command of <persName n="Johnston,,Joseph,E.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00074" reg="default:Johnston,Joseph,E.,,"><foreName>Joseph</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>Johnston</surname></persName>, and to move in the direction of <placeName reg="Pittsburgh, Alleghany, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7013927">Pittsburg, Pennsylvania</placeName>, for the purpose of invading that State. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="177"/> <num value="2">2</num>. Withdraw all forces from the coast of <placeName reg="South Carolina" key="tgn,7007712">South Carolina</placeName> and <placeName reg="Georgia" key="tgn,7007248">Georgia</placeName>, and concentrate them at <placeName reg="Chattanooga, Hamilton, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017496">Chattanooga</placeName>, or some adjacent point.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="178"/>This division to form another wing of the <orgName n="Confederate Army" type="org">Confederate army</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="179"/>under command of <persName n="Lee,,Robert,E.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00075" reg="default:Lee,Robert,E.,,"><foreName>Robert</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>Lee</surname></persName>, and to move in the direction of <placeName reg="Louisville, Jefferson, Kentucky" key="tgn,7013915">Louisville</placeName>, for the purpose of invading <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName> and <placeName reg="Ohio" key="tgn,7007706">Ohio</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="180"/> <num value="3">3</num>. Withdraw the forces from the coast of <placeName reg="Florida" key="tgn,7007240">Florida</placeName> and <placeName reg="Alabama" key="tgn,7002659">Alabama</placeName>, <placeName reg="Mississippi" key="tgn,7007522">Mississippi</placeName>, <placeName reg="Louisiana" key="tgn,7007256">Louisiana</placeName>, <placeName reg="Texas" key="tgn,7007826">Texas</placeName> and <placeName reg="Arkansas" key="tgn,7016172">Arkansas</placeName>, and concentrate them at <placeName key="tgn,7017649" n="1.000 1055" reg="corinth, alcorn, mississippi">Corinth</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="181"/>This wing to be commanded by <persName n="Beauregard,,G.,T.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00076" reg="default:Beauregard,G.,T.,,"><foreName>G.</foreName> <foreName>T.</foreName> <surname>Beauregard</surname></persName>, and to move in the direction of <placeName key="tgn,2040656" n="1.000 206" reg="paducah, mccracken, kentucky">Paducah</placeName>, with the intent of invading <placeName reg="Illinois" key="tgn,7007251">Illinois</placeName> and <placeName reg="Indiana" key="tgn,7007252">Indiana</placeName>. </p> </q><bibl n=""></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="182"/> This plan was formed by a full council of leading traitors.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="183"/>It is unnecessary for us to give the source of our information.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="184"/>Suffice it, that our informant obtained it from a native of this State, and whose name has often been given in the newspapers in the <rs>Southern States</rs> as a trusted and confided agent of the traitors against the <rs>Union</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="185"/>Socially and politically he stood among the most prominent before the rebellion. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="186"/> The objects to be gained in carrying out the plan was <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num>, to secure subsistence, of which there is none, or at least but very little, in the <rs>South</rs>--not enough to supply a lithe of the ordinary demand; and, secondly, to force into their armies all the fighting men. The several commanders were to push forward their forces with all possible dispatch, and possess themselves of all the important military posts on the rivers and in all the loyal States before these posts could be occupied by Federal forces, and thus, while the <rs>Union</rs> armies held and occupied the posts of importance in the <name>States</name> in rebellion, the force of the traitors, would advance into the very heart of the country. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="187"/> We think the reader will agree with us that the recent movements of the forces of the traitors show that this development of their plan is correct.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="188"/>It is true that their attempt in forming the middle wing under <persName n="Lane,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00077" reg="mostcommon:Lane,nomatch:0"><surname>Lane</surname></persName> at <placeName reg="Chattanooga, Hamilton, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017496">Chattanooga</placeName> has been, at least for the present, foiled by the energetic movements of <persName n="McClellan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00078" reg="mostcommon:McClellan,nomatch:0"><surname>McClellan</surname></persName>; but news from <placeName reg="West Virginia" key="tgn,7013961">Western Virginia</placeName> shows that <persName n="Johnston,,Joseph,E.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00079" reg="default:Johnston,Joseph,E.,,"><foreName n="Joseph">Jo.</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>Johnston</surname></persName> is concentrating all the forces he can bring against F&#x0153;mont's command in that direction &mdash; leading directly toward <placeName reg="Pittsburg Landing, Hardin, Tennessee" key="tgn,2586587">Pittsburg</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="189"/>And the evidence is overwhelming that all the forces from those States to constitute <orgName n="army"><persName n="Beauregard,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00080" reg="nearbymention:Beauregard,G.,T.,,"><surname>Beauregard</surname></persName>'s army</orgName> at <placeName key="tgn,7017649" n="1.000 1055" reg="corinth, alcorn, mississippi">Corinth</placeName> are concentrating there rapidly, with the design and hope of overpowering <orgName n="army"><persName n="Halleck,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00081" reg="mostcommon:Halleck,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Halleck</surname></persName>'s army</orgName>, and, if successful in the object, then moving according to their plan.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="190"/>They will, by this means, cause the <rs>Federal</rs> authorities to move an army in that direction to meet them, during which time the traitors will rally by persuasion, impressment, and under the conscription law, to their army every traitor and rebel in <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName> and <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="191"/> With these facts before us we, and the reader also, can see why it is that <persName n="Morgan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00082" reg="nearbymention:Morgan,John,,,"><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>, <persName n="Wood,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00083" reg="mostcommon:Wood,nomatch:0"><surname>Wood</surname></persName>, <persName n="King,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00084" reg="mostcommon:King,nomatch:0"><surname>King</surname></persName> and <persName n="Scott,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00085" reg="mostcommon:Scott,nomatch:0"><surname>Scott</surname></persName>, with their marauding bands, are thrown forward into <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName> and <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="192"/>They are ready to act in gathering up all the <orgName n="Confederate Forces" type="org">Confederate forces</orgName> that can be mustered, fully enforcing the conscript law in the <name>States</name> whenever <persName n="Beauregard,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00086" reg="nearbymention:Beauregard,G.,T.,,"><surname>Beauregard</surname></persName> moves forward, and also to cut off the small detachment of Union forces stationed at various points in <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName> and <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName>, and small bodies that may be sent out. They are, further, to steal and rob, intimidate and despoil loyal citizens, and act in conjunction with the traitors in the various communities in suppressing the <rs>Union</rs> element, and giving encouragement to the drooping spirits of the secession traitors. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="17"> 
<head>The War in <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825"><rs type="direction">East</rs> Tennessee</placeName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="193"/> The <placeName reg="Columbus, Muscogee, Georgia" key="tgn,7013643">Columbus (Ga.)</placeName> <hi rend="italics">Sun</hi> has an editorial reviewing the position of affairs in <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825"><rs type="direction">East</rs> Tennessee</placeName>, which we copy, inasmuch as, in the whirl of stirring events near home, the more distant fields of operation have to some extent been lost sight of: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="194"/> It is now quite evident that the enemy are about to put into execution their long threatened inroad upon <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825"><rs type="direction">East</rs> Tennessee</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="195"/>From the best information we can gather of the situation of affairs in that section, we take it that fighting will soon commence there in earnest.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="196"/>The <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> already have possession of <placeName reg="Sequatchie Valley, Tennessee, Tennessee" key="tgn,2652659">Sequatchie Valley</placeName>, a productive and stock growing country, and have a force of perhaps not less than <num value="5000">5,000</num> men in <placeName reg="Powells Valley, Dauphin, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,2092210">Powell's Valley</placeName>, a portion of country still more important to an army in the way of provisions.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="197"/>But the great valleys of the <placeName reg="Tennessee River, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,2715022">Tennessee</placeName>, <placeName reg="Hiwassee River, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,2392528">Hiwassee</placeName>, <placeName key="tgn,1124664" n="1.000 3" reg="holston, tennessee, united states">Holston</placeName>, and <placeName reg="French Broad River, Cocke, Tennessee" key="tgn,2340188">French Broad rivers</placeName>, are still in possession of our troops, and can we have reason to hope, be held against almost any force that may assail them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="198"/>We think it altogether probable that <placeName reg="Poor Fork Cumberland River, Kentucky, United States" key="tgn,2592540">Cumberland</placeName>, <persName n="Wheeler,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00087" reg="mostcommon:Wheeler,nomatch:0"><surname>Wheeler</surname></persName>'s, and Big <rs n="Creek" type="nativeamerican">Creek</rs> Caps, will be evacuated, if indeed they have not been already, and that our forces will make a stand at <placeName reg="Chattanooga, Hamilton, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017496">Chattanooga</placeName>, <placeName reg="Kingston, Roane, Tennessee" key="tgn,2099865">Kingston</placeName>, and <placeName reg="Bean's Station, Grainger, Tennessee" key="tgn,2153468">Bean's Station</placeName>, in order to keep the enemy <rs>North</rs> of <placeName key="tgn,2749253" n="1.000 1" reg="Wallen Ridge, United States">Wallen's Ridge</placeName> and the <rs type="place">Clinch Mountains</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="199"/>This, we feel confident, can be done successfully with the force now under <orgName n="command"><persName n="Smith,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00088" reg="mostcommon:Smith,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Smith</surname></persName>'s command</orgName>, which cannot be less than <num value="30000">30,000</num> men. There are, besides this force, which is a low estimate, several efficient guerilla bands, among which that of the famous <rs>Morgan</rs> is the most conspicuous.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="200"/>This line of defence, should it be adopted, will save to us about <num value="3">three</num> <num value=".25">fourths</num> of the territory of <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825"><rs type="direction">East</rs> Tennessee</placeName>, including <placeName reg="Jonesboro, Clayton, Georgia" key="tgn,2023284">Jonesborough</placeName>, <placeName reg="Greeneville, Greene, Tennessee" key="tgn,2099367">Greenville</placeName>, <placeName reg="Knoxville, Knox, Tennessee" key="tgn,7013841">Knoxville</placeName>, <placeName reg="Athens, McMinn, Tennessee" key="tgn,2097784">Athens</placeName>, <persName n="Cleveland,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00089" reg="mostcommon:Cleveland,nomatch:0"><surname>Cleveland</surname></persName>, <placeName reg="Chattanooga, Hamilton, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017496">Chattanooga</placeName>, and the line of railroad from the latter place to the <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> line. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="201"/> The part of <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825"><rs type="direction">East</rs> Tennessee</placeName> thus defended is <num value="1">one</num> of the most productive and healthy regions of country in the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="202"/>It contains, even now, bacon, corn, and flour, in great abundance.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="203"/>Nearly every farmer has bacon to sell, and which can be bought at not exceeding <measure n="27cents" type="currency">twenty seven cents</measure> per pound.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="204"/>It is <num value="1">one</num> of the finest wheat countries in the <rs>South</rs>, and we have it from good authority that the wheat crop in that section this year will fall but little short of the average crop, particularly in the upper counties.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="205"/>There is, per haps, at this time, more hogs and cattle in the <num value="31">thirty-one</num> counties of <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825"><rs type="direction">East</rs> Tennessee</placeName> than in the whole <placeName reg="Georgia" key="tgn,7007248">State of Georgia</placeName>, and upon this account, were there no other consideration, that section should be defended at any cost. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="206"/> While it is true that the majority of the voting population in <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825"><rs type="direction">East</rs> Tennessee</placeName> is deeply tinged with <hi rend="italics">toryism,</hi> it is equally true that some of the most staunch Southern men, and many of our ablest military leaders, are East Tennesseeans.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="207"/>There is <num value="1">one</num> fact in connexion with this disloyal section not generally known.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="208"/>Nearly every man and boy capable of bearing arms, who were advocates of separate State action are now in the <rs>Southern</rs> army, and although the conscription act is not in force there they have joined for the war. In addition to this, there are, to our certain knowledge, not less than <num value="1">one</num>-<num value="3" type="ordinal">third</num> of the original <q>&#x0022;Union&#x0022;</q> men now in that section &mdash; the ultras having joined <persName n="Lincoln,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00090" reg="nearbymention:Lincoln,Abraham,,,"><surname>Lincoln</surname></persName> in <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName>--many of the more moderate have changed their views since <persName n="Lincoln,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00091" reg="nearbymention:Lincoln,Abraham,,,"><surname>Lincoln</surname></persName>'s free-negro policy was promulgated in <dateStruct value="-11-"><month reg="11">November</month></dateStruct> last; while the remainder, being too indolent and cowardly to take any part in the contest of arms, are content to remain at home, cultivating their farms, and make something to support the army. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="18"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">The affair at <placeName reg="Boonville, Cooper, Missouri" key="tgn,2058115">Boonville</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="209"/> --The <orgName n="Wilmington Journal" type="newspaper">Wilmington <hi rend="italics">Journal</hi></orgName> gives the following version of the queer affair which occurred at <placeName reg="Boonville, Cooper, Missouri" key="tgn,2058115">Boonville</placeName>, related by <unclear></unclear> who knows the facts: </p> <cit><q> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="210"/> So quietly had all the arrangements for the evacuation of <placeName key="tgn,7017649" n="1.000 1055" reg="corinth, alcorn, mississippi">Corinth</placeName> been made, that <persName n="Halleck,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00092" reg="mostcommon:Halleck,nomatch:0"><surname>Halleck</surname></persName> was completely fooled, and in perfect ignorance of what was going on, so that, suspecting no such immediate movement on our part, he had secretly dispatched a body of troops, mainly cavalry, with the object of reaching, by a wide circuit, a point on the <rs type="place">Mobile and Ohio Road</rs> in the rear of <placeName key="tgn,7017649" n="1.000 1055" reg="corinth, alcorn, mississippi">Corinth</placeName>, and of destroying some bridges, with the view of interrupting our communication.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="211"/>A mer dash and away.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="212"/>Preparatory to the evacuation, a number of our sick, amounting in all to about <num value="1500">fifteen hundred</num>, with an escort of about <num value="200">two hundred</num> well men, bad been sent down from <placeName key="tgn,7017649" n="1.000 1055" reg="corinth, alcorn, mississippi">Corinth</placeName> to <placeName reg="Boonville, Cooper, Missouri" key="tgn,2058115">Boonville</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="213"/>The <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> bridge-burning force suddenly came upon these sick men with their attendants, and had them all ranged in line ready to be carried off as prisoners, although many were so worn down by dysentery and diarrhoea as to be hardly able to stand.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="214"/>While this affair was going on, so also was the evacuation of <placeName key="tgn,7017649" n="1.000 1055" reg="corinth, alcorn, mississippi">Corinth</placeName>, and just at the critical moment, the head of our retiring column came in sight of the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> and their line of sick prisoners.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="215"/>As if by magic the captors were gone.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="216"/>They broke and took to horse and away.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="217"/>The trembling line of sick prisoners seeing the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> stampede, but not knowing its cause, stood a moment, and then sick, un armed, feeble, broke for the woods in another direction, most of them determined to avail themselves of any chance to escape captivity and a few, in their weak and nervous state, no doubt stampeded, they hardly knew why. This is about the story of the capture of our sick and wounded by the enemy.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="218"/>and of our rescue of them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="219"/>The enemy may have done some damage to ears, etc., before they, in their turn, were surprised, last it was very trotting. </p> </q><bibl n="Wilmington Journal"></bibl></cit> </div3> 
<div3 type="artcle" n="19"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="220"/> <persName n="Burnett,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00093" reg="mostcommon:Burnett,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Burnett</surname></persName>, a widow lady living in <placeName reg="Bedford, Virginia, Virginia" key="tgn,2002144">Bedford county</placeName>, has <num value="8">eight</num> sons in the <rs>Confederate</rs> service. </p> </div3> <milestone unit="column" n="5"/> 
<div3 type="article" n="20"> 
<head><persName n="Lincoln,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00094" reg="nearbymention:Lincoln,Abraham,,,"><surname>Lincoln</surname></persName>'s defence of Camereit.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="221"/> We have obtained a copy of <persName n="Lincoln,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00095" reg="nearbymention:Lincoln,Abraham,,,"><surname>Lincoln</surname></persName>'s late message to the <orgName n="Federal Congress" type="congress">Federal Congress</orgName> in reference to the resolution of consure upon his ex-Secretary of War. We publish it as part of the history of the times; <hi rend="italics">To the <name>Senate</name> and <orgName n="House of Representatives" type="government">House of Representatives</orgName>:</hi> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="222"/> The insurrection which is yet existing in the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> and aims at the overthrow of the <rs>Federal Constitution</rs> and the <rs>Union</rs>, was clandestinely prepared during the winter of <dateStruct value="1860--"><year reg="1860">1860</year></dateStruct> and <dateStruct value="1861--"><year reg="1861">1861</year></dateStruct>, and assumed an open organization in the form of a reasonable provisional Government at <placeName reg="Montgomery, Montgomery, Alabama" key="tgn,7013928">Montgomery</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="223"/><placeName reg="Alabama" key="tgn,7002659">Alabama</placeName>, on the <date value="1861-02-18">8th day of February, 1861.</date> On the <date value="1861-04-12">12th day of April, 1861,</date>the insurgents committed the flagrant act of civil war by the bombardment and capture of <placeName key="tgn,7013582" n="1.000 46" reg="charleston, charleston, south carolina">Fort Sumter</placeName>, which cut off the hope of immediate conciliation.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="224"/>Immediately after wards, all the roads and avenues to this city were obstructed, and the capital was put into the condition of a siege. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="225"/> The mails in every direction were stopped, and the lines of telegraph cut off by the insurgents, and military and naval forces, which had been called out by the <rs>Government</rs> for the defence of <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>, were prevented from reaching the city by organized and combined treasonable resistance in the <placeName reg="Maryland" key="tgn,7007516">State of Maryland</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="226"/>There was no adequate and effective organization for the public defence.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="227"/>Congress had indefinitely adjourned.--There was no time to convene them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="228"/>It became necessary for me to choose whether, using only the existing means, agencies and processes which Congress had provided, I should let the <rs>Government</rs> fall at once into rain, or whether, availing myself of the broader powers conferred by the <rs>Constitution</rs> in cases of insurrection, I would make an effort to save it, with all its blessings, for the present age and for posterity. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="229"/> I thereupon summoned my constitutional advisers, the heads of all the <name>Departments</name>, to meet on <dateStruct><day type="name">Sunday</day></dateStruct>, the <date value="1861-04-21">21st day of April, </date><dateStruct value="1861--"><year reg="1861">1861</year></dateStruct>, at the office of the <orgName n="Navy Department" type="department">Navy Department</orgName>, and then and there, with their unanimous concurrence.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="230"/>I directed that an armed revenue cutter should proceed to sea, to afford protection to the commercial marine, and especially the <rs>California</rs> treasure ships, then on their way to this coast.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="231"/>I also directed the commandant of the <rs type="place">Navy Yard</rs> as <placeName reg="Boston, Suffolk, Massachusetts" key="tgn,7013445">Boston</placeName> to purchase or charter, and arm as quickly as possible, <num value="5">five</num> steamships for purposes of public defence.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="232"/>I directed the commandant of the <rs type="place">Navy-Yard</rs> at <placeName reg="Philadelphia, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7014406">Philadelphia</placeName> to purchase or charter and arm an equal number for the same purpose.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="233"/>I directed the commandant at New York to purchase or charter and arm an equal number.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="234"/>I directed <persName n="Gillies,Commander,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00096" reg="mostcommon:Gillies,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Commander">commander</roleName> <surname>Gillies</surname></persName> to purchase or charter and arm and put to sea <num value="2">two</num> other vessels.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="235"/>Similar directions were given to <persName n="Dupont,Commodore,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00097" reg="mostcommon:Dupont,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Commodore">Commodore</roleName> <surname>Dupont</surname></persName>, with a view to the opening of passages by water to and from the capital. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="236"/> I directed the several officers to take the advice and obtain the aid and efficient services in the matter of his <rs type="role2">Excellency</rs>, <persName><foreName>Edwin</foreName></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="237"/><persName n="Morgan,,D.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00098" reg="default:Morgan,D.,,,"><foreName>D.</foreName> <surname>Morgan</surname></persName>, the <rs>Governor</rs> of New York, or, in his absence, <persName n="Morgan,,George,D.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00099" reg="default:Morgan,George,D.,,"><foreName>George</foreName> <foreName>D.</foreName> <surname>Morgan</surname></persName>, <persName n="Evarts,,William,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00100" reg="default:Evarts,William,M.,,"><foreName>William</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Evarts</surname></persName>, <persName n="Blatchford,,R.,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00101" reg="expanded:Blatchford,Richard,M.,,"><foreName>R.</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Blatchford</surname></persName>, and <persName n="Grinnell,,Moses,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00102" reg="default:Grinnell,Moses,H.,,"><foreName>Moses</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Grinnell</surname></persName>, who were, by my directions, especially empowered by the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of the Navy">Secretary of the Navy</rs> to act for his Department in that crisis in matters pertaining to the forwarding of troops and supplies for the public defence.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="238"/>On the same occasion I directed that <persName n="Morgan,Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00103" reg="nearbymention:Morgan,George,D.,,"><roleName n="Governor">Gov.</roleName> <surname>Morgan</surname></persName> and <persName n="Cummings,,Alexander,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00104" reg="default:Cummings,Alexander,,,"><foreName n="Alexander">Alex.</foreName> <surname>Cummings</surname></persName>, of the <placeName type="city" key="tgn,7007567">city of New York</placeName>, should be authorized by the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs> (<persName n="Cameron,,Simon,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00105" reg="default:Cameron,Simon,,,"><foreName>Simon</foreName> <surname>Cameron</surname></persName>) to make all necessary arrangements for the transportation of troops and munitions of war in aid and assistance of the officers of the <orgName n="U. S. Army" type="org">army of the United States</orgName>, until communication by mails and telegraph should be completely re-established between the cities of <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName> and New York.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="239"/>No security was required to be given by them, and either of them was authorized to act in case of inability to consult with the others. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="240"/> On the same occasion I authorized and directed the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of the Treasury">Secretary of the Treasury</rs> to advance, without requiring security, <num value="2000000">two millions</num> of dollars of public money to <persName n="Dix,,John,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00106" reg="default:Dix,John,A.,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName> <surname>Dix</surname></persName>, <persName n="Opdyke,,George,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00107" reg="default:Opdyke,George,,,"><foreName>George</foreName> <surname>Opdyke</surname></persName>, and <persName n="Blatchford,,Richard,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00108" reg="default:Blatchford,Richard,M.,,"><foreName>Richard</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Blatchford</surname></persName>, of New York, to be used by them in meeting such requisitions as should be directly consequent upon the military and naval measures necessary for the defence and support of the <rs>Government</rs>, requiring them only to act without compensation, and to report their transactions when duly called upon.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="241"/>The several departments of the <rs>Government</rs> at that time contained so large a number of disloyal persons that it would have been impossible to provide safely, through official agents only, for the performance of the duties thus confided to citizens favorably known for their ability, loyalty and patriotism. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="242"/> The several orders issued upon these occurrences were transmitted by private messengers, who pursued a circuitous way to the seaboard cities inland, across the <name>States</name> of <placeName reg="Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7007710">Pennsylvania</placeName> and <placeName reg="Ohio" key="tgn,7007706">Ohio</placeName>, and the <rs type="place">Northern Lakes</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="243"/>I believe that by these and other similar measures taken in that crisis, some of which were without any authority of law, the <rs>Government</rs> was saved from overthrow.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="244"/>I am not aware that a dollar of the public funds thus confided without authority of law to unofficial persons, was either lost or wasted, although apprehensions of such misdirections occurred to me as objections to these extraordinary proceedings and were necessarily overruled.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="245"/>I recall these transactions now, because my attention has been directed to a resolution which was passed by the <orgName n="House of Representatives" type="government">House of Representatives</orgName> on the <dateStruct value="--30"><day reg="2">30th</day></dateStruct> of last month, which is in these words: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="246"/> <q>&#x0022;<hi rend="italics">Resolved,</hi> That <persName n="Cameron,,Simon,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00109" reg="default:Cameron,Simon,,,"><foreName>Simon</foreName> <surname>Cameron</surname></persName>, late <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>, by investing <persName n="Cummings,,Alexander,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00110" reg="default:Cummings,Alexander,,,"><foreName>Alexander</foreName> <surname>Cummings</surname></persName> with the control of large sums of public money, and authority to purchase military supplies, without restriction, without requiring from him any guarantee for the faithful performance of his duties, when the services of competent public officers were available, and by involving the <rs>Government</rs> in a vast number of contracts with persons not legitimately engaged in the business pertaining to the subject matter of such contracts, especially in the purchase of arms for future delivery, has adopted a policy highly injurious to the public service, and deserves the censure of this <name>House</name>.&#x0022;</q> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="247"/> Congress will see that I should be wanting equally in candor and in justice, if I should leave the censure, expressed in this resolution, to rest exclusively or chiefly upon <persName n="Cameron,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00111" reg="nearbymention:Cameron,Simon,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Cameron</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="248"/> The same sentiment is unanimously entertained by the heads of departments, who participated in the proceedings which the <orgName n="House of Representatives" type="government">House of Representatives</orgName> has censured.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="249"/>It is due to <persName n="Cameron,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00112" reg="nearbymention:Cameron,Simon,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Cameron</surname></persName> to say that, although he fully approved the proceedings, they were not moved nor suggested by him, and that not only the <rs>President</rs>, but all the other heads of departments, were at least equally responsible, with him, for whatever error, wrong or fault was committed in the premises.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="250"/><hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Lincoln,,Abraham,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00113" reg="default:Lincoln,Abraham,,,"><foreName>Abraham</foreName> <surname>Lincoln</surname></persName>.</hi> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="251"/> <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>, <date value="1862-05-26">May 26th, 1862</date> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="252"/> On motion of <persName n="Holman,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00114" reg="mostcommon:Holman,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Holman</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Indiana" key="tgn,7007252">Indiana</placeName>, it was referred to the <orgName n="Whole Committee" type="committee">Committee of the Whole</orgName> House. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="21"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Morgan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00115" reg="nearbymention:Morgan,George,D.,,"><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>'s Latest Exploit.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="253"/> --A correspondent of the <orgName n="Mobile Register" type="newspaper">Mobile <hi rend="italics">Register</hi></orgName>, writing from <placeName reg="Chattanooga, Hamilton, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017496">Chattanooga</placeName>, recounts the following: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="254"/> <persName n="Morgan,Colonel,John,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00116" reg="default:Morgan,John,H.,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Morgan</surname></persName> returned last evening from his scout up the river, having gone in pursuit of some of the enemy's cavalry, who were reported to have gone up in search of our <term type="ship">steamer</term>, the <rs type="ship">Paint Rock</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="255"/>About <measure n="7miles" type="distance">seven miles</measure> up the river he broke up some flatboats, and brought others across to this side.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="256"/>Seeing no signs of the enemy, he crossed at a point above the island to make an exploration.--Taking a small canoe, accompanied by his cousin, <persName n="Morgan,Major,Washington,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00117" reg="default:Morgan,Washington,,,"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <foreName n="Washington">Wash.</foreName> <surname>Morgan</surname></persName>, (who commands a company of <rs n="Cherokee" type="nativeamerican">Cherokee</rs> <rs n="Indian" type="group">Indians</rs>,) and <persName n="Grenfell,Colonel,George,St.,Ledger," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00118" reg="default:Grenfell,George,St.,Ledger,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <foreName>George</foreName> <foreName>St.</foreName> <foreName>Ledger</foreName> <surname>Grenfell</surname></persName>, be crossed the river, and after proceeding out some distance heard some voices.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="257"/>Approaching. they came on a man and a boy. Col <persName n="Morgan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00119" reg="nearbymention:Morgan,Washington,,,"><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>, seeing that the man mistook them for <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs>, asked him if he knew anything about the <rs>Secesh</rs> fellows over the river.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="258"/><q>&#x0022;No.&#x0022;</q>said he, <q>&#x0022;but I've learn that that rascal <persName n="Morgan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00120" reg="nearbymention:Morgan,Washington,,,"><surname>Morgan</surname></persName> was over thar yesterday, but the derned fellow flies about so thar's no tellin' whar he is now!&#x0022;</q> </p> </q><bibl n="A correspondent of the Mobile Register,"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="259"/> The <rs>Major</rs> and <persName n="Grenfell,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00121" reg="nearbymention:Grenfell,George,St.,Ledger,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Grenfell</surname></persName> could hardly keep straight faces.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="260"/><persName n="Morgan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00122" reg="nearbymention:Morgan,Washington,,,"><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>, after putting several questions to the man, asked if he was really a good Union man. He solemnly declared he was, and would do anything to help the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="261"/> <q>&#x0022;Well,&#x0022;</q> said <persName n="Morgan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00123" reg="nearbymention:Morgan,Washington,,,"><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>, <q>&#x0022;can't you paddle us over the river?--we would like to see if any <num value="1">one</num> is over there.&#x0022;</q> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="262"/> <q>&#x0022;I will,&#x0022;</q> said the fellow, <q>&#x0022;if you will just let me run up to the house a minute to change my breeches.&#x0022;</q> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="263"/> <q>&#x0022;Oh, those will do now,&#x0022;</q> said <persName n="Morgan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00124" reg="nearbymention:Morgan,Washington,,,"><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>, <q>&#x0022;as we are in a hurry,&#x0022;</q> and the man was compelled to go with them to the river.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="264"/>After the man had paddled the canoe about half way across it being necessary to keep very still in order to prevent the canoe from upsetting.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="265"/><persName n="Morgan,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00125" reg="nearbymention:Morgan,Washington,,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Morgan</surname></persName> changed his position, and the canoe came near going over, when the <rs>Major</rs> cried out, <q>&#x0022;<persName n="Morgan,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00126" reg="nearbymention:Morgan,Washington,,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Morgan</surname></persName>, if you don't keep still you will upset us.&#x0022;</q> At this announcement the <rs>Union</rs> man's face presented a perfect picture of terror, and he cried out, <q>&#x0022;Are you <persName n="Morgan,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00127" reg="nearbymention:Morgan,Washington,,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Morgan</surname></persName>, sir?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="266"/>For <name n="God" type="God">God's</name> sake don't hang me!&#x0022;</q> <q>&#x0022;Well,&#x0022; </q> said <persName n="Morgan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00128" reg="nearbymention:Morgan,Washington,,,"><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>, <q>&#x0022;hurry over, and I'll see about it,&#x0022;</q> Such tall paddling as the <rs>Union</rs> man then did was never beaten by the <rs n="Indian" type="group">Indian</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="267"/>The poor fellow, trembling with fear as he reached the shore, was afterwards let go. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="22"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">From <placeName reg="Memphis, Shelby, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017750">Memphis</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="268"/> --<persName n="Fitch,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00129" reg="mostcommon:Fitch,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Colonel</roleName> <surname>Fitch</surname></persName> has been superseded as military commander at <placeName reg="Memphis, Shelby, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017750">Memphis</placeName>, by <persName n="Slack,Colonel,James,R.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00130" reg="default:Slack,James,R.,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <foreName>James</foreName> <foreName>R.</foreName> <surname>Slack</surname></persName>, and the latter has commenced his tyranny by issuing the following order, prohibiting the use of Confederate notes by the people: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="269"/> Hereafter the dealing in, and passage of, currency known as <q>&#x0022;Confederate Script,&#x0022; </q> or <q>&#x0022;Confederate Notes,&#x0022;</q> is positively prohibited; and the use there after as a circulating medium regarded as an insult to the <rs>Government</rs> of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName>, and an imposition upon the ignorant and deluded. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="270"/> All persons offending against the provisions of this order will be promptly arrested and severely punished by the military authorities. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="271"/> The <hi rend="italics">Avalanche,</hi> of the <num value="15" type="ordinal">15th</num>, remarks that by this unusual order, without an hour's notice, the commercial value of Confederate notes is destroyed, by which the means of living are taken away from <num value="19">nineteen</num>-twentieths of the citizens.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="272"/>The poor of <placeName reg="Memphis, Shelby, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017750">Memphis</placeName> will long have cause to remember the unnecessary severity of their present rulers. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="273"/> The oath was administered on the <num value="14" type="ordinal">14th</num> to about severely <num value="5">five</num> officers and soldiers of the <orgName n="Confederate Army" type="org">Confederate army</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="274"/>The <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> flag floats over several buildings in the city.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="275"/>Northern men are arriving in <placeName reg="Memphis, Shelby, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017750">Memphis</placeName>, with a view to trade and speculation. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="276"/> The <hi rend="italics">Appeal</hi> says of <persName n="Johnson,,Andy,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00131" reg="default:Johnson,Andy,,,"><foreName>Andy</foreName> <surname>Johnson</surname></persName>: </p> <cit><q> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="277"/> The story now going the rounds, stating that this notorious individual had been killed by <persName n="Brown,Ex-Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00132" reg="nearbymention:Brown,Neil,S.,,"><roleName n="Ex-Governor">Ex- Gov.</roleName> <surname>Brown</surname></persName>, was put to rest by the traitor making his appearance at <placeName reg="Memphis, Shelby, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017750">Memphis</placeName> on <dateStruct><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> last.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="278"/>He was, at last advices, making his headquarters on board the <rs>Benton</rs> gunboat, being evidently afraid to trust himself in the city. </p> </q><bibl n=""></bibl></cit> </div3> <milestone unit="column" n="6"/> 
<div3 type="article" n="23"> 
<head><persName n="Halleck,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00133" reg="mostcommon:Halleck,nomatch:0"><surname>Halleck</surname></persName>'s misrepresentations &mdash; <persName n="Beauregard,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00134" reg="nearbymention:Beauregard,G.,T.,,"><surname>Beauregard</surname></persName>'s Reply.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="279"/> We copy from the <orgName n="Mobile Evening News" type="newspaper">Mobile <hi rend="italics">Evening News</hi></orgName> the communication of <persName n="Beauregard,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00135" reg="nearbymention:Beauregard,G.,T.,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Beauregard</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="280"/>to which brief allusion has been made through the medium of the telegraph.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="281"/>It will be seen that the opinion heretofore expressed with regard to the falsity of <persName n="Haileck,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00136" reg="mostcommon:Haileck,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Haileck</surname></persName>'s dispatches, is fully sustained by this straight-forward statement: </p> 
<div4 type="letter" n="1"> 
<head></head> <opener> <dateline> <name type="place">Headq'rs <orgName n="Department of the West" type="department">Western Department</orgName>,</name> <date value="1862-06-17">June 17th, 1862.</date> </dateline> <salute>Gentlemen:</salute> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="282"/> My attention has just been called to the following dispatch (published in your issue of yesterday) of <persName n="Halleck,Major-General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00137" reg="mostcommon:Halleck,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major-General">Major-General</roleName> <surname>Halleck</surname></persName>, commanding enemy's forces, which, coming from such a source, is most remarkable in <num value="1">one</num> respect &mdash; that it contains as many misrepresentations as lines: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="283"/> <hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>,</hi> <date value="1862-06-04">June 4. 1862.</date>--The following dispatch was received this afternoon at the <orgName n="War Department" type="department">War Department</orgName>: </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="letter" n="2"> 
<head></head> <opener> <dateline> <name type="place">Halleck's Headquarters,</name> <date value="1862-06-04">June 4, 1862.</date> </dateline> <salute><persName n="Stanton,the Honorable,E.,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00138" reg="default:Stanton,E.,M.,,"><roleName n="the Honorable">Hon.</roleName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Stanton</surname></persName>, <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>:</salute> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="284"/> <persName n="Pope,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00139" reg="mostcommon:Pope,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Pope</surname></persName>, with <num value="40000">40,000</num> men, is <placeName><distance reg="30miles">thirty miles</distance> <offset>south</offset> of  <placeName key="tgn,7017649" n="1.000 1055" reg="corinth, alcorn, mississippi">Corinth</placeName></placeName>, pushing the enemy hard.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="285"/>He already reports <measure n="10000" type="prisoners">10,000 prisoners</measure> and deserters from the enemy, and <num value="15000">15,000</num> stand of arms captured. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="286"/> <num value="1000">Thousands</num> of the enemy are throwing away their arms.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="287"/>A farmer says that when <persName n="Beauregard,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00140" reg="nearbymention:Beauregard,G.,T.,,"><surname>Beauregard</surname></persName> learned that <persName n="Elliott,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00141" reg="nearbymention:Elliott,W.,M.,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Elliott</surname></persName> bad cut the railroad on his line of retreat he became frantic, and told his men to save themselves the best way they could. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="288"/> We have <measure n="9" type="captured">captured nine</measure> locomotives and a number of cars.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="289"/><num value="1">One</num> of the former is already repaired.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="290"/>and is running to day, Several more will be in running order in <num value="2">two</num> or <measure n="3days" type="date">three days</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="291"/> The result is all I could possibly desire. </p> <closer> <signed>H. W.Halleck,</signed> <salute><rs type="role" reg="Major-General">Major General</rs> Commanding.&#x0022;</salute> </closer> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="292"/> <rs type="role">Gen.</rs> <hi rend="italics"><persName n="Pope,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00142" reg="mostcommon:Pope,nomatch:0"><surname>Pope</surname></persName> did not</hi> <q>&#x0022;push hard&#x0022;</q> upon me with <num value="40000">40,000</num> men, <placeName><distance reg="30miles">thirty miles</distance> from <placeName key="tgn,7017649" n="1.000 1055" reg="corinth, alcorn, mississippi">Corinth</placeName></placeName>, on the <dateStruct value="--4"><day reg="4">4th inst.</day></dateStruct>, for my troops occupied a defensive line in rear of <q>&#x0022;<measure n="20Mile" type="distance">Twenty Mile</measure> <rs n="Creek" type="nativeamerican">Creek</rs>,&#x0022;</q> less than <placeName><distance reg="25miles">25 miles</distance> from <placeName key="tgn,7017649" n="1.000 1055" reg="corinth, alcorn, mississippi">Corinth</placeName></placeName>, until the <dateStruct value="--8"><day reg="8">8th inst.</day></dateStruct>, when the want of good water induced me to retire at <hi rend="italics">my leisure</hi> to a better position; moreover, if <persName n="Pope,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00143" reg="mostcommon:Pope,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Pope</surname></persName> had attempted, at any time during the retreat from <placeName key="tgn,7017649" n="1.000 1055" reg="corinth, alcorn, mississippi">Corinth</placeName>, to <hi rend="italics">push hard</hi> upon me, I would have given him such a lesson as would have cheeked his ardor; but he was careful to advance on <hi rend="italics">after</hi> my troops had retired from each successive position. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="293"/> The retreat was conducted with great order and precision, doing much credit to the officers and men under my orders, and must be looked upon in every respect by the country as equivalent to a brilliant victory. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="294"/> <persName n="Pope,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00144" reg="mostcommon:Pope,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Pope</surname></persName> must certainly have dreamed of having taking <measure n="10000" type="prisoners">10,000 prisoners</measure> and <num value="15000">15,000</num> stand of arms!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="295"/>for we positively <hi rend="italics">never lost them;</hi> about <num value="1">one</num> or <num value="200">two hundred</num> stragglers would probably cover, all the prisoners he took, and about <num value="500">five hundred</num> damaged muskets all the arms he got; these belonged to a convalescent camp (<placeName><distance reg="4miles">four miles</distance> <offset>south</offset> of  <placeName key="tgn,7017649" n="1.000 1055" reg="corinth, alcorn, mississippi">Corinth</placeName></placeName>) evacuated during the night, and were overlooked on account of the darkness.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="296"/>The actual number of <hi rend="italics">prisoners</hi> taken during the retreat was about equal on both sides, and they were but few. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="297"/> <persName n="Halleck,Major-General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00145" reg="mostcommon:Halleck,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major-General">Major General</roleName> <surname>Halleck</surname></persName> must be a very credulous man indeed to believe the absurd story of <q>&#x0022;that farmer,&#x0022;</q> He ought to know that the burning of <num value="2">two</num> or more cars on a railroad is not sufficient to make <q>&#x0022;<persName n="Beauregard,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00146" reg="nearbymention:Beauregard,G.,T.,,"><surname>Beauregard</surname></persName> frantic&#x0022;</q> and ridiculous!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="298"/>especially when I expected every moment to hear of the capture of his marauding party, whose departure from <placeName reg="Farmington, Alcorn, Mississippi" key="tgn,2056417">Farmington</placeName> had been communicated to me the day before, and I had given in consequence all necessary orders; but a part of my forces passed <placeName reg="Booneville, Prentiss, Mississippi" key="tgn,2056008">Booneville</placeName> an hour before the arrival of <orgName n="command"><persName n="Elliott,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00147" reg="nearbymention:Elliott,W.,M.,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Elliott</surname></persName>'s command</orgName>, and the other part arrived just in time to drive it away and liberate the convalescents captured; unfortunately, however, not in time to save <num value="4">four</num> of the sickle, who were barbarously consumed in the station-house!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="299"/>Let <persName n="Elliott,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00148" reg="nearbymention:Elliott,W.,M.,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Elliott</surname></persName>'s name descend to infamy as the author of such a revolting deed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="300"/><persName n="Halleck,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00149" reg="mostcommon:Halleck,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Halleck</surname></persName> <hi rend="italics">did not</hi> capture <hi rend="italics">nins</hi> locomotives.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="301"/>It was only by the accidental destruction of a bridge before some trains had passed that he got <hi rend="italics"><num value="7">seven</num></hi> engines in a damaged condition, the cars having been burst by my orders. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="302"/> It is indeed lamentable to see how little our enemies respect truth and justice when speaking of their military operations, especially when, through inability or over-confidence, they meet with deserved failure. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="303"/> If the result be <q>&#x0022;all he desired,&#x0022;</q> it can be said he is easily satisfied; it remains to be seen whether his Government and people will be of the like opinion. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="304"/> I attest that all we lost at <placeName key="tgn,7017649" n="1.000 1055" reg="corinth, alcorn, mississippi">Corinth</placeName> and during the retreat would not amount to <num value="1">one</num> day's expenses of his army. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="305"/> Respectfully, your ob't serv't, </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="306"/> G. T. <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Beauregard,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00150" reg="nearbymention:Beauregard,G.,T.,,"><surname>Beauregard</surname></persName>.</hi> </p> </div4> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="24"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">An Atrocious Edict.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="307"/> --The <rs type="role" reg="commanding-Officer">commanding officer</rs> of the <term n="US Steamer">U. S. Steamer</term> <rs type="ship">Winona</rs>, <persName n="Nichols,Lieutenant,E.,T.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00151" reg="default:Nichols,E.,T.,,"><roleName n="Lieutenant">Lieut.</roleName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <foreName>T.</foreName> <surname>Nichols</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="308"/>lately addressed an insolent letter to the authorities of <placeName reg="Rodney, Jefferson, Mississippi" key="tgn,2057379">Rodney, Miss.</placeName>, of which the following is an extract: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="309"/> You are doubtless aware that the town of <placeName reg="Grand Gull">Grand Gull</placeName> was fired upon a short time since by some of the vessels of the <orgName n="U. S. Government" type="org">United States Government</orgName> as a punishment for permitting a battery to fire upon some of our transport steamers while passing down. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="310"/> I deem it my duty to inform you that should any battery or artillery fire upon any of our vessels while passing up or down from or near the town of <placeName reg="Rodney, Jefferson, Mississippi" key="tgn,2057379">Rodney</placeName>, the punishment for the offence will be visited on the town.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="311"/>We are not here to war upon unarmed or peaceable persons, and we would deprecate any event compelling us to fire upon the property of inoffensive people. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="312"/> This infamous letter was replied to by <persName n="Lovell,Major-General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00152" reg="mostcommon:Lovell,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major-General">Major Gen.</roleName> <surname>Lovell</surname></persName>, as follows: </p> <cit><q> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="313"/> When <num value="2">two</num> nations are at war, it has become customary among civilized people &#x0022;to punish the offence&#x0022; of an attack by the armed forces of <num value="1">one</num> upon those of the other by a combat with the attacking party. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="314"/> If such attack be made from a town, the assaulting party is not entitled to, and, so far as our troops are concerned, does not claim any immunity by reason of the presence of women and children; what we do claim, however, and insist upon, is that whenever your vessels or transports are fired into by our troops, they shall not fasten to the nearest collection of <q>&#x0022;unarmed and peaceable&#x0022;</q> women and children, and wreak their vengeance upon them, as was done lately at <placeName reg="Grand Gulf, Claiborne, Mississippi" key="tgn,2056516">Grand Gulf</placeName> by <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> vessels in retaliation for an attack with which the town had nothing more to do than had the city of <placeName reg="Saint Louis, Saint Louis City, Missouri" key="tgn,7014444">St. Louis</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="315"/> My batteries are located at such points upon the river as are deemed best suited for the desired purposes, and without reference to, or connection with, the people of the towns.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="316"/>Should the site happen to fall within a village, you, of course, are at liberty to return the fire; should it be in the vicinity of <num value="1">one</num>, however, the usages of civilized warfare do not justify its destruction unless demanded by the necessities of attack or defence. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="317"/> I cannot bring myself to believe that the barbarous and cowardly policy indicated in the enclosed letter will meet with the approval of any officer of rank or standing in the <orgName n="U. S. Navy" type="org">U. S. Navy</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="318"/>I have therefore thought proper to transmit it to you under a flag of truce, with the confident expectation that you will direct those under your command to confine their offensive operations as far as possible to our troops, and forbid the wanton destruction of defenseless towns, filled with unoffending non-combatants, unless required by imperious military necessity. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="319"/> The practice of slaying women and children as act of retaliation, has happily fallen into disuse in this country with the disappearance of the <rs n="Indian" type="group">Indian</rs> tribes, and I trust it will not be revived by the officers of the <orgName n="U. S. Navy" type="org">United States Navy</orgName>, but that the demolition and plunder of the unoffending little village of <placeName reg="Grand Gulf, Claiborne, Mississippi" key="tgn,2056516">Grand Gulf</placeName> may be permitted to stand alone and without parallel upon the record. </p> </q><bibl n="Major Gen. Lovell"></bibl></cit> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="25"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Evacuation of <placeName reg="Cumberland Gap, Claiborne, Tennessee" key="tgn,2098735">Cumberland Gap</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="320"/> --From the <orgName n="Knoxville Register" type="newspaper">Knoxville <hi rend="italics">Register</hi></orgName> we learn that <placeName key="tgn,2098735" n="1.000 724" reg="cumberland gap, claiborne, tennessee">Cumberland Gap</placeName> has been evacuated by the <rs>Confederates</rs>, and that the force which has so long been stationed there, has fallen back to a position on the <placeName reg="Clinch River, Grainger, Tennessee" key="tgn,2244440">Clinch river</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="321"/>The <hi rend="italics">Register,</hi> in noticing the evacuation, says, <cit><q rend="inline">&#x0022;that the croakers may not draw any conclusions from this movement distressing to the nerves of those who have of late been so shaky in regard to the safety of <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825"><rs type="direction">East</rs> Tennessee</placeName>, we may state that before the <rs type="place">Gap</rs> was evacuated the <rs>Federals</rs> had left there, after so blockading the road in their flight that they could not return if they would.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="322"/>In the opinion of some of our military men, the abandonment of the <rs type="place">Gap</rs> has long been held to be a politic measure.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="323"/>The <num value="5">five</num> or <num value="6000">six thousand</num> men that it has required to watch it can now be sent to a field of operations more destructive the foe.&#x0022; </q><bibl n="Register"></bibl></cit> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="26"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="324"/> <persName n="Whitner,Major,John,C.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00153" reg="default:Whitner,John,C.,,"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>C.</foreName> <surname>Whitner</surname></persName>, late of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName> army, has been appointed to write up the proceedings of the <orgName n="Provisional Congress" type="congress">Provisional Congress</orgName>--a work which <persName n="Hooper,,Johnson,J.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00154" reg="default:Hooper,Johnson,J.,,"><foreName>Johnson</foreName> <foreName>J.</foreName> <surname>Hooper</surname></persName>, by his death, left unfinished. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="325"/> A letter found on the battle-field of the <rs type="place">Seven Pines</rs>, from a wife to her husband in the <rs>Federal</rs> army, says, <cit><q rend="inline">&#x0022;throw away your arms and come home, for the people here say there is no use in fighting the rebels any longer.&#x0022; </q><bibl n="wife to her husband"></bibl></cit> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="326"/> The hanging of <persName n="Mumford,,William,B.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00155" reg="default:Mumford,William,B.,,"><foreName n="William">Wm.</foreName> <foreName>B.</foreName> <surname>Mumford</surname></persName> in New Orleans, by Butter's order, for tearing down a Federal flag, raises the question of retaliation again.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="327"/>Somebody must hang for <persName n="Mumford,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00156" reg="nearbymention:Mumford,William,B.,,"><surname>Mumford</surname></persName>, the New Orleans martyr. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="328"/> The late freshet in <placeName reg="Roanoke River, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,2621311">Roanoke river</placeName>, <placeName reg="North Carolina" key="tgn,7007709">N. C.</placeName>, was very heavy and destructive.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="329"/>Apprehensions are felt of severe losses in crops, cattle, &#x0026;c., in <placeName reg="Halifax, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002166">Halifax</placeName> and <placeName reg="Northampton, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,1002730">Northampton counties</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="330"/> The <orgName n="Cincinnati Commercial" type="newspaper">Cincinnati <hi rend="italics">Commercial</hi></orgName> <hi rend="italics">calls the <orgName n="New York Tribune" type="newspaper">New York Tribune's</orgName></hi> information regarding Unionism in <placeName reg="Texas" key="tgn,7007826">Texas</placeName>, <q>&#x0022;a cock and bull story.&#x0022;</q> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="331"/> It is stated that <persName n="Graves,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00157" reg="mostcommon:Graves,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Graves</surname></persName>, of the <orgName type="regiment" key="8MIRegiment">8th Michigan regiment</orgName>, was killed in the recent fight at <placeName reg="Secessionville, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,2096672">Secessionville, S. C.</placeName> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="332"/> Ample and well-arranged measures should be taken in season to procure a supply of fresh fruit and preserved vegetables for the use of our army. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="333"/> Mis. <persName n="Thorne,,Mary,C.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00158" reg="default:Thorne,Mary,C.,,"><foreName>Mary</foreName> <foreName>C.</foreName> <surname>Thorne</surname></persName>, the last surviving witness of the execution of <persName n="Andre,Major,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00159" reg="mostcommon:Andre,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <surname>Andre</surname></persName>, died in New York a few days since at the age of <num value="92">92</num>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="334"/> <persName n="Ruffin,Doctor,George,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00160" reg="default:Ruffin,George,W.,,"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <foreName>George</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Ruffin</surname></persName>, a well-known physician, died at his residence in <placeName reg="Wilson, North Carolina, United States" key="tgn,2001554">Wilson county, N. C.</placeName>, on the <dateStruct value="--5"><day reg="5">5th instant</day></dateStruct>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="335"/> The veteran soldier and patriot, <persName n="Twiggs,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00161" reg="mostcommon:Twiggs,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Twiggs</surname></persName>, has taken up his residence near <placeName reg="Augusta Georgia">Augusta Georgia</placeName>, the place of his nativity. </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="7"/> 
<div2 type="local"> 
<head>Local matters.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics"><persName n="Jack,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00162" reg="mostcommon:Jack,nomatch:0"><surname>Jack</surname></persName> with a lantern.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="336"/> --We do not subscribe to the assertion of <persName n="Johnson,Doctor,Samuel,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00163" reg="default:Johnson,Samuel,,,"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <foreName>Samuel</foreName> <surname>Johnson</surname></persName>, that <q>&#x0022;the man who killed fat beeves should be fat himself,&#x0022;</q> but we do hold to the partially analogous doctrine that the lady who washes clothes should herself be clean &mdash; yet the appearance of <persName n="McNell,Mrs.,Nelly,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00164" reg="default:McNell,Nelly,,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <foreName>Nelly</foreName> <surname>McNell</surname></persName>, laundress by profession, who came before the <rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Provost Marshal">Assistant Provost Marshal</rs> on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Sunday</day></dateStruct> <time>morning</time>, was strikingly at variance with this maxim,--for <persName n="Nelly,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00165" reg="mostcommon:Nelly,nomatch:0"><surname>Nelly</surname></persName> was <q>&#x0022;<num value="1">one</num> cake of mud &#x0022;</q> from the peak of her bonnet to the sole of her slipper.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="337"/><persName n="McNell,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00166" reg="nearbymention:McNell,Nelly,,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>McNell</surname></persName> had, in the hours of repose on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time>, been picked out from a clay-pit in a brick-yard on the south side of <address><street n="Main street">Main street</street></address>, in the <orgName n="Eastern district" type="district">Eastern District</orgName>--the guard, with unpardonable lack of courtesy to the sex, mistaking her at <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> for a hog, but attempting to rouse her with the exclamation--<q>&#x0022;<persName n="Sue,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00167" reg="mostcommon:Sue,nomatch:0"><surname>Sue</surname></persName>&#x0022;</q> and a touch of his foot, he was made aware that it was a rational and reflective being, by being desired to <q>&#x0022;go to h--,&#x0022;</q> and offered certain humorous advice respecting his conduct in that region, so well described by <persName n="Milton,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00168" reg="mostcommon:Milton,nomatch:0"><surname>Milton</surname></persName> and <persName n="Dante,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00169" reg="mostcommon:Dante,nomatch:0"><surname>Dante</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="338"/>The guard, beginning to suspect that it was a lady, and not a porker, who addressed him, assisted her to rise, and conveyed her to a place very similar in some respects to that whither she had just before wished to send him <persName n="McNell,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00170" reg="nearbymention:McNell,Nelly,,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>McNell</surname></persName>, at the request of the <rs>Assistant Prevent Marshal</rs> gave a very lucid and circumstantial account of her last night's mishap &mdash; which account we are compelled to abbreviate and change some what in phraseology.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="339"/>She was bringing over a batch of clothes from the eastern suburbs, where she dwells, to the residence of a family living on upper <address><street n="Main street">Main street</street></address>, for which she washes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="340"/>As a precaution against contagion she brought with her a flask of whiskey, which she tasted <q>&#x0022;several times&#x0022;</q> on her solitary way, Seeing a light before her, which she took to be a city lamp, she followed it, and couldn't leave off following it, though she knew it was making a fool of her, <q>&#x0022;by raison that her head was all in a buzz, and whin she came to herself she found herself lying insensible in the bog.&#x0022;</q> The reason she spoke in such sharp terms to the guard was <q>&#x0022;because she had a consist that he was the devil, believing that she was haunted entirely by spirits of avail, and she thought it no more than decent to tell the <sic>ould</sic> boy to go the place where he belonged&#x0022;</q> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="341"/> It seemed likely that <persName n="Nelly,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00171" reg="mostcommon:Nelly,nomatch:0"><surname>Nelly</surname></persName> had been misled by a Jack with a lantern &mdash; at least the <rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Provost Marshal">Assistant Provost Marshal</rs>, with amiable sympathy for her weakness, was disposed to put this construction on the matter.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="342"/>She was therefore discharged, without verbal rebuke or pecuniary penalty. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">City <orgName n="Gas Works" type="works">gas Works</orgName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="343"/> --The report of the <rs>Council Committee</rs> on Light, and that of the <rs n="General Superintendent" type="misc">General Superintendent</rs> of the <name>Works</name>, after having been delayed for some months, has just been printed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="344"/>They in detail give the operations of the works for the year ending <date value="1862-02-28">February 28th, 1862,</date> and present an exceedingly satisfactory exhibit.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="345"/>The committee say that the <orgName n="Gas Works" type="works">Gas Works</orgName> made this year, over and above all expenses to the credit of the city, <measure n="75744dollars" type="currency">seventy-five thousand seven hundred and forty-four dollars</measure>, besides furnishing street lamps and public buildings with gas free. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="346"/> The committee have felt the necessity of having an additional holder, as recommended by the <rs>Superintendent</rs> last year; but knowing it was impossible to obtain material for that purpose, do not recommend it. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="347"/> They, however, recommend the erection of a shed for coal, so as to enable them to lay in a large supply in the summer. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="348"/> The <rs n="General Superintendent" type="misc">General Superintendent</rs> of the works says that <num value="57000000">fifty-seven million</num> <measure n="383900feet" type="distance">three hundred and eighty-three thousand and nine hundred feet</measure> of gas was manufactured during the year, being an increase on the year previous of <num value="3000000">three million</num> <measure n="60060feet" type="distance">sixty thousand and sixty feet</measure>, which, after deducting for condensation and leakage, leaves <num value="51000000">fifty-one million</num> <measure n="685491feet" type="distance">six hundred and eighty-five thousand four hundred and ninety-one feet</measure>; of the amount made there was over <measure n="10000000feet" type="distance">ten million feet</measure> consumed by street lamps and public buildings free of charge. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="349"/> The whole amount of street mains laid to date is <measure n="34miles" type="distance">34 miles</measure> <measure n="1251feet" type="distance">1,251 feet</measure>. The number of public lamps now in use is <num value="869">869</num>, viz: in <persName n="Ward,,Jefferson,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00172" reg="default:Ward,Jefferson,,,"><foreName>Jefferson</foreName> <surname>Ward</surname></persName>, <num value="238">238</num>, in <persName n="Ward,,Madison,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00173" reg="default:Ward,Madison,,,"><foreName>Madison</foreName> <surname>Ward</surname></persName>, <num value="379">379</num>; and in <persName n="Ward,,Monroe,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00174" reg="default:Ward,Monroe,,,"><foreName>Monroe</foreName> <surname>Ward</surname></persName>; <num value="252">252</num>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="350"/> The largest amount of gas made in any <measure n="24hours" type="date">twenty-four hours</measure> was on the <date value="12-19">December </date>--<measure n="262400feet" type="distance">262,400 feet</measure>--and the greatest consumption occurred on the night of <date value="11-07">November 7th,</date> which reached <measure n="259749feet" type="distance">259,749 feet</measure>. The whole amount of gas manufactured since the commencement of the works is <measure n="452826240feet" type="distance">452,826,240 feet</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="351"/> At the date of last report the number of consumers was <num value="2639">2,639</num>; an addition of <num value="161">161</num> was made during the past year, making the whole <num value="2800">number 2,800</num>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics"><orgName n="Police Court" type="court">Police Court</orgName>, <dateStruct><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct>, <date value="06-23">June 23d.</date></head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="352"/> --The following eases were disposed of by the sitting magistrate: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="353"/> <persName n="Mann,,Henry,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00175" reg="default:Mann,Henry,,,"><foreName>Henry</foreName> <surname>Mann</surname></persName>, a soldier, drunk and trespassing on the premises of <persName n="Hutzler,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00176" reg="mostcommon:Hutzler,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Hutzler</surname></persName>, on <address><street n="18 Street">18th street</street></address> sent to the <rs type="role" reg="Provost Marshal">Provost Marshal</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="354"/> <persName n="Duesberry,,William,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00177" reg="default:Duesberry,William,,,"><foreName n="William">Wm.</foreName> <surname>Duesberry</surname></persName>, riotous and disorderly conduct, and threatening to shoot <persName n="Wartzman,,Julius,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00178" reg="default:Wartzman,Julius,,,"><foreName>Julius</foreName> <surname>Wartzman</surname></persName>, placed under the custody of a young man in <q>&#x0022;sojer clothes&#x0022;</q> and allowed to go. Wartzman, who had indulged in the muss himself, was sent to the <rs type="role" reg="Provost Marshal">Provost Marshal</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="355"/> <persName n="Devallar,,Thomas,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00179" reg="default:Devallar,Thomas,,,"><foreName>Thomas</foreName> <surname>Devallar</surname></persName>, for assaulting a soldier with rocks, was sent to the <rs type="role" reg="Provost Marshal">Provost Marshal</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="356"/> <persName n="Webber,,Philip,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00180" reg="default:Webber,Philip,,,"><foreName>Philip</foreName> <surname>Webber</surname></persName>, charged with stealing <num value="2">two</num> coats, <num value="1">one</num> pair pants, <num value="1">one</num> cap, <num value="2">two</num> pairs socks, and <num value="1">one</num> prayer book, the property of <persName n="McAvoy,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00181" reg="default:McAvoy,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>McAvoy</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="357"/>Bailed to appear at <orgName n="Hustings Court" type="court">Hustings Court</orgName> for examination, </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="358"/> A few other cases of no importance were disposed of. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Negro boy drowned.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="359"/> --<persName n="Sanxay,Acting-Coroner,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00182" reg="mostcommon:Sanxay,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Acting-Coroner">Acting Coroner</roleName> <surname>Sanxay</surname></persName> was summoned to the vicinity of the <rs type="place">Pump-House</rs> about <time value="9oclock">9 o'clock</time> on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time> to hold an inquest over the body of a drowned negro.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="360"/>Arriving at the locality indicated, <rs type="role">Mr.</rs> S. found the body of a mulatto boy about <measure n="17years" type="date">seventeen years</measure> of age, who had evidently lost his life by the means alluded to. As nobody could tell his name, or whether he was free or slave, or how he came to be drowned, the <rs>Coroner</rs> decided not to hold an inquest.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="361"/>We heard yesterday from parties living near the scene of the casualty that the deceased was induced to go in bathing on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> <time>evening</time> below the <rs type="place">Pump-House</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="362"/>with several soldiers and that <num value="1">one</num> of them tried to convey him across the canal on his back.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="363"/>During the performance of this feat the boy slipped off or was pushed off and being unable to swim, was drowned.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="364"/>The parties present dressed themselves and left hurriedly. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Accident.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="365"/> --<persName n="Rupert,Miss,Josephine,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00183" reg="default:Rupert,Josephine,,,"><roleName n="Miss">Miss</roleName> <foreName>Josephine</foreName> <surname>Rupert</surname></persName>, <num value="1">one</num> of the young ladies engaged at <placeName reg="St. Paul's Church">St. Paul's Church</placeName> in fabricating equipments for the soldiers, repaired yesterday evening, with a number of her companions, to the belfry of the church, and while in that elevated position missed her footing and fell through the trap door, a distance of <measure n="45feet" type="distance">forty-five feet</measure>, to the floor below, containing the organ.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="366"/>Beyond the fright and bruising consequent on such an affair, she was not materially injured, and was able to be conveyed to her residence on French <placeName key="tgn,2344787" n="1.000 10" reg="Garden Hill, Orange, Vermont">Garden Hill</placeName> in a carriage.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="367"/>Her escape was a lucky <num value="1">one</num>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics"><orgName n="City Council" type="council">City Council</orgName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="368"/> --The city fathers were to have convened yesterday at <time value="5oclock">5 o'clock</time> at the <placeName reg="City Hall">City Hall</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="369"/>Repairing <measure n="30minutes" type="date">thirty minutes</measure> after the prescribed hour, <unclear></unclear> reporter found the entire upper story of the building deserted and is justified in supposing that, as usual, they did nothing very important.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="370"/>Should his conclusion be erroneous, he will hereafter insert their proceedings. </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="rent"> 
<head>For Rent.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="371"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> <milestone unit="page" n="2"/> 
<div1 type="page-image"> 
<head></head> 
<p><figure entity="NW_RichTimesD_022_150_002"> <figDesc>Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume <num value="22">22</num>, <num value="150">Number 150</num>, <ref n="page 2">page 2</ref>. </figDesc> </figure></p> </div1> <milestone unit="column" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.</head> 
<div2 type="morning"> 
<head><date value="1862-06-24">Tuesday morning...June 24, 1862.</date></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head><rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> bayonet Charging.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="372"/> The late <rs>Robert Baylor Semple</rs> used to tell of a notorious bully who was suspected of having negro blood in his veins, and who always charged his adversary for the time with being a negro.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="373"/>This was done, of course to divert attention from his own shortcomings on the negro question, as a thief joins in the hue and cry, and is the loudest in the shout of <q>&#x0022;stop thief. &#x0022;</q> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="374"/> Doubtless <persName n="McClellan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00184" reg="mostcommon:McClellan,nomatch:0"><surname>McClellan</surname></persName> is actuated by some such feeling, or knows the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> nation to be sore on this subject, when he feeds them with the fond fancy that their soldiers have immortalized themselves by their desperate charges with the bayonet upon the thick array of the rebel legions.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="375"/><persName n="McClellan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00185" reg="mostcommon:McClellan,nomatch:0"><surname>McClellan</surname></persName> guesses right.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="376"/>The <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> are sore upon this subject &mdash; very sore.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="377"/>From the beginning of this war they have never made a single charge of the bayonet, nor have they ever stood before <num value="1">one</num> of the many charges that have been made upon <hi rend="italics">them</hi> long enough for the weapons to cross.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="378"/>They invariably run before their adversary gets within <measure n="30yards" type="distance">thirty yards</measure> of them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="379"/>The correspondent of the <orgName n="London Times" type="newspaper">London <hi rend="italics">Times</hi></orgName>, <persName n="Russell,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00186" reg="mostcommon:Russell,nomatch:0"><surname>Russell</surname></persName>, was unlucky enough to State in <num value="1">one</num> of his letters that they neither made nor attempted a single charge during the whole day at <placeName key="tgn,2112877" n="1.000 541" reg="manassas, manassas, virginia">Manassas</placeName>, and the contemptuous comments with which his statement was accompanied brought down a shower of abuse upon his head.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="380"/>It did more than that.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="381"/>It caused his exclusion from the <orgName>army of <persName n="McClellan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00187" reg="mostcommon:McClellan,nomatch:0"><surname>McClellan</surname></persName></orgName>, who had no notion of allowing a shrewd foreigner to be a witness to his defeats in the field and his victories on paper, thereby circumscribing the limits within which his imagination might range when giving a tongue to his exploits.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="382"/>He can now with safety make the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> nation believe that his men are famous men at the bayonet, and he makes good use of his immunity from criticism.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="383"/>There is nobody to contradict him, or tell unpalatable truths to the world. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="384"/> <num value="1">One</num> of the gentlemen connected with the <hi rend="italics">Examiner</hi> went to all the hospitals to see if there was any person therein who received his wounds from the bayonet.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="385"/>This happened nearly a fortnight since and we do not know that we precisely recollect the issue of the investigation as stated in the paper.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="386"/>We are under the impression, however, that only <num value="1">one</num> or <num value="2">two</num> were found thus wounded, and that they were accidentally hurt by some of their own comrades in the hurry of the conflict.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="387"/>This statement agrees with all we have heard from other quarters.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="388"/>We have examined many persons &mdash; officers and men &mdash; with regard to the matter, and they all say the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> made no bayonet charge, either at <placeName reg="Williamsburg, Williamsburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7014629">Williamsburg</placeName> or at <placeName key="tgn,1122759" n="1.000 34" reg="chickahominy, virginia">Chickahominy</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="389"/>Indeed, they all asseverate the direct reverse.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="390"/>They say that our men repeatedly charged, and that in no instance did the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> stand long enough to receive the shock.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="391"/><persName n="McClellan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00188" reg="mostcommon:McClellan,nomatch:0"><surname>McClellan</surname></persName>'s statement, on his official dispatch with regard to a charge made upon <orgName n="brigade"><persName n="Early,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00189" reg="mostcommon:Early,nomatch:0"><surname>Early</surname></persName>'s brigade</orgName> at <placeName reg="Williamsburg, Williamsburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7014629">Williamsburg</placeName>, was so notoriously false that <persName n="Early,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00190" reg="mostcommon:Early,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Early</surname></persName> felt himself constrained to give it the lie direct, under his own hand, in the newspapers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="392"/>His statements about <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> charges at <placeName key="tgn,1122759" n="1.000 34" reg="chickahominy, virginia">Chickahominy</placeName> are given the lie just as direct by every General on the field.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="393"/>But it is not wonderful.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="394"/>A man who can descend to lie as he did about that battle in other respects, will descend to anything. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="395"/> <persName n="McClellan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00191" reg="mostcommon:McClellan,nomatch:0"><surname>McClellan</surname></persName> evidently wishes to stimulate his men to the bayonet trial.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="396"/>He has tried whiskey, and it failed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="397"/>He is now trying to make them believe that they did things which they never did, in the hope that they may try to do the same thing again. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head>The enemy's loss at <placeName key="tgn,1122759" n="1.000 34" reg="chickahominy, virginia">Chickahominy</placeName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="398"/> The truth with regard to the loss of the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> at <placeName key="tgn,1122759" n="1.000 34" reg="chickahominy, virginia">Chickahominy</placeName> begins to come out, in spite of all <persName n="McClellan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00192" reg="mostcommon:McClellan,nomatch:0"><surname>McClellan</surname></persName>'s attempts to suppress it. At <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> it was stated, roughly, at <num value="3000">3,000</num> men killed, wounded and missing.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="399"/>We knew that was an under estimate, for intelligence received from within their lines made it, by their own confession, amount to at least <num value="4000">4,000</num> in wounded.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="400"/>Next came the statement of the <orgName n="New York Herald" type="newspaper">New York <hi rend="italics">Herald</hi></orgName>, which gave <measure n="800" type="killed">800 killed</measure> and <measure n="4000" type="wounded">4,000 wounded</measure>, besides a number of missing.--Knowing the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> propensity to lie, we then expressed our conviction that they had lost at least <num value="10000">ten thousand</num> men. In the meantime out came <persName n="McClellan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00193" reg="mostcommon:McClellan,nomatch:0"><surname>McClellan</surname></persName>'s report, in which, after claiming a great victory, he acknowledged a loss of <num value="5724">5,724</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="401"/>Week before last, a lady arrived in this city from beyond the enemy's lines, who had heard their officers say, in the cars, that they were badly beaten, and that their loss was at least <num value="10000">10,000</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="402"/>Now, the correspondent of the <orgName n="New York Tribune" type="newspaper">New York <hi rend="italics">Tribune</hi></orgName> lets out the whole secret, and there can be no farther doubt.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="403"/>The loss was <hi rend="italics">at least </hi> <num value="10000">10,000</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="404"/>The correspondent is apprehensive that when the truth is all told, it will have been found to be greatly more. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="405"/> Was this a victory for <persName n="McClellan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00194" reg="mostcommon:McClellan,nomatch:0"><surname>McClellan</surname></persName>?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="406"/>Beaten out of his entrenchments, driven for a mile before our troops, losing <num value="16">sixteen</num> guns and <measure n="800" type="prisoners">800 prisoners</measure>, with an additional loss of <num value="10000">10,000</num>, while our own loss amounted to only about <num value="2300">twenty-three hundred</num>, all told, and while we kept possession of the ground until the water compelled us to withdraw to a higher, where was there an incident to give him a claim to a triumph?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="407"/>He lost at least <num value="1">one</num>-<num value="5" type="ordinal">fifth</num> of the force he employed, a loss greater proportionally than any sustained by the <rs>French</rs> in any of their conflicts with <persName n="Wellington,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00195" reg="mostcommon:Wellington,nomatch:0"><surname>Wellington</surname></persName>, <placeName key="tgn,7008561" n="1.000 1" reg="salamanca,salamanca,castilla-leon,espana,europe">Salamanca</placeName>, and <placeName reg="Waterloo, Lauderdale, Alabama" key="tgn,2005702">Waterloo</placeName>, alone excepted. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="408"/> Astounded at the tremendous damage which we inflicted upon the enemy, the <orgName n="New York Tribune" type="newspaper">New York <hi rend="italics">Tribune</hi></orgName> estimates the number of our troops engaged in the battle at about <num value="60000">sixty thousand</num>, The truth is we had but between <num value="20000">20,000</num> and <num value="25000">25,000</num> all told.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="409"/>Had <num value="60000">60,000</num> been brought to bear on them early in the day &mdash; as was the intention of the <rs>General</rs> in command &mdash; the whole force of the enemy, numbering <orgName type="corps" n="Corps 3">three corps</orgName>, or between <num value="50000">50,000</num> and <num value="60000">60,000</num> men, would have been entirely annihilated.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="410"/>There would not have been left a man to tell the tale.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="411"/>By some unfortunate accident or misunderstanding, this was not the case.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="412"/>We fought them, as it was, in the proportion of <num value="1">one</num> to <num value="2.5">two and a half</num>, and we completely defeated them, although they were entrenched up to their chins, and were defended by swamps deemed impassable, and almost impenetrable thickets. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="413"/> A more gallant achievement than that of our men on this occasion, is not mentioned in history.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="414"/>It ought to animate them to the highest degree.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="415"/>They know, now, and feel, that the enemy is no match for them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="416"/>They see that no odds, however tremendous, can avail anything against the daring impetuosity of Southern soldiers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="417"/>Their country is grateful to them, and they deserve her gratitude.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="418"/>It was their country that animated them to the exertion which won the field and made heroes of them all. But for the consciousness that they were fighting for all they hold dear, it may be doubted whether their exertions could have been so strenuous, so long continued, so successful.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="419"/>Brave in any cause, in that of their country they have proved themselves to be invincible.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="420"/>All honor to the officers and soldiers who fought on that glorious day! </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">The <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> in <placeName reg="Louisiana" key="tgn,7007256">Louisiana</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="421"/> --Not long since, a party of Federal officers and soldiers went <placeName><distance reg="10miles">ten miles</distance> <offset>east</offset> of  <placeName reg="Baton Rouge, Baton Rouge, Louisiana" key="tgn,7017543">Baton Rouge, La.</placeName></placeName>, to the plantation of <persName n="Roberts,Major,Stephen,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00196" reg="default:Roberts,Stephen,,,"><roleName n="Major">Maj.</roleName> <foreName>Stephen</foreName> <surname>Roberts</surname></persName>, an old veteran of <dateStruct value="1814--"><year reg="1814">1814</year></dateStruct>, to devastate his place.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="422"/>As the <rs>Federals</rs> entered his house he shot <num value="1">one</num> of their officers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="423"/>His son, <persName n="Roberts,,Josiah,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00197" reg="default:Roberts,Josiah,,,"><foreName>Josiah</foreName> <surname>Roberts</surname></persName>, was killed in the affair.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="424"/>The old veteran is now a prisoner in <placeName key="tgn,7017543" n="1.000 293" reg="baton rouge, baton rouge, louisiana">Baton Rouge</placeName>, together with another <num value="1">one</num> of his sons, <persName n="Roberts,,Washington,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00198" reg="default:Roberts,Washington,,,"><foreName>Washington</foreName> <surname>Roberts</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="425"/>The Federals destroyed everything on the place but a smoke-house and barn. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">The capture of <placeName reg="Holly Springs, Marshall, Mississippi" key="tgn,2056637">Holly Springs</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="426"/> --The <orgName n="Jackson Mississippian" type="newspaper">Jackson <hi rend="italics">Mississippian</hi></orgName>, of the <num value="18" type="ordinal">18th</num>, says: <cit><q rend="inline">&#x0022;A gentleman who came on the <rs>Northern</rs> train this morning, reports that the <rs>Federals</rs> entered <placeName reg="Holly Springs, Marshall, Mississippi" key="tgn,2056637">Holly Springs</placeName> on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time> or <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> <time>morning</time>, and that the town was in their possession when he left.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="427"/>He also states that <persName n="Bradford,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00199" reg="mostcommon:Bradford,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Bradford</surname></persName>, his neighbor, and <num value="3">three</num> others, were killed by the enemy.&#x0022;</q><bibl n="The Jackson Mississippian,"></bibl></cit> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="Holly Springs, Marshall, Mississippi" key="tgn,2056637">Holly Springs</placeName> and Manchaca.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="428"/> --<placeName reg="Holly Springs, Marshall, Mississippi" key="tgn,2056637">Holly Springs</placeName>, which is reported to have been captured by the enemy, is the county seat of <placeName reg="Marshall, Mississippi, United States" key="tgn,2001132">Marshall county, Miss.</placeName>, and is on the <orgName n="Mississippi Central Railroad" type="railroad">Mississippi Central Railroad</orgName>, <placeName><distance reg="120miles">one hundred and twenty miles</distance> <offset>north</offset> of  <placeName reg="Jackson, Hinds, Mississippi" key="tgn,7016129">Jackson</placeName></placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="429"/>Manchaca, Louisiana, (also reported captured,) is a depot on the <placeName reg="New Orleans, Orleans, Louisiana" key="tgn,7014214">New Orleans</placeName> and <placeName reg="Jackson, Hinds, Mississippi" key="tgn,7016129">Jackson</placeName> road, near the head of <placeName reg="Lake Pontchartrain, Louisiana, United States" key="tgn,1117781">Lake Pontchartrain</placeName>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">From <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="430"/> --The <hi rend="italics"><rs n="Whig" type="political">Whig</rs>,</hi> of the <dateStruct value="--18"><day reg="18">18th inst.</day></dateStruct>, has a dispatch from <placeName reg="Grenada, Grenada, Mississippi" key="tgn,2056541">Grenada</placeName> <placeName reg="Mississippi" key="tgn,7007522">Miss.</placeName>, stating that the <sic>the</sic> <placeName reg="Memphis, Shelby, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017750">Memphis</placeName> papers, of the <num value="15" type="ordinal">15th</num>, report that most of the gun and mortar boats had left for <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName>.--The <hi rend="italics"><rs n="Whig" type="political">Whig</rs></hi> says <q>&#x0022;they are now due here, and we may soon expect the work to commence.&#x0022;</q> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="7"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Stone,Doctor,Warren,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00200" reg="default:Stone,Warren,,,"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <foreName>Warren</foreName> <surname>Stone</surname></persName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="431"/> --The <orgName n="New Orleans Delta" type="newspaper">New Orleans <hi rend="italics">Delta</hi></orgName>, of the <dateStruct value="--12"><day reg="12">12th inst.</day></dateStruct>, intimates that this gentlemen is to be unconditionally released from <placeName reg="Fort Jackson, Plaquemines, Louisiana" key="tgn,2335345">Fort Jackson</placeName>, by <persName n="Butler,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00201" reg="mostcommon:Butler,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Butler</surname></persName>'s order. </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="2"/> 
<div2 type="telegraphic"> 
<head>Telegraphic News.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>From <placeName reg="Chattanooga, Hamilton, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017496">Chattanooga</placeName>.</head> <opener> <dateline> <name type="place">Augusta,</name> <date value="06-23">June 23.</date> </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="432"/> --A dispatch from <placeName reg="Chattanooga, Hamilton, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017496">Chattanooga</placeName>, dated <dateStruct value="--21"><day reg="21">21st inst.</day></dateStruct>, says <persName n="Davis,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00202" reg="mostcommon:Davis,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Davis</surname></persName>, of the <orgName type="regiment" key="2FLRegiment">2d Florida regiment</orgName>, with his command, crossed the river this morning at the <name>Narrows</name>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="433"/>Sharp skirmishing ensued.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="434"/>The result was that the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> were driven back with considerable loss.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="435"/><orgName n="cavalry"><persName n="Scott,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00203" reg="mostcommon:Scott,nomatch:0"><surname>Scott</surname></persName>'s cavalry</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="436"/><persName n="Forrest,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00204" reg="mostcommon:Forrest,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Forrest</surname></persName> commanding, also engaged the enemy.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="437"/>The expedition was commanded by <persName n="Leadbetter,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00205" reg="mostcommon:Leadbetter,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Leadbetter</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="438"/>Our loss was <num value="1">one</num> mortally and <num value="3">three</num> slightly wounded. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="439"/> <persName n="Gurly,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00206" reg="mostcommon:Gurly,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Capt.</roleName> <surname>Gurly</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Alabama" key="tgn,7002659">Alabama</placeName>, and his partisan corps, brought in to-day a captain and <num value="2">two</num> lieutenants of the <orgName type="regiment" key="19ILRegiment">19th Illinois regiment</orgName>, who were captured <placeName><distance reg="12miles">12 miles</distance> from <placeName reg="Huntsville, Madison, Alabama" key="tgn,7013732">Huntsville</placeName></placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="440"/> <persName n="Coffer,Major,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00207" reg="mostcommon:Coffer,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <surname>Coffer</surname></persName>, captured by <persName n="Morgan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00208" reg="nearbymention:Morgan,Washington,,,"><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>, is to be exchanged for <persName n="Wood,Lieutenant-Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00209" reg="mostcommon:Wood,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lieutenant-Colonel">Lieut. Col.</roleName> <surname>Wood</surname></persName>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head>Operations near <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName>.</head> <opener> <dateline> <name type="place">Charleston,</name> <date value="06-22">June 22.</date> </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="441"/> --A fleet of <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> gunboats, yesterday, crossed the bar, and shelled <placeName reg="Morris Island, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,2525074">Morris Island</placeName> beach for a considerable distance towards <placeName key="tgn,7013582" n="1.000 46" reg="charleston, charleston, south carolina">Fort Sumter</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="442"/>They then returned to the blockading fleet. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="443"/> <num value="30">Thirty</num> <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> ascended the <rs n="Santee" type="nativeamerican">Santee</rs> river, <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct>, and cut out a small schooner, loaded with cotton, and a steam tug. </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="444"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="amusements"> 
<head>Amusements.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="445"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="runaways"> 
<head>Runaways.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head type="nobreak">Runaway--<measure n="20dollars" type="currency">$20</measure> reward.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="446"/> --Runaway, our negro man, <persName n="Claiborne,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00210" reg="mostcommon:Claiborne,nomatch:0"><surname>Claiborne</surname></persName>, who has served in our office for <num value="8">8</num> or <measure n="9years" type="date">9 years</measure>. He is a very dark mulatto, small size, about <measure n="35years" type="date">35 years</measure> old. He has some decayed teeth in front, and usually smiles when spoken to, and wears a small goatee and moustache.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="447"/>He wore off a brown roundabout and soft black hat. He was lurking about the city for <measure n="2weeks" type="date">two weeks</measure> and may be still, though he may have taken a situation as cook for some <num value="1">one</num> in the army.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="448"/>We will pay <measure n="20dollars" type="currency">$20</measure> for his delivery to us, or confinement in jail, so that we get him. <orgName><persName n="Maddux,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00211" reg="mostcommon:Maddux,nomatch:0"><surname>Maddux</surname></persName> &#x0026; Co.</orgName>, </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="449"/> je <num value="24">24</num>--6t* <address><street n="Cary street">Cary street</street></address>, <num value="3">3</num> doors below <num value="13" type="ordinal">13th</num>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head type="nobreak">Runaway</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="450"/> --From my house, on the <dateStruct value="--11"><day reg="11">11th inst.</day></dateStruct>, my Negro Girl <persName><foreName>Mary</foreName></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="451"/>She is about <num value="11">11</num> or <measure n="12years" type="date">12 years</measure> of age; <measure n="4feet" type="distance">4 feet</measure> <measure n="6inches" type="distance">6 inches</measure> in height; her skin of a dark brown color, and hair curly.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="452"/>Had on, when she left, a blue striped homespun frock.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="453"/>A liberal reward will be paid to any <num value="1">one</num> who will apprehend and deliver said Girl to me, at <address><street n="Broad Street 235">No. 235 Broad street</street></address>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="454"/> je <num value="24">24</num>--6t* Samuel Stern. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head type="nobreak"><measure n="30dollars" type="currency">Thirty dollars</measure> reward.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="455"/> --Left me, while at <placeName reg="Yorktown, York, Virginia" key="tgn,2115169">Yorktown</placeName>, my boy <persName><foreName>Dave</foreName></persName>, who is about <measure n="25years" type="date">25 years</measure> old, black complected, spare made, will weigh about <measure n="140l." type="pounds"><num value="140">140</num> pounds</measure>, <measure n="5feet" type="distance">5 feet</measure> <num value="10">10</num> or <measure n="11inches" type="distance">11 inches</measure> in height.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="456"/>Last heard from was at <placeName reg="Williamsburg, Williamsburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7014629">Williamsburg</placeName>, time of the fight.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="457"/>I will pay the above reward for his delivery at camp, or at some safe jail, so that I get him. <persName n="Thomas,,P.,F.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00212" reg="default:Thomas,P.,F.,,"><foreName>P.</foreName> <foreName>F.</foreName> <surname>Thomas</surname></persName>, </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="458"/> je <num value="24">24</num>--6t* <orgName type="company" n="Company K">Co. K</orgName>, <num value="6" type="ordinal">6th</num> Reg't <orgName type="mil" key="ALVolunteer">Ala. Vols.</orgName> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="groceries"> 
<head>Groceries, Liquors, &#x0026;c.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="459"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="horses"> 
<head>Horses for sale.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="460"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="3"/> 
<div2 type="announcements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="married" n="1"> 
<head>Married,</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="461"/> <date>Thursday</date>, the <dateStruct value="--19"><day reg="19">19th inst.</day></dateStruct>, by <persName n="Minnegerode,Reverend-Doctor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00213" reg="mostcommon:Minnegerode,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Reverend-Doctor">Rev. Dr.</roleName> <surname>Minnegerode</surname></persName>, at the residence of the bride's father, <persName n="Spratt,Major,L.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00214" reg="default:Spratt,L.,W.,,"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <foreName>L.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Spratt</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston, S. C.</placeName>, and <persName><foreName>Mary</foreName></persName> A., only <persName n="Wadsworth,IsFather,John,E.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00215" reg="default:Wadsworth,John,E.,,"><roleName n="IsFather">daughter of</roleName> <foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>Wadsworth</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Va.</placeName> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="death" n="2"> 
<head>Died,</head> 
<div4 type="obit" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="462"/> On the <date value="06-22">22d of June,</date> of scarlet fever, <persName n="Washington,,Thomas,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00216" reg="default:Washington,Thomas,,,"><foreName>Thomas</foreName> <surname>Washington</surname></persName>, only child of <persName><foreName>William</foreName></persName> R, and <persName n="Brown,,Rosa,B.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00217" reg="default:Brown,Rosa,B.,,"><foreName>Rosa</foreName> <foreName>B.</foreName> <surname>Brown</surname></persName>, aged <measure n="18months" type="date">18 months</measure>. </p> <cit><q> <lg type="stanza"> <l>Has my darling <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Thomas,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00218" reg="nearbymention:Thomas,P.,F.,,"><surname>Thomas</surname></persName></hi> gone </l><l>To number with the rest?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="463"/></l><l>And has my dearest <persName><foreName>Jesus</foreName></persName> </l><l>Taken him from my breast?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="464"/></l> </lg> <lg type="stanza"> <l>Hush, my child, lie still and slumber, </l><l>Holy angels guard thy bed; </l><l>Heavenly blessings without number </l><l>Gently fall upon they heads.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="465"/></l> </lg> </q><bibl n="A Friend"></bibl></cit> 
<p> The friends of the family are requested to attend his funeral to day, at <time value="10oclock">10 o'clock</time>, without further notice. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="466"/> On the <dateStruct value="--23"><day reg="23">23d instant</day></dateStruct>, at <time value="9am">9 o'clock A. M.</time>, at the residence of her father, on <address><street n="Marshall Street">Marshall</street></address>, between <address><street n="17 Street">17th</street></address> and <address><street n="18 Street">18th streets</street></address>, <persName n="Sims,,Cora,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00219" reg="default:Sims,Cora,,,"><foreName>Cora</foreName> <surname>Sims</surname></persName>, only <persName n="Thos,IsFather,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00220" reg="mostcommon:Thos,nomatch:0"><roleName n="IsFather">daughter of</roleName> <surname>Thos</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="467"/>and <persName n="French,,Harriet,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00221" reg="default:French,Harriet,,,"><foreName>Harriet</foreName> <surname>French</surname></persName>, aged <num value="1">1</num> year and <measure n="4months" type="date">4 months</measure>. </p> <cit><q> <lg type="stanza"> <l>The little crib is empty </l><l>Where oft I've seen thee lie, </l><l>So beautiful in thy deep sleep, </l><l>Emblem of purity.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="468"/></l><l>And, oh!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="469"/>how silent is the place </l><l>Where late I heard thy voice </l><l>In gleeful shout, or merry laugh, </l><l>Making my heart rejoice.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="470"/></l> </lg> <lg type="stanza"> <l>In vain I look around me, </l><l>Thy cherub form to see; </l><l>Art thou not hiding, baby-- </l><l>Is this reality?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="471"/></l><l><name n="God" type="God">God's</name> sunshine streameth in the room, </l><l>But midnight's in my heart; </l><l>I never dreamed such agony, </l><l>Baby, that we should part.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="472"/></l> </lg> </q><bibl></bibl></cit> 
<p> The funeral will take place at <placeName reg="Union, Union, South Carolina" key="tgn,2096848">Union Station</placeName> this evening at <time value="5oclock">5 o'clock</time>. The friends and acquaintances of the family are respectfully invited to attend. * </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="473"/> At his father's residence, on <placeName reg="Gamble's Hill">Gamble's Hill</placeName>, on <dateStruct value="--23"><day reg="23">23d inst.</day></dateStruct>, <persName n="O'Brien,,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00222" reg="default:O'Brien,James,,,"><foreName>James</foreName> <surname>O'Brien</surname></persName>, aged <measure n="33years" type="date">33 years</measure>, after a painful illness. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="474"/> His funeral will take place this morning at <time value="10oclock">10 o'clock</time>, from his late residence.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="475"/>The friends of the family are invited to attend without further notice. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="476"/> On <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct>, <date value="1862-06-20">June 20th, 1862,</date> <persName n="Skinner,Private,Joseph,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00223" reg="default:Skinner,Joseph,H.,,"><roleName n="Private">Private</roleName> <foreName>Joseph</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Skinner</surname></persName>, of the <orgName n="Mobile Rifles" type="rifles">Mobile Rifles</orgName>, <orgName type="regiment" key="3ALVolunteer">3d regiment Alabama volunteers</orgName>, of wounds received in the battle of the <rs>Chickahominy</rs>, <date value="06-01">June 1st.</date> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="477"/> When his country called upon her sons to take up their arms in her defence, he was among the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> to respond.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="478"/>He has gone, and among the many kindred spirits offered a sacrifice to liberty there was none more true, none more dauntless, than his. He was a dutiful son, an affectionate brother, a true friend, and a brave soldier.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="479"/>Peace to his ashes. (*) <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Comrade,,A.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00224" reg="default:Comrade,A.,,,"><foreName>A.</foreName> <surname>Comrade</surname></persName>.</hi> </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="480"/> At the residence of <persName n="Taylor,,Thomas,S.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00225" reg="default:Taylor,Thomas,S.,,"><foreName n="Thomas">Thos.</foreName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <surname>Taylor</surname></persName>, on <dateStruct value="--19"><day type="name">Thursday</day>, <day reg="19">19th inst.</day></dateStruct>, at <time value="10pm">10 o'clock P. M.</time>, after a protracted and painful illness, which she bore with <name>Christian</name> resignation, <persName n="Taylor,Miss,Alice,T.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00226" reg="default:Taylor,Alice,T.,,"><roleName n="Miss">Miss</roleName> <foreName>Alice</foreName> <foreName>T.</foreName> <surname>Taylor</surname></persName>, a native of <placeName reg="Loudoun, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,7015770">Loudoun county, Va.</placeName>, but for several years past a resident of this city, in the <num value="65" type="ordinal">65th</num> year of her age. * </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="481"/> On <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> <time>morning</time>, at <time value="12:20">20 minutes past 12</time> o'clk, at her grandfather's, (<persName n="Brown,Mister,Joseph,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00227" reg="default:Brown,Joseph,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>Joseph</foreName> <surname>Brown</surname></persName>,) of brain fever, <persName n="Catherine,,Mary,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00228" reg="default:Catherine,Mary,,,"><foreName>Mary</foreName> <surname>Catherine</surname></persName>, <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> child of <persName><foreName>George</foreName></persName> E. and <persName n="Bowden,,Mary,J.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00229" reg="default:Bowden,Mary,J.,,"><foreName>Mary</foreName> <foreName>J.</foreName> <surname>Bowden</surname></persName>, aged <measure n="11months" type="date">11 months</measure> and <measure n="19days" type="date">19 days</measure>. * </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="482"/> At the residence of <persName n="Terry,Mister,M.,J.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00230" reg="default:Terry,M.,J.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <foreName>J.</foreName> <surname>Terry</surname></persName>, <placeName reg="Goochland, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002163">in Goochland county, Va.</placeName>, on the <date value="1862-06-18"> 18th of June, 1862,</date> <persName n="Hopkins,,Edward,B.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00231" reg="default:Hopkins,Edward,B.,,"><foreName>Edward</foreName> <foreName>B.</foreName> <surname>Hopkins</surname></persName>, only child of J. N. and <persName n="Hopkins,,Bettle,J.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00232" reg="default:Hopkins,Bettle,J.,,"><foreName>Bettle</foreName> <foreName>J.</foreName> <surname>Hopkins</surname></persName>, aged <measure n="8months" type="date">8 months</measure> and <measure n="26days" type="date">26 days</measure>. </p> <cit><q> <lg type="stanza"> <l>Weep not for me, my parents dear, </l><l>I've gone to rest &mdash; you need not fear.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="483"/></l><l>My stay was short, as you may see, </l><l>Therefore prepare to follow me. </l> </lg> </q><bibl></bibl></cit> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="484"/> On the night of the <dateStruct value="--17"><day reg="17">17th</day></dateStruct>, after a long and painful illness, <persName n="Beauregard,,Johnston,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00233" reg="default:Beauregard,Johnston,,,"><foreName>Johnston</foreName> <surname>Beauregard</surname></persName>, infant <persName n="Julia,IsFather,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00234" reg="mostcommon:Julia,nomatch:0"><roleName n="IsFather">son of</roleName> <surname>Julia</surname></persName> A. and <persName n="Wright,,Philip,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00235" reg="default:Wright,Philip,M.,,"><foreName>Philip</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Wright</surname></persName>, aged <measure n="6months" type="date">6 months</measure>. </p> <cit><q> <lg type="stanza"> <l>Happy infant, early rest, </l><l>Rest, in peaceful slumbers rest; </l><l>Early rescued from thy cares, </l><l>Which increased with growing years.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="485"/></l> </lg> </q><bibl></bibl></cit> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> On <dateStruct value="--21"><day type="name">Saturday</day>, <day reg="21">21st instant</day></dateStruct>, <persName><foreName>Willie</foreName></persName> T., infant <persName n="Wm,IsFather,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00236" reg="mostcommon:Wm,nomatch:0"><roleName n="IsFather">son of</roleName> <surname>Wm</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="486"/>H. and <persName n="Clemmitt,,Jane,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00237" reg="default:Clemmitt,Jane,W.,,"><foreName>Jane</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Clemmitt</surname></persName>, aged <measure n="3months" type="date">3 months</measure>. </p> <cit><q> <lg type="stanza"> <l>Now know ye why we could not keep </l><l>This bud &mdash; it was not given, </l><l>'Twas only lent it went to sleep, </l><l>To wake a flower in heaven.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="487"/></l> </lg> <lg type="stanza"> <l>This lovely bud, so young and fair, </l><l>Called hence by early doom, </l><l>Is gone to show how sweet a flower </l><l>In Paradise would bloom.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="488"/></l> </lg> </q><bibl></bibl></cit> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> In this city, on <dateStruct value="--21"><day type="name">Saturday</day>, <day reg="21">21st inst.</day></dateStruct>, of typhoid fever, <persName n="Roy,,Mary,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00238" reg="default:Roy,Mary,,,"><foreName>Mary</foreName> <surname>Roy</surname></persName>, aged <measure n="13years" type="date">13 years</measure>, only daughter of <persName n="John,Doctor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00239" reg="mostcommon:John,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <surname>John</surname></persName> H. and <persName n="Ellerson,,Laura,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00240" reg="default:Ellerson,Laura,,,"><foreName>Laura</foreName> <surname>Ellerson</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Hanover, York, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,2089058">Hanover</placeName> co., Va. </p> <cit><q> <lg type="stanza"> <l><q>&#x0022;She is not dead, but sleepeth.&#x0022;</q> </l> </lg> </q><bibl></bibl></cit> </div4> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="personal"> 
<head>Personal.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="489"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="13"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="boarding"> 
<head>Boarding.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="490"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="4"/> 
<div2 type="wants"> 
<head>Wants.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="491"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="13"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="14"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="15"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="16"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="17"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="18"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="19"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="20"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="real estate"> 
<head><rs n="real estate" type="product">Real Estate</rs> for sale.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="492"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="5"/> 
<div2 type="lost"> 
<head>Lost, Strayed, &#x0026;c.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="493"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="13"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="14"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="15"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="16"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="17"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="18"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="19"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="20"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="21"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="22"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="23"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="24"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="25"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="26"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="27"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="28"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="29"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="30"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="6"/> 
<div2 type="military"> 
<head>Military Notices.</head> 
<div3 type="orders" n="1"> 
<head type="nobreak">The Richmond Battalion.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="494"/> --Since the granting of authority to raise a battalion in <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> for special service, embracing persons of any age, some difficulty seems to have existed with those enrolled among the <num value="2" type="ordinal">Second</num> Class Militia, as to whether such of them as desired to join the battalion would be allowed to do so. The following correspondence leaves no doubt on the subject: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="495"/> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, <date value="1862-06-23">June 23, 1862.</date> <persName n="Elliott,,W.,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00241" reg="default:Elliott,W.,M.,,"><foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Elliott</surname></persName>. </p> 
<div4 type="letter" n="1"> 
<head></head> <opener> <dateline> <name type="place">C. S. of America, <orgName n="War Department" type="department">War Department</orgName>, Richmond,</name> <date value="1862-06-20">June 20, 1862.</date> </dateline> <salute>His <rs type="role2">Excellency</rs>, <persName n="Letcher,Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00242" reg="mostcommon:Letcher,John,,,:1"><roleName n="Governor">Gov.</roleName> <surname>Letcher</surname></persName>, <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>:</salute> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="496"/> Sir &mdash; I respectfully request permission for the militia called out in the city of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> to volunteer in the battalion authorized to be raised by <rs type="role">Capt.</rs> W. M. <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Elliott,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00243" reg="nearbymention:Elliott,W.,M.,,"><surname>Elliott</surname></persName>,</hi> for local service within the circuit of the redoubts around <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> and <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Manchester</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="497"/>The battalion will consist of <num value="5">five</num> companies, of <num value="100">one hundred</num> men each, will be mustered into the <rs>Confederate</rs> service, and will, in addition to their pay in the <orgName n="Confederate Army" type="org">Confederate army</orgName>, receive a bounty from the city government of <measure n="20dollars" type="currency">$20</measure> per month to each noncommissioned officer and private. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="498"/> They will be charged with the important duty of guarding the bridges, prisons, public and private property, and with maintaining order in the city.--I think that the organization of this Battalion will probably render it unnecessary to make any further call on the militia of the city, and is considered of very great importance to the public service. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="499"/> I most earnestly request your <rs type="role2">Excellency</rs> to facilitate its formation by every means in your power. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="500"/> <persName n="Elliott,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00244" reg="nearbymention:Elliott,W.,M.,,"><roleName n="Captain">Captain</roleName> <surname>Elliott</surname></persName> will give you any further explanation that may be desired. </p> <closer> <salute>Very respectfully,<lb/>Your obedient servant.</salute> <signed><persName n="Randolph,,George,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00245" reg="default:Randolph,George,W.,,"><foreName n="George">Geo.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName>  <surname>Randolph</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>. </closer> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="501"/> Any of the <num value="2" type="ordinal">Second</num> Class Militia that prefer service in the <name>Battalion</name> herein referred to, have the right to enlist therein.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="502"/>When any of them so enlist, their names will be reported to <persName n="Wilkins,Major,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00246" reg="mostcommon:Wilkins,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <surname>Wilkins</surname></persName>, who will thereupon strike them from the rolls. </p> <closer> <date value="1861-06-21">June 21, 1861.</date> <signed><persName n="Letcher,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00247" reg="default:Letcher,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName>  <surname>Letcher</surname></persName>.</signed> <lb/> je <num value="24">24</num>--3t </closer> </div4> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="2"> 
<head type="nobreak">Attention!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="503"/>Marylanders.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="504"/> --I have been authorized to Recruit for the <orgName type="regiment" key="1MDRegiment">1st Maryland Regiment</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="505"/>All <placeName key="tgn,7007516" n="1.000 5429" reg="maryland">Maryland</placeName> men are earnestly solicited to rally around the little blue flag of their State, and add new trophies of triumph to those which already adorn its staff.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="506"/>All Marylanders, now serving in any corps other than the <placeName key="tgn,7007516" n="1.000 5429" reg="maryland">Maryland</placeName> Line, are, at their option, entitled to be transferred to the <rs type="place">Line</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="507"/> Applications for this purpose should be made to <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Kyle,Major,George,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00248" reg="default:Kyle,George,H.,,"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <foreName n="George">Geo.</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Kyle</surname></persName>,</hi> at the <name>Headquarters</name>, <address><street n="Pearl Street 14">No. 14 Pearl street</street></address>, or to myself.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="508"/>A large amount of excellent clothing has just been forwarded to the regiment for gratuitous distribution, and all enlisting will receive the usual bounty of <measure n="50dollars" type="currency">$50</measure>. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Diggs,,Eugene,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00249" reg="default:Diggs,Eugene,,,"><foreName>Eugene</foreName>  <surname>Diggs</surname></persName>,</signed> lately Lieut. <orgName type="regiment" key="MD1">1st Md.</orgName> <persName n="Reg,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00250" reg="mostcommon:Reg,nomatch:0"><surname>Reg</surname></persName>. <lb/> Office on Main, near the corner of <address><street n="Pearl street">Pearl street</street></address>. <lb/> Hours: From <time value="10am">10 A. M.</time> to <time value="2pm">2 P. M.</time> je <num value="24">24</num>--1w* </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="3"> 
<head><orgName n="Greanor's Company"><persName n="Greanor,Company,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00251" reg="mostcommon:Greanor,John,H.,,:1"><roleName n="Company"></roleName><surname>Greanor</surname></persName>'s company</orgName>!<lb/><persName n="Elliott,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00252" reg="nearbymention:Elliott,W.,M.,,"><surname>Elliott</surname></persName>'s city Battalion!<lb/>Permanently stationed at <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="509"/> Members of this Battalion are exempt from conscript and militia duty. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="510"/> Men of all ages received. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="511"/> <hi rend="smallcaps">Pay</hi>--<measure n="31dollars" type="currency">$31</measure> per month and rations.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="512"/>Clothing and quarters furnished. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="513"/> <placeName reg="Recruiting office">Recruiting office</placeName>, <address><street n="Main Street 93">93 Main street</street></address>. </p> <closer> je <num value="24">24</num>--3t* <signed><persName n="Greanor,,John,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00253" reg="default:Greanor,John,H.,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName>  <surname>Greanor</surname></persName>, <persName n="Com,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00254" reg="mostcommon:Com,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Capt.</roleName> <surname>Com</surname></persName>'g.</signed> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="4"> 
<head type="nobreak">Attention, Marylanders!</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="514"/> --The undersigned, having been authorized by the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs> to raise a company of Sharpshooters for the <placeName key="tgn,7007516" n="1.000 5429" reg="maryland">Maryland</placeName> Line, has opened a recruiting office at the southeast corner of <address><street n="Main Street">Main</street></address> and <address><street n="Pearl Street">Pearl</street></address> streets. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="515"/> Marylanders desirous of joining their brothers in arms who have covered themselves with glory in the recent battles under <q>&#x0022;<persName n="Jackson,,Stonewall,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00255" reg="default:Jackson,Stonewall,,,"><foreName>Stonewall</foreName> <surname>Jackson</surname></persName>,&#x0022;</q> will come forward and enroll their names at once.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="516"/>Subsistence furnished from date of enlistment. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="517"/> Marylanders in other organizations can be transferred to this corps upon application by mail or in person. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Clark,,Matthew,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00256" reg="default:Clark,Matthew,,,"><foreName>Matthew</foreName>  <surname>Clark</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> Late <rs type="role" reg="Commander">Commander</rs> of Lanier Guards, <lb/> je <num value="23">23</num>--6t* of <placeName reg="Baltimore, Baltimore Independent City, Maryland" key="tgn,7013352">Baltimore, Md.</placeName> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="5"> 
<head><hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="Royster Hospital">Royster Hospital</placeName>,</hi> <date value="1862-06-20">June 20, 1862.</date></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="518"/>All out Patients registered at this Hospital are hereby notified to report immediately in person, or send <rs type="role2">Surgeon</rs>'s certificate of their inability to do so, else they will be reported as deserters. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Harrison,,V.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00257" reg="default:Harrison,V.,W.,,"><foreName>V.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName>  <surname>Harrison</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> je <num value="21">21</num>--3t* <rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Surgeon">Assistant Surgeon</rs> in charge. </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="6"> 
<head><placeName reg="Banner Hospital">Banner Hospital</placeName>,<date value="1862-06-19">June 19th, 1862.</date></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="519"/> all out-patients registered at this Hospital, must report immediately at the <rs type="place">Hospital</rs>, or they will be reported as deserters.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="520"/>Office hours from <num value="10">10</num> to <time value="1oclock">1 o'clock</time>. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Thom,,William,Alexander,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00258" reg="default:Thom,William,Alexander,,"><foreName n="William">Wm.</foreName> <foreName n="Alexander">Alex.</foreName>  <surname>Thom</surname></persName>.</signed> <lb/> je <num value="20">20</num>--3t* <rs type="role2">Surgeon</rs> in charge. </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="7"> 
<head type="nobreak">Charlotte Cavalry.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="521"/> --The Charlotte Cavalry, having at this time only <num value="63">sixty-three</num>, rank and file, <num value="17">Seventeen</num> Recruits are desired to fill it up to the maximum number.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="522"/>This company is <num value="1">one</num> of the best armed companies in the service, being armed with <persName n="Merril,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00259" reg="mostcommon:Merril,nomatch:0"><surname>Merril</surname></persName>'s Carbine, <persName n="Colt,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00260" reg="mostcommon:Colt,nomatch:0"><surname>Colt</surname></persName>'s Navy Pistol, and Sabres.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="523"/>I have at my disposal enough arms of the above kind to arm quite a number of recruits, which will be distributed to them as they join this company.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="524"/>Recruits wishing to join us will equip themselves.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="525"/>and report to me in camp, near the <rs>Greenbrier White Sulphur</rs>, where arms will be furnished them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="526"/>Further information can be had of <persName n="Friend,Mister,William,G.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00261" reg="default:Friend,William,G.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName n="William">Wm.</foreName> <foreName>G.</foreName> <surname>Friend</surname></persName>, near <placeName reg="Drake's Branch, Charlotte, Virginia" key="tgn,2111511">Drake's Branch, Charlotte county, Va.</placeName>, who is requested to act as <rs type="role" reg="Recruiting-Agent">Recruiting Agent</rs> for the company. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Bouldin,,E.,E.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00262" reg="default:Bouldin,E.,E.,,"><foreName>E.</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName>  <surname>Bouldin</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> je <num value="19">19</num>--6t <persName n="Charlotte,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00263" reg="mostcommon:Charlotte,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Captain</roleName> <surname>Charlotte</surname></persName> Cavalry. </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="8"> 
<head>City Battalion--<lb/><hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Elliot,Major,W.,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00264" reg="default:Elliot,W.,M.,,"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Elliot</surname></persName>,</hi> commanding.<lb/>pay <measure n="31dollars" type="currency">$31</measure> per month and rations.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="527"/> <num value="100">one hundred</num> men Wanted, between the ages of <num value="16">16</num> and <num value="45">45</num>, for a company in the above battalion, for local and special defence of the city of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> or <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Manchester</placeName>, for a term of <measure n="6months" type="date">six months</measure>, unless sooner discharged by order of the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="528"/> None but men of good character will be received. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="529"/> Apply, between the hours of <time value="9am">9 A. M.</time> and <time value="2pm">2 P. M.</time>, to </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Harrison,,W.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00265" reg="default:Harrison,W.,W.,,"><foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName>  <surname>Harrison</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> at <persName n="Ragland,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00266" reg="mostcommon:Ragland,nomatch:0"><surname>Ragland</surname></persName> &#x0026; Bro.'s, cor. <address><street n="9 Street">9th</street></address> and <address><street n="Main Street">Main sts.</street></address>; <lb/> <signed><persName n="Baughman,,George,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00267" reg="default:Baughman,George,,,"><foreName n="George">Geo.</foreName>  <surname>Baughman</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <signed><persName n="Allison,,W.,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00268" reg="default:Allison,W.,H.,,"><foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName>  <surname>Allison</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <address><street n="Main Street 121">121 Main street</street></address>; <lb/> <signed><persName n="West,,John,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00269" reg="default:West,John,M.,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName>  <surname>West</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> je <num value="19">19</num>--6t* <address><street n="Main Street 145">145 Main street</street></address>. </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="9"> 
<head type="nobreak">Attention!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="530"/>Marylanders.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="531"/> --I am authorized to recruit for the <orgName type="regiment" key="MD1">first Maryland</orgName> Line, and start for headquarters (at <placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName>,) positively next <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> <time>morning</time>. I have opened an office over D. H. <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Brotherton,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00270" reg="mostcommon:Brotherton,nomatch:0"><surname>Brotherton</surname></persName>'s</hi> store, corner of <address><street n="Main Street">Main</street></address> and <address><street n="14 Street">14th streets</street></address>, for the reception and enrolling of Recruits.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="532"/>There is no excuse for any <persName n="Marylander,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00271" reg="mostcommon:Marylander,nomatch:0"><surname>Marylander</surname></persName> longer.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="533"/>Those who wish to see their native State and homes at an early day, guided by accomplished and gallant officers, have now the last opportunity offered. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Mullen,,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00272" reg="default:Mullen,James,,,"><foreName>James</foreName>  <surname>Mullen</surname></persName>.</signed> <lb/> je <num value="19">19</num>--4t* <rs type="role">1st Lieut.</rs> <orgName type="regiment" key="MD1">1st Maryland</orgName> Line. </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="10"> 
<head type="nobreak">To <rs type="role" reg="Colonel">Colonels</rs> of regiments.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="534"/> --The services of a <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num>-class Drummer, competent to instruct, can be had by addressing <q>&#x0022;X. Y. Z.,&#x0022;</q> <placeName reg="Staunton Post-Office">Staunton P. O.,</placeName> <placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName>, Va. je <num value="19">19</num>--7t* </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="11"> 
<head rend="smallcaps">Headq'rs <orgName type="regiment" n="Reg. 3">3d Reg.</orgName> <orgName type="mil" key="VAInfantry">Va. Infantry</orgName>,</head> <opener> <dateline> <name type="place">Camp near Richmond</name> <date value="1862-06-16">16th June, 1862.</date> </dateline> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="535"/>All officers who are absent from this command, for whatever cause, are hereby ordered to report at once to their companies for duty, or else send every week a certificate of unfitness from some Army <rs type="role" reg="Surgeon">Surgeon</rs> of <hi rend="italics">good standing;</hi> otherwise, they will be published as deserters, and their names stricken from the rolls. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Mayo,,Joseph,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00273" reg="default:Mayo,Joseph,,,"><foreName n="Joseph">Jos.</foreName>  <surname>Mayo</surname>, <genName n="junior">Jr.</genName></persName>,</signed> <persName n="Com,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00274" reg="mostcommon:Com,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Com</surname></persName>'g. <lb/> <orgName n="Petersburg Express" type="newspaper">Petersburg Express</orgName> copy the above. <lb/> je <num value="17">17</num>--6t* </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="substitute"> 
<head>Substitute Notices.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="536"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="13"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="14"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="7"/> 
<div2 type="auction"> 
<head><rs n="auction sales" type="product">Auction Sales</rs>.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="deserters"> 
<head>Deserters.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="537"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> </body> </text> </TEI.2>
