<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> <!DOCTYPE TEI.2 PUBLIC "-//TEI P4//DTD Main DTD Driver File//EN" "http://www.tei-c.org/Guidelines/DTD/tei2.dtd" [ <!ENTITY % TEI.XML "INCLUDE"> <!ENTITY % PersProse PUBLIC "-//Perseus P4//DTD Perseus Prose//EN" "http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/DTD/1.0/PersProse.dtd" > %PersProse; <!NOTATION jpg SYSTEM "JPEG"> <!ENTITY NW_RichTimesD_025_038_001 SYSTEM "NW_RichTimesD_025_038_001.jpg" NDATA jpg> <!ENTITY NW_RichTimesD_025_038_002 SYSTEM "NW_RichTimesD_025_038_002.jpg" NDATA jpg> ]> <TEI.2 id="NW_RichTimesD_025_038"> <teiHeader type="aacr2"> <fileDesc> <titleStmt> <title type="245">The Daily Dispatch: August 13, 1863. </title> <title type="gmd">[Electronic resource] </title> <funder> Institute of Museum and Library Services National Leadership Grant </funder> <respStmt> <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> <resp>Creation of digital images: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> <resp>Conversion to Tei.2-conformant markup: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> </respStmt> </titleStmt> <extent>ca. <num value="30">XXX</num> kilobytes </extent> <publicationStmt> <publisher>University of <orgName n="Richmond Library" type="library">Richmond Library</orgName> </publisher> <pubPlace>Richmond, Virginia </pubPlace> <idno type="Url">Nw_richtimesd_025_038</idno> <availability> 
<p>&#x00A9; 2004 by the University of Richmond. </p> 
<p>Url: http://oncampus.Richmond.edu/academics/Library/digital/ </p> </availability> <date> </date> </publicationStmt> <seriesStmt> 
<p>Institute of Museum and Library Services Civil War Newspaper Project </p> </seriesStmt> <notesStmt> <note>page images have been included from the microfilm version. </note> <note>images were scanned with a Sunrise 2000 scanner from microfilm, at 14x reduction ratio at 400 dpi Optical Resolution. Creation Software: Pixel Translations. Pixtiff version 1.135. </note> <note>Ddd note: shipped: 2005_03_25_ddd_url. </note> </notesStmt> <sourceDesc> <biblFull> <titleStmt> <title type="245">The Daily Dispatch: August 13, 1863. </title> <title type="246"><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName> </title> <respStmt> <resp> </resp> <name> </name> </respStmt> </titleStmt> <editionStmt> 
<p> </p> </editionStmt> <extent>2 pages. </extent> <publicationStmt> <publisher>by Cowardin &#x0026; Hammersley. </publisher> <pubPlace>Richmond </pubPlace> <date value="1863-08-13">August 13, 1863</date><idno type="vol">25.38</idno> </publicationStmt> <seriesStmt> <title> </title> </seriesStmt> <notesStmt> <note>microfilm. Ann Arbor, Mi : Proquest. 1 microfilm reel ; 35 mm. </note> </notesStmt> </biblFull> </sourceDesc> </fileDesc> <encodingDesc> <projectDesc> 
<p>Imls Civil War Newspaper Project. </p> </projectDesc> <editorialDecl> 
<p>the images exist as archival Tiff images, with Jpeg versions for internet access. </p> </editorialDecl> <refsDecl> <state unit="article" /> </refsDecl> <classDecl> <taxonomy id="lcsh"> <bibl> <title>Library of Congress subject Headings, </title> <edition>21st edition, 1998</edition> </bibl> </taxonomy> </classDecl> </encodingDesc> <profileDesc> <creation> <date value="1863">1863 </date> </creation> <langUsage> <language id="eng">English </language> <language id="fre">French </language> </langUsage> 
<textClass> <keywords scheme="lcsh"> 
<list type="simple"> 
<item>Newspapers -- Virginia -- Richmond</item> </list> </keywords> </textClass> </profileDesc> <revisionDesc> <change> <date>September, 2005 </date> <respStmt> <resp>Checker </resp> <name>Grant Dickie, of the University of <orgName n="Richmond Library" type="library">Richmond Library</orgName> </name> </respStmt> 
<item>File checked, not corrected: DO NOT return to vendor. Ur Corrector Note: Did not key "Runaway Ad" page 2, column 2. 1 article. </item> </change> </revisionDesc> </teiHeader> 
<text id="NW_RichTimesD_025_038T"> <front> <milestone unit="page" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="page-image"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="1"/><figure entity="NW_RichTimesD_025_038_001"> <figDesc>Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume <num value="25">25</num>, <num value="38">Number 38</num>, <ref n="page 1">page 1</ref>. </figDesc> </figure></p> </div1> <titlePage> <docTitle><titlePart type="main"> Daily Dispatch </titlePart> </docTitle> <docImprint> Vol. Xxv &mdash; no.<num value="38">38</num> <pubPlace> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Va.</placeName> </pubPlace> <date value="1863-08-13">Thursday, August 13, 1863</date> <persName n="Price,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00001" reg="mostcommon:Price,nomatch:0"><surname>Price</surname></persName> <num value="1">one</num> Cent </docImprint> </titlePage> 
<div1 type="subscription"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName><lb/> by <persName n="Cowardin,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00002" reg="mostcommon:Cowardin,nomatch:0"><surname>Cowardin</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="Hammersley,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00003" reg="mostcommon:Hammersley,nomatch:0"><surname>Hammersley</surname></persName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="2"/>the <rs>Daily Dispatch</rs> is served to subscribers at <measure n="6.25cents" type="currency">six and A Quarter cents</measure> per Week, payable to the <name>Carrier</name> weekly.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="3"/><persName n="Price,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00004" reg="mostcommon:Price,nomatch:0"><surname>Price</surname></persName> for mailing, <measure n="4dollars" type="currency">$4</measure> a year, or <measure n="2.50dollars" type="currency">$2.50</measure> for <measure n="6months" type="date">six months</measure>, in advance.</p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="4"/>the <rs>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</rs> is issued every <dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> and <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> at <measure n="2.00dollars" type="currency">$2.00</measure>, in advance.</p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="5"/>the <rs>Weekly Dispatch</rs> is issued every <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct>, and mailed to subscribers at <measure n="1dollars" type="currency">$1</measure> per annum.</p> </div1> 
<div1 type="advertising"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="6"/> 
<table rows="4" cols="4"> 
<head rend="italics">Terms of Advertising.</head> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <num value="1">1</num> day,</cell><cell><measure n="0.50dollars" type="currency">$0.50</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="5days" type="date">5 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="1.50dollars" type="currency">$1.50</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="2days" type="date">2 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="0.75dollars" type="currency">$0.75</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="5days" type="date">5 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="1.75dollars" type="currency">$1.75</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square <measure n="3days" type="date">3 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="1.00dollars" type="currency">$1.00</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="12days" type="date">12 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="3.00dollars" type="currency">$3.00</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square <measure n="4days" type="date">4 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="1.25dollars" type="currency">$1.25</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <dateStruct value="-1-"><month reg="1">1 month</month></dateStruct>,</cell><cell><measure n="5.00dollars" type="currency">$5.00</measure></cell></row> </table></p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="7"/><hi rend="italics">Larger advertisements in exact properties.</hi></p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="8"/>Advertisements published until forbid, will be charged <measure n="50cents" type="currency">50 cents</measure> per square of <num value="8">eight</num> lines for the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> insertion, and <measure n="25cents" type="currency">25 cents</measure> for each continuance</p> </div1> </front> <body> <milestone unit="column" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.</head> 
<div2 type="morning"> 
<head><date value="1863-08-13">Thursday morning...Aug., 13, 1863.</date></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>The Impotency of their Malice.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="9"/> We lately published from a Massachusetts newspaper a statement of the puissant editor that the only terms the <rs>North</rs> would give the <rs>South</rs> would be to hang a <num value="100">hundred</num> of the ringleaders, make the <rs>Southern States</rs> pay the debt of the war, and hold them thenceforth as territories of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="10"/> And suppose they could do it, the <rs>South</rs> would even then hold a grander place in history than the victorious <rs>North</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="11"/>They cannot degrade us; they cannot humiliate us; they cannot rob the <rs>South</rs> of its place among the <name>Immortals</name>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="12"/>Does not <placeName key="tgn,7006278" n="1.000 27" reg="magyarorszag">Hungary</placeName>, conquered by colossal odds, hold a higher place this hour in the estimation of all mankind than <placeName key="tgn,1000062" n="1.000 128" reg="austria">Austria</placeName>?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="13"/>Is not the blood of martyrs for the truth more precious in the eyes of <name n="God" type="God">God</name> and man than the brute force which dragged them to the stake?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="14"/>Is not the fallen oak, uprooted by the hurricane, a nobler object than the wild winds which have laid its leafy glories in the dust? </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="15"/> Suppose we could be subjugated, and our name and country taken from us, they cannot take away our place in history and in the admiration of all mankind.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="16"/>They cannot obliterate the fact that a feeble population heroically battled for years against <num value="4">four</num> times its numbers, having the resources and the men of the whole world at its command, and only succumbed when resistance was no longer possible.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="17"/>They cannot blot out the sacrifices which men and women have made through all this war of life and worldly goods, and case and home, for the sake of principle and liberty.--They cannot achieve for their own name anything but the intense scorn and disgust which all mankind must feel for a nation which can only overcome its adversary by an enormous preponderance of numbers, and which is base enough to glorify itself on account of victory thus achieved.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="18"/>Who would not rather hold the place in history of the heroic <rs>South</rs> thus conquered than of besotted conquerors, who have proved themselves inferior to their fallen adversary in everything but brute strength? </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="19"/> No. Even if we perish we shall live and triumph.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="20"/>Every Southern battle field will shine on the pages of history in immortal light.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="21"/>Every Southern soldier's grave will be a spot more sacred than the enemy's triumphal arch of victory.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="22"/>The heroic dead of every valley shall rise and stand upon their feet, and lead the vanguard of all future struggles of the oppressed for liberty.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="23"/>Every Southern warrior's tomb shall be kept green by the tears of grateful generations, and their posterity shall be proud of the blood that once coursed through their veins, whilst the descendants of their conqueror shall blush to remember that it was only by <num value="4">four</num> to <num value="1">one</num>, and by piling upon the top of such tremendous odds hordes of foreigners and negroes, that they could crush a struggling handful to the dust. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="24"/> But, Heaven helping us, we shall neither be conquered nor crushed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="25"/>If there were no <name n="God" type="God">God</name>, if numbers and cannon were <name n="God" type="God">God</name>, if Eternal Justice were a dream, we might have despaired of the result at the beginning.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="26"/>But the same <rs>Providence</rs> which has so signally delivered us from the beginning is able still to vindicate the righteous cause.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="27"/>We are in less danger of subjugation at this moment than we were at the very outset of the <rs>War</rs>. If we learn to put our trust in <name n="God" type="God">God</name>, and not in man, <name n="God" type="God">God</name>, who has so often crowned our arms with victory, will conduct our armies to still more glorious success.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="28"/>All in His own good time, He will achieve our deliverance, and will chastise with a retribution as gigantic as their crimes the incarnate fiends who are panting for our destruction. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head>Charge to <persName n="Corday,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00005" reg="nearbymention:Corday,Charlotte,,,"><surname>Corday</surname></persName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="29"/> We find that in our article respecting <persName n="Morgan,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00006" reg="default:Morgan,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Morgan</surname></persName> yesterday, we did not state the circumstances attending the death of <persName n="Corday,,Charlotte,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00007" reg="default:Corday,Charlotte,,,"><foreName>Charlotte</foreName> <surname>Corday</surname></persName> with historical exactness.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="30"/>Our only object was to impress the public as strongly as we could with the distinction between guilt and punishment &mdash; to show that the most sublime patriot, if thrown by misfortune into the hands of a malignant enemy, might be made to suffer the penalty of a common felony &mdash; that, therefore, the only proper rule in such cases &mdash; and that a rule which had been adopted by the instinctive discretion of ages &mdash; was to affix to guilt itself the brand of disgrace, and to leave to innocence its own vindication at its own proper time.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="31"/>But history ought, in all cases where it is possible, to be enunciated with the utmost distinctness.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="32"/>We, therefore,--in obedience to what we consider a maxim that never should be departed from &mdash; give a succinct history of the trial and execution of <persName n="Corday,,Charlotte,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00008" reg="default:Corday,Charlotte,,,"><foreName>Charlotte</foreName> <surname>Corday</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="33"/>It is <num value="1">one</num> of the most affecting incidents in all history. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="34"/> <placeName reg="Charlotte, Mecklenburg, North Carolina" key="tgn,7013584">Charlotte</placeName> was a native of St. Saturnine in the department of the <name>Orme</name>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="35"/>She had received, under the superintendence of her father, a classical education &mdash; had become deeply imbued with the spirit of the ancient writers &mdash; and was in the habit of assimilating certain periods of ancient history to the scenes and events that were passing immediately before her eyes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="36"/>In imitation of her father, she had deeply imbibed the principles of the <name>Girondist</name>, and believed that their overthrow would certainly produce the destruction of the sanguinary triumvirate, (Marat, <persName n="Danton,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00009" reg="mostcommon:Danton,nomatch:0"><surname>Danton</surname></persName>, Robespierre,) who were at that time overwhelming <placeName key="tgn,1000070" n="1.000 1012" reg="france">France</placeName> with blood.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="37"/>But when she saw the citizens of the department of <persName n="Cash,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00010" reg="mostcommon:Cash,nomatch:0"><surname>Cash</surname></persName> enrolling to march to the defence of the <rs>Convention</rs>, she saw that there was no hope in the people, and she conceived the singular design of freeing the world of that monstrous tyrant, who had declared that <num value="300000">300,000</num> heads must fall before <hi rend="italics">liberty</hi> could be safe in <placeName key="tgn,1000070" n="1.000 1012" reg="france">France</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="38"/>She went to <placeName reg="Department de Ville de Paris, Ile-de-France, France" key="tgn,7002980">Paris</placeName> without the knowledge of her father &mdash; obtained admission to Marat &mdash; pretended to be a violent Jacobin &mdash; presented to him a list of several <num value="1000">thousand</num> who had been concerned in the late insurrection against the <rs>Convention</rs> &mdash; and, with out difficulty obtained from him a promise that every man of them should be sent to the guillotine.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="39"/>No sooner had this promise been obtained than she struck the tyrant to the heart with a knife which she had purchased expressly for the occasion.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="40"/>She was immediately arrested and brought before the revolutionary tribunal, where she boldly acknowledged what she had done, and declared that whilst she detested assassination (on principle) she yet felt that she owed it as a duty to her country, to <name n="God" type="God">God</name>, and to human nature, to rid the world by any means of a monster whose sole object in life seemed to be to destroy everything that bore the form of humanity.--Her deportment during the trial was exceedingly modest, and the farthest possible removed from everything that we can conceive of what is called in modern times a &#x0022;strong minded woman.&#x0022; At the close of her trial she took <num value="3">three</num> letters from her bosom and presented them to the <rs type="place">Court</rs>. <num value="2">Two</num> of them were directed to Barbarous, and related entirely to her adventures from the time of her leaving home.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="41"/>The <num value="3" type="ordinal">third</num> was directed to her father.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="42"/>In it she took a solemn farewell of him &mdash; spoke with the utmost simplicity of what she had done &mdash; begged him not to suppose that she could be affected by the criminal's doeth that awaited her &mdash; said that she had <unclear>ty</unclear> of <milestone unit="column" n="2"/> nothing for which he need blush &mdash; and concluded with the line of <persName n="Corneille,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00011" reg="mostcommon:Corneille,nomatch:0"><surname>Corneille</surname></persName>, which we had by mistake supposed she spoke on the scaffold: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="43"/> <cit><q> <lg type="stanza"> <l><foreign lang="fre">&#x0022;Cest la crime qui fait la brute, et nou pasil'schaf fand.&#x0022;</foreign> </l> </lg> </q><bibl></bibl></cit> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="44"/> She was not insulted by the mob on the way to the guillotine.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="45"/>On the contrary, she was the only victim of those bloody times who was not thus insulted.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="46"/>It is true that the women who were called the &#x0022;Furies of the <name>Guillotine</name>&#x0022; had been assembled at the door of the prison for the purpose of insulting her; but when the door was thrown open, and, instead of a strong minded virago, whom probably they expected to see and to hear, they saw her as she was &mdash; so young, so beautiful, so unpromising, and so entirely helpless &mdash; even their hard hearts relented, and while some of them uncovered their heads, others burst into a passion of tears.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="47"/>She ascended the scaffold with undaunted firmness.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="48"/>She had learned the mode of her death, but not the details, and when the executioner proceeded to tie her feet she resisted from an apprehension that he meant to insult her. When he took off the handkerchief, that covered her bosom, at the moment of the fetal stroke, she blushed deeply; and it is even said that her head, which was held up to the multitude immediately after it had fallen, retained this impression of offended modesty. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head>Fortifying the <rs>Pamunkey</rs>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="49"/> The Government ought to give immediate attention to preventing future raids from the <placeName key="tgn,7014664;tgn,2115169;tgn,2115031;tgn,2113715;tgn,2110221" n="0.009 000000.0455	placename;tgn,7014664;Tunstall, New Kent, Virginia,New Kent,Virginia,United States,North and Central America;0.009 000000.0455	placename;tgn,2115169;Yorktown, York, Virginia,York,Virginia,United States,North and Central America;0.009 000000.0455	placename;tgn,2115031;White House, Mecklenburg, Virginia,Mecklenburg,Virginia,United States,North and Central America;0.009 000000.0455	placename;tgn,2113715;Port Republic, Rockingham, Virginia,Rockingham,Virginia,United States,North and Central America;0.009 000000.0455	placename;tgn,2110221;Aarons Creek, Halifax, Virginia,Halifax,Virginia,United States,North and Central America" reg="Tunstall, New Kent, Virginia,New Kent,Virginia,United States,North and Central America;Yorktown, York, Virginia,York,Virginia,United States,North and Central America;White House, Mecklenburg, Virginia,Mecklenburg,Virginia,United States,North and Central America;Port Republic, Rockingham, Virginia,Rockingham,Virginia,United States,North and Central America;Aarons Creek, Halifax, Virginia,Halifax,Virginia,United States,North and Central America">White House</placeName> by selecting <num value="1">one</num> of several eligible positions which may be found on the <rs>Pamunkey</rs> for preventing the ascent of <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> vessels.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="50"/>A few guns, placed on <num value="1">one</num> of the bluffs of the <rs>Pamunkey</rs>, would secure a large and fertile tract of country from destructive visitations. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head>Reported fighting at <placeName reg="Brock's Gap">Brock's Gap</placeName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="51"/> Yesterday evening a report was brought down by passengers from <placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName> that the enemy have made <num value="2">two</num> attempts to pass through <placeName reg="Brock's Gap">Brock's Gap</placeName>, which is a passage in the <rs type="place">North Mountain</rs>, in <placeName reg="Rockingham, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002187">Rockingham county</placeName>, about <placeName><distance reg="12miles">twelve miles</distance> <offset>north</offset> of  <placeName reg="Harrisonburg, Harrisonburg, Virginia" key="tgn,2112170">Harrisonburg</placeName></placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="52"/>On Monday they made their appearance at the gap, but were easily and soon driven off by a portion of <persName n="Imboden,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00012" reg="mostcommon:Imboden,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Imboden</surname></persName>'s forces.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="53"/>On Tuesday they renewed their attempt to force their way through the mountain pass, and this time in greater force; but they were a <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> time repulsed, with considerable loss. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="54"/> This force of <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> is believed to be under command of <persName n="Kelly,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00013" reg="mostcommon:Kelly,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Kelly</surname></persName>, and that they have marched down through <placeName key="tgn,2002266" n="1.000 32" reg="hardy, west virginia, united states">Hardy county</placeName> from the neighborhood of New <rs n="Creek" type="nativeamerican">Creek</rs> and <placeName reg="Cumberland, Allegany, Maryland" key="tgn,2046811">Cumberland</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="55"/>They are doubtless summing to reach <placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head>From the <name>Trans</name>--<placeName reg="Mississippi" key="tgn,7007522">Mississippi</placeName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="56"/> A gentleman who left <placeName><persName n="Taylor,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00014" reg="mostcommon:Taylor,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Taylor</surname></persName>'s headquarters</placeName>, on the other side of the <rs>Mississippi</rs>, on the <num value="25" type="ordinal">25th</num> ult, informs the <orgName n="Mobile Advertiser" type="newspaper">Mobile <hi rend="italics">Advertiser</hi></orgName> that our troops hold undisputed sway of all those late conquests in <placeName reg="Louisiana" key="tgn,7007256">Louisiana</placeName> west of the <rs>Mississippi</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="57"/>They, as well as the people, are in fine spirits, undepressed by the <rs n="Fall of Vicksburg" type="battle">fall of Vicksburg</rs>, and not only able to hold their own, but at the proper time to help us on this side the river.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="58"/><persName n="Magruder,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00015" reg="mostcommon:Magruder,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Magruder</surname></persName> is fortifying at <placeName reg="Sabine Pass, Jefferson, Texas" key="tgn,2107319">Sabine Pass</placeName>, and ready to cooperate with <persName n="Smith,,Kirby,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00016" reg="default:Smith,Kirby,,,"><foreName>Kirby</foreName> <surname>Smith</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="59"/><persName n="Taylor,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00017" reg="mostcommon:Taylor,nomatch:0"><surname>Taylor</surname></persName> is securing his conquests and is zealously supported by the planters, who, when <persName n="Banks,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00018" reg="mostcommon:Banks,nomatch:0"><surname>Banks</surname></persName> overrun the country, were ready to give up and take the oath.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="60"/><persName n="Banks,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00019" reg="mostcommon:Banks,nomatch:0"><surname>Banks</surname></persName> scouted at their oaths and took their property.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="61"/>They are now fighting men and war men to the bitter end. Our informant believes that our combined forces under <persName n="Price,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00020" reg="mostcommon:Price,nomatch:0"><surname>Price</surname></persName>, <persName n="Walker,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00021" reg="mostcommon:Walker,H.,P.,,:1"><surname>Walker</surname></persName>, and <persName n="Taylor,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00022" reg="mostcommon:Taylor,nomatch:0"><surname>Taylor</surname></persName> &mdash; <persName n="Smith,,Kirby,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00023" reg="default:Smith,Kirby,,,"><foreName>Kirby</foreName> <surname>Smith</surname></persName> commanding the whole &mdash; will reach <num value="50000">50,000</num> men, and are increasing. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head>From <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="62"/> The latest official news from <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName> represents that matters are progressing finely for our cause.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="63"/>On Tuesday the enemy bombarded our works at long range, doing no damage.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="64"/>Yesterday all was quiet, the monitors having drawn off a distance or <measure n="3miles" type="distance">three miles</measure>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="7"> 
<head><persName n="Trimble,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00024" reg="mostcommon:Trimble,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Trimble</surname></persName> and his Staff.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="65"/> We were yesterday permitted to read a letter written by <persName n="Trimble,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00025" reg="mostcommon:Trimble,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Trimble</surname></persName>, at <placeName reg="Gettysburg, Adams, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7014060">Gettysburg</placeName> and dated <date value="07-30">July 30th.</date> He states that he is doing well, and says that in <measure n="2weeks" type="date">two weeks</measure> he expected to be entirely cured.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="66"/>His sufferings with the wound which now afflicts him have not been near so great as those which he endured from the wounds he received in the <rs n="Second Battle of Manassas" type="battle">second battle of Manassas</rs>, in <dateStruct value="-08-"><month reg="08">August</month></dateStruct> last.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="67"/><persName n="Grogan,Lieutenant,Charles,O.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00026" reg="default:Grogan,Charles,O.,,"><roleName n="Lieutenant">Lt.</roleName> <foreName n="Charles">Chas.</foreName> <foreName>O.</foreName> <surname>Grogan</surname></persName> and Frank Champion, his orderly, are with him and doing well.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="68"/><persName n="Davis,Lieutenant,Samuel,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00027" reg="default:Davis,Samuel,,,"><roleName n="Lieutenant">Lt.</roleName> <foreName>Samuel</foreName> <surname>Davis</surname></persName>, another of his aids, who was wounded at <placeName reg="Gettysburg, Adams, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7014060">Gettysburg</placeName>, is at <placeName reg="Chester, Delaware, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7015967">Chester, Pa.</placeName>, and recovering rapidly.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="69"/>The General writes in cheerful spirits, and is willing to take the chances of a prisoner of war. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="8"> 
<head>Patriotism of a Colored man.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="70"/> A day or <num value="2">two</num> ago a letter was received at the <orgName n="Treasury Department" type="department">Treasury Department</orgName> from a negro man, named <persName n="Jones,,Henry,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00028" reg="default:Jones,Henry,,,"><foreName>Henry</foreName> <surname>Jones</surname></persName>, the property of <persName n="Cannon,Mister,E.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00029" reg="default:Cannon,E.,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>Cannon</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Clarksville, Montgomery, Tennessee" key="tgn,7015659">Clarksville</placeName>, in this State, which is worthy of the highest commendation, and justly entitled to be imitated by those who have been hoarding their treasure during the troubles which at present afflict the country.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="71"/><placeName key="tgn,6002055" n="1.000 83" reg="fort henry, stewart, tennessee">Henry</placeName> places at the disposal of the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of the Treasury">Secretary of the Treasury</rs> <measure n="465dollars" type="currency">$465</measure> in gold, which he hopes will be of some service to the <rs>Government</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="72"/>In his letter he speaks of &#x0022;our glorious cause,&#x0022; and declares that the slaves of the <rs>South</rs> have a deeper interest in the establishment of Southern independence than the white population.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="73"/>He thinks if the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> are successful the negroes are destined to the most cruel treatment at their hands. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="74"/> &#x0022;<hi rend="smallcaps">The Southern Punch</hi>&#x0022; is the title of a new weekly, just issued in this city, by <persName n="Overall,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00030" reg="mostcommon:Overall,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Messrs.</roleName> <surname>Overall</surname></persName>, <persName n="Campbell,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00031" reg="mostcommon:Campbell,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Campbell</surname></persName>, <orgName><persName n="Hughes,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00032" reg="mostcommon:Hughes,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Hughes</surname></persName> &#x0026; Co.</orgName> The title page is an excellent specimen of engraving, and well designed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="75"/>Its literary department is under the supervision of <persName n="Overall,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00033" reg="mostcommon:Overall,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Overall</surname></persName>, formerly of the New Orleans press, and is filled with humorous articles, original and selected. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="10"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">The reported <placeName reg="Louisiana, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007256">Louisiana</placeName> victory.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="76"/> --The <orgName n="Mobile Advertiser" type="newspaper">Mobile <hi rend="italics">Advertiser</hi></orgName>, of the <dateStruct value="--9"><day reg="9">9th inst.</day></dateStruct>, has the subjoined paragraph, which is probably the foundation from which grew the story about <persName n="Taylor,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00034" reg="mostcommon:Taylor,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Taylor</surname></persName> having <measure n="6000" type="captured">captured six thousand</measure> prisoners at <placeName key="tgn,2042665" n="1.000 57" reg="donaldsonville, ascension, louisiana">Donaldsonville</placeName>, <address><street n="La place">La</street></address>: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="77"/> We learn that a bearer of dispatches from <persName n="Taylor,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00035" reg="mostcommon:Taylor,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Taylor</surname></persName> to the <rs>Government</rs> at <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> arrived here yesterday.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="78"/>We are informed that he reports that a battle had taken place at <placeName key="tgn,2042665" n="1.000 57" reg="donaldsonville, ascension, louisiana">Donaldsonville</placeName>, on the <num value="13" type="ordinal">13th</num> ult, between a portion of the forces of <persName n="Taylor,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00036" reg="mostcommon:Taylor,nomatch:0"><surname>Taylor</surname></persName> and <persName n="Banks,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00037" reg="mostcommon:Banks,nomatch:0"><surname>Banks</surname></persName> &mdash; the former with <num value="700">seven hundred</num> and the latter <num value="1000">one thousand</num> men. Our forces won a victory, and <measure n="500" type="captured">captured five hundred</measure> prisoners.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="79"/>No battle to the extent that has been rumored has occurred within his knowledge. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="11"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Suicide.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="80"/> --On <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time> last, <persName n="Howard,Mister,Birdsong,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00038" reg="default:Howard,Birdsong,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>Birdsong</foreName> <surname>Howard</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Greenville, Greenville, South Carolina" key="tgn,7014143">Greenville, South Carolina</placeName>, committed suicide by hanging himself with a rope.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="81"/>He had for some time been in feeble health, suffering from palsy, and for the purpose of assisting himself in getting into and out of bed a rope had been attached to the joints above.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="82"/>With the lower portion of this rope, it seems, be made a swoons during the night, and slipping it on his neck thus terminated his life. </p> </div3> <milestone unit="column" n="3"/> 
<div3 type="article" n="12"> 
<head>Our army Correspondence.</head> <opener> <dateline> Army <placeName reg="Virginia" key="tgn,7007919">Northern Va.</placeName>, <dateStruct value="1863-08-11"><month reg="08">Aug.</month>, <day reg="11">11</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="83"/> I write again this morning, but without the transpiring of anything denoting a material change in &#x0022;the situation.&#x0022; The main body of the enemy retains its position along the line of the <orgName n="Orange and Alexandria Railroad" type="railroad">Orange and Alexandria Railroad</orgName>, and there have been no movements that decidedly indicate a disposition or intention on the part of <persName n="Meade,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00039" reg="nearbymention:Meade,Gen,,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Meade</surname></persName> to advance on the <orgName>army of <persName n="Lee,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00040" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Stephen,D.,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Lee</surname></persName></orgName>, although a small body of infantry, estimated by some refugees at a corps, by others at only a division, crossed a day or <num value="2">two</num> since to the south side of the river at <placeName reg="Rappahannock Ford">Rappahannock Ford</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="84"/>Their reserve, or main force, of cavalry are reported to be concentrated around <placeName reg="Kelly's Ford, Culpeper, Virginia" key="tgn,2112479">Kelly's Ford</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="85"/>A body of cavalry advanced in the direction and within <placeName><distance reg="1.5miles">one and a half miles</distance> of <placeName reg="Culpeper Court House">Culpeper C. H.</placeName></placeName>, but soon fell back on the appearance of a confronting arty of ours.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="86"/>The cavalry of both armies remain in line of battle from day to-day, with nothing to interrupt the monotony save an occasional shot of the pickets at each other. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="87"/> <persName n="Stuart,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00041" reg="mostcommon:Stuart,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Stuart</surname></persName> is commanding on our side, and his coolness, vigilance, and general management since the appearance of the enemy in his front, have elicited general satisfaction. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="88"/> Diverse opinions prevail as to <persName n="Meade,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00042" reg="nearbymention:Meade,Gen,,,"><surname>Meade</surname></persName>'s probable intentions, although no movement of his has yet been made which furnishes a key to his plans &mdash; if he has yet adopted any. Some are of opinion that he will attempt what both his predecessors failed to accomplish at <placeName reg="Fredericksburg, Fredericksburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013943">Fredericksburg</placeName>; while others think he will cooperate in the &#x0022;on to <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>&#x0022; move via the <rs type="place">Peninsula</rs>, so plausibly urged in some quarters by both <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> and Confederate.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="89"/>There are not a few, also, who believe there are reasonable probabilities of a collision of the <num value="2">two</num> armies in this immediate section.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="90"/>It so, we may have to record another bloody fight at <placeName reg="Cedar Mountain, Culpeper, Virginia" key="tgn,2229381">Cedar Mountain</placeName>, already classic by the memorable rout, the beginning of the series of disasters to the splendidly equipped army of the infamous <rs>Pope</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="91"/><persName n="Meade,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00043" reg="nearbymention:Meade,Gen,,,"><surname>Meade</surname></persName>, thus far, has made no encroachments on our position.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="92"/>His delay in following up what nobody but his own miserable people claim as a victory at <placeName reg="Gettysburg, Adams, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7014060">Gettysburg</placeName>, can be accounted for only on <num value="1">one</num> of the <num value="2">two</num> suppositions of bad Generalship or want of strength sufficient, and the necessity of waiting for reinforcements, or the slow and uncertain results of the draft.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="93"/>Most probably his army was badly cut up, broken down by weary marches, and needed rest and recruiting. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="94"/> There is nothing of special interest from our own army to communicate, save the interesting fact that the good effect of the call of the <rs type="role" reg="Commander-in-Chief">Commander-in-Chief</rs> and the proclamation of the <rs>President</rs> are visible in the <num value="1000">thousands</num> of convalescent sick and wounded returning to their post and ready to meet the foe once more in the reeking front of battle.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="95"/>The cry daily is, &#x0022;still they come,&#x0022; and I will not attempt to estimate how much stronger we are now than when we recrossed the <rs>Potomac</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="96"/>There is yet room and heed for many more to meet the next onset of overwhelming avalanche of men which it is believed the enemy are collecting for our destruction.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="97"/><persName n="Lee,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00044" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Stephen,D.,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Lee</surname></persName>, with his usual military acumen, has doubtless surveyed the whole field; but whether his plans are aggressive or defensive will depend, it is presumed, altogether on the condition and movements of the enemy. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="98"/> A meeting of chaplains of the <num value="21">21</num> and <orgName type="corps" n="corps 3">3d corps</orgName> is to be held to-day at <placeName reg="Orange, Virginia" key="tgn,7014299">Orange C. H.</placeName> Its object has not transpired, but it is probably to adopt measures to promote concert of action and the general efficiency of that useful body of men. That their labors have been productive of much good is evinced in the religious tone of feeling prevalent in the army, and the nightly assembling in each camp of groups of soldiers whose songs of praise ascend to Heaven with the smoke of the camp fires, and whose untutored invocations call down the blessings of <name n="God" type="God">God</name> on the absent ones at home, our cause, and our country.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="99"/>Some of these scenes that I have witnessed are worthy of the pencil of the most gifted artist. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="100"/> A <orgName n="Inquiry Court" type="court">Court of Inquiry</orgName> has been convened at <placeName reg="Brandy Station, Culpeper, Virginia" key="tgn,2110767">Brandy Station</placeName>, consisting of <persName n="Mahone,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00045" reg="mostcommon:Mahone,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Mahone</surname></persName>, <persName n="Battle,Colonel,C.,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00046" reg="default:Battle,C.,A.,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <foreName>C.</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName> <surname>Battle</surname></persName>, and others, to investigate the case of the capture of a portion of the wagon train of <orgName n="corps"><persName n="Ewell,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00047" reg="mostcommon:Ewell,nomatch:0"><surname>Ewell</surname></persName>'s corps</orgName> while returning from <placeName reg="Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7007710">Pennsylvania</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="101"/>The train was convoyed by a regiment of cavalry, and it is alleged the inferior force of <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> that attacked the train might and should have been captured, instead of being captors. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="102"/> I am informed by a <placeName reg="North Carolina" key="tgn,7007709">North Carolina</placeName> officer that meetings have been recently held in several regiments in this army from that State, with reference to the course of the <orgName n="Raleigh North Carolina Standard" type="newspaper">Raleigh (N. C.) <hi rend="italics">Standard</hi></orgName>, and resolutions denunciatory of the editor, and repelling the imputations cast upon them and their State in consequence, have been adopted.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="103"/>The tone of that sheet has been a constant libel upon such men as the gallant <rs>Ramseur</rs>, <persName n="Hoke,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00048" reg="mostcommon:Hoke,nomatch:0"><surname>Hoke</surname></persName>, <persName n="Lane,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00049" reg="mostcommon:Lane,nomatch:0"><surname>Lane</surname></persName>, <persName n="Daniel,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00050" reg="mostcommon:Daniel,nomatch:0"><surname>Daniel</surname></persName>, <persName n="Pender,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00051" reg="mostcommon:Pender,nomatch:0"><surname>Pender</surname></persName>, and the brave troops under their command, as well as on the memory of the many brave dead from the &#x0022;<orgName n="Old North State" type="newspaper">Old North State</orgName>.&#x0022; whose blood consecrate every battle-field of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="104"/>There are no better troops in this army, I venture to say, than the brigades from <placeName reg="North Carolina" key="tgn,7007709">North Carolina</placeName> with which I am acquainted.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="105"/>Such was the gallantry and lofty bearing of <persName n="Ramseur,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00052" reg="mostcommon:Ramseur,nomatch:0"><surname>Ramseur</surname></persName>, for instance, at <placeName reg="Gettysburg, Adams, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7014060">Gettysburg</placeName>, under the most terrific fire, as to elicit the admiration of all who beheld him. A veteran brigade &mdash; formerly <persName n="Rodes,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00053" reg="mostcommon:Rodes,nomatch:0"><surname>Rodes</surname></persName>'s &mdash; about to make a charge, stopped to give him the tribute of <num value="3">three</num> cheers.--The impunity with which the <hi rend="italics">Standard</hi> has attempted to foment discord in its own State, and to alienate her troops from the common cause, is a forcible illustration of the latitude of speech and of the press in the <rs>Confederacy</rs>, and presents a striking contrast to the genius of the <rs>Government</rs> at <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>; yet it is becoming the opinion of many, including not a few <name>North</name> <rs n="Carolinian" type="group">Carolinians</rs> in this army, that the <hi rend="italics">Standard</hi> has abused that liberty to the verge of aid and comfort to the enemy, and that something more effective should be adopted than resolutions and remonstrances. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="106"/> <persName n="Pegram,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00054" reg="mostcommon:Pegram,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Pegram</surname></persName>, latterly stationed in the <rs>West</rs>, has arrived here, and will probably be transferred and assigned to duty in this army.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="107"/>His visit is understood to have reference to that end. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="108"/> My acknowledgments are due various officers at the headquarters of the army, as well as of different divisions, for offers of facilities, and of which I will avail myself at such times as such information as can be derived only from such sources will be valuable, and can be with propriety given to the public. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="13"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Anecdote of Mosey.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="109"/> --<num value="1">One</num> of the correspondents of the <orgName n="New York Herald" type="newspaper">New York <hi rend="italics">Herald</hi></orgName> tells the following story of this daring officer: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="110"/> At a town, which shall be nameless, that we passed through, I was told the following circumstance about <persName n="Mosby,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00055" reg="mostcommon:Mosby,nomatch:0"><surname>Mosby</surname></persName>, which, as it has never found its way into print, I think worth giving, as illustrative of the bold and reckless audacity of the man. A squad of Northern cavalry got on the track of him and his men, pursued him into the village, captured some of his men, and hoped to take him captive.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="111"/>Guards were placed at the entrance of every street, and the search for <persName n="Mosby,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00056" reg="mostcommon:Mosby,nomatch:0"><surname>Mosby</surname></persName> began &mdash; a search up stairs, down stairs, in garret, in cellar, in beds, under beds, in closets, wardrobes, and every imaginable cuddy-hole big enough to hold a man. <persName n="Mosby,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00057" reg="mostcommon:Mosby,nomatch:0"><surname>Mosby</surname></persName> was not to be found.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="112"/>In quick time he had changed his military dress for the coarse spun habiliments of a non-combatant, and, while the search was progressing, passed for <num value="1">one</num> of the curious throng of street lookers on. He took <num value="99">ninety-nine</num> chances out of a <num value="100">hundred</num> of being captured, and fortune favored him, as it always does the brave.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="113"/>It is this bravery and this good fortune that make him and his exploits the theme of every tongue, and particularly tongues feminine, which, when they get to wagging about him, wag with a sneering fanciness, a vindictive exultation, indicating that the extent of their joy is only surpassed by <num value="1">one</num> thing &mdash; the unending prolongation of their tongues. </p> </q><bibl n="New York Herald"></bibl></cit> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="14"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Arrival of <persName n="Munroe,Mayor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00058" reg="mostcommon:Munroe,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mayor">Mayor</roleName> <surname>Munroe</surname></persName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="114"/> --<persName n="Munroe,Mayor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00059" reg="mostcommon:Munroe,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mayor">Mayor</roleName> <surname>Munroe</surname></persName>, of New Orleans, whose patriotic firmness at the evacuation of New Orleans so incensed Beast <persName n="Butler,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00060" reg="mostcommon:Butler,nomatch:0"><surname>Butler</surname></persName> that he sent that gentleman to <placeName key="tgn,7021610" n="1.000 43" reg="fort pickens, santa rosa island, santa rosa, florida">Fort Pickens</placeName> like a felon, arrived at <placeName reg="Mobile, Mobile, Alabama" key="tgn,7017444">Mobile</placeName> on the <dateStruct value="--7"><day reg="7">7th inst.</day></dateStruct>, with his family.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="115"/><persName n="Munroe,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00061" reg="mostcommon:Munroe,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Munroe</surname></persName> looks hale and hearty, notwithstanding his long incarceration by the malignant <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs>. </p> </div3> <milestone unit="column" n="4"/> 
<div3 type="article" n="15"> 
<head>Later from the <rs>North</rs>.</head> 
<argument> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="116"/> retaliation on guerillas by <persName n="Meade,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00062" reg="nearbymention:Meade,Gen,,,"><surname>Meade</surname></persName> &mdash; Correspondence between <persName n="Seymour,Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00063" reg="mostcommon:Seymour,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Governor">Gov.</roleName> <surname>Seymour</surname></persName>, of New York, and <persName n="Lincoln,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00064" reg="mostcommon:Lincoln,nomatch:0"><surname>Lincoln</surname></persName> &mdash; Fatal insult of the <rs>Gen</rs> best expedition up <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">James river</placeName>, &#x0026;c. </p> </argument> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="117"/> The agent of the <rs>Press Association</rs> has furnished the following news summary, copied from the <orgName n="Baltimore American" type="newspaper">Baltimore <hi rend="italics">American</hi></orgName>, of <dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct>, <num value="11" type="ordinal">11th</num> inst: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="118"/> <persName n="Meade,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00065" reg="nearbymention:Meade,Gen,,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Meade</surname></persName> has issued an order announcing severe measures of retaliation against the disloyal farmers residing on the line of the <orgName n="Orange and Alexandria Railroad" type="railroad">Orange and Alexandria Railroad</orgName>, between <placeName reg="Alexandria, Alexandria, Virginia" key="tgn,7013269">Alexandria</placeName> and <placeName reg="Warrenton, Fauquier, Virginia" key="tgn,2114921">Warrenton</placeName>, who aid <persName n="Mosby,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00066" reg="mostcommon:Mosby,nomatch:0"><surname>Mosby</surname></persName> in his guerilla raids.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="119"/>They are to be made responsible for all damages committed on the railroad by guerilla forces, to be impressed as laborers for the repair of the road, and their houses to be taken for Government use. With the exception of the capture of a number of <persName n="Mosby,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00067" reg="mostcommon:Mosby,nomatch:0"><surname>Mosby</surname></persName>'s guerillas, there is no active movement of <persName n="Meade,,Gen,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00068" reg="default:Meade,Gen,,,"><foreName>Gen</foreName> <surname>Meade</surname></persName>'s <orgName n="army">army</orgName> to be reported. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="120"/> <persName n="Seymour,Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00069" reg="mostcommon:Seymour,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Governor">Gov.</roleName> <surname>Seymour</surname></persName>, of New York, has addressed a letter to the <rs>President</rs> relative to the draft, in which he complains of the injustice done to the <rs>State</rs> by the mode of enrollment, and asks for a suspension of the draft until the errors can be corrected.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="121"/>He states that a large body of the people believe the <name>Conscription</name> act to be unconstitutional, and claims that its legality should be tested in the <rs type="place">Courts</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="122"/><placeName reg="The President">The President</placeName> replies very briefly.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="123"/>He says:<q>&#x0022;I cannot consent to suspend the draft in New York.&#x0022;</q> He promises to see that justice shall be done, and will not object to see the constitutionality of the conscription tested.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="124"/>But at present no time can be wasted or argument used, if we would prevent the rebels from turning upon our now victorious soldiers. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="125"/> <placeName reg="The President">The President</placeName> has ordered that <measure n="3" type="prisoners">three prisoners</measure> from <placeName reg="South Carolina" key="tgn,7007712">South Carolina</placeName> shall be held in close confinement as hostages for <num value="3">three</num> negro seamen, captured on the <term type="ship">gunboat</term> <rs type="ship">Isaac Smith</rs>, and who are now in prison at <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="126"/> The <term type="ship">frigate</term> <rs type="ship">Hartford</rs>, with <persName n="Farragut,Rear admiral,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00070" reg="mostcommon:Farragut,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Rear admiral">Rear Admiral</roleName> <surname>Farragut</surname></persName> on board, arrived at New York on the <dateStruct value="--10"><day reg="2">10th</day></dateStruct>, and was received with salutes from the <rs n="American" type="group">American</rs>, <persName n="French,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00071" reg="mostcommon:French,nomatch:0"><surname>French</surname></persName>, and <persName><foreName>Spanish</foreName></persName> war vessels in port. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="127"/> At the latest dates from <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName> <persName n="Banks,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00072" reg="mostcommon:Banks,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Banks</surname></persName> had just arrived there on a visit to <persName n="Grant,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00073" reg="mostcommon:Grant,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Grant</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="128"/>The British Consul at New Orleans and the commander of a French man-of-war in port, accompanied <persName n="Banks,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00074" reg="mostcommon:Banks,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Banks</surname></persName> on his visit to <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="129"/> The <orgName n="Nashville Union" type="newspaper">Nashville <hi rend="italics">Union</hi></orgName> is officially authorized to announce that <persName n="Johnson,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00075" reg="mostcommon:Johnson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Johnson</surname></persName> proposes issuing writs of election for a Legislature, at the very earliest practicable day. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="130"/> The expedition up <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">James river</placeName> was accompanied by the turret <term type="ship">iron-clad</term> <rs type="ship">Sangamon</rs> and <term type="ship">gunboats</term> <rs type="ship">Com</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="131"/><persName n="Barney,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00076" reg="mostcommon:Barney,nomatch:0"><surname>Barney</surname></persName> and <placeName key="tgn,2049619" n="1.000 8" reg="cohasset, norfolk county, massachusetts">Cohasset</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="132"/>A torpedo was exploded under the bows of the <rs>Barney</rs>, lifting them completely out of the water, and throwing a great quantity of water high in the air, which fell upon the deck of the boat, washing overboard <num value="15">fifteen</num> of her men, including <persName n="Cashing,Lieutenant,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00077" reg="mostcommon:Cashing,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lieutenant">Lt.</roleName> <surname>Cashing</surname></persName>, the <rs type="role" reg="commanding-Officer">commanding officer</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="133"/><persName n="Foster,,Maj-Gen,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00078" reg="default:Foster,Maj-Gen,,,"><foreName>Maj-Gen</foreName> <surname>Foster</surname></persName> was upon this boat.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="134"/>The <rs>Barney</rs> and <rs>Cohasset</rs> were injured by shots from field pieces. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="135"/> Returns from <num value="38">38</num> counties in <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName> show a Union majority of <num value="20350">20,350</num>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="136"/> Parson <persName n="Brown,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00079" reg="mostcommon:Brown,nomatch:0"><surname>Brown</surname></persName> low, on the testimony of a surgeon recently returned from <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, states that <persName n="Alken,Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00080" reg="mostcommon:Alken,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Governor">Gov.</roleName> <surname>Alken</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="South Carolina" key="tgn,7007712">S. C.</placeName>, is a prisoner in the <rs type="place">Libby prison</rs>, his crime being persistent fidelity to the <rs>Union</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="137"/>The surgeon states that he was confined in the same room with <persName n="Aiken,Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00081" reg="mostcommon:Aiken,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Governor">Gov.</roleName> <surname>Aiken</surname></persName> and had many conversations with him [This is the richest joke of the season.] </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="138"/> Foreign advices to the <num value="2" type="ordinal">2d</num> inst, have been received.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="139"/>It was believed that the <name>Polish</name> question would be settled by diplomacy, and the war panic had subsided in <placeName reg="Department de Ville de Paris, Ile-de-France, France" key="tgn,7002980">Paris</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="140"/>The <rs n="American" type="group">American</rs> question is discussed much in the usual style.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="141"/>The rebel loan was heavy at <num value="0.15">15 per cent</num>, discount.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="142"/>Both the cotton and bread stuffs markets were dull. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="143"/> The latest quotations of gold in New York is <num value="126.5">126&#x00BD;</num>; <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> sixes <num value="61">61</num>; <placeName reg="North Carolina" key="tgn,7007709">North Carolina</placeName> do <num value="68">68</num>. </p> </q><bibl n="Baltimore American"></bibl></cit> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="16"> 
<head>Progress of the <rs>War</rs>.</head> 
<argument> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="144"/> <hi rend="italics">from <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName>.--the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> expedition to <placeName reg="Jackson, Hinds, Mississippi" key="tgn,7016129">Jackson</placeName>, <rs type="role2">Miss</rs> &mdash; what was accomplished, and what force accomplished it &mdash; the next move, &#x0026;c.</hi> </p> </argument> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="145"/> A correspondent of the <orgName n="New York Tribune" type="newspaper">New York <hi rend="italics">Tribune</hi></orgName>, writing from <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName> on the <dateStruct value="--27"><day reg="27">27th ult.</day></dateStruct>, says <orgName n="corps"><persName n="McPherson,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00082" reg="mostcommon:McPherson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>McPherson</surname></persName>'s corps</orgName> is garrisoning that post, and <persName n="Smith,Brigadier-General,J.,E.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00083" reg="default:Smith,J.,E.,,"><roleName n="Brigadier-General">Brig. Gen.</roleName> <foreName>J.</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>Smith</surname></persName> is acting as post commandant.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="146"/>The expedition to <placeName reg="Jackson, Hinds, Mississippi" key="tgn,7016129">Jackson, Miss.</placeName>, had returned.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="147"/>The troops employed in this expedition were <orgName n="Army Corps" type="corps"><persName n="Sherman,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00084" reg="mostcommon:Sherman,nomatch:0"><surname>Sherman</surname></persName>'s army corps</orgName>, the <num value="15" type="ordinal">15th</num>, commanded by <persName n="Steele,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00085" reg="mostcommon:Steele,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Steele</surname></persName>; the <orgName type="corps" n="corps 13">13th army corps</orgName>, <persName n="Ord,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00086" reg="mostcommon:Ord,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Ord</surname></persName> commanding, with <orgName n="division"><persName n="Lanman,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00087" reg="mostcommon:Lanman,nomatch:0"><surname>Lanman</surname></persName>'s division</orgName> of the <orgName type="corps" n="corps 16">16th army corps</orgName> attached, a portion of the <orgName type="corps" n="corps 16">16th</orgName> and <orgName type="corps" n="corps 9">9th army corps</orgName>, commanded by <persName n="Parker,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00088" reg="mostcommon:Parker,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Parker</surname></persName>, and <orgName n="division"><persName n="McArthur,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00089" reg="mostcommon:McArthur,nomatch:0"><surname>McArthur</surname></persName>'s division</orgName> of <orgName n="corps"><persName n="McPherson,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00090" reg="mostcommon:McPherson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>McPherson</surname></persName>'s corps</orgName> &mdash; in all about <num value="4">four</num> <orgName n="Army Corps" type="corps">army corps</orgName>, the whole commanded by <persName n="Sherman,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00091" reg="mostcommon:Sherman,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Sherman</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="148"/>These several commands are now encamped around the city, <persName n="Ord,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00092" reg="mostcommon:Ord,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Ord</surname></persName>'s being on the flat just below, while the remainder are scattered about, a portion being on the line of works extending from <placeName reg="Haines's Bluff">Haines's Bluff</placeName> to Big Black.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="149"/><orgName n="corps"><persName n="Heron,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00093" reg="mostcommon:Heron,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Heron</surname></persName>'s corps</orgName> has been sent down the river to occupy and hold <rs n="Natchez" type="nativeamerican">Natchez</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="150"/>The correspondent says: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="151"/> The result of the expedition to <placeName reg="Jackson, Hinds, Mississippi" key="tgn,7016129">Jackson</placeName> may be stated briefly to be the destruction by fire of the town, and the driving of <persName n="Johnston,,Joe,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00094" reg="default:Johnston,Joe,,,"><foreName>Joe</foreName> <surname>Johnston</surname></persName> and his army further into the interior.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="152"/>This statement of the result makes it seem insignificant; but I presume that nothing more important was intended or expected.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="153"/>The march to <placeName reg="Jackson, Hinds, Mississippi" key="tgn,7016129">Jackson</placeName> from the Big Black was a very hard <num value="1">one</num>; but the return there from, accomplished in <measure n="3days" type="date">three days</measure> by <orgName n="corps"><persName n="Ord,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00095" reg="mostcommon:Ord,nomatch:0"><surname>Ord</surname></persName>'s corps</orgName>, was still harder.--Some of the veterans of this corps, who have experienced nearly everything possible in the way of marching, assure me that the suffering of the men was greater than ever known before.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="154"/>They were compelled to use water from the pool and lagoons on the route; rations were whittled down almost to the starving point, and the heat was terrific. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="155"/> <persName n="Johnston,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00096" reg="nearbymention:Johnston,Joe,,,"><surname>Johnston</surname></persName> skirmished with <persName n="Sherman,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00097" reg="mostcommon:Sherman,nomatch:0"><surname>Sherman</surname></persName> on a small scale until the latter arrived in the neighborhood of <placeName reg="Jackson, Hinds, Mississippi" key="tgn,7016129">Jackson</placeName> and invested the place.--On the <dateStruct value="--13"><day reg="2">13th</day></dateStruct> <orgName n="division"><persName n="Lanman,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00098" reg="mostcommon:Lanman,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Lanman</surname></persName>'s division</orgName> made an assault upon the enemy on ground which that General was ordered to reconnoiter.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="156"/>It was an unfortunate affair.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="157"/><hi rend="italics"><num value="1">One</num> brigade of the division was badly cut up, and the loss in killed and wounded now foots up <num value="700">seven hundred</num>.</hi>--For this assault, which was alleged to have been made contrary to orders, <persName n="Lanman,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00099" reg="mostcommon:Lanman,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Lanman</surname></persName> was relieved of his command this division in addition to his own division. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="158"/> On the <dateStruct value="--17"><day reg="17">17th instant</day></dateStruct>, it was discovered that <persName n="Johnston,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00100" reg="nearbymention:Johnston,Joe,,,"><surname>Johnston</surname></persName> had evacuated during the night, after destroying all the war material that he could not take away with him. As soon as this was known our troops entered the place.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="159"/>The men of <orgName n="division"><persName n="Lanman,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00101" reg="mostcommon:Lanman,nomatch:0"><surname>Lanman</surname></persName>'s division</orgName> were exasperated by the losses which their ranks had sustained, and commenced a destruction of the houses by fire, which was kept up until there was but little left of the town but ashes.--<persName n="Jackson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00102" reg="mostcommon:Jackson,Jesse,,,:1"><surname>Jackson</surname></persName> has been an ill-fated place.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="160"/>When it was captured before, there was a great destruction worked.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="161"/><persName n="Johnston,,Joe,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00103" reg="default:Johnston,Joe,,,"><foreName>Joe</foreName> <surname>Johnston</surname></persName> caused <num value="1">one</num> or <num value="2">two</num> of the main blocks of buildings to be burned before he evacuated, and the work then commenced was finished on the <num value="17" type="ordinal">17th</num> and <num value="18" type="ordinal">18th</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="162"/>Where was but lately a thriving and pretentious town of between <num value="4">four</num> and <num value="5000">five thousand</num> inhabitants, with a State house, lunatic asylum; and many other public buildings, there is now a heap of ruins.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="163"/>The fate of the inhabitants of <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName> has been enviable beside that of the people of <placeName reg="Jackson, Hinds, Mississippi" key="tgn,7016129">Jackson</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="164"/> The country between here and <persName n="Jackson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00104" reg="mostcommon:Jackson,Jesse,,,:1"><surname>Jackson</surname></persName> is represented as being completely devastated. --Between the <num value="2">two</num> armies which have been marching and countermarching over it, it has been ground to powder.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="165"/>The town of <placeName reg="Raymond, Hinds, Mississippi" key="tgn,2057320">Raymond</placeName> was spared this destruction, I learn; for what reason I do not know. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="166"/> There are no indications, that I can discover as yet, of any very active movements in this quarter soon.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="167"/>In fact, I incline to the opinion that the next <num value="6">six</num> or <measure n="8weeks" type="date">eight weeks</measure> will be employed by <persName n="Grant,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00105" reg="mostcommon:Grant,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Grant</surname></persName> in quiet preparation for an active and decisive fall campaign.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="168"/>There is urgent need for this preparation.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="169"/>This army has been in the field a long time, and the wear and tear, so to speak, is tremendous.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="170"/>In every department repairs and reforms are needed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="171"/>The organization of the army needs an overhauling.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="172"/>It seems particularly necessary, owing to the incidents of the campaign ending with the capture of <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName> and the destruction of <persName n="Jackson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00106" reg="mostcommon:Jackson,Jesse,,,:1"><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>, that the entire army should be <milestone unit="column" n="5"/> brigaded anew.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="173"/>If our old regiments are ever to be filled up by recruits or by drafted men, now is the time to do it. There are many, alas, too many regiments, represented here by mere quads of men. To fill up or be consolidate these regiments requires time and much clerical labor.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="174"/>Our army regulations are such that it is impossible to put and keep <unclear></unclear> in such shape that they will work satisfactorily without consuming a great deal of <unclear></unclear>. The intricate system of checks and balances in the army under which we are operating, and which has come to be called red tape, works out delays the necessity for which few civilians can comprehend, and which no General, however energetic, can prevent. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="175"/> There is another reason why this army should remain in comparative inactivity as regards movements until perhaps the <dateStruct value="-10-1"><day reg="1">first</day> of <month reg="10">October</month></dateStruct>, and that is the fact that the season for a summer campaign has passed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="176"/>There has been much said and written about the endurance of Western troops.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="177"/>It has been demonstrated that they can endure as much in this climate as Southern or any other kind of troops.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="178"/>Still I hold that there is a species of inhumanity involved in making <dateStruct><month>August</month></dateStruct> and <dateStruct value="-09-"><month reg="09">September</month></dateStruct>, the very worst months in the year, the time for active military operations, unless the strategic reasons therefore are very urgent.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="179"/>Because another feather could be added to the camel's load without breaking his back is no reason for adding the feather.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="180"/>Let us not hunt for the limit to the powers of our armies until the occasion imperatively demands it. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="181"/> Furloughs are being granted freely &mdash; amounting to about <num value="0.05">five per cent</num> of the army.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="182"/>In my opinion this percentage could be increased without detriment to the service. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="183"/> It is really wonderful that our men stand this climate as well as they do, but it is nevertheless true that there is an amount of sickness in the army which is lamentable.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="184"/>Marching and trench life in <placeName reg="Mississippi" key="tgn,7007522">Mississippi</placeName> during the midsummer months are trying on the stoutest constitutions.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="185"/>Chronic diarri&#x0153;t prevails to an alarming extent, and all the various forms of bilious and typhoid fevers are rife here.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="186"/>I have seen in some Northern papers a statement that there had been cases of yellow fever in <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="187"/>This is not true.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="188"/>But Yellow <persName n="Jack,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00107" reg="mostcommon:Jack,nomatch:0"><surname>Jack</surname></persName> will probably visit us with his scourge if we do not clean up the place soon.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="189"/>The town is now reeking with the filthy debris of the <num value="2">two</num> armies. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="190"/> Walking in through the railroad depot yesterday I witnessed a sad sight.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="191"/>The train from <placeName key="tgn,2736813;tgn,2672126;tgn,2671185;tgn,2369625;tgn,2177310;tgn,2142202" n="0.067 000000.6735	placename;tgn,2736813;Twisty Bayou, Avoyelles, Louisiana,Avoyelles,Louisiana,United States,North and Central America;0.067 000000.6735	placename;tgn,2672126;Smiths, Robeson, North Carolina,Robeson,North Carolina,United States,North and Central America;0.067 000000.6735	placename;tgn,2671185;Smith Crossroads), Bladen, North Carolina,Bladen,North Carolina,United States,North and Central America;0.067 000000.6735	placename;tgn,2369625;Black River, Caldwell, North Carolina,Caldwell,North Carolina,United States,North and Central America;0.067 000000.6735	placename;tgn,2177310;Black River, Tensas, Louisiana,Tensas,Louisiana,United States,North and Central America;0.067 000000.6735	placename;tgn,2142202;Black River, Berkeley, South Carolina,Berkeley,South Carolina,United States,North and Central America" reg="Twisty Bayou, Avoyelles, Louisiana,Avoyelles,Louisiana,United States,North and Central America;Smiths, Robeson, North Carolina,Robeson,North Carolina,United States,North and Central America;Smith Crossroads), Bladen, North Carolina,Bladen,North Carolina,United States,North and Central America;Black River, Caldwell, North Carolina,Caldwell,North Carolina,United States,North and Central America;Black River, Tensas, Louisiana,Tensas,Louisiana,United States,North and Central America;Black River, Berkeley, South Carolina,Berkeley,South Carolina,United States,North and Central America">Black river</placeName> was just in, and was filled with soldiers emaciated and sallow hued.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="192"/><num value="1">One</num> poor fellow who did not seem to be as far gone as the others, thought that with a little assistance he could get from the car he was in to the platform.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="193"/><persName n="White,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00108" reg="mostcommon:White,nomatch:0"><surname>White</surname></persName> attempting this he was attacked by a congestive chill.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="194"/>He begged to be laid down where he was. The men laid him down in the dust and dirt, thinking he would be better in a moment.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="195"/>In less than <measure n="5minutes" type="date">five minutes</measure> he was dead.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="196"/>The men around him did not even know his name, nor the regiment to which he belonged.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="197"/>To breathe <num value="1">one</num>'s last lying in the dust of a much-traveled road, without even an acquaintance near, is seemingly worse than to meet death gallantly on the battle field. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="198"/> On the <rs>Louisiana</rs> side of the river, in the country opposite <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName>, <persName n="Smith,,Kirby,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00109" reg="default:Smith,Kirby,,,"><foreName>Kirby</foreName> <surname>Smith</surname></persName> has saved <persName n="Grant,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00110" reg="mostcommon:Grant,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Grant</surname></persName> all further trouble about looking after guerillas, for a time at least.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="199"/>He has literally destroyed everything for <num value="30">thirty</num> or <measure n="40miles" type="distance">forty miles</measure> back from the river, and driven the inhabitants, including the negroes, within his lines.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="200"/>Consequently <placeName reg="Louisiana, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007256">Louisiana</placeName>, opposite <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName>, is now a waste and howling wilderness that will not subsist guerillas.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="201"/>What the poor people will do for the necessaries of life it is hard to say, Surely they are paying the penalty of treason at such a rate as to bring them to their senses soon. </p> </q><bibl n="New York Tribune"></bibl></cit> 
<div4 type="entry" n="1"> 
<head rend="italics">Progress of the draft in the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName>--the<lb/> manner in which it is being Enforced.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="202"/> The <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> papers have various paragraphs about the progressing draft.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="203"/>All of them show more and more plainly that the <orgName n="U. S. Treasury" type="org">United States treasury</orgName> and not the <orgName n="U. S. Army" type="org">U. S. army</orgName> is to be benefited by the conscription.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="204"/>We make some extracts from Northern papers of the <num value="7" type="ordinal">7th</num>, which are interesting.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="205"/>Referring to the draft in <placeName reg="Washington, New York, United States" key="tgn,1002993">Washington county, N. Y.</placeName>, the <orgName n="Troy Times" type="newspaper">Troy <hi rend="italics">Times</hi></orgName> says: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="206"/> The drafting for <placeName reg="Washington, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002194">Washington county</placeName> has been completed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="207"/>Something over <measure n="25000dollars" type="currency">$25,000</measure> has been realized from the payment of commutations.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="208"/>The number of conscripts secured for service does not exceed over <num value="25">twenty five</num> or <num value="30">thirty</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="209"/>All but about <num value="100">one hundred</num> of the persons drafted have reported to the <rs type="role" reg="Provost Marshal">Provost Marshal</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="210"/>The exemptions under the law are so numerous that a large percentage of the drafted &mdash; considerably more than <num value="0.5">one-half</num>--get off free. </p> </q><bibl n="N. Y., the Troy Times"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="211"/> Probably of the <num value="100">one hundred</num> who have not reported but very few can now be found.--Some have run away, and others had left when the enrollment was made, or soon after.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="212"/>It is a pretty clean sweep when all but <num value="100">one hundred</num> from a county respond to the call of the <rs type="role" reg="Provost Marshal">Provost Marshal</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="213"/> The draft in the <orgName type="district" n="district 30">30th district</orgName> commences to-day at <placeName reg="Buffalo, Erie, New York" key="tgn,7013463">Buffalo</placeName>, and will continue daily till <date>Saturday</date>, the <dateStruct value="--15"><day reg="15">15th</day></dateStruct>, under <persName n="Scroggs,Provost Marshal,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00111" reg="mostcommon:Scroggs,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Provost Marshal">Provost Marshal</roleName> <surname>Scroggs</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="214"/>The fort has been put in readiness for the reception of the officers and the transaction of the necessary business of the draft.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="215"/>A detachment of <num value="400">four hundred</num> soldiers from <placeName reg="Elmira, Chemung, New York" key="tgn,7014109">Elmira</placeName> will be present to support the authorities if necessary. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="216"/> It is stated that the draft in <placeName reg="Ohio, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007706">Ohio</placeName> will take place in a few days; preparations are being perfected for it at <placeName reg="Columbus, Lowndes, Mississippi" key="tgn,2056204">Columbus</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="217"/>Detailed squads from the <rs>Ohio</rs> regiments, to take charge of the drafted men, are arriving. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="218"/> The draft in the <rs>West</rs>, the <name>Milwaukie</name> <hi rend="italics"><placeName reg="Wisconsin" key="tgn,7007922">Wisconsin</placeName></hi> remarks, has very properly been deferred in order to enable the <rs>Western</rs> farmers to ingather their prolific harvest, and also because the surrender of <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName> diminishes the necessity of immediate reinforcements to our Southwestern army; and as <persName n="Rosecrans,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00112" reg="mostcommon:Rosecrans,nomatch:0"><surname>Rosecrans</surname></persName> is taking it quietly he certainly has troops enough to meet <persName n="Bragg,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00113" reg="mostcommon:Bragg,nomatch:0"><surname>Bragg</surname></persName>'s small army.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="219"/>The draft will come along some time in <dateStruct value="-08-"><month reg="08">August</month></dateStruct>, or perhaps not until the <date value="09-01">1st of September.</date> It is desirable to reinforce our armies early in the autumn, as <persName n="Grant,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00114" reg="mostcommon:Grant,nomatch:0"><surname>Grant</surname></persName> should be so strengthened as to make the decisive movement against the rebellion in <placeName reg="Alabama" key="tgn,7002659">Alabama</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="220"/> By mixing the new conscripts in the old regiments, it will require but a few weeks to make them all veterans.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="221"/>We suppose that the folly of creating more regiments will be abandoned.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="222"/>It was a mistake last year.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="223"/>Let every regiment be filled to its maximum before a new regiment is authorized.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="224"/>The old officers have now obtained an invaluable experience, not merely in fighting, but in the management of men. They know how to take care of them. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="225"/> The <placeName reg="Middleburg, Snyder, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,2090700">Middleburg (Pa.)</placeName> <hi rend="italics">Tribune</hi> says: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="226"/> It is generally known that of the drafted men of last summer a large number in <placeName reg="Chapman township">Chapman township</placeName> deserted and refused to serve their time.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="227"/>On last <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Thursday</day></dateStruct> <time>evening</time> <num value="2">two</num> of the provost guards went to <persName n="Chapman,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00115" reg="mostcommon:Chapman,nomatch:0"><surname>Chapman</surname></persName> and arrested <num value="7">seven</num> of these deserters and lodged them in the jail here previous to taking them to <placeName reg="Harrisburg, Dauphin, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7013694">Harrisburg</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="228"/>On <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> news was brought to town that a body of armed men, numbering <num value="60">sixty</num>, were on their way to rescue the prisoners &mdash; threatening to burn the town if necessary.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="229"/>The circulation of this news created consternation, and spread like wild fire, until some country boys came to town with their trusty rifles.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="230"/>In the meantime the prisoners were sent off to <placeName reg="Harrisburg, Dauphin, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7013694">Harrisburg</placeName>, by way of <placeName reg="Lewiston, Androscoggin, Maine" key="tgn,7013885">Lewiston</placeName>, as the mob had threatened to waylay the guard between this place and <placeName key="tgn,2092899" n="1.000 5" reg="selinsgrove, snyder, pennsylvania">Selinsgrove</placeName>, if foiled in the attempt in town.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="231"/>The mob came within half a mile of town, when they learned that the prisoners were gone, upon which they turned back as they came. </p> </q><bibl n="The Middleburg (Pa.) Tribune"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="232"/> <persName n="Lambert,,Samuel,S.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00116" reg="default:Lambert,Samuel,S.,,"><foreName>Samuel</foreName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <surname>Lambert</surname></persName>, who was charged with the business of notifying the drafted men of <placeName key="tgn,2045026" n="1.000 2" reg="kingfield, franklin, maine">Kingfield</placeName>, Mass, gives a full and explicit statement, in the <orgName n="Farmington Chronicle" type="newspaper">Farmington <hi rend="italics">Chronicle</hi></orgName>, of what occurred at <placeName key="tgn,2045026" n="1.000 2" reg="kingfield, franklin, maine">Kingfield</placeName> on his arrival there.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="233"/>He says when he drove into the village of <placeName key="tgn,2045026" n="1.000 2" reg="kingfield, franklin, maine">Kingfield</placeName> the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> thing that attracted his attention was the store of <persName n="Saunders,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00117" reg="mostcommon:Saunders,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Saunders</surname></persName>, the enrolling officer, liberally besmeared with black paint, and groups of men at various points, much excited.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="234"/>When he arrived at the tavern he heard the cry, &#x0022;That's him,&#x0022; &#x0022;that's him,&#x0022; and he was soon surrounded by a crowd who were loud in their threats of personal violence.--They said they had entered into a combination to resist the draft, and that they would resist it to death, and they would rather spill their blood at K than at the <rs>South</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="235"/>They brought his horse and carriage along, and said they would give him <measure n="15minutes" type="date">fifteen minutes</measure> in which to leave town. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="236"/> The <placeName reg="Pittsburgh, Alleghany, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7013927">Pittsburg (Pa.)</placeName> <hi rend="italics">Chronicle</hi> is very much afraid that the draft there, so far as filling up the ranks of the old regiments with conscripts goes, will turn out a failure.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="237"/><num value="0.5">One-half</num> the <milestone unit="column" n="6"/> city has been gone over now, yet, exclusive of substitutes, less than <num value="50">fifty</num> of these drafted have reported for duty.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="238"/>The balance have either procured substitutes, paid <measure n="300dollars" type="currency">$300</measure>, obtained exemption, or &#x0022;skedaddled.&#x0022; In the <orgName type="division" n="Ward 1">First Ward</orgName> the &#x0022;skedaddler&#x0022; number over <num value="50">fifty</num>, in the <num value="2" type="ordinal">Second</num> over <num value="30">thirty</num>, and so on. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="2"> 
<head rend="italics">The last order previous to Surrendering <placeName reg="Port Hudson, East Baton Rouge, Louisiana" key="tgn,7017544">Port Hudson</placeName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="239"/> The following is a copy of the last order issued by <persName n="Gardner,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00118" reg="mostcommon:Gardner,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Gardner</surname></persName> before he surrendered <placeName reg="Port Hudson, East Baton Rouge, Louisiana" key="tgn,7017544">Port Hudson</placeName>: </p> 
<list type="ordered"> 
<head><hi rend="smallcaps">Headquarters, <placeName reg="Port Hudson, East Baton Rouge, Louisiana" key="tgn,7017544">Port Hudson</placeName>, <date value="1863-07-08">July 8, 1863.</date></hi> <hi rend="italics">General Orders--<num value="31">no. 31</num>.</hi></head> 
<item n="1"> <persName n="Nobly,,I.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00119" reg="default:Nobly,I.,,,"><foreName>I.</foreName> <surname>Nobly</surname></persName> have the troops performed their duty in the defence of this position, continued from the <date value="05-21">21st of May</date> to the present time.--The cheerfulness, bravery and zeal displayed by the troops during the hardships and suffering of this long siege have never been surpassed, and every man can feel the proud satisfaction that he had done his part in the heroic defence of <placeName reg="Port Hudson, East Baton Rouge, Louisiana" key="tgn,7017544">Port Hudson</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="240"/>The place is surrendered at the last moment it is proper to hold it, and after a most gallant defence in several severe attacks, in all of which the enemy have been signally repulsed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="241"/>Let all continue, during the duties that still remain to be performed, to show that cheerful obedience which has distinguished them as soldiers up to this time.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="242"/></item> 
<item n="2"> <num value="2">II</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="243"/>The troops will be paraded at <time value="6oclock">six o'clock</time> this morning for surrender, in line of battle, in the same order as they are now at the breast works, with the <orgName n="Heavy Artillery" type="artillery">heavy artillery</orgName> on the right, on the edge of the prairie in the rear of the railroad depot the left extending towards the town of <placeName reg="Port Hudson, East Baton Rouge, Louisiana" key="tgn,7017544">Port Hudson</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="244"/>All officers and men will be in their places under arms.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="245"/></item> </list> <closer> By order of <signed><persName n="Gardner,Major-General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00120" reg="mostcommon:Gardner,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major-General">Major General</roleName> <surname>Gardner</surname></persName>.</signed> </closer> </div4> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="17"> 
<head><persName n="Mosby,Major,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00121" reg="mostcommon:Mosby,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <surname>Mosby</surname></persName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="246"/> <hi rend="italics">Editors of the <name>Dispatch</name>:</hi> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="247"/> In reading your correspondent's letter of the <dateStruct value="--10"><day reg="10">10th inst.</day></dateStruct>, of the <orgName n="Army of Northern Virginia" type="army">Army of Northern Virginia</orgName>, he alludes to <persName n="Mosby,Major,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00122" reg="mostcommon:Mosby,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <surname>Mosby</surname></persName> in a complimentary manner, in <num value="1">one</num> respect, though he shows great ignorance of him and his character when he alludes to the fear of injuring him by promotion.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="248"/>He does not know that <persName n="Mosby,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00123" reg="mostcommon:Mosby,nomatch:0"><surname>Mosby</surname></persName> refused a commission urged upon him to accept for at least <measure n="18months" type="date">eighteen months</measure>. He has letters from <persName n="Johnston,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00124" reg="nearbymention:Johnston,Joe,,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Johnston</surname></persName> (while in command at <placeName key="tgn,2112877" n="1.000 541" reg="manassas, manassas, virginia">Manassas</placeName>) to the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>, from <persName n="Stuart,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00125" reg="mostcommon:Stuart,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Stuart</surname></persName> as well as <persName n="Lee,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00126" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Stephen,D.,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Lee</surname></persName> to the <rs>President</rs>, for great services rendered, all of which he has, in his modesty, declined to deliver, preferring, in his loyalty, to work on in his hazardous, adventurous way against the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs>, in whose lines he has lived and moved since the war, in which he entered as a private, receiving no pay. And not until lately has he accepted a commission, suggested by <persName n="Stuart,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00127" reg="mostcommon:Stuart,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Stuart</surname></persName>, (his friend, upon whose staff he served as a volunteer scout,) arguing that he could do more service in his way by a separate and larger command, which had not been over <num value="25">twenty-five</num> or <num value="30">thirty</num> in his various and <num value="100">hundred</num> raids. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="249"/> It is with due respect and great love of his character I make these remarks to you about <persName n="Mosby,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00128" reg="mostcommon:Mosby,nomatch:0"><surname>Mosby</surname></persName>, whom I have known as a boy, lawyer, and a noble soldier, thinking of nothing but serving his country. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="250"/> There are few <persName n="Mosby,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00129" reg="mostcommon:Mosby,nomatch:0"><surname>Mosby</surname></persName>'s in this war. </p> <closer> <salute>Yours, truly,</salute> <signed>G. S.P.</signed> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="18"> 
<head>The <rs>Price</rs> of wood.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="251"/> <hi rend="italics">To the <name>Editors</name> of the <name>Dispatch</name>:</hi> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="252"/> In your paper of this date you (no doubt unintentionally) do great injustice to the wood dealers of this city, or at least to myself as <num value="1">one</num> of them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="253"/>You state as a fact, from unquestionable authority, that wood is put on the boats in the canal at a &#x0022;total cost of <measure n="9.50dollars" type="currency">$9.50</measure> per cord,&#x0022; and that it is sold at the basin for <measure n="35dollars" type="currency">$35</measure> per cord, thus leaving the impression on the public mind that the dealers (I being <num value="1">one</num> of them,) realize a profit of <measure n="25.50dollars" type="currency">$25.50</measure> per cord.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="254"/>If this was so you ought to have marked the passage with <num value="20">twenty</num> instead of <num value="3">three</num> points of admiration.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="255"/>What it costs a farmer or wood chopper to put wood on the canal boats I do not know, but presume it cost twice <measure n="9.50dollars" type="currency">$9.50</measure> from the fact that I have an advertisement in your paper of this date offering to pay <measure n="16dollars" type="currency">$16</measure> per cord to haul wood <measure n="6miles" type="distance">six miles</measure> from town to my office on the basin bank, and have not yet had <num value="1">one</num> offer to do so, although the advertisement has been in the paper <num value="1">one</num> week.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="256"/>Another <hi rend="italics">fact</hi> is that I pay from <measure n="27dollars" type="currency">$27</measure> to <measure n="28dollars" type="currency">$28</measure> per cord for <rs n="oak wood" type="product">oak wood</rs> at my yard on the basin bank, pay <measure n="4dollars" type="currency">$4</measure> to haul it out, <measure n="87.5cents" type="currency">87&#x00BD; cents</measure> per cord tax to the <orgName n="Confederate Government" type="org">C. S. Government</orgName>, <measure n="35cents" type="currency">35 cents</measure> to the <rs>State</rs>, in all <measure n="33.22.5dollars" type="currency">$33.22&#x00BD;</measure>, whilst I see the same delivered to customers as <measure n="34dollars" type="currency">$34</measure>, leaving to me only <measure n="78cents" type="currency">78 cents</measure> per cord profit to pay yard rent, (<measure n="400dollars" type="currency">$400</measure>,) clerk's hire, and to support a large family.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="257"/>If this is extortion, then the <name>Devil</name> help others, for I am sure <name n="God" type="God">God</name> will not. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="258"/> <hi rend="italics"><placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, <date value="1863-08-12">August 12th, 1863.</date></hi> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="19"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">How they vote in <placeName key="tgn,1000070" n="1.000 1012" reg="france">France</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="259"/> --A correspondent of the <rs>London</rs> <hi rend="italics">Examiner</hi> visited the voting polls in <placeName reg="Department de Ville de Paris, Ile-de-France, France" key="tgn,7002980">Paris</placeName> during the recent elections, and reports that &#x0022;nothing can be more orderly and tranquil than the proceedings.&#x0022; He gives an interesting description of the manner in which the details of a French election are conducted: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="260"/> A police officer is stationed at the entrance of the bail of voting, who merely inquires whether you are an elector.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="261"/>As a stranger, I was invited by the <rs>Mayor</rs>, with my companion, to witness what was going on. The <rs>Mayor</rs> presided over the table, on which was placed the ballot-box.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="262"/>Every elector had at the door separate tickets given him, on which were printed the names of the candidates.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="263"/>Each ticket resembled the others, so that when folded it was utterly impossible to distinguish the name of the person voted for. The elector presented a document printed on green paper, containing his name, quality, place of abode, and certificate of registration.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="264"/>The name having been called out, the scrutineers, of whom there were <num value="4">four</num>, examined the electoral lists, and on ascertaining that the name was found there the elector delivered his folded ticket to the <rs>President</rs>, by whom it was dropped into the box. Voting always takes place on a Sunday, for the convenience of the laboring classes, and on the following <rs>Monday</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="265"/>If any question of identity arise, <num value="2">two</num> known inhabitants of the district are allowed to identify the individual who comes forward to vote.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="266"/>At <time value="4oclock">four o'clock</time> the ballot box is sealed; that of yesterday was courteously put into our hands.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="267"/>We found that the great proportion of the electors vote on the <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> day, as an additional security against any tampering with the ballot box. There were at no time more than <num value="4">four</num> or <num value="5">five</num> electors in the room, and no <num value="1">one</num> was detained a minute after his certificate or registration was found to agree with the electoral lists. </p> </q><bibl n="Examiner"></bibl></cit> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="20"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Death of the father of Hom&#x0153;pathy.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="268"/> --The death of <rs type="role2">Count</rs> S. <persName n="Dei,,G.,S.,M.," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00130" reg="default:Dei,G.,S.,M.,"><foreName>G.</foreName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Dei</surname></persName> Guidi is reported at <placeName reg="Lyons, Wayne, New York" key="tgn,2070324">Lyons</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="269"/>The <rs>Count</rs> was in his <num value="94" type="ordinal">ninety-fourth</num> year, and was the father of hom&#x0153;pathy, having in <dateStruct value="1828--"><year reg="1828">1828</year></dateStruct> converted Habnemann from allopathy.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="270"/><persName n="Guidi,Comte,Dei,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00131" reg="default:Guidi,Dei,,,"><roleName n="Comte">Count</roleName> <foreName>Dei</foreName> <surname>Guidi</surname></persName> had previously been a <rs n="Neapolitan" type="ethnic">Neapolitan</rs> conspirator against <persName><roleName n="Queen">Queen</roleName> <foreName>Caroline</foreName></persName>, (in <dateStruct value="1799--"><year reg="1799">1799</year></dateStruct>,) a prisoner, exile, professor of mathematics, inspector of the <rs type="place">University of Grenoble</rs>, a doctor of medicine, and finally of anti-medicine, and he died a chevalier of the <name>Legion</name> of Honor.--<hi rend="italics">Gulignant.</hi> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="21"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Foreign Consul's mode of sending dispatches.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="271"/> --The <name n="United Kingdom">British</name> <term type="ship">ship of war</term> <rs type="ship">Plover</rs> arrived off Clariston, S. C, on the <num value="4" type="ordinal">4th</num> inst, with dispatches for the <rs>British Consul</rs> at that port.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="272"/>She was destined for <placeName key="tgn,7013920" n="1.000 1" reg="Fortress Monroe, Hampton, Virginia">Fortress Monroe</placeName>, <persName n="Walker,Mister,H.,P.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00132" reg="default:Walker,H.,P.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <foreName>P.</foreName> <surname>Walker</surname></persName>, the <rs>British</rs> acting Consul there, having important dispatches to forward to his Government, acting in conformity with the regulation prescribed by the <rs>President</rs> of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName> forbidding the transmission of dispatches through the enemy's lines, made a requisition for a change of deed nation, and in consequence the <name>Plover</name> has sailed for <placeName reg="Halifax,Nova Scotia,Canada,North and Central America" key="tgn,7013046">Halifax, N. S.</placeName> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="22"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="273"/> <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Lee,Major-General,Stephen,D.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00133" reg="default:Lee,Stephen,D.,,"><roleName n="Major-General">Major General</roleName> <foreName>Stephen</foreName> <foreName>D.</foreName> <surname>Lee</surname></persName>,</hi> recently promoted for gallantry and efficiency as Brigadier during the <rs n="Fall of Vicksburg" type="battle">siege of Vicksburg</rs>, has been exchanged as prisoner, and ordered to take command of the cavalry of the <rs>Southwestern</rs> army. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="23"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="274"/> <persName n="Stanton,Secretary,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00134" reg="mostcommon:Stanton,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Secretary">Secretary</roleName> <surname>Stanton</surname></persName> boasted some time slave in this wise:<q>&#x0022;If a single regiment of <orgName n="army"><persName n="Lee,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00135" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Stephen,D.,,"><surname>Lee</surname></persName>'s army</orgName> gets back into <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> in an organized condition, it will prove that I am totally unfit to be <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>.&#x0022;</q> <persName n="Lee,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00136" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Stephen,D.,,"><surname>Lee</surname></persName> having get his army into <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>, some of the <rs>Northern</rs> papers are calling upon the self-acknowledged incompetent to resign. </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="7"/> 
<div2 type="local"> 
<head>Local matters.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Stabbing Affray.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="275"/> --Yesterday afternoon, about <time value="4oclock">4 o'clock</time>, on <address><street n="8 Street">8th street</street></address>, between <address><street n="Main street">Main</street></address> and <address><street n="Cary street">Cary</street></address>, <persName n="Burns,,Thomas,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00137" reg="default:Burns,Thomas,,,"><foreName>Thomas</foreName> <surname>Burns</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Louisiana" key="tgn,7007256">Louisiana</placeName> was seriously stabbed by <persName n="Reynolds,,Peter,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00138" reg="default:Reynolds,Peter,,,"><foreName>Peter</foreName> <surname>Reynolds</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="276"/>It appears that <persName n="Reynolds,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00139" reg="nearbymention:Reynolds,Peter,,,"><surname>Reynolds</surname></persName> was the <unclear></unclear> party and chased <persName n="Burns,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00140" reg="nearbymention:Burns,Thomas,,,"><surname>Burns</surname></persName> into an alley <unclear></unclear> restaurants, and plunged a knife into his right side.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="277"/><persName n="Burns,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00141" reg="nearbymention:Burns,Thomas,,,"><surname>Burns</surname></persName> fell to the ground, and <persName n="Reynolds,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00142" reg="nearbymention:Reynolds,Peter,,,"><surname>Reynolds</surname></persName>, after wiping the blade of his knife on his coat, went on through the alley and undo his escape.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="278"/><persName n="Burns,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00143" reg="nearbymention:Burns,Thomas,,,"><surname>Burns</surname></persName> was taken in a back to his boarding-house, on <address><street n="Franklin street">Franklin street</street></address>. His wound is quite serious.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="279"/>The parties <sic>had had</sic> several encounters before this <num value="1">one</num>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Horse stealing.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="280"/> --<persName n="Curtis,,William,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00144" reg="default:Curtis,William,H.,,"><foreName>William</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Curtis</surname></persName>, a resident of <placeName reg="Chesterfield, Chesterfield, Virginia" key="tgn,2111165">Chesterfield</placeName>, charged with stealing a horse, last <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time>, from <persName n="Rommell,,John,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00145" reg="default:Rommell,John,A.,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName> <surname>Rommell</surname></persName>, was before the <rs>Mayor</rs> yesterday for examination, Rommell stated that he tied his horse to a tree on <address><street n="Franklin street">Franklin street</street></address>, and went into a house on business.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="281"/>After being absent a short time he found that his horse had been taken away.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="282"/>The next day <persName n="Boussall,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00146" reg="mostcommon:Boussall,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Boussall</surname></persName> found his horse in <persName n="Head,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00147" reg="mostcommon:Head,nomatch:0"><surname>Head</surname></persName>'s stable, where he had been seat by <persName n="Whitfield,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00148" reg="mostcommon:Whitfield,nomatch:0"><surname>Whitfield</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="Burns,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00149" reg="nearbymention:Burns,Thomas,,,"><surname>Burns</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="283"/>Boussall claimed the animal, when <persName n="Burns,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00150" reg="nearbymention:Burns,Thomas,,,"><surname>Burns</surname></persName> gave him up, and at the same time secured the arrest of the accused.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="284"/><persName n="Burns,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00151" reg="nearbymention:Burns,Thomas,,,"><surname>Burns</surname></persName> and <persName n="Whitfield,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00152" reg="mostcommon:Whitfield,nomatch:0"><surname>Whitfield</surname></persName> testified that they bought the horse of Cartle on the night he was stolen, paying <measure n="450dollars" type="currency">$450</measure> for him. After hearing the evidence <rs>Curtis</rs> asked no questions of the witnesses, but stated that he purchased the horse of a man named <persName n="Ross,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00153" reg="mostcommon:Ross,nomatch:0"><surname>Ross</surname></persName>, a member of <orgName n="cavalry"><persName n="Rogers,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00154" reg="mostcommon:Rogers,nomatch:0"><surname>Rogers</surname></persName>'s cavalry</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="285"/><persName n="Curtis,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00155" reg="nearbymention:Curtis,William,H.,,"><surname>Curtis</surname></persName> was sent on to an examining Court, to be held on the <dateStruct value="--19"><day reg="19">19th inst.</day></dateStruct>, and committed to jail. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Cold plunge.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="286"/> --At a late hour last <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time>, as <persName n="Carpenter,Mister,S.,G.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00156" reg="default:Carpenter,S.,G.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <foreName>G.</foreName> <surname>Carpenter</surname></persName> was posting along the south bank of the basin, he heard a plunge and splash in the water, and soon after a cry for help.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="287"/>Hurrying to the spot from which the sound proceeded, he there discovered a <rs n="German" type="group">German</rs> in the water, struggling for life.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="288"/>Finding a pole near by, <rs type="role">Mr.</rs> C. soon fished out the frightened man, who gave his name as Rush, and professed to be a bread-baker in <num value="1">one</num> of the hospitals.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="289"/>Rush stated that he was on his way to <placeName reg="Gamble's Hill">Gamble's Hill</placeName>, from the east end of the city, and that, knowing but little of the basin, he fell into the water before he was aware of it. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Throwing stones.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="290"/> --Frequent complaints are made to the <rs>Mayor</rs>, of bad boys who threw stones in the streets, at all hours, regardless of any injury they may inflict on persons passing.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="291"/>The <rs>Mayor</rs> can do nothing but fine the parents of these lads; but persons who are injured or annoyed by them more than once will not be satisfied unless the lads themselves are punished.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="292"/>Every man in the city knows that throwing stones in the streets is a violation of the ordinances, and if he does not teach his children the importance of respecting law, and compel them to do so, he need expect nothing less than trouble and disgrace. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics"><orgName n="Hustings Court" type="court">Hustings Court</orgName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="293"/> --The Justices composing this Court disposed of the following cases brought before them yesterday for hearing: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="294"/> <persName n="Faries,,John,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00157" reg="default:Faries,John,A.,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName> <surname>Faries</surname></persName>, charged with receiving <measure n="300dollars" type="currency">$300</measure> worth of clothing stolen from <persName n="McDonough,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00158" reg="default:McDonough,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>McDonough</surname></persName>, knowing the same to have been stolen.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="295"/>Sent on to be tried before <persName n="Lyons,Judge,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00159" reg="mostcommon:Lyons,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Judge">Judge</roleName> <surname>Lyons</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="296"/> <persName n="Solon,,Daniel,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00160" reg="default:Solon,Daniel,,,"><foreName>Daniel</foreName> <surname>Solon</surname></persName>, stealing <measure n="400l." type="pounds"><num value="400">400</num> pounds</measure> of <rs n="scrap iron" type="product">scrap iron</rs> from the <orgName n="Confederate Government" type="org">Confederate Government</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="297"/>Seat on for trial. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="298"/> <persName n="Doland,,Thomas,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00161" reg="default:Doland,Thomas,,,"><foreName>Thomas</foreName> <surname>Doland</surname></persName> and <persName n="Felburg,,Charles,P.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00162" reg="default:Felburg,Charles,P.,,"><foreName>Charles</foreName> <foreName>P.</foreName> <surname>Felburg</surname></persName>, obtaining by false pretences <measure n="2000dollars" type="currency">$2,000</measure> of <persName n="Smith,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00163" reg="default:Smith,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Smith</surname></persName>, as substitute agents.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="299"/>Examined and acquitted. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="300"/> <persName n="Newman,,William,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00164" reg="default:Newman,William,,,"><foreName>William</foreName> <surname>Newman</surname></persName>, stealing <measure n="50dollars" type="currency">$50</measure> from <persName n="Barker,,Jesse,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00165" reg="default:Barker,Jesse,,,"><foreName>Jesse</foreName> <surname>Barker</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="301"/>Examined and sent on. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="302"/> <persName n="Bender,,Conrad,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00166" reg="default:Bender,Conrad,,,"><foreName>Conrad</foreName> <surname>Bender</surname></persName>, receiving <measure n="200dollars" type="currency">$200</measure> worth of clothing stolen from <persName n="Pairo,,John,L.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00167" reg="default:Pairo,John,L.,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>L.</foreName> <surname>Pairo</surname></persName>, knowing the same to have been stolen.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="303"/>Acquitted. </p> 
<p> <persName n="Myers,,Myer,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00168" reg="default:Myers,Myer,,,"><foreName>Myer</foreName> <surname>Myers</surname></persName>, receiving <measure n="640l." type="pounds"><num value="640">640</num> pounds</measure> of coffee stolen from <persName n="Snead,,W.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00169" reg="default:Snead,W.,W.,,"><foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Snead</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="304"/>Acquitted. </p> 
<p> <persName><foreName>John</foreName></persName> and <persName n="Devzler,,Sarah,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00170" reg="default:Devzler,Sarah,,,"><foreName>Sarah</foreName> <surname>Devzler</surname></persName>, receiving <measure n="640l." type="pounds"><num value="640">640</num> pounds</measure> of coffee stolen from <persName n="Snead,,W.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00171" reg="default:Snead,W.,W.,,"><foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Snead</surname></persName>.-- <hi rend="italics">Acquitted.</hi> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Calf stealing.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="305"/> --<persName n="Acrea,,Thomas,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00172" reg="default:Acrea,Thomas,,,"><foreName n="Thomas">Thos.</foreName> <surname>Acrea</surname></persName>, a lad, charged with stealing a calf from <persName n="Edwards,Doctor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00173" reg="mostcommon:Edwards,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <surname>Edwards</surname></persName>, of <placeName key="possibilities=40" n="1.000 10" reg=",">Church Hill</placeName>, and attempting to sell it at the <rs>Second Market</rs>, was before the <rs>Mayor</rs> yesterday; but owing to the absence of the older and principal thief, who has not yet been arrested, his examination was adjourned. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="7"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Felony.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="306"/> --<persName n="Tolin,,Margaret,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00174" reg="default:Tolin,Margaret,,,"><foreName>Margaret</foreName> <surname>Tolin</surname></persName>, a white women, arrested on the charge of receiving <measure n="50dollars" type="currency">$50</measure> of <persName n="Coleman,,Pat,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00175" reg="default:Coleman,Pat,,,"><foreName>Pat</foreName> <surname>Coleman</surname></persName>, which was stolen of <persName n="Quinlan,,Martin,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00176" reg="default:Quinlan,Martin,,,"><foreName>Martin</foreName> <surname>Quinlan</surname></persName>, knowing the same to have been stolen, was examined before the <rs>Mayor</rs> yesterday.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="307"/><num value="2">Two</num> witnesses testified to seeing the prisoner with <persName n="Pat,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00177" reg="mostcommon:Pat,nomatch:0"><surname>Pat</surname></persName>, and that she purchase a dress to fit him, paying for the same out of a <measure n="50dollars" type="currency">$50</measure> note.--The examination was adjourned. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="8"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Prison record.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="308"/> --There were not more than a dozen prisoners received yesterday at the <name>Libby</name>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="309"/>These were sent down from <placeName key="tgn,2111971" n="1.000 34" reg="gordonsville, orange, virginia">Gordonsville</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="310"/> At Castle Thunder there were no commitments of public interest. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="9"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">New wheat.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="311"/> --Every farmer who wishes to do so can now help the <rs>Government</rs> and the people by sending in their wheat crops as speedily as possible.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="312"/><persName n="Warwick,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00178" reg="mostcommon:Warwick,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Messrs.</roleName> <surname>Warwick</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="Barksdale,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00179" reg="mostcommon:Barksdale,nomatch:0"><surname>Barksdale</surname></persName>, of the <unclear>Gallego ilia,</unclear> in this city, offer to buy new wheat at Government prices, and sell the flour made there from at Government prices &mdash; or to grind the wheat for the farmer, merely charging the usual tell.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="313"/>These gentlemen, by selling flour to families at <num value="0.5">one-half</num> the price asked by extortioners, have done a great deal to prevent suffering and want, and now that they are disposed to continue their patriotic efforts in behalf of the people and against the blood-suckers of the land, we sincerely trust that our farmers will exhibition equal amount of patriotism, and send them their crops of wheat with as little delay as possible. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="10"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Fined.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="314"/> --<persName n="Field,,C.,C.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00180" reg="default:Field,C.,C.,,"><foreName>C.</foreName> <foreName>C.</foreName> <surname>Field</surname></persName>, charged with keeping open doors on <dateStruct><day type="name">Sunday</day></dateStruct>, and selling liquor to be drunk in his house, in violation of law, was called before the <rs>Mayor</rs> yesterday, but came not. He was fined heavily for his short comings. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="11"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Helping the poor.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="315"/> --If the present high prices of the necessaries of life continue the poor of the city will require liberal aid at the hands of the <name>Council</name>, who must care for them, and no doubt will do so at any cost.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="316"/>Already liberal appropriations have been made from the public fund for this purpose, but the <name>Council</name> will yet have to appropriate <measure n="100000dollars" type="currency">$100,000</measure> to enable that class to get through the winter months.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="317"/>As many of these needy creatures are profligate of what they have, it would be wise policy in the <name>Council</name> to appoint again to buy up the necessaries of life and distribute them instead of money. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="318"/> <hi rend="italics">The health</hi> of the city during the prevailing dog days can only be preserved by cleanliness.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="319"/>Not only the streets and alleys, but every private lot and cellar, ought to be carefully cleansed, and, where necessary, timed, to prevent the stagnation of water and the accumulation of decomposed vegetable substances.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="320"/>The policies are at work in this matter, and will do a great deal towards putting the city in order, but without the aid of the citizens generally, they will not be able to do all that is necessary.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="321"/>Let every housekeeper look after his own promises, and see that they are as they should be. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="13"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Militia drills.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="322"/> --The utter disregard of orders for afternoon drills by large portions of the <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num>-class militia, will very soon compel the <rs>Governor</rs> to put them all into camps of instruction, so as to ensure their efficiency when needed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="323"/>In many of the companies we hear of members who have never been absent from roll-call and drill, and to think, it is expensed the <rs type="role" reg="Commander-in-Chief">Commander in Chief</rs> will be logical; but to those who are always too busy after the almighty dollar to give an occasional hear to their military duties, we have only to any, let them go into camp, and there be kept to the past moment. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="14"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Disgraceful.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="324"/> --that young men should be allowed to bathe in the canal and deck in daylight, regardless of the hundreds of ladies who have to pass by and witness their nudity.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="325"/>If they have no <unclear></unclear>--so shame &mdash; they ought to be punished and expressed as a warning to <unclear></unclear> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="15"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Body found.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="326"/> --The body of a new born infant, partly decomposed, was found in a guilty near <orgName n="the Poor House" type="org">the poor house</orgName> yesterday morning and interred. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="16"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Dog shooting.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="327"/> --<persName n="Spicer,,Martin,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00181" reg="default:Spicer,Martin,,,"><foreName>Martin</foreName> <surname>Spicer</surname></persName> was fined <measure n="18dollars" type="currency">$18</measure> by the <rs>Mayor</rs> for entering the <num value="1" type="ordinal">1st</num> of <persName n="Sholderer,,Frederick,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00182" reg="default:Sholderer,Frederick,,,"><foreName>Frederick</foreName> <surname>Sholderer</surname></persName> and shooting his dog. </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> <milestone unit="page" n="2"/> 
<div1 type="page-image"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="328"/><figure entity="NW_RichTimesD_025_038_002"> <figDesc>Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume <num value="25">25</num>, <num value="38">Number 38</num>, <ref n="page 2">page 2</ref>. </figDesc> </figure></p> </div1> <milestone unit="column" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.</head> 
<div2 type="morning"> 
<head><date value="1863-08-13">Thursday morning...Aug. 13, 1863.</date></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="329"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="telegraphic"> 
<head>Telegraphic.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>From <placeName reg="Pensacola, Escambia, Florida" key="tgn,7013972">Pensacola</placeName>.</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Mobile, Mobile, Alabama" key="tgn,7017444">Mobile</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-08-11"><month reg="08">Aug.</month> <day reg="11">11</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="330"/> --The <orgName n="Mobile Evening News" type="newspaper">Mobile <hi rend="italics">Evening News</hi></orgName> has a special dispatch giving later news from <placeName reg="Pensacola, Escambia, Florida" key="tgn,7013972">Pensacola</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="331"/>There were <num value="16">sixteen</num> vessels in the harbor, <num value="10">ten</num> of which are vessels of war, and the rest transports.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="332"/>The <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> are building <num value="2">two</num> immense hospitals at the <rs type="place">Navy Yard</rs>, each <measure n="300feet" type="distance">three hundred feet</measure> long and <num value="3">three</num> stories high. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="333"/> All the negroes are being sent to New Orleans, to be drilled and placed in the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> army there. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="334"/> <placeName reg="Pensacola, Escambia, Florida" key="tgn,7013972">Pensacola</placeName> itself was still considered neutral ground. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head>From <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName>.</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-08-11"><month reg="08">Aug.</month> <day reg="11">11</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="335"/> --All quiet here tonight. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="336"/> <persName n="Corcoran,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00183" reg="mostcommon:Corcoran,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Corcoran</surname></persName>, wife of <persName n="Concern,General,Michael,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00184" reg="default:Concern,Michael,,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <foreName>Michael</foreName> <surname>Concern</surname></persName>, died suddenly, in <orgName n="New York City" type="newspaper">New York city</orgName>, on <dateStruct><day type="name">Wednesday</day></dateStruct> last. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="337"/> <persName n="Devereux,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00185" reg="default:Devereux,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Devereux</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Raleigh, Wake, North Carolina" key="tgn,7013949">Raleigh, N. C.</placeName>, has been appointed <persName n="Tithing,Chief,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00186" reg="mostcommon:Tithing,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Chief">Chief</roleName> <surname>Tithing</surname></persName> man of <placeName reg="North Carolina" key="tgn,7007709">North Carolina</placeName>. </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="announcements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="death" n="1"> 
<head>Died,</head> 
<div4 type="obit" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="338"/> Yesterday morning, at <time value="9oclock">9 o'clock</time>, <persName n="Peterson,Mrs.,Elizabeth,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00187" reg="default:Peterson,Elizabeth,,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <foreName>Elizabeth</foreName> <surname>Peterson</surname></persName>, relict of <persName n="Paterson,,George,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00188" reg="default:Paterson,George,,,"><foreName>George</foreName> <surname>Paterson</surname></persName>, Con'd, of <placeName reg="Petersburg, Petersburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7014404">Petersburg</placeName>, aged <measure n="59years" type="date">59 years</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="339"/> Her funeral will take place from <orgName n="Trinity Church" type="church">Trinity Church</orgName>, corner <address><street n="Broad Street">Broad</street></address> and <address><street n="20 Street">20th streets</street></address>, this (<dateStruct><day type="name">Thursday</day></dateStruct>) <time>morning</time> <dateStruct value="-08-13"><month reg="08">August</month> <day reg="13">13th</day></dateStruct>, at <time value="10oclock">10 o'clock</time>. Her friends, and those of her son, <persName n="Chas,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00189" reg="mostcommon:Chas,nomatch:0"><surname>Chas</surname></persName> T <persName n="Paterson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00190" reg="nearbymention:Paterson,George,,,"><surname>Paterson</surname></persName>, and her son-in-law, T L D <persName n="Walford,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00191" reg="mostcommon:Walford,nomatch:0"><surname>Walford</surname></persName>, are respectfully invited to attend. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="340"/> On the <dateStruct value="--12"><day reg="2">12th</day></dateStruct> last, at <time value="1oclock">1 o'clock</time> P M, of typhoid fever, <persName n="Wayt,Private,William,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00192" reg="default:Wayt,William,,,"><roleName n="Private">Private</roleName> <foreName>William</foreName> <surname>Wayt</surname></persName>, <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> <persName n="Dr,IsFather,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00193" reg="mostcommon:Dr,nomatch:0"><roleName n="IsFather">son of</roleName> <surname>Dr</surname></persName> J G <persName n="Wayt,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00194" reg="nearbymention:Wayt,William,,,"><surname>Wayt</surname></persName>, a member of the <orgName type="regiment" key="1Company">1st Co.</orgName> Richmond Howitzers from the beginning of the war, aged <measure n="19years" type="date">19 years</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="341"/> The friends of the family are invited to attend his funeral from the residence of <persName n="Nelson,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00195" reg="mostcommon:Nelson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Nelson</surname></persName>, corner of <placeName reg="Marshall, Harrison, Texas" key="tgn,2105926">Marshall</placeName> and <num value="12" type="ordinal">12th</num> sts, at <time value="5oclock">5 o'clock</time> P M this day. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="342"/> On yesterday morning, at his residence in <placeName reg="Chester, Chesterfield, Virginia" key="tgn,2111160">Chester, Chesterfield Co.</placeName>, of typhoid fever, N G Chalk Ley, aged <measure n="33years" type="date">33 years</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="343"/> His funeral will take place this evening at <time value="3oclock">3 o'clock</time>, from his late residence.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="344"/>The friends and acquaintances of the family are requested to attend. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="345"/> On <dateStruct value="-08-10"><day type="name">Monday</day>, <month reg="08">August</month> <day reg="10">10th</day></dateStruct>, <persName><foreName>Johnny</foreName></persName>, <persName n="Jeremiah,IsFather,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00196" reg="mostcommon:Jeremiah,nomatch:0"><roleName n="IsFather">son of</roleName> <surname>Jeremiah</surname></persName> and <persName n="Coughlin,,Martha,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00197" reg="default:Coughlin,Martha,,,"><foreName>Martha</foreName> <surname>Coughlin</surname></persName>, aged <measure n="13months" type="date">13 months</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="346"/> <cit><q> <lg type="stanza"> <l>Now his cradle bed is empty, </l><l>And the darling is not there; </l><l>I miss him in the nursery, </l><l>And I miss him everywhere.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="347"/></l> </lg> <lg type="stanza"> <l>And that baby's little spirit, </l><l>Was borne to <persName><foreName>Jesus</foreName></persName>'s arms, </l><l>And lies upon his bosom now, </l><l>Safe from all earthly harms.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="348"/></l> </lg> <lg type="stanza"> <l>I am glad that he is happy, </l><l>But I shall miss him so; </l><l>I never wished before </l><l>To leave my home below.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="349"/></l> </lg> <lg type="stanza"> <l>But now my baby brother </l><l>Is gone to live above, </l><l>I almost long to join him there, </l><l>And live with him in love.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="350"/></l> </lg> <lg type="stanza"> <l>I will not think him sleeping </l><l>In the cold, <orgName n="Low Church" type="church">low church</orgName> yard bed; </l><l>But rather that he's keeping </l><l>A watch around my head.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="351"/></l> </lg> </q><bibl n="BY A SISTER"></bibl></cit> </p> 
<p> Of chronic hydrocephalus and whooping cough, on the <dateStruct value="-08-11"><day reg="11">11th</day> <month reg="08">August</month></dateStruct>, <persName n="Louis,,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00198" reg="default:Louis,James,,,"><foreName>James</foreName> <surname>Louis</surname></persName>, infant child J Rev Wm J and M's L T <persName n="Pettigrew,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00199" reg="mostcommon:Pettigrew,nomatch:0"><surname>Pettigrew</surname></persName>. </p> </div4> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="352"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="substitute"> 
<head>Substitute Notices</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>Substitute wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="353"/> --Wanted, a Substitute, over <measure n="40years" type="date">40 years</measure> of age an able bodied man, with good character and good references.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="354"/>Apply at the <rs type="place">Virginia House</rs>, on <address><street n="Grace street">Grace street</street></address>, between <time value="9">9</time> and <time value="11oclock">11 o'clock</time>, and for which a liberal price will be paid. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="355"/> <term type="printrun">au 13--1t</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head>Substitute wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="356"/> --To go in a <orgName n="Light Artillery" type="artillery">light artillery</orgName> company.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="357"/><num value="1">One</num> who can come well recommended and over <measure n="45years" type="date">45 years</measure> of age, or under <num value="18">18</num>, will be acceptable.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="358"/>The applicant must apply at <unclear></unclear> to. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Belvin,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00200" reg="mostcommon:Belvin,nomatch:0"><surname>Belvin</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="Atkinson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00201" reg="mostcommon:Atkinson,nomatch:0"><surname>Atkinson</surname></persName>.</signed> <term type="printrun">au 13--3t</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head>Substitute wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="359"/> --A liberal price will be paid for a man who is <measure n="45years" type="date">45 years</measure> of age. to be accepted at the <placeName reg="Camp of Instruction">camp of instruction</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="360"/>Apply at </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Hill,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00202" reg="mostcommon:Hill,nomatch:0"><surname>Hill</surname></persName> &#x0026; Noffleet's,</signed> <lb/> Corner of <address><street n="Cary Street">Cary</street></address> and <address><street n="Va Street">Va</street></address>. streets. <term type="printrun">au 13--1t</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head>Substitute wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="361"/> --The highest price will be paid for a man over <measure n="45years" type="date">45 years</measure> old to go as a Substitute.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="362"/>Call to-day at <persName n="Jas,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00203" reg="mostcommon:Jas,nomatch:0"><surname>Jas</surname></persName>. T. <unclear>Bu</unclear>. <address><street n="Cary street">Cary street</street></address>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="363"/> <term type="printrun">au 13--1t</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head>Substitute wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="364"/> --To take my place in <placeName reg="Camp Lee">Camp Lee</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="365"/>For <num value="1">one</num> in every way fit I will pay the most liberal price.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="366"/>None need apply but <num value="1">one</num> of undoubted fitness.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="367"/>Apply at this office.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="368"/>I will be in almost every hour in the day. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="369"/> <term type="printrun">au 12--2t</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head>Substitute wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="370"/> --Wanted, a Substitute over <measure n="45years" type="date">45 years</measure> of age, an able-bodied man, with good character and good reference &mdash; for which a liberal price will be paid.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="371"/>Apply at <address><street n="Main Street 140">No. 140 Main street</street></address>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="372"/> <term type="printrun">au 12--3t</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="7"> 
<head>Substitute wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="373"/> --To serve in cavalry.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="374"/>A liberal price will be paid, and horse, &#x0026;c., furnished. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Mercer,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00204" reg="mostcommon:Mercer,nomatch:0"><surname>Mercer</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="Hill,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00205" reg="mostcommon:Hill,nomatch:0"><surname>Hill</surname></persName>.</signed> <lb/> <address><street n="7 Street">7th street</street></address>, near Main. <term type="printrun">au 12--3t</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="military"> 
<head>Military Notices.</head> 
<div3 type="orders" n="1"> 
<head>Attention Co H, <num value="2" type="ordinal">2d</num> class militia.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="375"/> --You are hereby notified to meet on the <rs>Capt</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="376"/>to Square at <time value="5oclock">5 o'clock</time> this <time>Evening</time>, <dateStruct value="-08-13"><month reg="08">August</month> <day reg="13">13th</day></dateStruct>, for the election of <num value="2">two</num> commissioned officers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="377"/>Owing to the rain on yesterday there was no meeting. </p> <closer> By order of <signed>H R <persName n="Dupuy,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00206" reg="mostcommon:Dupuy,nomatch:0"><surname>Dupuy</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <persName n="Com,Lieutenant,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00207" reg="mostcommon:Com,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lieutenant">Lieut.</roleName> <surname>Com</surname></persName>'g Co. <term type="printrun">au 13--1t</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="2"> 
<head>Attention, Foreign Legion</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="378"/> --The members of this Company are requested to attend a meeting on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Thursday</day></dateStruct> <time>Evening</time>, <dateStruct value="-08-13"><month reg="08">August</month> <day reg="13">13th</day></dateStruct> at <time value="7oclock">7 o'clock</time> at the <rs type="place">Old Market</rs> <persName n="Hall,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00208" reg="mostcommon:Hall,nomatch:0"><surname>Hall</surname></persName>, an important business is to come before the meeting. </p> <closer> By order of the <rs>Captain</rs> <lb/> <signed>W P <persName n="Brown,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00209" reg="mostcommon:Brown,nomatch:0"><surname>Brown</surname></persName>, O S.</signed> <term type="printrun">au 12--2t</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="3"> 
<head>Special Notice.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="379"/> --For the benefit of absentees of the <orgName n="Hampden Artillery" type="artillery">Hampden Artillery</orgName>: </p> 
<list> 
<head></head> 
<item><persName><foreName>Samuel</foreName></persName> P Trewells, </item> 
<item>J T <persName n="Vaughan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00210" reg="mostcommon:Vaughan,nomatch:0"><surname>Vaughan</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Tucker,,Thos,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00211" reg="default:Tucker,Thos,,,"><foreName>Thos</foreName> <surname>Tucker</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Wright,,Carter,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00212" reg="default:Wright,Carter,,,"><foreName>Carter</foreName> <surname>Wright</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item>Wm F Breadlow, </item> 
<item><persName n="Maloy,,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00213" reg="default:Maloy,James,,,"><foreName>James</foreName> <surname>Maloy</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Brant,,Robert,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00214" reg="default:Brant,Robert,,,"><foreName>Robert</foreName> <surname>Brant</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Bune,,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00215" reg="default:Bune,James,,,"><foreName>James</foreName> <surname>Bune</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Jos,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00216" reg="mostcommon:Jos,nomatch:0"><surname>Jos</surname></persName> H <persName n="Williams,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00217" reg="mostcommon:Williams,nomatch:0"><surname>Williams</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Geo,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00218" reg="mostcommon:Geo,nomatch:0"><surname>Geo</surname></persName> P <persName n="Tyler,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00219" reg="mostcommon:Tyler,Giles,,,:1"><surname>Tyler</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item>S <persName n="Tyler,,Giles,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00220" reg="default:Tyler,Giles,,,"><foreName>Giles</foreName> <surname>Tyler</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Oakley,,Thos,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00221" reg="default:Oakley,Thos,,,"><foreName>Thos</foreName> <surname>Oakley</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item>Wm Goods, </item> 
<item>O C <placeName reg="Bridgewater, Rockingham, Virginia" key="tgn,2110776">Bridgewater</placeName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Thos,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00222" reg="mostcommon:Thos,nomatch:0"><surname>Thos</surname></persName> B <persName n="Ford,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00223" reg="mostcommon:Ford,nomatch:0"><surname>Ford</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Mayor,,Chris,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00224" reg="default:Mayor,Chris,,,"><foreName>Chris</foreName> <surname>Mayor</surname></persName>, </item> </list> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="380"/> And others, </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="381"/> Are hereby notified that orders they avail themselves of the pardon extended them in the <rs>President</rs>'s proclamation, and return immediately to camp, sufficient inducements will be offered to insure their arrest, and they will suffer the extreme penalty of the law. Beware of a <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> conviction of &#x0022;absence without leave.&#x0022; Report to me at the corner of <address><street n="Franklin Street">Franklin</street></address> and <address><street n="4 Street">4th streets</street></address>. </p> <closer> <signed>W H Caskin Capt. H A.</signed> <term type="printrun">au 11--eod2t</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="4"> 
<head>Military Notice.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="382"/> --We, the undersigned have authority from <rs type="role">Col.</rs> W M <persName n="Brown,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00225" reg="mostcommon:Brown,nomatch:0"><surname>Brown</surname></persName> to organize a Company of Cavalry for local defence, to be attached to his command Arms, equipments, and forage for horses furnished.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="383"/>This is a good opportunity for those having horses to join a good company, for local defence only as the <rs>Government</rs> purposes to pay each man <measure n="12dollars" type="currency">$12</measure> per month and furnish forage for his horse.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="384"/>Those wishing to join this company can do so by calling at Miles &#x0026; <rs type="role2">Brother</rs>'s, on <address><street n="13 Street">13th street</street></address>, between <address><street n="Main street">Main</street></address> and <address><street n="Cary street">Cary</street></address>. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Jones,,Parke,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00226" reg="default:Jones,Parke,,,"><foreName>Parke</foreName>  <surname>Jones</surname></persName>,</signed> <signed>L M Miles.</signed> <term type="printrun">jy 27--ts</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="385"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="2"/> 
<div2 type="special"> 
<head>Special Notices.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="386"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="lost"> 
<head>Lost, Strayed, &#x0026;c.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="387"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="13"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="14"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="15"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="16"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="17"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="horses"> 
<head>Horses, &#x0026;C., for Sale.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="388"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="3"/> 
<div2 type="wants"> 
<head>Wants.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="389"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="13"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="14"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="15"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="16"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="17"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="18"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="19"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="20"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="21"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="22"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="23"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="24"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="25"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="26"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="27"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="28"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="29"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="30"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="31"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="32"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="33"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="34"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="35"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="36"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="37"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="4"/> 
<div2 type="amusements"> 
<head>Amusements.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="390"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="runaway"> 
<head>Runaways.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>Runaway--<measure n="50dollars" type="currency">$50</measure> Reward.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="391"/> --Left home on the <dateStruct value="--9"><day reg="9">9th inst.</day></dateStruct>, my negro woman <persName><foreName>Jane</foreName></persName>, ginger broad color, long hair, about <measure n="5feet" type="distance">5 feet</measure> <measure n="2inches" type="distance">2 inches</measure> high, sprightly, and speaks quick when spoken to. Was raised by <persName n="John,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00227" reg="mostcommon:John,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>John</surname></persName> W <persName n="Bradly,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00228" reg="mostcommon:Bradly,nomatch:0"><surname>Bradly</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Chales City">Chales City</placeName>, and lived with <persName n="Nott,Mister,Wm,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00229" reg="default:Nott,Wm,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>Wm</foreName> <surname>Nott</surname></persName> last year.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="392"/>She may possibly stay on Church and <placeName reg="Union Hills, Maricopa, Arizona" key="tgn,2738822">Union Hills</placeName>, where she has relations, or also she may try to make way to <placeName reg="Charles City, Charles City, Virginia" key="tgn,2111055">Charles City</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="393"/>I will give the above reward for her delivery in any jail in <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> so that I may get her again. </p> <closer> <signed><persName><foreName>Hugh</foreName></persName> M Hutcher O S.</signed> <term type="printrun">au 12--1w</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head>Runaway in jail</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="394"/> --<persName n="Jackson,,Jesse,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00230" reg="default:Jackson,Jesse,,,"><foreName>Jesse</foreName> <surname>Jackson</surname></persName>, a slave, was committed to this jail on the <dateStruct value="-03-25"><day reg="25">25th</day> day of <month reg="03">March</month></dateStruct> last, <measure n="5feet" type="distance">5 feet</measure> <measure n="8inches" type="distance">8 inches</measure> high slender build, dark complexion.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="395"/>His owner will please come forward, prove property, and take him away. </p> <closer> <signed><persName><foreName>George</foreName></persName> D <persName n="Pleasants,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00231" reg="mostcommon:Pleasants,Nicholas,,,:1"><surname>Pleasants</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <persName n="Henrico,Sheriff,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00232" reg="mostcommon:Henrico,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Sheriff">Sheriff</roleName> <surname>Henrico</surname></persName> county. <term type="printrun">au 11--6w</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="396"/><measure n="25dollars" type="currency">Twenty-five Dollars</measure> Reward will be paid for the apprehension and delivery to who <persName n="Clopton,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00233" reg="mostcommon:Clopton,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Messrs.</roleName> <surname>Clopton</surname></persName> &#x0026; Lyne of my man Glasco, ranaway from the <rs type="place">Jackson Hospital</rs> several weeks ago. Said negro is about <measure n="5feet" type="distance">five feet</measure> <num value="9">nine</num> or <measure n="10inches" type="distance">ten inches</measure> high, of dark gingerbread color, very likely, and smiles generally when spoken to. He ranaway in the month of <dateStruct value="-03-"><month reg="03">March</month></dateStruct> last, but was apprehended in <placeName reg="Chesterfield, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,1002267">Chesterfield county</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="397"/>He may possibly have hired himself to some person in the army. </p> <closer> <signed>A W <persName n="Buckner,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00234" reg="mostcommon:Buckner,nomatch:0"><surname>Buckner</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> Lt Co &#x0022;C,&#x0022; <orgName type="regiment" key="1TXRegiment">1st Texas Reg't.</orgName> <term type="printrun">au 8--ts</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head>A &#x0026; D R E, <placeName reg="Sup'ts office">Sup'ts office</placeName>,</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, <dateStruct value="1863-07-28"><month reg="07">July</month> <day reg="28">28</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="398"/>Runaways &mdash; From the <num value="11" type="ordinal">11th</num> and <orgName type="regiment" key="14Section">14th sections</orgName> of the <orgName n="Richmond and Danville Railroad" type="railroad">Richmond and Danville Railroad</orgName>: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="399"/> <persName><foreName>John</foreName></persName>, belonging to <persName n="Dismukes,Mrs.,Martha,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00235" reg="default:Dismukes,Martha,,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <foreName>Martha</foreName> <surname>Dismukes</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Halifax, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002166">Halifax county</placeName>, is about <measure n="5feet" type="distance">5 feet</measure> <measure n="6inches" type="distance">6 inches</measure> high, jet black, bushy hair, quick spoken, and very stoutly built. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="400"/> Bill, belonging to R E <persName n="Dunkley,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00236" reg="mostcommon:Dunkley,nomatch:0"><surname>Dunkley</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Halifax, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002166">Halifax county</placeName>, is about <measure n="21years" type="date">21 years</measure> of age brown complexion, about <measure n="5feet" type="distance">5 feet</measure> <measure n="6inches" type="distance">6 inches</measure> high, stout built, round face, and snaggy hair. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="401"/> The usual reward will be paid for their recovery. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Chas,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00237" reg="mostcommon:Chas,nomatch:0"><surname>Chas</surname></persName> G <persName n="Talbott,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00238" reg="mostcommon:Talbott,nomatch:0"><surname>Talbott</surname></persName>, <rs type="role">Sup't.</rs></signed> <term type="printrun">ly 19--2w</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head><measure n="250dollars" type="currency">Two hundred and fifty Dollars</measure> Reward</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="402"/> --Will be paid for the apprehension and delivery of my man <persName n="Anderson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00239" reg="mostcommon:Anderson,nomatch:0"><surname>Anderson</surname></persName> to <persName n="Lea,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00240" reg="mostcommon:Lea,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Messrs.</roleName> <surname>Lea</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="James,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00241" reg="mostcommon:James,nomatch:0"><surname>James</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="403"/>He is about <measure n="5feet" type="distance">5 feet</measure> <num value="7">7</num> or <measure n="8inches" type="distance">8 inches</measure> high, has no marks remembered except a small knot just below <num value="1">one</num> knee; was last heard of when he escaped from the <rs>Staunton</rs> jail, with a number of others, about the <dateStruct value="-06-1"><day reg="1">1st</day> of <month reg="06">June</month></dateStruct> last.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="404"/>He is doubtless lurking around <placeName reg="Waynesboro, Waynesboro, Virginia" key="tgn,2114939">Waynesboro</placeName>', <placeName reg="Augusta, Richmond, Georgia" key="tgn,7017498">Augusta</placeName>, where he has a wife at the house of <persName n="Bush,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00242" reg="mostcommon:Bush,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Bush</surname></persName>. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Russell,,Richard,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00243" reg="default:Russell,Richard,,,"><foreName>Richard</foreName>  <surname>Russell</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> Near <persName n="Virginia,,Clarkesville,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00244" reg="default:Virginia,Clarkesville,,,"><foreName>Clarkesville</foreName> <surname>Virginia</surname></persName>. <term type="printrun">au 7--6t</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head>Runaway.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="405"/> --Was brought to my jail <dateStruct value="1863-07-20"><month reg="07">July</month> <day reg="20">20th</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>, a negro man named <persName n="Wade,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00245" reg="mostcommon:Wade,nomatch:0"><surname>Wade</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="406"/>He says he belongs to <persName n="Wilkes,,John,Davis,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00246" reg="default:Wilkes,John,Davis,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>Davis</foreName> <surname>Wilkes</surname></persName>, of the <orgName type="regiment" key="6SCRegiment">6th South Carolina regiment</orgName>, and came rem-Chester, S. C, and has stayed with the army about <measure n="13months" type="date">thirteen months</measure>. Said negro is of a dark complexion <num value="5">five</num> rest <measure n="2inches" type="distance">two inches</measure> high, and about <measure n="27years" type="date">twenty-seven years</measure> old; has a small scar under his right eye; says that a horse kicked him. The owner will come forward, pay expenses, and take him away. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Lumpkin,,Robert,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00247" reg="default:Lumpkin,Robert,,,"><foreName>Robert</foreName>  <surname>Lumpkin</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, <dateStruct value="1863-08-03"><month reg="08">August</month> <day reg="3">3d</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>. <term type="printrun">au 4--5t</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="7"> 
<head>Runaways</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="407"/> --<measure n="210dollars" type="currency">$210</measure> Reward &mdash; absconded from the defensive works around <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> the following free negroes, impressed from <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>-- </p> 
<list> 
<head></head> 
<item><persName><foreName>John</foreName></persName> H <persName n="Brown,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00248" reg="mostcommon:Brown,nomatch:0"><surname>Brown</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName><foreName>John</foreName></persName> H <persName n="Campbell,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00249" reg="mostcommon:Campbell,nomatch:0"><surname>Campbell</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Coleman,,Patrick,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00250" reg="default:Coleman,Patrick,,,"><foreName>Patrick</foreName> <surname>Coleman</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Pleasants,,Nicholas,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00251" reg="default:Pleasants,Nicholas,,,"><foreName>Nicholas</foreName> <surname>Pleasants</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Roper,,Timothy,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00252" reg="default:Roper,Timothy,,,"><foreName>Timothy</foreName> <surname>Roper</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Junius,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00253" reg="mostcommon:Junius,nomatch:0"><surname>Junius</surname></persName> E <persName n="Thomas,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00254" reg="mostcommon:Thomas,nomatch:0"><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Pittman,,Elijah,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00255" reg="default:Pittman,Elijah,,,"><foreName>Elijah</foreName> <surname>Pittman</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Dixon,,George,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00256" reg="default:Dixon,George,,,"><foreName>George</foreName> <surname>Dixon</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Thacker,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00257" reg="default:Thacker,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Thacker</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Toncuitt,,Jos,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00258" reg="default:Toncuitt,Jos,,,"><foreName>Jos</foreName> <surname>Toncuitt</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="George,,Wm,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00259" reg="default:George,Wm,,,"><foreName>Wm</foreName> <surname>George</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Clarke,,Robert,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00260" reg="default:Clarke,Robert,,,"><foreName>Robert</foreName> <surname>Clarke</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Harris,,William,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00261" reg="default:Harris,William,,,"><foreName>William</foreName> <surname>Harris</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Whiting,,Alex,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00262" reg="default:Whiting,Alex,,,"><foreName>Alex</foreName> <surname>Whiting</surname></persName>, </item> 
<item><persName n="Grey,,Edward,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00263" reg="default:Grey,Edward,,,"><foreName>Edward</foreName> <surname>Grey</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="408"/></item> </list> 
<p> By the act of the <orgName n="Virginia Legislature" type="legislature">Virginia Legislature</orgName>, passed <dateStruct value="1863-02-12"><day reg="12">12th</day> <month reg="02">February</month>, <year>1863</year>,</dateStruct> to provide for the enrollment and employment of free negroes in the public service, <num value="3">three</num> negroes being amenable to the rules and regulations of the articles of war, are deserters, and a reward of <measure n="30dollars" type="currency">thirty dollars</measure> each will be paid for their apprehension and delivery to <rs type="role2">Capt</rs> W G <persName n="Turpin,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00264" reg="mostcommon:Turpin,nomatch:0"><surname>Turpin</surname></persName>, at Engineers' office, corner <address><street n="19 Street">19th</street></address> and <address><street n="Cary Street">Cary sts.</street></address> </p> <closer> <signed>W H <persName n="Stevens,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00265" reg="mostcommon:Stevens,nomatch:0"><surname>Stevens</surname></persName>, <rs type="role" reg="Colonel-Engineer">Col. Eng.</rs></signed> <term type="printrun">jy 30--ts</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="rent"> 
<head>For rent and Sale</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="409"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="announcements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="orders" n="1"> 
<head>[Extract.]<lb/><hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Gen,Adjutant-and-Inspector,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00266" reg="mostcommon:Gen,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Adjutant-and-Inspector">Adj't and inspector</roleName> <surname>Gen</surname></persName>'ls office,</hi> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> <dateStruct value="1863-08-07"><month reg="08">August</month> <day reg="7">7</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="410"/>Special Orders, <num value="87">No. 87</num>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="411"/> <num value="20">XX</num> Under the act of Congress approved <dateStruct value="1863-03-20"><month reg="03">March</month> <day reg="20">20th</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>, <rs type="role" reg="Brigadier-General">Brigadier General</rs> A R <persName n="Lawton,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00267" reg="mostcommon:Lawton,nomatch:0"><surname>Lawton</surname></persName> is assigned to duty as <rs type="role" reg="Quartermaster-General">Quartermaster General</rs>, and will enter upon the discharge of his duties of the office on the <dateStruct value="--10"><day reg="10">10th inst.</day></dateStruct> </p> <closer> By command of the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>. <lb/> <signed><persName n="Withers,,Jno,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00268" reg="default:Withers,Jno,,,"><foreName>Jno</foreName>  <surname>Withers</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Adjutant General">Assistant Adjutant-General</rs>. <term type="printrun">au 12--1w</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="412"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="announcments"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="orders" n="1"> 
<head>Military Boots--<lb/>F <persName n="Thomas,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00269" reg="mostcommon:Thomas,nomatch:0"><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>, formerly of <persName n="Paris,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00270" reg="mostcommon:Paris,nomatch:0"><surname>Paris</surname></persName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="413"/> Has on hand, and is constantly manufacturing, Cavalry and Staff Boots, <unclear></unclear> and Military Boots of all kinds.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="414"/>Call at <address><street n="Broad Street 212">212 Broad st</street></address>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="415"/> A good Boot Maker wanted. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="416"/> <term type="printrun">au 8--2t*</term> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="5"/> 
<div2 type="condition"> 
<head>Condition of the <orgName n="Virginia Bank" type="bank">bank of Virginia</orgName>.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="417"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="real estate"> 
<head><rs n="real estate" type="product">Real Estate</rs> for Sale.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="418"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="13"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="14"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="announcements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>Notice</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="419"/> --All free negroes in the city of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> who have not reported for duty on city defences, are hereby ordered to report forthwith at <placeName reg="Engineer Headquarters">Engineer Headquarters</placeName>, corner <persName n="Cary,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00271" reg="mostcommon:Cary,nomatch:0"><surname>Cary</surname></persName> and <num value="19" type="ordinal">19th</num> sts, for examination.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="420"/>It has been ascertained that large numbers of free negroes are exhibiting &#x0022;bogus passes&#x0022; purporting to be from their <hi rend="italics">masters.</hi> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="421"/> <persName n="White,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00272" reg="mostcommon:White,nomatch:0"><surname>White</surname></persName> men employing such negroes, or keeping them out of service, are instructed to have them reported at once to </p> <closer> <signed>W H <persName n="Stevens,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00273" reg="mostcommon:Stevens,nomatch:0"><surname>Stevens</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <persName n="Bug,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00274" reg="mostcommon:Bug,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Bug</surname></persName>'rs and Chief of Construction, <address><street n="19 Street">19th</street></address> and <address><street n="Cage Street">Cage streets</street></address>. <term type="printrun">au 4--1w</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="422"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="6"/> 
<div2 type="auction"> 
<head><rs n="auction sales" type="product">Auction Sales</rs>--future days.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="423"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="announcements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="orders" n="1"> 
<head>[Extract]<lb/>Adj't and <placeName reg="Insp'r Gen'ls office">Insp'r Gen'ls office</placeName>, <hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>,</hi> <dateStruct value="1863-07-13"><month reg="07">July</month> <day reg="13">13th</day> <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="424"/>Special Orders, <num value="165">No. 165</num>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="425"/> <num value="25">XXV</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="426"/>All soldiers detached from the army, and detailed in <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> will be temporarily connected with the companies organized in the several Departments and Bureaus in the city, and be subject to all military duty. </p> <closer> By command of the Sec'y of War, <lb/> <signed><persName n="Withers,,Jno,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00275" reg="default:Withers,Jno,,,"><foreName>Jno</foreName>  <surname>Withers</surname></persName>, Ass't <rs type="role" reg="Adjutant-General">Adj't Gen.</rs></signed> <term type="printrun">ly 14--1w</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="2"> 
<head>[<hi rend="italics">Extract.</hi>]<lb/><hi rend="smallcaps">Adj't and <placeName reg="Insp'r General's office">Insp'r General's office</placeName>,</hi> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> may <num value="5">5</num>, <dateStruct value="1863--"><year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="427"/>Special Orders, <num value="108">No. 108</num>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="428"/> <num value="23">XXIII</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="429"/>The officers now in <placeName reg="Petersburg, Petersburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7014404">Petersburg</placeName> who have lately been prisoners will proceed to rejoin their proper commends so soon at they shall have been declared exchanged. </p> <closer> By command of the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>, <lb/> <signed><persName n="Withers,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00276" reg="expanded:Withers,"><foreName>John</foreName>  <surname>Withers</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Adjutant General">Assistant Adjutant General</rs>. <term type="printrun">my 6--ts</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="430"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="7"/> 
<div2 type="auction"> 
<head><rs n="auction sales" type="product">Auction Sales</rs>--this day.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="431"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="educational"> 
<head>Educational.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="432"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> </body> </text> </TEI.2>
 
