<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> <!DOCTYPE TEI.2 PUBLIC "-//TEI P4//DTD Main DTD Driver File//EN" "http://www.tei-c.org/Guidelines/DTD/tei2.dtd" [ <!ENTITY % TEI.XML "INCLUDE"> <!ENTITY % PersProse PUBLIC "-//Perseus P4//DTD Perseus Prose//EN" "http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/DTD/1.0/PersProse.dtd" > %PersProse; <!NOTATION jpg SYSTEM "JPEG"> <!ENTITY NW_RichTimesD_028_025_001 SYSTEM "NW_RichTimesD_028_025_001.jpg" NDATA jpg> <!ENTITY NW_RichTimesD_028_025_002 SYSTEM "NW_RichTimesD_028_025_002.jpg" NDATA jpg> <!ENTITY NW_RichTimesD_028_025_003 SYSTEM "NW_RichTimesD_028_025_003.jpg" NDATA jpg> <!ENTITY NW_RichTimesD_028_025_004 SYSTEM "NW_RichTimesD_028_025_004.jpg" NDATA jpg> ]> <TEI.2 id="NW_RichTimesD_028_025"> <teiHeader type="aacr2"> <fileDesc> <titleStmt> <title type="245">The Daily Dispatch: January 30, 1865. </title> <title type="gmd">[Electronic resource] </title> <funder> Institute of Museum and Library Services National Leadership Grant </funder> <respStmt> <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> <resp>Creation of digital images: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> <resp>Conversion to Tei.2-conformant markup: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> </respStmt> </titleStmt> <extent>ca. <num value="30">XXX</num> kilobytes </extent> <publicationStmt> <publisher>University of <orgName n="Richmond Library" type="library">Richmond Library</orgName> </publisher> <pubPlace>Richmond, Virginia </pubPlace> <idno type="Url">Nw_richtimesd_028_025</idno> <availability> 
<p>&#x00A9; 2004 by the University of Richmond. </p> 
<p>Url: http://oncampus.Richmond.edu/academics/Library/digital/ </p> </availability> <date> </date> </publicationStmt> <seriesStmt> 
<p>Institute of Museum and Library Services Civil War Newspaper Project </p> </seriesStmt> <notesStmt> <note>page images have been included from the microfilm version. </note> <note>images were scanned with a Sunrise 2000 scanner from microfilm, at 14x reduction ratio at 400 dpi Optical resolution. Creation Software: Pixel Translations. Pixtiff version 1.135. </note> <note>Ddd note: shipped: 2005_05_28_ddd_url. </note> </notesStmt> <sourceDesc> <biblFull> <titleStmt> <title type="245">The Daily Dispatch: January 30, 1865. </title> <title type="246"><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName> </title> <respStmt> <resp> </resp> <name> </name> </respStmt> </titleStmt> <editionStmt> 
<p> </p> </editionStmt> <extent>4 pages. </extent> <publicationStmt> <publisher>by Cowardin &#x0026; Hammersley. </publisher> <pubPlace>Richmond </pubPlace> <date value="1865-01-30">January 30, 1865</date><idno type="vol">28.25</idno> </publicationStmt> <seriesStmt> <title> </title> </seriesStmt> <notesStmt> <note>microfilm. Ann Arbor, Mi : Proquest. 1 microfilm reel ; 35 mm. </note> </notesStmt> </biblFull> </sourceDesc> </fileDesc> <encodingDesc> <projectDesc> 
<p>Imls Civil War Newspaper Project. </p> </projectDesc> <editorialDecl> 
<p>the images exist as archival Tiff images, with Jpeg versions for internet access. </p> </editorialDecl> <refsDecl> <state unit="article" /> </refsDecl> <classDecl> <taxonomy id="lcsh"> <bibl> <title>Library of Congress subject Headings, </title> <edition>21st edition, 1998</edition> </bibl> </taxonomy> </classDecl> </encodingDesc> <profileDesc> <creation> <date value="1865">1865 </date> </creation> <langUsage> <language id="eng">English </language> <language id="fre">French </language> </langUsage> 
<textClass> <keywords scheme="lcsh"> 
<list type="simple"> 
<item>Newspapers -- Virginia -- Richmond</item> </list> </keywords> </textClass> </profileDesc> <revisionDesc> <change> <date>October, 2005 </date> <respStmt> <resp>Checker </resp> <name>Lesley Byrd, of the University of <orgName n="Richmond Library" type="library">Richmond Library</orgName> </name> </respStmt> 
<item>File checked, not corrected: DO NOT return to vendor. </item> </change> </revisionDesc> </teiHeader> 
<text id="NW_RichTimesD_028_025T"> <front> <milestone unit="page" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="page-image"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="1"/><figure entity="NW_RichTimesD_028_025_001"> <figDesc>Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume <num value="28">28</num>, <num value="25">Number 25</num>, <ref n="page 1">page 1</ref>. </figDesc> </figure></p> </div1> <titlePage> <docTitle><titlePart type="main"> Daily Dispatch </titlePart> </docTitle> <docImprint> Vol. Xxviii &mdash; no.<num value="25">25</num> <pubPlace> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Va.</placeName> </pubPlace> <date value="1865-01-30">Monday, January 30, 1865</date> price <num value="1">one</num> Cent </docImprint> </titlePage> 
<div1 type="subscription"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName><lb/> by <persName n="Cowardin,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00001" reg="mostcommon:Cowardin,nomatch:0"><surname>Cowardin</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="Hammersley,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00002" reg="mostcommon:Hammersley,nomatch:0"><surname>Hammersley</surname></persName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="2"/>the <rs>Daily Dispatch</rs> is served to subscribers at <num value="6.25">Six and A Quarter</num> Cents Per Week, payable to the <name>Carrier</name> weekly.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="3"/><persName n="Price,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00003" reg="mostcommon:Price,nomatch:0"><surname>Price</surname></persName> for mailing, <measure n="4dollars" type="currency">$4</measure> a year, or <measure n="2.50dollars" type="currency">$2.50</measure> for <measure n="6months" type="date">six months</measure>, in advance.</p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="4"/>the <rs>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</rs> is issued every <dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> and <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> at <measure n="2.00dollars" type="currency">$2.00</measure>, in advance.</p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="5"/>the <rs>Weekly Dispatch</rs> is issued every <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct>, and mailed to subscribers at <measure n="1dollars" type="currency">$1</measure> per annum.</p> </div1> 
<div1 type="advertising"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="6"/> 
<table rows="4" cols="4"> 
<head rend="italics">Terms of Advertising.</head> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <num value="1">1</num> day,</cell><cell><measure n="0.50dollars" type="currency">$0.50</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="5days" type="date">5 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="1.50dollars" type="currency">$1.50</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="2days" type="date">2 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="0.75dollars" type="currency">$0.75</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="5days" type="date">5 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="1.75dollars" type="currency">$1.75</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square <measure n="3days" type="date">3 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="1.00dollars" type="currency">$1.00</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="12days" type="date">12 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="3.00dollars" type="currency">$3.00</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square <measure n="4days" type="date">4 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="1.25dollars" type="currency">$1.25</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <dateStruct value="-1-"><month reg="1">1 month</month></dateStruct>,</cell><cell><measure n="5.00dollars" type="currency">$5.00</measure></cell></row> </table></p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="7"/><hi rend="italics">Larger advertisements in exact properties.</hi></p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="8"/>Advertisements published until forbid, will be charged <measure n="50cents" type="currency">50 cents</measure> per square of <num value="8">eight</num> lines for the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> insertion, and <measure n="25cents" type="currency">25 cents</measure> for each continuance</p> </div1> </front> <body> <milestone unit="column" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="9"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.</head> 
<div2 type="morning"> 
<head><date value="1865-01-30">Monday morning...January 30, 1865.</date></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head rend="italics">&#x0022;rich man's War &mdash; poor man's fight.&#x0022;</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="10"/> Poverty is certainly not without its disadvantages.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="11"/>It is the lot of the great mass of mankind.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="12"/>The rich, in all countries and in all ages, are a respectable minority.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="13"/>But among its many misfortunes, none is greater than the facility with which, in democratic countries, it can be duped by demagogues to its own utter ruin.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="14"/>At the head of this article we have placed a shallow but mischievous sophism, invented by enemies of the <rs>Confederate</rs> cause to paralyze the valiant hearts on which it relies for success.--If there are any soldiers of the <rs>Confederacy</rs> weak enough to be deluded by this <sic>transparant</sic> but malignant device, we invoke them to listen to a few words of warning. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="15"/> Granting, for the sake of the argument, that the mass of <orgName n="Confederate Armies" type="org">Confederate armies</orgName> is composed of poor men, is their condition any worse in this respect than that of all the armies of all the wars that from the beginning of the world have been fought to this day?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="16"/>What interest had the rank and file of <placeName reg="United Kingdom" key="tgn,7002445">England</placeName>, <placeName reg="France" key="tgn,1000070">France</placeName>, <placeName reg="Espana" key="tgn,1000095">Spain</placeName>, <placeName reg="Germany" key="tgn,7000084">Germany</placeName>, in most of the wars that those nations have waged?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="17"/>None on the face of the earth, except to advance the selfish ends of kings and rulers, whom lust of power, or revenge, or, sometimes, the most contemptible personal feuds and jealousies, stimulated to draw the sword?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="18"/>What interest have the <rs>Northern</rs> soldiers in the war now waged against the <rs>South</rs>?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="19"/>If ever there was &#x0022;a rich man's war, a poor man's fight,&#x0022; it is this bloody invasion, carried on for the aggrandizement of <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> lords of the loom, merchant princes and shoddy contractors, by hard-handed laborers and artisans, who fight and die for a few dollars a month.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="20"/>To the battles of peace, as well as those of war, the same sophism is applicable.--The grand march of civilization is carried on by the poor.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="21"/>They cut down the trees and clear the forests; they cultivate the soil and raise the staples of commerce; they build the ships and man them when built; they toil in the mines, the factories, the workshops; all the splendid cities, the palace-like houses, costly furniture which they contain, are the fruits of their industry.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="22"/>And, amidst all this splendor, they, who created it, live poor, and die, like the silkworm, in the costly winding sheet which they themselves have brought forth.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="23"/>Is it in the power of man to change the order of nature?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="24"/>Shall not we, who are poor, bow with submission to the decrees of <placeName reg="Providence, Providence, Rhode Island" key="tgn,7013952">Providence</placeName>, take our position cheerfully in that place in life's battles where.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="25"/>He has stationed us, and patiently await at His hands the final rewards of obedience and fidelity? </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="26"/> But if ever there was a war to which the miserable sophism we have quoted has no application whatever, it is this universal uprising of the <rs>South</rs> against <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> invasion.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="27"/>What brought to the field the great mass of the <rs>Southern</rs> armies &mdash; the men who, from <placeName key="tgn,2112877" n="1.000 541" reg="manassas, manassas, virginia">Manassas</placeName> to this hour, have illustrated the <rs>Confederate</rs> flag with prodigies of valor and endurance?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="28"/>They came voluntarily, poor and rich, to drive from their common soil a <milestone unit="column" n="2"/> common enemy.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="29"/>Whilst the majority of them, like the majority of all armies, are not rich men, more rich men have entered the <rs>Confederate</rs> ranks than any army of which we have any knowledge.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="30"/>It is true enough, there are some rich men who have never shouldered a musket and never will.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="31"/>But they are mostly those who were poor at the beginning of the war, and have made fortunes since by extortion and speculation.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="32"/>If they could be taken by the nape of the neck and thrust into the front of the battle, it would give universal satisfaction.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="33"/>Many men who were rich before the war have become utterly impoverished, and would consider themselves fortunate now if they could be assured of soldier's fare and soldier's clothing. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="34"/> And now, suppose the work of subjugation complete, and that <orgName n="Slavery Institution" type="institution">institution of slavery</orgName>, in which we are told none but slaveholders have any interest, abolished, how are the poor to be benefitted?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="35"/>What is the condition of the poor in <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName>, in <placeName key="tgn,1000070" n="1.000 1012" reg="france">France</placeName>, in the <rs>North</rs>?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="36"/>Is it not an incessant and painful struggle for the bare necessaries of life by the performance of labors which are here performed by slaves?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="37"/>Is it not a rigid exclusion from all social sympathies and considerations, so that the foreigner and Northern employer treats his employee with less indulgence and civility than the <rs>Southern</rs> master treats his slaves?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="38"/>Here, color is the only real distinction of classes.--No <num value="1">one</num>, whatever his circumstances, is denied the name and the treatment of a gentleman, unless he forfeits it by his own bad conduct.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="39"/>We should like to see the poor man in the <rs>North</rs> who is called a gentleman, or invited to sit down at the tables of the rich.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="40"/>A Southern slave would scarcely be more astonished at such a compliment.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="41"/>There is not under the canopy of Heaven a land in which the poor are as exempt from physical want, and as free from the rich man's contumely,&#x0022; as in these Southern States.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="42"/>What would be the result of Northern success in this war?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="43"/>The slaveholder, it is true, would be driven off, and in his place would be <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> landholders, who would, of course, buy up the forfeited estates of the original proprietors, and then the deluded poor man of the <rs>South</rs> would learn, for the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> time, what it is to be poor under a race which never even pretended to have compassion for poor <hi rend="italics">white</hi> men. The slaves would disappear and who would take their place?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="44"/>Who would plough the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> nabob's farm, who would drive his carriage, who would be his butler, and his dining-room and body servant, who would be his wife's cook, washer-woman and chambermaid, who would black the boots and shoes of the family?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="45"/>The poor of the <rs>South</rs>, who would have to live, and, in order to live, would be compelled to degrade themselves to the condition of white negroes to <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> taskmasters.--And again: &#x0022;It is,&#x0022; as has been justly remarked, &#x0022;a matter of very great importance to the poor of any country that the value of labor be kept at the highest price possible.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="46"/>It is the constant interest of the laboring man to use every fair and honorable means to keep the price of labor up. In the <rs>South</rs>, the poor have the co-operation of the rich in estimating the worth of labor, because it is also the interest of the rich that the price of a day, or a week, or a month's work, stands at the highest possible figure.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="47"/>The rich man wants a high estimate placed upon the labor of his servants, and the poor man desires a similar estimate to be fixed for his labor; thus they co- operate to keep up the price of labor, while there is no considerable part of our people who have any reason to wish its worth reduced.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="48"/>With us, all classes conspire for the constant increase of the value of labor &mdash; because it is their interest to do so. But remove the institution of <rs n="African" type="ethnic">African</rs> slavery, and will this be true any longer?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="49"/>No, verily; at once it becomes the interest of every rich man to put the price of labor down to the lowest figure.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="50"/>He owns the land, he owns the factories, he holds the property and the money of the country, and he must have his tenants, his laborers and his hired servants.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="51"/>Then the rich conspire to reduce the price of labor in all its departments, and the poor man must work at the prices established for him by the rich; I say <hi rend="italics">must,</hi> because he must eat; and if he eat, he must work; and if he work, he must work at the rich man's price, though it be but a penny a day. And the only means of raising the <milestone unit="column" n="3"/> worth of labor is an occasional bread riot &mdash; such as so often occurs in the so-called free countries.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="52"/>The <orgName n="Slavery Institution" type="institution">institution of slavery</orgName> constitutes the reason why labor is worth so much more in the <rs>South</rs> than anywhere else on the globe.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="53"/> Nor are these the only evils which the poor man of the <rs>South</rs> has reason to apprehend from <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> subjugation.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="54"/>The hardships of war are, at present, the great grievance of his condition. --war, <num value="1">one</num> of the most terrible and, at the same time, the most universal and inevitable of the afflictions of fallen man. If they expect to avoid this by submission to <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> domination, they will discover, when too late, that they have made the most egregious and tragical of human blunders.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="55"/>If the <rs>South</rs> succeeds, it is probable that, with her present experience, she will carefully avoid war with any and every foreign Power.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="56"/>She has no quarrels to adjust with any nation but the <rs>North</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="57"/>Her policy will not be <num value="1">one</num> of territorial aggrandizement, nor such, in any respect, as to bring her into collision with other countries.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="58"/>Her soil is productive of staples essential to the commerce and manufactures of the world, and she will be, besides, <num value="1">one</num> of the most valuable of their customers.--They will, therefore, be no more inclined to quarrel with her than she with them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="59"/>The only hope of future peace and quiet is in the success of the <rs>Confederacy</rs>.--The <rs>North</rs>, on the other hand, already proclaims that, as soon as the rebellion is crushed, she will punish <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName> for the wrongs inflicted upon her in this war, and drive <persName n="Maximilian,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00004" reg="mostcommon:Maximilian,nomatch:0"><surname>Maximilian</surname></persName> from his throne.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="60"/>Her policy is <num value="1">one</num> of territorial aggrandizement.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="61"/>She has determined to have <placeName reg="Canada" key="tgn,7005685">Canada</placeName>, <placeName reg="Mexico" key="tgn,1001893">Mexico</placeName> and <placeName reg="Cuba" key="tgn,7005380">Cuba</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="62"/>And who will be her instruments to accomplish these objects?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="63"/>Who will be her soldiers?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="64"/>Will she go to <placeName key="tgn,7001181" n="1.000 212" reg="eire">Ireland</placeName> then, or to <placeName reg="Deutschland, Europe, " key="tgn,7000084">Germany</placeName>, or rely upon negroes?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="65"/>She does that now rather than draw upon her own precious population.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="66"/>But she would not do it in a future war, when the white soldiers of the <rs>South</rs>, whom some of her own generals admit to be the best fighting men in the world, could be drafted into the service.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="67"/>The poor men of the <rs>South</rs> would be forced into the <orgName n="U. S. Armies" type="org">United States armies</orgName>, and compelled to fight the battles of the <rs>North</rs> against <placeName reg="United Kingdom" key="tgn,7002445">England</placeName>, <placeName reg="France" key="tgn,1000070">France</placeName>, <placeName reg="Espana" key="tgn,1000095">Spain</placeName>; against any and every Power that stood in the way of Northern revenge and cupidity.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="68"/>Their bones would bleach every battle-field from <placeName reg="Canada, North and Central America, " key="tgn,7005685">Canada</placeName> to the tropics, and their wives and children be doomed to endless servitude and starvation.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="69"/>They would then know what that thing means in reality: &#x0022;a rich man's war &mdash; a poor man's fight.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="70"/> We honestly believe that the welfare and happiness of Southern poor men are as much involved in the success of this struggle as any other class of the community &mdash; more so than the rich, who can leave the country and escape brutality and degradation of foreign lands. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head rend="italics">Falling back.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="71"/> The worst kind of &#x0022;falling back&#x0022; that has occurred during the war is the &#x0022;falling back&#x0022; of some who, when <persName n="Lincoln,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00005" reg="mostcommon:Lincoln,nomatch:0"><surname>Lincoln</surname></persName> was elected, had to be held by the collar by rational people to prevent them from capturing <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName> and setting fire to the <rs>Potomac</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="72"/>There are some of those persons who do not now occupy that advanced position, and who manifest the more dispassionate sentiments of the <rs n="American" type="group">American</rs> soldier when the <rs>British</rs> advanced upon the <rs>Federal</rs> capital, and who, when the red-coats and bayonets appeared in sight, rode up to his commander-in-chief and remarked: &#x0022;See here, General, can't this thing be compromised?&#x0022; The number, we are happy to know, is few; and in this old State, which went late into the conflict, and bore the brunt of it, is by no means &#x0022;Legion.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="73"/> A list of &#x0022;falling-back&#x0022; heroes in <placeName reg="Savannah, Chatham, Georgia" key="tgn,7014487">Savannah</placeName> is given by a correspondent of the <orgName n="Charleston Courier" type="newspaper">Charleston <hi rend="italics">Courier</hi></orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="74"/>Not <num value="1">one</num> of them is a soldier.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="75"/>Every <num value="1">one</num> has been basking in prosperity and ease since the war began.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="76"/><persName n="Arnold,Doctor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00006" reg="mostcommon:Arnold,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <surname>Arnold</surname></persName>, the <rs>Mayor</rs>, is spoken of as a physician of merit and a man of intellect, but very old--&#x0022;the wit is out.&#x0022; <persName n="Rockwell,Colonel,W.,S.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00007" reg="default:Rockwell,W.,S.,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Colonel</roleName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <surname>Rockwell</surname></persName> is said to have achieved his chief military distinction by drinking champagne and eating oysters.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="77"/><persName n="Willis,Doctor,T.,T.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00008" reg="default:Willis,T.,T.,,"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <foreName>T.</foreName> <foreName>T.</foreName> <surname>Willis</surname></persName>, who came to <placeName reg="Savannah, Chatham, Georgia" key="tgn,7014487">Savannah</placeName> from <placeName reg="Augusta, Richmond, Georgia" key="tgn,7017498">Augusta</placeName>, and perhaps further north, is mentioned as held in affectionate remembrance by the stockholders of the <rs>Augusta</rs> and <rs>Savannah</rs> <milestone unit="column" n="4"/> railroad for a dexterous purchase of a large quantity of stock in said road, at a low figure, before he published to the dumb-founded stockholders a scheme which he had some time before perpetrated, and which had the effect of doubling the value of the stock.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="78"/><persName n="Hartridge,,A.,S.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00009" reg="default:Hartridge,A.,S.,,"><foreName>A.</foreName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <surname>Hartridge</surname></persName> filled the comfortable position of war tax collector.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="79"/><persName n="Erwin,Mister,Robert,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00010" reg="default:Erwin,Robert,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>Robert</foreName> <surname>Erwin</surname></persName> was delighted in former days to descant upon the virtues of his native State, <placeName key="tgn,7007712" n="1.000 6435" reg="south carolina">South Carolina</placeName>; but times are changed, and he now &#x0022;rears you gently as a sucking dove.&#x0022; <persName n="Villalongs,Alderman,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00011" reg="mostcommon:Villalongs,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Alderman">Alderman</roleName> <surname>Villalongs</surname></persName>, a very weak disciple and wealthy; <persName n="Lippman,Alderman,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00012" reg="mostcommon:Lippman,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Alderman">Alderman</roleName> <surname>Lippman</surname></persName>, speculator; <persName n="Mills,,L.,G.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00013" reg="default:Mills,L.,G.,,"><foreName>L.</foreName> <foreName>G.</foreName> <surname>Mills</surname></persName>, who gave up the fight and cried &#x0022;hold, enough!&#x0022; ere it began; <persName n="Duggan,,Martin,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00014" reg="default:Duggan,Martin,,,"><foreName>Martin</foreName> <surname>Duggan</surname></persName> and <persName n="O'Byrne,Alderman,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00015" reg="mostcommon:O'Byrne,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Alderman">Alderman</roleName> <surname>O'Byrne</surname></persName>, famous only for the facility with which they changed <num value="1">one</num> flag to another; <persName n="Weed,,W.,D.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00016" reg="default:Weed,W.,D.,,"><foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>D.</foreName> <surname>Weed</surname></persName>, a coarse, unmannered <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs>, who sent his sons and his money to <placeName key="tgn,1000003" n="1.000 139" reg="europe,">Europe</placeName> at the beginning of the war, and <persName n="Lachlison,Alderman,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00017" reg="mostcommon:Lachlison,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Alderman">Alderman</roleName> <surname>Lachlison</surname></persName>, &#x0022;a canny Scotchman, who has, by his unguarded act, caused the blush of shame to mantle the cheek of his &#x0022;brave braw ladies,&#x0022; complete the roll of &#x0022;falling-back&#x0022; patriots and heroes. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="80"/> We wish <persName n="Sherman,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00018" reg="mostcommon:Sherman,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Sherman</surname></persName> joy of these accessions.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="81"/>We can promise him heavy reinforcements from the same classes in every Confederate city which it may be his felicity to occupy.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="82"/>The speculators and extortioners, the men who have been growing rich by this war, while their sons and brothers have fought its battles, will hasten to his standard wherever he advances.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="83"/>These penitent sinners will fling themselves on their knees as soon as he comes in sight, each <num value="1">one</num> bawling &#x0022;<hi rend="italics">Peccavi,</hi>&#x0022; singing <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> Doodle at the top of his voice, and wiping their streaming eyes with the <orgName n="Star Spangled Banner" type="newspaper">Star-Spangled Banner</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="84"/>It would be a blessing to the <rs>Confederacy</rs> if they could all be massed into solid column, and double-quicked into his lines to the tune of the <rs>Rogue</rs>'s March.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="85"/>They have done more harm to the <rs>Confederacy</rs> than he and all other generals of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> combined.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="86"/>They have impoverished and eaten out the substance of the land, and provoked the judgments of Heaven upon our cause.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="87"/>It would have been better for us to-day if they had all joined the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> before the war. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head rend="italics">Religious duties of masters to slaves.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="88"/> The <rs n="Protestant" type="religion">Protestant</rs> and <rs n="Catholic" type="religion">Catholic</rs> clergy of the <rs>Confederacy</rs> are calling attention to the duty of enforcing the sanctity of the marriage relation among slaves.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="89"/>The <orgName n="Georgia Baptist Convention" type="convention">Baptist Convention of Georgia</orgName> has adopted an emphatic resolution upon this subject.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="90"/>The <hi rend="italics"><orgName n="Southern Churchman" type="newspaper">Southern Churchman</orgName> </hi> quotes various religious authorities, setting forth the sinfulness of any neglect by masters of this <name>Christian</name> duty; among them <persName n="Verot,Bishop,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00019" reg="mostcommon:Verot,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Bishop">Bishop</roleName> <surname>Verot</surname></persName>, (<rs n="Roman Catholic" type="religion">Roman Catholic</rs> <rs type="role" reg="Bishop">Bishop</rs> of <placeName reg="Savannah, Chatham, Georgia" key="tgn,7014487">Savannah</placeName>,) who says: <q>&#x0022;Slavery, to become a permanent institution of the <rs>South</rs>, must be made to conform to the law of <name n="God" type="God">God</name>; a <orgName n="Southern Confederacy" type="newspaper">Southern Confederacy</orgName> will never thrive unless it rests upon morality and order; the <rs>Supreme Arbiter</rs> of Nations will not bless with stability and prosperity a state of things which would be a flagrant violation of His holy commandments.&#x0022;</q> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="91"/> Privateers, it appears, will occasionally slip from the <rs>English</rs> ports, and go forth to harass and devastate what <persName n="Semmes,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00020" reg="mostcommon:Semmes,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Captain</roleName> <surname>Semmes</surname></persName> has left of <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> commerce on the ocean.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="92"/>We chronicled some days ago <num value="1">one</num> of these unavoidable escapes, and learn from the <rs>English</rs> newspapers that it is next to impossible to prevent such things.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="93"/>The statutes of Parliament have many loopholes, and the vigilance of the police requires a little nap at times.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="94"/>Hence, it is next to impossible always to stop the egress of these pestilent vermin.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="95"/>Once in a while, the furtive rogues will be caught in the act, and handed over to the Old Bailey.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="96"/>But the highways of travel are very much infested by these little pickpockets; and honest <rs n="American" type="group">American</rs> gentlemen, who were never given to such practices, and are daily losing gold watches and pocketbooks, begin to consider the exemplary <persName n="Bull,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00021" reg="mostcommon:Bull,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Bull</surname></persName> little better than an Old Fagin, who trains up Artful <persName n="Dodgers,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00022" reg="mostcommon:Dodgers,nomatch:0"><surname>Dodgers</surname></persName> to prey upon the community. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="97"/> It is in vain that excellent soul denies the soft impeachment.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="98"/>He is very indignant that such crimes should be committed, and shocked to be suspected of complicity therewith.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="99"/>If there is any <milestone unit="column" n="5"/> thing that he does pride himself upon, it is good faith and fair play.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="100"/>These are his traditional, immemorial virtues.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="101"/>To be robbed of his good name is a worse affliction than the loss of <rs n="pocket books" type="product">pocket books</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="102"/>We condole with honest <persName><foreName>John</foreName></persName> in his tribulations.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="103"/>This is an uncharitable world. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head rend="italics">The fall of <placeName key="tgn,6002050" n="1.000 164" reg="fort fisher, new hanover, north carolina">Fort Fisher</placeName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="104"/>The facts about the fall of <placeName key="tgn,6002050" n="1.000 164" reg="fort fisher, new hanover, north carolina">Fort Fisher</placeName> are gradually coming to light.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="105"/>The <orgName n="Raleigh Confederate" type="newspaper">Raleigh <hi rend="italics">Confederate</hi></orgName> publishes the following statement from a gentleman who, it says, is as accurately informed concerning the affair as any <num value="1">one</num> else: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="106"/> &#x0022;The movement of the enemy was sudden, as we all know.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="107"/>After the previous failure it was not anticipated that so quick a repetition of the effort would be made.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="108"/><persName n="Hoke,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00023" reg="mostcommon:Hoke,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Hoke</surname></persName> had been withdrawn towards <placeName reg="Wilmington, New Hanover, North Carolina" key="tgn,7014631">Wilmington</placeName>, or above it. On <dateStruct><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct>, <persName n="McMillan,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00024" reg="mostcommon:McMillan,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">a Mr.</roleName> <surname>McMillan</surname></persName>--as our informant heard &mdash; discovered, from near <placeName reg="Topsail Sound, Pender, North Carolina" key="tgn,2725657">Topsail sound</placeName>, the approach of the enemy, and sought to communicate by telegraph to <persName n="Bragg,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00025" reg="mostcommon:Bragg,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Bragg</surname></persName> the fact; but the operator was not in a condition to send the dispatch, and it became necessary to transmit the news by a messenger.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="109"/>In <measure n="2hours" type="date">two hours</measure> after the intelligence was received, <persName n="Hoke,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00026" reg="mostcommon:Hoke,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Hoke</surname></persName> was on the march to confront the enemy at his point of landing. </p> </q><bibl n="The Raleigh Confederate"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="110"/> On <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct>, the enemy landed, under cover of his fleet, near battery <persName n="Gatlin,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00027" reg="mostcommon:Gatlin,nomatch:0"><surname>Gatlin</surname></persName>, about <placeName><distance reg="9miles">nine miles</distance> from <placeName key="tgn,6002050" n="1.000 164" reg="fort fisher, new hanover, north carolina">Fort Fisher</placeName></placeName>.--While he was landing, <persName n="Hoke,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00028" reg="mostcommon:Hoke,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Hoke</surname></persName> appeared and drew up in line parallel, to watch his movements, and intercept them when possible to do so. It was not possible to prevent the landing, owing to the situation of the point chosen.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="111"/>The enemy landed on the banks, just above the neck of the sound, thus interposing a small surface of water between them and an attacking force; or compelling such force to circle around the lower extreme of the sound &mdash; either of which movements would have to be done under the fire of the whole fleet. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="112"/> When <persName n="Hoke,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00029" reg="mostcommon:Hoke,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Hoke</surname></persName> found this to be the situation, he established a line facing the sea, and threw out what cavalry he required (if he had it) on his right flank, towards <orgName n="Battery Anderson" type="battery">Battery Anderson</orgName>, which was down the beach, towards <placeName key="tgn,6002050" n="1.000 164" reg="fort fisher, new hanover, north carolina">Fort Fisher</placeName>, about <measure n="4miles" type="distance">four miles</measure>. The intervening country here is broken; and the low places are grown up with thick bushes, and are marshy.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="113"/>The purpose of this cavalry was to observe the movements, and give the signal of the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> advance of the enemy towards establishing a line across the neck of land to the river, it being the order and purpose of <persName n="Bragg,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00030" reg="mostcommon:Bragg,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Bragg</surname></persName> to have <persName n="Hoke,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00031" reg="mostcommon:Hoke,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Hoke</surname></persName> attack him as soon as he advanced.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="114"/>In this condition matters rested until <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time>. During the night the enemy, passing between the cavalry, and threading their way through the thick, marshy undergrowth, made their way to the river, and on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> <time>morning</time> <persName n="Hoke,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00032" reg="mostcommon:Hoke,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Hoke</surname></persName> found an entrenched line on his right flank, extending across the peninsula, from the sea to, or near to, the river.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="115"/>He succeeded, however, in maintaining his base at <placeName key="possibilities=106" n="1.000 10" reg=",">Sugarloaf</placeName>, immediately changed his line, and informed <persName n="Bragg,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00033" reg="mostcommon:Bragg,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Bragg</surname></persName> of the <hi rend="italics">status.</hi> Then <persName n="Bragg,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00034" reg="mostcommon:Bragg,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Bragg</surname></persName> gave the order to charge the enemy in their works.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="116"/>In the meantime, <persName n="Hoke,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00035" reg="mostcommon:Hoke,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Hoke</surname></persName> had made a close reconnaissance, under the fire of the enemy, and discovered the strength of their force and position.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="117"/>On receiving the order to charge, he communicated the result of his observations, and asked <persName n="Bragg,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00036" reg="mostcommon:Bragg,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Bragg</surname></persName> to reconnoitre in person, which he did; and both of these officers concurred that it was not proper to assault the lines.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="118"/>It was then determined to reinforce the fort; and steps were taken which, but for a natural, but, as far as we can see, unblamable miscarriage, ought to have succeeded, failed to a great extent.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="119"/>By this time, the enemy, <num value="4000">four thousand</num> strong, were secure behind their works; and the fleet proceeded to bombard <placeName key="tgn,6002050" n="1.000 164" reg="fort fisher, new hanover, north carolina">Fort Fisher</placeName>, which was done uninterruptedly until Sunday about <time value="6pm">6 P. M.</time> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="120"/> On <dateStruct><day type="name">Sunday</day></dateStruct>, the column of assault, numbering about <num value="4000">four thousand</num>, moved from the enemy's lines, and as they advanced, they were plainly visible from <placeName key="tgn,6002050" n="1.000 164" reg="fort fisher, new hanover, north carolina">Fort Fisher</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="121"/>But her beleaguered garrison was kept close confined within the bomb proofs, by the concentrated and continued fire of <num value="700">seven hundred</num> guns pouring torrents of shells and missiles on every spot.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="122"/>On the land side of <placeName key="tgn,6002050" n="1.000 164" reg="fort fisher, new hanover, north carolina">Fort Fisher</placeName>, we had <num value="17">seventeen</num> guns &mdash; sufficient, could they have been used, to make it impossible that any force could have advanced under their fire.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="123"/>But, as the line of assailants got nearer to the fort, the whole fleet concentrated the fire, in ricochet shot, on the land side, and speedily dismounted every gun; and this unintermittent &#x0022;<foreign lang="fre"> <hi rend="italics">fou d'enfor</hi></foreign>&#x0022;--or, in plain <persName n="English,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00037" reg="mostcommon:English,nomatch:0"><surname>English</surname></persName>, <hi rend="italics">hell fire</hi>--was kept up until the enemy's line was in <measure n="60yards" type="distance">sixty yards</measure> of the works.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="124"/>Then it ceased, and with a rush and yell the charge was made.--<persName n="Braddy,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00038" reg="mostcommon:Braddy,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Captain</roleName> <surname>Braddy</surname></persName>, it is said, commanded the company guarding the sally-port.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="125"/>On him the hope of the garrison bung to keep the assailants out until the men and officers, who had been packed in the bomb proofs for <measure n="56hours" type="date">fifty-six hours</measure>, could get out and make ready.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="126"/>Instead of making defence, this officer and his command, it is said, surrendered, and the enemy entered the open gate.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="127"/>Our men <milestone unit="column" n="6"/> were benumbed and exhausted, and the thing was the work of a moment.--They were obliged to fall back in order to rally.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="128"/><persName n="Lamb,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00039" reg="mostcommon:Lamb,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Colonel</roleName> <surname>Lamb</surname></persName>, with that cool precision which distinguishes him as an officer of great merit, brought his men into line near headquarters, <persName n="Whiting,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00040" reg="mostcommon:Whiting,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Whiting</surname></persName> being present, encouraging and cheering on the troops and creating enthusiasm by his ardent and whole-souled heroism.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="129"/>Under these inspiring influences, our men were brought to the charge.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="130"/>The numbers were against them in the proportion of <num value="4000">four thousand</num>, aided by <num value="2000">two thousand</num> marines, to <num value="2000">two thousand</num>, but they forced the enemy back to the mound, and a hand-to-hand fight, of unmitigated desperation and fury, ensued, continuing from <num value="7">seven</num> to about <time value="10oclock">ten o'clock</time>, when bravery, endurance and devotion failed to overcome numbers.--Our men were overpowered, and the work of assault was accomplished; but not until the enemy had paid dearly for his prize.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="131"/>He had not lost a man until he entered the fort. </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="official"> 
<head>Official.</head> 
<div3 type="orders" n="1"> 
<head><hi rend="smallcaps">Treasury Departments,</hi><lb/><hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States of America</placeName>.,</hi><lb/><placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 11" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName>, <dateStruct value="1865-01-02"><month reg="01">January</month> <day reg="2">2</day>, <year reg="1865">1865</year></dateStruct>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="132"/>Notice to Holders and Owners of <num value="0.06">Six Per Cent.</num> Non-Taxable Certificates of Indebtedness, issued under the <orgName type="regiment" key="14Section">Fourteenth section</orgName> of act of <dateStruct value="1864-02-17"><month reg="02">February</month> <day reg="17">17</day>, <year reg="1864">1864</year></dateStruct>.--Notice is hereby given to holders and owners of <num value="0.06">Six Per Cent.</num> non-Taxable Certificates of Indebtedness, issued under the <orgName type="regiment" key="14Section">fourteenth section</orgName> of the act of <dateStruct value="1864-02-17"><month reg="02">February</month> <day reg="17">17</day>, <year reg="1864">1864</year></dateStruct>, that the interest due on the same to <dateStruct value="1865-01-1"><day reg="1">1st</day> <month reg="01">January</month>, <year>1865</year>,</dateStruct> will be paid upon presentation of the bonds at any time after <dateStruct value="-01-1"><day reg="1">1st</day> <month reg="01">January</month></dateStruct> to the <rs>Treasurer</rs>, <rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Treasurer">Assistant Treasurer</rs> or Pay Depositaries named below. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Trenholm,,G.,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00041" reg="default:Trenholm,G.,A.,,"><foreName>G.</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName>  <surname>Trenholm</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <signed><rs type="role" reg="Secretary of the Treasury">Secretary of Treasury</rs>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>Treasurer at <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Virginia</placeName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed><rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Treasurer">Assistant Treasurers</rs> at <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName> and <placeName reg="Mobile, Mobile, Alabama" key="tgn,7017444">Mobile</placeName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>Depositaries at <placeName reg="Raleigh, Wake, North Carolina" key="tgn,7013949">Raleigh</placeName> and <placeName reg="Wilmington, New Hanover, North Carolina" key="tgn,7014631">Wilmington, North Carolina</placeName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>Depositaries at <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName> and <placeName reg="Columbia, Richland, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013641">Columbia, South Carolina</placeName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>Depositaries at <placeName reg="Savannah, Chatham, Georgia" key="tgn,7014487">Savannah</placeName> and <placeName reg="Augusta, Richmond, Georgia" key="tgn,7017498">Augusta, Georgia</placeName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>Depositaries at <placeName reg="Tallahassee, Leon, Florida" key="tgn,7013938">Tallahassee, Florida</placeName>, and <placeName reg="Montgomery, Montgomery, Alabama" key="tgn,7013928">Montgomery, Alabama</placeName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>Depositaries at <placeName reg="Columbus, Lowndes, Mississippi" key="tgn,2056204">Columbus, Mississippi</placeName>, and <placeName reg="Houston, Harris, Texas" key="tgn,7013727">Houston</placeName> and <placeName reg="Marshall, Harrison, Texas" key="tgn,2105926">Marshall, Texas</placeName>.</signed> <term type="printrun">ja 6--Staw1m</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="133"/>Notice to Holders and Owners of <num value="0.04">four Per Cent.</num> <rs n="registered bond" type="product">Registered bonds</rs>, issued under act of <dateStruct value="1864-02-17"><month reg="02">February</month> <day reg="17">17</day>, <year reg="1864">1864</year></dateStruct>,--Notice is hereby given to holders and owners of <num value="0.04">four per cent</num> <rs n="registered bond" type="product">registered bonds</rs>, issued under act of <dateStruct value="1864-02-17"><month reg="02">February</month> <day reg="17">17</day>, <year reg="1864">1864</year></dateStruct>, that the interest due on the same to <dateStruct value="1865-01-1"><day reg="1">1st</day> <month reg="01">January</month>, <year>1865</year>,</dateStruct> will be paid upon presentation of the bonds, at any time after <num value="1" type="ordinal">1st</num> proximo; to the <rs>Treasurer</rs>, <rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Treasurer">Assistant Treasurers</rs> or Pay Depositaries named below.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="134"/>It is impracticable to prepare schedules for the payment of interest on these bonds, as the number and amount of those surrendered in payment of taxes have not been yet ascertained. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Trenholm,,G.,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00042" reg="default:Trenholm,G.,A.,,"><foreName>G.</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName>  <surname>Trenholm</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <signed><rs type="role" reg="Secretary of the Treasury">Secretary of Treasury</rs>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>Treasurer at <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Virginia</placeName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed><rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Treasurer">Assistant Treasurers</rs> at <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName> and <placeName reg="Mobile, Mobile, Alabama" key="tgn,7017444">Mobile</placeName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>Depositaries at <placeName reg="Raleigh, Wake, North Carolina" key="tgn,7013949">Raleigh</placeName> and <placeName reg="Wilmington, New Hanover, North Carolina" key="tgn,7014631">Wilmington, North Carolina</placeName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>Depositaries at <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName> and <placeName reg="Columbia, Richland, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013641">Columbia, South Carolina</placeName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>Depositaries at <placeName reg="Savannah, Chatham, Georgia" key="tgn,7014487">Savannah</placeName> and <placeName reg="Augusta, Richmond, Georgia" key="tgn,7017498">Augusta, Georgia</placeName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>Depositaries at <placeName reg="Tallahassee, Leon, Florida" key="tgn,7013938">Tallahassee, Florida</placeName>, and <placeName reg="Montgomery, Montgomery, Alabama" key="tgn,7013928">Montgomery, Alabama</placeName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>Depositaries at <placeName reg="Columbus, Lowndes, Mississippi" key="tgn,2056204">Columbus, Mississippi</placeName>, and <placeName reg="Houston, Harris, Texas" key="tgn,7013727">Houston</placeName> and <placeName reg="Marshall, Harrison, Texas" key="tgn,2105926">Marshall, Texas</placeName>.</signed> <term type="printrun">de 16--eod2m</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="3"> 
<head><hi rend="smallcaps"><orgName n="Treasury Department" type="department">Treasury Department</orgName>,</hi><lb/><hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Va.</placeName>,</hi><dateStruct value="1864-11-28"><month reg="11">November</month> <day reg="28">28</day>, <year reg="1864">1864</year></dateStruct>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="135"/>Notice is hereby given to Holders and Owners of Certificates of Stock and <rs n="coupon bond" type="product">Coupon bonds</rs>, issued under the act of <dateStruct value="1861-08-19"><month reg="08">August</month> <day reg="19">19</day>, <year reg="1861">1861</year></dateStruct>, redeemable after the <dateStruct value="1865-01-1"><day reg="1">1st</day> day of <month reg="01">January</month>, <year>1865</year>,</dateStruct> to present the same for payment on the <dateStruct value="-01-2"><day reg="2">Second</day> day of <month reg="01">January</month></dateStruct> Next, or at any time thereafter, to the <rs>Treasurer</rs> of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName>, <num value="1">one</num> of the <rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Treasurer">Assistant Treasurers</rs> of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName>, or a Pay Depositary of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName>, funds having been placed in the hands of said agents for the purpose of redeeming such stock and <rs n="coupon bond" type="product">coupon bonds</rs>.--No interest will be allowed on such stock and <rs n="coupon bond" type="product">coupon bonds</rs> after <dateStruct value="1865-01-01"><month reg="01">January</month> <day reg="1">1st</day>, <year reg="1865">1865</year></dateStruct>. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Trenholm,,G.,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00043" reg="default:Trenholm,G.,A.,,"><foreName>G.</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName>  <surname>Trenholm</surname></persName>.</signed> <term type="printrun">de 7--eod2m</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="4"> 
<head><hi rend="smallcaps"><orgName n="Treasury Department" type="department">Treasury Department</orgName>,</hi><lb/><hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States of America</placeName>,</hi><lb/><hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 11" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName>,</hi> <dateStruct value="1864-11-28"><month reg="11">November</month> <day reg="28">28</day>, <year reg="1864">1864</year></dateStruct>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="136"/>The Holders and Owners of <rs n="coupon bond" type="product">Coupon bonds</rs> and Certificates of Stock issued under the act of <dateStruct value="1861-08-19"><month reg="08">August</month> <day reg="19">19th</day>, <year reg="1861">1861</year></dateStruct>, redeemable after the <num value="1" type="ordinal">1st</num> days of <dateStruct value="1864-01-"><month reg="01">January</month></dateStruct> and <dateStruct value="1864-07-"><month reg="07">July</month>, <year reg="1864">1864</year></dateStruct>, are hereby notified to present the same for payment to the <rs>Treasurer</rs>, <num value="1">one</num> of the <rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Treasurer">Assistant Treasurers</rs>, or a Pay Depositary of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName>, funds having been placed in the hands of those officers for the purpose of redeeming said bonds and stock.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="137"/>No interest will be allowed thereon after <dateStruct value="1865-01-01"><month reg="01">January</month> <day reg="1">1st</day>, <year reg="1865">1865</year></dateStruct>. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Trenholm,,G.,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00044" reg="default:Trenholm,G.,A.,,"><foreName>G.</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName>  <surname>Trenholm</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <signed><rs type="role" reg="Secretary of the Treasury">Secretary of Treasury</rs>.</signed> <term type="printrun">de 7--eod2m</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="138"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> <milestone unit="page" n="2"/> 
<div1 type="page-image"> 
<head></head> 
<p><figure entity="NW_RichTimesD_028_025_002"> <figDesc>Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume <num value="28">28</num>, <num value="25">Number 25</num>, <ref n="page 2">page 2</ref>. </figDesc> </figure></p> </div1> <milestone unit="column" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="139"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.</head> 
<div2 type="morning"> 
<head><date value="1865-01-30">Monday morning.........January 30, 1865.</date></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head rend="italics"><orgName n="Confederate Congress" type="Congress">Confederate Congress</orgName>.</head> 
<div4 type="entry" n="1"> 
<head>Senate.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="140"/> <hi rend="smallcaps"><dateStruct><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct>,</hi> <date value="1865-01-28">January 28, 1865.</date> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="141"/> Prayer by <persName n="Burrows,Reverend,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00045" reg="mostcommon:Burrows,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Reverend">the Rev. Dr.</roleName> <surname>Burrows</surname></persName>, of the <orgName n="Baptist Church" type="church">Baptist Church</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="142"/> <persName n="Butler,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00046" reg="mostcommon:Butler,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Butler</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Florida" key="tgn,7007240">Florida</placeName>, offered a resolution of concurrence that Congress be adjourned on the <date value="02-20">20th of February</date> next.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="143"/>Laid over for further consideration. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="144"/> <persName n="Wigfall,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00047" reg="mostcommon:Wigfall,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Wigfall</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Texas" key="tgn,7007826">Texas</placeName>, introduced a bill to provide that certain evidences of debt, viz., all receipts, certified accounts, and other evidences of the value of property purchased or impressed for the use of the <rs>Government</rs>, which have been, or shall hereafter be, received from the impressing officer or agent, shall be receivable in payment of taxes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="145"/>The bill was referred to the <orgName n="Finance Committee" type="committee">Finance Committee</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="146"/> <persName n="Semmes,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00048" reg="mostcommon:Semmes,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Semmes</surname></persName> introduced a bill to extend and continue in force till the <date value="1866-06-10"> 10th of June, 1866,</date> the &#x0022;act to graduate the pay of general officers,&#x0022; approved <date value="1864-06-10">10th of June, 1864.</date> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="147"/> The following message of the <rs>President</rs>, returning, with his objections, Senate bill to authorize newspapers to be mailed to soldiers free of postage, was taken up and considered: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="148"/> <hi rend="italics">&#x0022;To the <orgName n="Confederate States Senate" type="senate">Senate of the Confederate States of <placeName reg="America, Walker, Alabama" key="tgn,2002460">America</placeName></orgName>:</hi> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="149"/> &#x0022;I return to your honorable body, without my approval, an act which originated in the <name>Senate</name>, entitled &#x0027;an act to authorize newspapers to be mailed to soldiers free of postage.&#x0027; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="150"/> &#x0022;The act provides &#x0027;that all newspapers mailed to any officer, musician or private, engaged in the actual service of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName>, may be transmitted through the mails free of postage.&#x0027; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="151"/> &#x0022;The Constitution (article <num value="1">1</num>, section <num value="3">3</num>, clause <num value="7">7</num>,) gives power to Congress &#x0027;to establish post-offices and post-routes; but the expenses of the <orgName n="Post Office Department" type="department">Post-office Department</orgName> after the <dateStruct value="-03-1"><day reg="1">first</day> day of <month reg="03">March</month></dateStruct>, <dateStruct value="1863--">in the year of our Lord <year reg="1863">eighteen hundred and sixty-three</year></dateStruct>, shall be paid out of its own revenues.&#x0027; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="152"/> &#x0022;This provision that the <orgName n="Post Office Department" type="department">Post-office Department</orgName> shall be self-sustaining was not contained in the <rs>Constitution</rs> of our former government.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="153"/>It is important that its spirit and object should be correctly determined now, because many members of the present Congress were also members of the <orgName n="Provisional Congress" type="congress">Provisional Congress</orgName> which adopted this new clause, and legislation by them will be deemed hereafter to possess peculiar value as a precedent and as a contemporaneous interpretation of the <rs>Constitution</rs> by those best acquainted with its meaning. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="154"/> &#x0022;It was generally understood that the clause under consideration was intended by its framers to correct what was deemed to be <num value="2">two</num> great vices that had been developed in the postal system of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="155"/>The <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> was, the injustice of taxing the whole people for the expense of the mail facilities afforded to individuals, and the remedy devised was to limit the <rs>Government</rs> to the furnishing of the machinery for carrying the mails, and compelling those who might use the facilities thus furnished to pay the expense thereof. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="156"/> &#x0022;The <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> evil, against which this clause was intended as a safeguard, was the wasteful extravagance which grew out of its franking privilege, with its attendant abuses of large contracts for stationery, printing, binding, etc., and increased Government patronage, with its train of corrupting influences. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="157"/> &#x0022;With this knowledge of the purpose of the framers of the <rs>Constitution</rs>, and of the evils against which they intended to provide by the clause under consideration, I cannot escape the conclusion, that to authorize the transmission of any mail matter free of postage is to violate the true intent and meaning of the <rs>Constitution</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="158"/> &#x0022;If the act now before me should become a law, the <rs type="role" reg="Postmaster General">Postmaster-General</rs> would be bound to pay railroads and other carriers for conveying newspapers to the armies without reimbursement from any source whatever.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="159"/>He could not be paid out of the general treasury without a violation of the letter of the <rs>Constitution</rs>; nor out of the other revenues of his department without, in effect, imposing on those who pay for carrying their own correspondence an additional charge to defray the cost of carrying newspapers for others. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="160"/> &#x0022;If it be competent for Congress, under this clause, to order newspapers to be carried free of postage, the power exists to order the free transmission of any other mail matter.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="161"/>But we must ever remember that Congress can exercise no implied powers &mdash; certainly none not necessary to carry into effect the powers expressly granted; and where shall we find in the <rs>Constitution</rs> any power in the <orgName n="Confederate Government" type="org">Confederate Government</orgName>, express or implied, for dividing either the people or the public servants into classes unequally burthened with postal charges? </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="162"/> &#x0022;In that part of the <rs>Constitution</rs> which specially treats of the burthen of taxation, every precaution has been taken to secure uniformity and to guard against bounties or preferences of any kind, and although not directly applicable to the subject of postage, the spirit of the whole provision is so opposed to inequality in legislation that the passage may well serve for illustration.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="163"/>The <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> clause of article <num value="1">1</num>, section <num value="3">3</num>, gives to Congress the power &#x0027;to lay and collect duties, imposts and excises for revenue necessary to pay the debts, provide for the common defence, and carry on the <rs>Government</rs> of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName>; but no bounties shall be granted from the <name>Treasury</name>; nor shall any duties or taxes on importations from foreign nations be laid to promote or foster any branch of industry; and all duties, imposts and excises shall be uniform throughout the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName>.&#x0027; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="164"/> &#x0022;It is true that the payment of postage is not properly a tax, but compensation for service rendered; yet it would scarcely be ingenuous to deny that so to regulate the rates of postage as to produce an excess of receipts over expenses of carrying mail matter for <num value="1">one</num> class, and to use this excess in order to carry, free of cost, the mail matter for another class, would strongly conflict with the just equality of privileges and burthens which the above-cited clauses were designed to secure. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="165"/> &#x0022;I regret to be compelled to object to a measure devised by Congress for the benefit or relief of the army, but with my convictions on the subject, it is not possible to approve the act now before me. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="166"/> &#x0022;<hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Davis,,Jefferson,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00049" reg="default:Davis,Jefferson,,,"><foreName>Jefferson</foreName> <surname>Davis</surname></persName>.</hi> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="167"/> &#x0022;<placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Virginia</placeName>, <dateStruct value="1865-01-25"><month reg="01">January</month> <day reg="25">25</day>, <year reg="1865">1865</year></dateStruct>.&#x0022; </p> </q><bibl n="The President"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="168"/> After debate, the vote being taken whether the bill should pass notwithstanding the objections of the <rs>President</rs>, it was decided in the affirmative &mdash; yeas, <num value="13">13</num>; nays, <num value="4">4</num>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="169"/> Those who voted in the affirmative were: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="170"/> <persName n="Baker,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00050" reg="mostcommon:Baker,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Messrs.</roleName> <surname>Baker</surname></persName>, <persName n="Caperton,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00051" reg="mostcommon:Caperton,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Caperton</surname></persName>, <persName n="Garland,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00052" reg="mostcommon:Garland,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Garland</surname></persName>, <persName n="Graham,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00053" reg="mostcommon:Graham,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Graham</surname></persName>, <persName n="Haynes,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00054" reg="mostcommon:Haynes,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Haynes</surname></persName>, <persName n="Henry,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00055" reg="mostcommon:Henry,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Henry</surname></persName>, <persName n="Maxwell,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00056" reg="mostcommon:Maxwell,Robert,,,:1"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Maxwell</surname></persName>, <persName n="Oldham,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00057" reg="mostcommon:Oldham,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Oldham</surname></persName>, <persName n="Semmes,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00058" reg="mostcommon:Semmes,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Semmes</surname></persName>, <persName n="Simms,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00059" reg="mostcommon:Simms,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Simms</surname></persName>, <persName n="Walker,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00060" reg="mostcommon:Walker,Robert,S.,,:1"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Walker</surname></persName>, <persName n="Watson,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00061" reg="mostcommon:Watson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Watson</surname></persName> and <persName n="Wigfall,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00062" reg="mostcommon:Wigfall,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Wigfall</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="171"/> Those who voted in the negative were: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="172"/> <persName n="Brown,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00063" reg="mostcommon:Brown,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Messrs.</roleName> <surname>Brown</surname></persName>, <persName n="Burnett,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00064" reg="mostcommon:Burnett,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Burnett</surname></persName>, <persName n="Dortch,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00065" reg="mostcommon:Dortch,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Dortch</surname></persName> and <persName n="Sparrow,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00066" reg="mostcommon:Sparrow,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Sparrow</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="173"/> On motion, the <name>Senate</name> resolved into secret session. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="2"> 
<head><orgName n="House of Representatives" type="government">House of Representatives</orgName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="174"/> The <rs type="place">House</rs> met at <time value="11oclock">11 o'clock</time>. Prayer by <persName n="Tichenor,Reverend,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00067" reg="mostcommon:Tichenor,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Reverend">the Rev. Dr.</roleName> <surname>Tichenor</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="175"/> Leave of absence was granted <persName n="Lester,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00068" reg="mostcommon:Lester,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Messrs.</roleName> <surname>Lester</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Georgia" key="tgn,7007248">Georgia</placeName>; <persName n="Lamkin,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00069" reg="mostcommon:Lamkin,nomatch:0"><surname>Lamkin</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Mississippi" key="tgn,7007522">Mississippi</placeName>, and Shewmaker, of <placeName reg="Georgia" key="tgn,7007248">Georgia</placeName>, called home on important private business, and <persName n="Rives,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00070" reg="mostcommon:Rives,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Rives</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Virginia" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>, who is confined to his room by indisposition. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="176"/> The <rs type="place">House</rs> then resumed the consideration of the <name>Senate</name> bill &#x0022;to provide for the employment of free negroes and slaves to work upon fortifications and perform other labor connected with the defences of the country.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="177"/> [After the <rs type="place">House</rs> went into secret session <milestone unit="column" n="2"/> on yesterday, upon the consideration of this bill, </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="178"/> <persName n="Leach,Mister,J.,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00071" reg="default:Leach,J.,M.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>J.</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Leach</surname></persName> offered the following proviso to the <orgName type="regiment" key="3Section">third section</orgName>: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="179"/> &#x0022;<hi rend="italics">Provided further,</hi> That in no event shall any portion of said slaves or free negroes so impressed have arms placed in their hands, or be mustered into the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName> service, or be used at any time as soldiers in said service.&#x0022; </p> </q><bibl n="Mr. J. M. Leach"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="180"/> The proviso was laid on the table by the following vote: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="181"/> <hi rend="smallcaps">Ayes.</hi>--<persName n="Akin,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00072" reg="mostcommon:Akin,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Messrs.</roleName> <surname>Akin</surname></persName>, <persName n="Atkins,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00073" reg="mostcommon:Atkins,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Atkins</surname></persName>, <persName n="Baldwin,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00074" reg="mostcommon:Baldwin,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>, <persName n="Barksdale,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00075" reg="mostcommon:Barksdale,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Barksdale</surname></persName>, <persName n="Batson,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00076" reg="mostcommon:Batson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Batson</surname></persName>, <persName n="Baylor,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00077" reg="mostcommon:Baylor,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Baylor</surname></persName>, <persName n="Bell,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00078" reg="mostcommon:Bell,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Bell</surname></persName>, <persName n="Blandford,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00079" reg="mostcommon:Blandford,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Blandford</surname></persName>, <persName n="Branch,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00080" reg="mostcommon:Branch,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Branch</surname></persName>, <persName n="Bruce,Mister,E.,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00081" reg="default:Bruce,E.,M.,,"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><foreName>E.</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Bruce</surname></persName>, <persName n="Burnett,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00082" reg="mostcommon:Burnett,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Burnett</surname></persName>, <persName n="Carroll,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00083" reg="mostcommon:Carroll,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Carroll</surname></persName>, <persName n="Chilton,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00084" reg="mostcommon:Chilton,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Chilton</surname></persName>, <persName n="Clark,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00085" reg="mostcommon:Clark,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Clark</surname></persName>, <persName n="Clopton,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00086" reg="mostcommon:Clopton,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Clopton</surname></persName>, <persName n="Cluskey,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00087" reg="mostcommon:Cluskey,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Cluskey</surname></persName>, <persName n="Colyar,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00088" reg="mostcommon:Colyar,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Colyar</surname></persName>, <persName n="Conrow,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00089" reg="mostcommon:Conrow,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Conrow</surname></persName>, <persName n="Dickinson,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00090" reg="mostcommon:Dickinson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Dickinson</surname></persName>, <persName n="Dupre,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00091" reg="mostcommon:Dupre,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Dupre</surname></persName>, <persName n="Elliott,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00092" reg="mostcommon:Elliott,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Elliott</surname></persName>, <persName n="Ewing,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00093" reg="mostcommon:Ewing,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Ewing</surname></persName>, <persName n="Farrow,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00094" reg="mostcommon:Farrow,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Farrow</surname></persName>, <persName n="Gaither,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00095" reg="mostcommon:Gaither,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Gaither</surname></persName>, <persName n="Garland,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00096" reg="mostcommon:Garland,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Garland</surname></persName>, <persName n="Gholson,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00097" reg="mostcommon:Gholson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Gholson</surname></persName>, <persName n="Gray,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00098" reg="mostcommon:Gray,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Gray</surname></persName>, <persName n="Hatcher,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00099" reg="mostcommon:Hatcher,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Hatcher</surname></persName>, <persName n="Hilton,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00100" reg="mostcommon:Hilton,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Hilton</surname></persName>, <persName n="Holder,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00101" reg="mostcommon:Holder,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Holder</surname></persName>, <persName n="Johnston,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00102" reg="mostcommon:Johnston,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Johnston</surname></persName>, <persName n="Keeble,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00103" reg="mostcommon:Keeble,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Keeble</surname></persName>, <persName n="Lester,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00104" reg="mostcommon:Lester,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Lester</surname></persName>, <persName n="Lyon,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00105" reg="mostcommon:Lyon,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Lyon</surname></persName>, <persName n="Machen,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00106" reg="mostcommon:Machen,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Machen</surname></persName>, <persName n="Marshall,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00107" reg="mostcommon:Marshall,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Marshall</surname></persName>, <persName n="Menees,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00108" reg="mostcommon:Menees,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Menees</surname></persName>, <persName n="Miller,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00109" reg="mostcommon:Miller,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Miller</surname></persName>, <persName n="Moore,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00110" reg="mostcommon:Moore,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Moore</surname></persName>, <persName n="Norton,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00111" reg="mostcommon:Norton,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Norton</surname></persName>, <persName n="Read,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00112" reg="mostcommon:Read,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Read</surname></persName>, <persName n="Russell,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00113" reg="mostcommon:Russell,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Russell</surname></persName>, <persName n="Sexton,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00114" reg="mostcommon:Sexton,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Sexton</surname></persName>, <persName n="Shewmake,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00115" reg="mostcommon:Shewmake,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Shewmake</surname></persName>, <persName n="Simpson,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00116" reg="mostcommon:Simpson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Simpson</surname></persName>, <persName n="Snead,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00117" reg="mostcommon:Snead,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Snead</surname></persName>, <persName n="Triplett,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00118" reg="mostcommon:Triplett,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Triplett</surname></persName>, <persName n="Villere,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00119" reg="mostcommon:Villere,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Villere</surname></persName>, <persName n="Wilkes,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00120" reg="mostcommon:Wilkes,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Wilkes</surname></persName> and <persName n="Witherspoon,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00121" reg="mostcommon:Witherspoon,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Witherspoon</surname></persName>--<num value="50">50</num>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="182"/> <hi rend="smallcaps">Nats.</hi>--<persName n="Anderson,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00122" reg="mostcommon:Anderson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Messrs.</roleName> <surname>Anderson</surname></persName>, <persName n="Chambers,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00123" reg="mostcommon:Chambers,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Chambers</surname></persName>, <persName n="Cruikshank,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00124" reg="mostcommon:Cruikshank,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Cruikshank</surname></persName>, <persName n="Darden,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00125" reg="mostcommon:Darden,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Darden</surname></persName>, <persName n="Echols,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00126" reg="mostcommon:Echols,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Echols</surname></persName>, <persName n="Fuller,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00127" reg="mostcommon:Fuller,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Fuller</surname></persName>, <persName n="Gilmer,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00128" reg="mostcommon:Gilmer,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Gilmer</surname></persName>, <persName n="Goode,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00129" reg="mostcommon:Goode,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Goode</surname></persName>, <persName n="Herbert,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00130" reg="mostcommon:Herbert,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Herbert</surname></persName>, <persName n="Lamkin,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00131" reg="mostcommon:Lamkin,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Lamkin</surname></persName>, <persName n="Leach,Mister,J.,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00132" reg="default:Leach,J.,M.,,"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><foreName>J.</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Leach</surname></persName>, <persName n="Leach,Mister,J.,T.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00133" reg="default:Leach,J.,T.,,"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><foreName>J.</foreName> <foreName>T.</foreName> <surname>Leach</surname></persName>, <persName n="Logan,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00134" reg="mostcommon:Logan,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Logan</surname></persName>, <persName n="McMullin,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00135" reg="mostcommon:McMullin,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>McMullin</surname></persName>, <persName n="Miles,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00136" reg="mostcommon:Miles,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Miles</surname></persName>, <persName n="Orr,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00137" reg="mostcommon:Orr,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Orr</surname></persName>, <persName n="Ramsay,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00138" reg="mostcommon:Ramsay,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Ramsay</surname></persName>, <persName n="Smith,Mister,J.,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00139" reg="default:Smith,J.,M.,,"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><foreName>J.</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Smith</surname></persName>, <persName n="Smith,Mister,W.,E.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00140" reg="default:Smith,W.,E.,,"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>Smith</surname></persName>, <persName n="Smith,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00141" reg="nearbymention:Smith,W.,E.,,"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Smith</surname></persName> of <placeName reg="North Carolina" key="tgn,7007709">North Carolina</placeName>, <persName n="Turner,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00142" reg="mostcommon:Turner,nomatch:0"><surname>Turner</surname></persName>, <persName n="Wickham,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00143" reg="mostcommon:Wickham,nomatch:0"><surname>Wickham</surname></persName> and <rs type="role" reg="Mister Speaker">Mr. Speaker</rs>--<num value="23">23</num>.] </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="183"/> <persName n="Shewmake,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00144" reg="mostcommon:Shewmake,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Shewmake</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Georgia" key="tgn,7007248">Georgia</placeName>, moved to amend the <num value="3" type="ordinal">third</num> so as to provide that payment shall be made for any slaves who may die or be lost to their owners by reason of such employment, at valuations to be fixed under the <orgName type="regiment" key="1Section">first section</orgName> of an act to regulate impressments, passed <date value="1863-03-26">March 26, 1863,</date> which places the valuation under the control of vicinage boards.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="184"/>The amendment was adopted &mdash; ayes, <num value="43">43</num>; noes, <num value="22">22</num>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="185"/> <persName n="Colyar,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00145" reg="mostcommon:Colyar,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Colyar</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName>, moved to strike out the condition of the clause, which restricts the impressment to <num value="1">one</num> out of every <num value="5">five</num> male slaves of those employed in agricultural or mechanical pursuits, so that not more than <num value="1">one</num> out every <num value="5">five</num> male slaves within the ages of <num value="18">eighteen</num> and <num value="40">forty</num> shall be taken from any <num value="1">one</num> owner, irrespective of the employment in which such slaves are engaged. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="186"/> The amendment, after an animated debate, was adopted &mdash; yeas, <num value="50">50</num>; nays, <num value="24">24</num>, </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="187"/> <persName n="Miles,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00146" reg="mostcommon:Miles,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Miles</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="South Carolina" key="tgn,7007712">South Carolina</placeName>, in behalf of the <rs>Committee</rs> on Military Affairs, moved to strike out the clause exempting from impressment, under this act, such slaves in any locality, or of any person, who shall be exempted by the laws or regulations of any State from impressment to labor on the fortifications or other <orgName n="Public Works" type="works">public works of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName></orgName>, and to insert the following: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="188"/> &#x0022;But no such slaves shall be taken from any owner or estate where <num value="0.5">one-half</num> of the male slaves between the ages of <num value="18">eighteen</num> and <num value="40">forty</num>, belonging to such owner or estate, shall have absconded to the enemy, or been abducted by them.&#x0022; </p> </q><bibl n="Mr. Miles, of South Carolina"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="189"/> The motion was not agreed to &mdash; ayes, <num value="8">8</num>; noes, <num value="60">60</num>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="190"/> <persName n="Miles,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00147" reg="mostcommon:Miles,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Miles</surname></persName> thought it rather surprising that, although the <rs>Committee</rs> on Military Affairs had instructed him to move this amendment, but <num value="1">one</num> member of the committee had voted in favor of it. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="191"/> <persName n="Wickham,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00148" reg="mostcommon:Wickham,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Wickham</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> (a member of the <orgName n="Military Committee" type="committee">Military Committee</orgName>), stated that he had voted with the prevailing side in order to move a reconsideration of the vote by which the amendment was rejected. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="192"/> <persName n="Miles,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00149" reg="mostcommon:Miles,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Miles</surname></persName>.--That makes <num value="2">two</num> votes from the committee, I believe.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="193"/>I will now simply move to strike out the provision referred to, without offering anything in lieu thereof.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="194"/>I believe if this clause is retained we will get very few slaves under this act. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="195"/> The motion to strike out was adopted &mdash; ayes, <num value="35">35</num>; noes, <num value="29">29</num>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="196"/> The amendment of the committee striking out the proviso &#x0022;that if the <rs>Governor</rs> of any State shall certify to the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>, or the <rs type="role" reg="Commanding-General">Commanding General</rs> of the <orgName n="Department of Trans-Mississippi" type="department">Trans-Mississippi Department</orgName>, that slaves cannot be impressed in any locality in such State without great detriment to such locality, then the quota of said locality shall be impressed from other portions of such State,&#x0022; and inserting a provision &#x0022;that the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs> shall be authorized to exempt from the operations of this act any locality where, in his judgment, the labor of the slaves therein is indispensable to the production of grain and provisions for the support of soldiers' families and non producers in such locality; and the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs> may exempt from impressment slaves necessarily employed on works of internal improvement of importance to the common defence; but nothing contained in this proviso shall be construed to diminish the quota of slaves in any State authorized to be impressed under the provisions of this act,&#x0022; was rejected. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="197"/> <persName n="Fuller,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00150" reg="mostcommon:Fuller,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Fuller</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="North Carolina" key="tgn,7007709">North Carolina</placeName>; offered a proviso, to be inserted at the end of the <orgName type="regiment" key="4Section">fourth section</orgName>, declaring that each State shall receive credit in the quota to be impressed for the number of free negroes impressed in such State.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="198"/>Rejected. </p> 
<p> A proviso that the impressment shall only be made for <num value="1">one</num> year was defeated, and the bill was finally passed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="199"/>The bill, as amended and passed, reads as follows: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="200"/> &#x0022;A bill to provide for the employment of free negroes and slaves to work upon Fortifications and Perform other labor Connected with the <name>Defences</name> of the country. </p> 
<list type="ordered"> 
<head></head> 
<item n="1"> &#x0022;<hi rend="smallcaps">Section</hi> <num value="1">1</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="201"/>Whereas, the efficiency of the army is at times greatly diminished by the withdrawal from the ranks of soldiers to perform labor and duties which can as well be done by free negroes and slaves.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="202"/><lb/> &#x0022;<hi rend="italics">The <orgName n="Confederate States Congress" type="congress">Congress of the Confederate States of <placeName reg="America, Walker, Alabama" key="tgn,2002460">America</placeName></orgName> do rennet.</hi> That all free male negroes between the ages of <num value="18">eighteen</num> and <measure n="50years" type="date">fifty years</measure> shall be held liable to perform any labor or discharge any duties with the army, or in connection with the military defences of the country, such as working upon fortifications, producing and preparing materials of war, building and repairing roads and bridges, and doing other work usually done by engineer troops and pontoniers, acting as cooks, teamsters, stewards and waiters in military hospitals, or other like labor, or similar duties which may required or prescribed by the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs> or the <rs>General Commanding</rs> the <orgName n="Department of Trans-Mississippi" type="department">Trans-Mississippi Department</orgName>, from time to time.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="203"/>And said free negroes, whilst thus engaged, shall receive rations and clothing, under such regulations as the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs> may prescribe, and shall receive pay at the rate of <measure n="18dollars" type="currency">eighteen dollars</measure> per month.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="204"/></item> 
<item n="2"> &#x0022;<hi rend="smallcaps">Section</hi> <num value="2">2</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="205"/>That the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs> and the <rs>General Commanding</rs> the <orgName n="Department of Trans-Mississippi" type="department">Trans-Mississippi Department</orgName> are each authorized to employ, for duties like those named in the <orgName type="regiment" key="1Section">first section</orgName> of this act, as many male negro slaves between the ages of <num value="18">eighteen</num> and <measure n="40years" type="date">forty years</measure>, as the wants of the service may require.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="206"/>And the said slaves, whilst so employed, shall be furnished rations and clothing, as provided in the proceeding section, and the owners paid such hire for their services as may be agreed upon, not to exceed <measure n="18dollars" type="currency">eighteen dollars</measure> per month; and in the event <milestone unit="column" n="3"/> of the loss of any slaves whilst so employed, by the act of the enemy or by escape to the enemy, or by wounds or death inflicted by the enemy, or by disease contracted whilst in any service required of said slaves, and by reason of said service, then the owners thereof, respectively, shall be entitled to receive the full value of such slaves, to be ascertained and fixed by agreement at the time said slaves are so hired, under rules to be prescribed by the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>. </item> 
<item n="3"> &#x0022;<hi rend="smallcaps">Section</hi> <num value="3">3</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="207"/>That whenever the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>, or the <rs>General Commanding</rs> the <orgName n="Department of Trans-Mississippi" type="department">Trans-Mississippi Department</orgName>, shall be unable to procure the services of slaves by hiring them, as above provided, in sufficient numbers, then it shall be lawful for the said <rs>Secretary</rs> or General to order the impressment, and to impress as many male slaves within the ages named in the <orgName type="regiment" key="2Section">second section</orgName> of this act, and for the purposes and uses above stated, as the wants of the service may require; <hi rend="italics">Provided,</hi> That slaves so impressed shall, whilst in the <rs>Government</rs> employment, receive the same clothing and rations allowed to slaves hired from their owners, and in the event of their loss or death in the manner or from the causes above stated, their value shall be estimated and fixed as provided by the <orgName type="regiment" key="1Section">first section</orgName> of an act to regulate impressments, passed <date value="1863-03-20">March 20, 1863,</date> and paid as in the case of slaves hired from their owners, and the value of the hire of said slaves shall be fixed in like manner.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="208"/></item> 
<item n="4"> &#x0022;<hi rend="smallcaps">Section</hi> <num value="4">4</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="209"/>That the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs> and the <rs>General</rs> commanding the <orgName n="Department of Trans-Mississippi" type="department">Trans-Mississippi Department</orgName> shall, in ordering the impressment of slaves, regulate the same, as far as practicable, so that slaves shall be taken from each State in proportion to the whole number hired and impressed under this act, whether owned by citizens of such State or not, but not more than <num value="1">one</num> in every <num value="5">five</num> male slaves within the said ages of <num value="18">eighteen</num> and <measure n="40years" type="date">forty years</measure> shall be taken from any <num value="1">one</num> owner, nor where an owner has less than <num value="5">five</num> slaves shall said slaves be impressed, and all impressments under this act shall, as far as practicable, be taken in equal ratio from all owners in the same locality, city, county or district; <hi rend="italics">Provided, however,</hi> That nothing herein contained shall be so construed as to exempt any State from furnishing its fair quota of slaves for the purposes herein specified, and according to the provisions of this act: <hi rend="italics">Provided further,</hi> That in each case care be taken to allow each owner a credit for all male slaves between the ages aforesaid heretofore impressed, or impressed under this act, or hired to the <rs>Government</rs>, who are still in service, or who may have died or been lost while in service: <hi rend="italics">Provided further,</hi> That if the <rs>Governor</rs> of any State shall certify to the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>, or the <rs type="role" reg="Commanding-General">Commanding General</rs> of the <orgName n="Department of Trans-Mississippi" type="department">Trans-Mississippi Department</orgName>, that slaves cannot be impressed in any locality, county, district, parish or city in such State without great detriment to such locality, county, district, parish or city, and can be impressed without detriment in other portions of the <rs>State</rs>, then the quota of said locality, county, district, parish or city shall be impressed from other portions of such State.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="210"/></item> 
<item n="5"> &#x0022;<hi rend="smallcaps">Section</hi> <num value="5">5</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="211"/>If any slave is now held for service who is not liable thereto under the provisions of this act, such slave shall be forthwith returned to the owner on demand and proof of the fact.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="212"/></item> 
<item n="6"> &#x0022;<hi rend="smallcaps">Section</hi> <num value="6">6</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="213"/>Duplicate rolls shall be prepared of all the slaves hired or impressed under this act, which shall contain a description of the slaves, the names and residences of the owners; and a statement of the value and rate of hire of the slaves at the date they are hired or impressed, <num value="1">one</num> of which rolls shall, in the <name>States</name> east of the <placeName reg="Mississippi River" key="tgn,7022231">Mississippi river</placeName>, be forwarded to the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>, and in those west of the <placeName reg="Mississippi River" key="tgn,7022231">Mississippi river</placeName>, to the headquarters of the general commanding that department, and the other roll shall be sent to the general commanding the army where said slaves may be employed; and the officer having charge of said slaves, or of the work upon which they may be engaged, shall have a copy of said roll, and shall regularly enter thereon the nature of the labor or duties in which said slaves are engaged, and any changes which may be made therein, and of the absence, sickness or death of any of said slaves, and make monthly returns thereof to the general commanding the army where said slaves are employed, who shall transmit the same to the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs> or to the <rs type="role" reg="Commanding-General">Commanding General</rs> in the <orgName n="Department of Trans-Mississippi" type="department">Trans-Mississippi Department</orgName>, as the case may be. </item> 
<item n="7"> &#x0022;<hi rend="smallcaps">Section</hi> <num value="7">7</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="214"/>That all laws or parts of laws providing for the hiring or impressment of slaves be, and the same are hereby, repealed, except so far as they may provide for regulating and fixing, in case of impressment, the value of said slaves, or the value of their services.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="215"/></item> 
<item n="8"> &#x0022;<hi rend="smallcaps">Section</hi> <num value="8">8</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="216"/>No slaves shall be hereafter impressed except in pursuance of the provisions of this act; and any officer who may violate the provisions thereof shall be court-martialed, and, on conviction, cashiered.&#x0022; </item> </list> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="217"/> The <rs type="place">House</rs> then adjourned. </p> </div4> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head rend="italics"><orgName n="Virginia Legislature" type="legislature">Virginia Legislature</orgName>.</head> <byline>[extra session.]</byline> 
<div4 type="entry" n="1"> 
<head>Senate.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="218"/> <hi rend="smallcaps"><dateStruct><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct>,</hi> <date value="1865-01-28">January 28, 1865.</date> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="219"/> <persName n="Price,Lieutenant-Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00151" reg="mostcommon:Price,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lieutenant-Governor">Lieutenant-Governor</roleName> <surname>Price</surname></persName> called the <name>Senate</name> to order at <time value="12oclock">12 o'clock</time>. Prayer by <persName n="Burrows,Reverend-Doctor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00152" reg="mostcommon:Burrows,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Reverend-Doctor">Rev. Dr.</roleName> <surname>Burrows</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="220"/> A communication was read from the <orgName n="House of Delegates" type="government">House of Delegates</orgName>, announcing that they had agreed to the joint resolution relating to an additional track on the <orgName n="Piedmont Railroad" type="railroad">Piedmont railroad</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="221"/> <persName n="Collier,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00153" reg="mostcommon:Collier,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Collier</surname></persName>'s resolution, providing for the adjournment of the <name>Legislature</name> on the <date value="02-20">20th of February</date> to the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> Monday in <dateStruct value="-12-"><month reg="12">December</month></dateStruct>, was taken up and advocated by its patron. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="222"/> <persName n="Keen,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00154" reg="mostcommon:Keen,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Keen</surname></persName> regarded the resolution as premature, and moved that it be indefinitely postponed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="223"/>Agreed to. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="224"/> <persName n="Newlon,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00155" reg="mostcommon:Newlon,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Newlon</surname></persName>, from the <rs>Committee</rs> on Privileges and Elections, reported a bill to amend and re- enact an act entitled &#x0022;an act to prescribe the mode of ascertaining and <sic>certifiying </sic> elections of Delegates and <rs type="role2">Senators</rs> during the existing war,&#x0022; passed <date value="1863-03-24">March 24, 1863.</date> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="225"/> <persName n="Dulaney,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00156" reg="mostcommon:Dulaney,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Dulaney</surname></persName>, by leave, reported a bill to amend and re-enact the <orgName type="regiment" key="16Section">16th section</orgName> of chapter, <num value="179">179</num> of the <name>Code</name> of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>, in relation to receivers; which was agreed to. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="226"/> The resolutions adopted by the <placeName key="tgn,2069961" n="1.000 4" reg="jordan, onondaga, new york">Jordan</placeName> Battery, welcoming all the horrors of war in preference to peace on dishonorable terms, etc., offered by <persName n="Collier,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00157" reg="mostcommon:Collier,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Collier</surname></persName> some days since, were called up. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="227"/> They were read by the <rs>Clerk</rs>, and, on motion of <persName n="Frazier,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00158" reg="mostcommon:Frazier,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Frazier</surname></persName>, referred to the <rs>Committee</rs> on Confederate Relations. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="228"/> <persName n="Christian,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00159" reg="mostcommon:Christian,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Christian</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Augusta, Richmond, Georgia" key="tgn,7017498">Augusta</placeName>, called up the joint resolution relating to securing the use of the military maps of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> prepared by the <orgName n="Engineer Corps" type="corps">Engineer corps</orgName>, in order to perfect the map of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="229"/> <persName n="Tayloe,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00160" reg="mostcommon:Tayloe,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Tayloe</surname></persName>, of <persName><roleName n="King">King</roleName> <foreName>George</foreName></persName>, offered the following resolution as a substitute, which was accepted, and afterwards adopted: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="230"/> &#x0022;<hi rend="italics">Resolved, by the <orgName n="General Assembly" type="misc">General Assembly of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName></orgName>,</hi> That the <rs>Secretary</rs> of Commonwealth apply to the proper authorities of the <orgName n="Confederate Government" type="org">Confederate Government</orgName> for copies of the maps of the several counties of the <rs>State</rs> made under the direction of the <orgName n="Topographical Bureau" type="bureau">Topographical Bureau</orgName>, and procure the same for the purpose of constructing a complete map of the <placeName reg="Virginia" key="tgn,7007919">State of Virginia</placeName>.&#x0022; </p> </q><bibl n="Mr. Tayloe, of King George"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="231"/> <persName n="Hunter,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00161" reg="nearbymention:Hunter,R.,M.,T.,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Hunter</surname></persName> then called up the bill providing for an increase of compensation of the <rs>Judge</rs> of the <num value="13" type="ordinal">Thirteenth</num> Judicial Circuit, which was considered till the hour for going into secret session. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="2"> 
<head><orgName n="House of Delegates" type="government">House of Delegates</orgName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="232"/> The <rs type="place">House</rs> was called to order at <time value="12pm">noon</time>. Prayer by <persName n="Tennent,Reverend-Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00162" reg="mostcommon:Tennent,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Reverend-Mister">Rev. Mr.</roleName> <surname>Tennent</surname></persName>, of the <orgName n="Episcopal Church" type="church">Episcopal Church</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="233"/> The following bills were reported: A bill to incorporate the <rs>Petersburg Glass Company</rs>; a bill prohibiting <rs n="auction sales" type="product">auction sales</rs> in certain cases. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="234"/> <persName n="Deane,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00163" reg="mostcommon:Deane,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Deane</surname></persName> introduced a resolution inquiring what steps are necessary to secure <milestone unit="column" n="4"/> the payment of claims due <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> by the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="235"/> <persName n="White,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00164" reg="mostcommon:White,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>White</surname></persName> submitted a resolution that it be entrusted to the <rs>Joint Committee</rs> on Salt to inquire into the conduct of the <rs>Superintendent</rs> of Salt for his failure to supply the quota of salt to the respective counties of the <rs>State</rs>; and that the committee have power to send for persons and papers. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="236"/> <persName n="Magruder,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00165" reg="mostcommon:Magruder,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Magruder</surname></persName> brought forward a resolution looking to the introduction of a bill to enlarge the appropriation to the <orgName n="University of Virginia" type="university">University of Virginia</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="237"/> <persName n="Butler,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00166" reg="mostcommon:Butler,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Butler</surname></persName> introduced a resolution changing the hour for the meeting of the <rs type="place">House</rs> from <time value="12mid">12 M.</time> to <time value="11am">11 A. M.</time>, which was adopted. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="238"/> <persName n="Irving,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00167" reg="mostcommon:Irving,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Irving</surname></persName> submitted a resolution instructing the <rs>Committee</rs> on the <name>Penitentiary</name> to inquire and report how many pairs of shoes and other garments can be furnished in <measure n="12months" type="date">twelve months</measure> by the workshops of the penitentiary; and also, how far the resources of the institution can be made available and applied to the clothing of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> troops in the field. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="239"/> The consideration of the unfinished business of <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct>--the bill amending the law creating a commercial agency for the <placeName reg="Virginia" key="tgn,7007919">State of Virginia</placeName>--was then resumed, and continued to the hour of <time value="1oclock">1 o'clock</time>, when the <rs type="place">House</rs> went into secret session for the consideration of business on the secret calendar. </p> </div4> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head rend="italics">Interesting foreign news.</head> 
<div4 type="entry" n="1"> 
<head>The <dateStruct value="-01-01"><occasion>New year's</occasion></dateStruct> Speech of <persName n="Napoleon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00168" reg="mostcommon:Napoleon,nomatch:0"><surname>Napoleon</surname></persName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="240"/> A <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> <persName n="Paris,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00169" reg="mostcommon:Paris,nomatch:0"><surname>Paris</surname></persName> correspondent says: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="241"/><rs type="role" reg="Emperor">The Emperor</rs> said nothing in the few remarks which he made to each member of the <hi rend="italics">corpe diplomatique</hi> at New Year which, in the slightest degree, indicated the policy he intended adopting upon any particular question. </p> </q><bibl n="A Yankee Paris correspondent"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="242"/> To <persName n="Pennington,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00170" reg="mostcommon:Pennington,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Pennington</surname></persName>, our <hi rend="italics">charge d'affaires,</hi> the <rs>Emperor</rs> expressed a few words of regret at the death of <persName n="Dayton,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00171" reg="mostcommon:Dayton,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Dayton</surname></persName>, but said nothing whatever about our affairs in general. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="2"> 
<head>Facility for a War with <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="243"/> The <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName> correspondent of the <orgName n="New York Herald" type="newspaper">New York <hi rend="italics">Herald</hi></orgName> thus writes about the probability of getting up a war with <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="244"/>He speaks of it as an easy affair to manage: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="245"/> The <placeName reg="Canada, North and Central America, " key="tgn,7005685">Canada</placeName> affair may breed hot blood.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="246"/>If you want a war with <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName>, there is no doubt but you can be gratified.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="247"/>The bad faith of the <rs>Canadian</rs> authorities is seen in the failure to arrest the <rs>St. Albans</rs> robbers on the right kind of process. &#x0022;But,&#x0022; say they, &#x0022;you must not send hostile expeditions into <placeName reg="Canada, North and Central America, " key="tgn,7005685">Canada</placeName> unless you want a big row.&#x0022; If a war was to occur between the <num value="2">two</num> countries, they would expect to lose <placeName reg="Canada, North and Central America, " key="tgn,7005685">Canada</placeName>, and would only have a partial revenge in helping the rebels to their independence.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="248"/>They would anticipate both results.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="249"/>Injudicious men can very easily fan that <placeName reg="Canada, North and Central America, " key="tgn,7005685">Canadian</placeName> matter into a flame that will not be quenched for years.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="250"/>But the question is, &#x0022;Will it pay?&#x0022; </p> </q><bibl n="New York Herald"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="251"/> <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName> is already looking on the various colonies and dependencies of the empire as very uncertain possessions.--On that account, perhaps, they would have less hesitation with regard to a war with the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> than they would if <placeName reg="Canada, North and Central America, " key="tgn,7005685">Canada</placeName> were not almost certain to go in a few years.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="252"/>Self aggrandizement <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num>, and if that cannot be, damage the rivals of <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName> as much as possible.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="253"/>Rise as high as possible, and kick everybody else down the ladder that attempts to climb up. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="3"> 
<head>Trial of Polish Insurrectionists.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="254"/> A Berlin letter says: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="255"/> The trial of the <name>Polish</name> &#x0022;conspirators&#x0022; was concluded on <date>Friday</date>, the <dateStruct value="--23"><day reg="23">23d ultimo</day></dateStruct>, with much the same result as was anticipated in my last report.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="256"/><num value="11">Eleven</num> of the accused were condemned to death, <hi rend="italics">in contumaciam,</hi> among whom are <persName n="Dzielinski,Comte,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00172" reg="mostcommon:Dzielinski,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Comte">Count</roleName> <surname>Dzielinski</surname></persName>, the greatest landed proprietor in <placeName reg="Polska" key="tgn,7006366">Prussian Poland</placeName>; Guthier, member of the <rs>Polish National Government</rs> and of the <rs type="place">Prussian Chamber</rs> of Deputies, and Taczanowski and Seifried, who distinguished themselves as leaders in the insurrection, they not having appeared for trial being considered an acknowledgment of their guilt.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="257"/>Of the accused actually present <num value="28">twenty-eight</num> were found guilty of acts preparatory to the commission of high treason, but with extenuating circumstances, and sentenced to terms of imprisonment varying from <num value="1">one</num> to <measure n="2years" type="date">two years</measure>. All the other prisoners, about <num value="100">one hundred</num> in number, were acquitted; but against some of them the <rs type="role" reg="Attorney-General">Attorney General</rs> moved proceedings in a <orgName n="New Court" type="court">new court</orgName>. </p> </q><bibl n="A Berlin letter"></bibl></cit> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="4"> 
<head>General news.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="258"/> Various rumors have been in circulation in <placeName reg="Rome, Floyd, Georgia" key="tgn,2024102">Rome</placeName> as to the reasons which had caused the visit of the hereditary <rs type="role" reg="Grand Duke">Grand Duke</rs> of <placeName key="tgn,7002435" n="1.000 184" reg="rossiya">Russia</placeName> to that city to be countermanded.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="259"/>Numerous efforts have been made by the <rs>Russian Government</rs> to induce the <rs>Pope</rs>, like the other sovereigns, to abandon the cause of <placeName key="tgn,7006366" n="1.000 33" reg="polska">Poland</placeName>; and, with glorious persistence, the generous Pontiff showed himself the only organ of the protests of the martyr nation.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="260"/>Very recently, <persName n="Meyendorff,,M.,,,de" id="n-0001.0000.00000.00173" reg="expanded:Meyendorff,M.,,,"><foreName>M.</foreName> <nameLink>de</nameLink> <surname>Meyendorff</surname></persName> addressed himself to <persName n="Antonelli,,Cardinal,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00174" reg="default:Antonelli,Cardinal,,,"><foreName>Cardinal</foreName> <surname>Antonelli</surname></persName>, and to the <rs>Pope</rs> himself, to request that <name n="his Holiness" type="role"><rs type="role" reg="Pope">His Holiness</rs></name> would at least promise to abstain from any manifestation during the stay of the <rs type="role" reg="Grand Duke">Grand Duke</rs> at <placeName reg="Rome, Floyd, Georgia" key="tgn,2024102">Rome</placeName>. --The Holy Father refused that abandonment, even temporarily, of his heroic children of <persName n="Poland,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00175" reg="mostcommon:Poland,nomatch:0"><surname>Poland</surname></persName>, and it was in consequence of that reply to the overtures of <persName n="Meyendorff,,M.,,,de" id="n-0001.0000.00000.00176" reg="expanded:Meyendorff,M.,,,"><foreName>M.</foreName> <nameLink>de</nameLink> <surname>Meyendorff</surname></persName> that the announced visit of the <name>Czarewitch</name> was countermanded. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="261"/> The <rs>French</rs> and Papal Governments have concluded a telegraph treaty.--After <dateStruct value="-01-01"><occasion>New Year's day</occasion></dateStruct>, a simple dispatch from <persName n="Paris,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00177" reg="mostcommon:Paris,nomatch:0"><surname>Paris</surname></persName> to <placeName reg="Rome, Floyd, Georgia" key="tgn,2024102">Rome</placeName>, and <hi rend="italics">vice versa,</hi> will <milestone unit="column" n="5"/> cost only <num value="5">five</num> francs instead of <num value="13">thirteen</num> francs and <num value="50">fifty</num> centimes. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="262"/> The municipal elections just over in <placeName key="tgn,7016786" n="1.000 94" reg="prussia">Prussia</placeName> have all resulted in the success of Liberal candidates. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="263"/> A Paris letter in the <hi rend="italics">Salut Public</hi> of <persName n="Lyons,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00178" reg="mostcommon:Lyons,nomatch:0"><surname>Lyons</surname></persName> says: <q>&#x0022;Do you know the history of the <num value="780">seven hundred and eighty</num> galley slaves whom the <rs>Holy See</rs> is about to restore to <placeName key="tgn,1000080" n="1.000 187" reg="italia">Italy</placeName>?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="264"/>Mm. Pisanelli and <persName><foreName>Peruzzi</foreName></persName> had thought proper to restore to the <rs>Holy See</rs> about <num value="200">two hundred</num> convicts belonging to the provinces comprised in the present domain of <placeName key="tgn,2055458" n="1.000 3" reg="saint peter, nicollet, minnesota">St. Peter</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="265"/><persName n="Antonelli,,Cardinal,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00179" reg="default:Antonelli,Cardinal,,,"><foreName>Cardinal</foreName> <surname>Antonelli</surname></persName>, not over grateful for this indirect recognition of the <rs>Pope</rs>'s temporal sovereignty, then called on the <rs n="Italian" type="group">Italian</rs> Government to accept delivery of <num value="780">seven hundred and eighty</num> convicts belonging to the provinces of the <name>Marches</name> and <placeName reg="Umbria, Italia, Europe" key="tgn,7003125">Umbria</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="266"/>The exchange is not considered at all advantageous to mm. Pisanelli and <persName><foreName>Peruzzi</foreName></persName>, and the discomfiture of those gentlemen is the cause of no little merriment not only at <placeName reg="Rome, Floyd, Georgia" key="tgn,2024102">Rome</placeName> but also at <placeName key="tgn,7005688" n="1.000 2" reg="torino,torino,piemonte,italia,europe">Turin</placeName>.&#x0022;</q> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="267"/> Letters from Saigon, <persName n="China,,Cochin,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00180" reg="default:China,Cochin,,,"><foreName>Cochin</foreName> <surname>China</surname></persName>, to the <date value="10-28">28th of October,</date> mention the arrival there, <measure n="3days" type="date">three days</measure> previously, of <name n="his Majesty" type="role">His Majesty</name> Sandachprea-Norodon, <rs type="role" reg="King">King</rs> of Cambodia, on a visit to the <rs>French Governor</rs>, who had sent him an invitation and placed a gunboat at his disposal for the voyage.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="268"/>On the occasion of <name n="his Majesty" type="role">His Majesty's</name> arrival, all the vessels in the harbor were decked out with flags, as was also the <rs type="place">Chinese town</rs> of Cho-len.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="269"/>The gunboat was followed by <name n="his Majesty" type="role">His Majesty's</name> <term type="ship">yacht</term>, the <rs type="ship">Gia Dinh</rs>, on board of which were several of his <num value="40">forty</num> wives, with their attendants.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="270"/>The <rs>King</rs> wore the military costume presented to him by the <rs>French</rs> on the occasion of the coronation in <dateStruct value="-07-"><month reg="07">July</month></dateStruct> last, and also the golden crown given to him at the same time.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="271"/><name n="his Majesty" type="role">His Majesty</name> was accompanied by his principal officers of State and his magicians, without whose advice he never takes any important step.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="272"/>Nearly all those personages were clothed in <rs n="silk robe" type="product">silk robes</rs>, richly embroidered and of very picturesque effect. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="273"/> <rs type="role" reg="Emperor">The Emperor</rs> of <placeName key="tgn,7002435" n="1.000 184" reg="rossiya">Russia</placeName> has issued an ukase extending the abolition of serfdom to Transcaucasia, the only province of the <placeName reg="Rossiya" key="tgn,7002435">Russian Empire</placeName> where that institution still exists. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="274"/> The railway between <placeName key="tgn,7009861" n="1.000 6" reg="stockholm,stockholm,sverige,europe">Stockholm</placeName> and Malmoe, a town at the south of the <rs n="Swedish" type="political">Swedish</rs> peninsula, on the <rs type="place">Sound</rs>, nearly opposite <placeName key="tgn,7003474" n="1.000 2" reg="kobenhavn,kobenhavn,danmark,europe">Copenhagen</placeName>, has been opened.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="275"/>The capital of <placeName key="tgn,1000097" n="1.000 73" reg="sverige">Sweden</placeName> is, in consequence, at a distance of only <measure n="20hours" type="date">twenty hours</measure> from the <name>Continent</name>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="276"/> <persName n="Maltitz,,L.,,,Von" id="n-0001.0000.00000.00181" reg="expanded:Maltitz,L.,,,"><foreName>L.</foreName> <nameLink>Von</nameLink> <surname>Maltitz</surname></persName>, a Dutchman, of Colesberg, in the <rs type="place">Cape of Good Hope</rs>, has discovered a new industry.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="277"/>He says he can tame ostriches and keep them like poultry, and has actually bred <num value="17">seventeen</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="278"/>They want about <measure n="10acres" type="area">ten acres</measure> of grazing land apiece, but each bird yields <num value="24">twenty-four</num> feathers every <measure n="6months" type="date">six months</measure>, worth, with the small feathers, about &#x00A3;<num value="12">12</num> 10s. or &#x00A3;<num value="25">25</num> a year. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="279"/> The number of persons who emigrated from <placeName key="tgn,1000070" n="1.000 1012" reg="france">France</placeName> to foreign countries in <dateStruct value="1863--"><year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct> amounted to <num value="4285">4,285</num>, and those to <placeName key="tgn,7016752" n="1.000 6" reg="algeria">Algeria</placeName>, <num value="1486">1,486</num>, making a total of <num value="5771">5,771</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="280"/>This number is less by <num value="1029">1,029</num> than in <dateStruct value="1862--"><year reg="1862">1862</year></dateStruct>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="281"/> The <rs>King</rs> of <placeName key="tgn,1000074" n="1.000 48" reg="ellas">Greece</placeName> has decided that <num value="4">four</num> officers of the army or navy shall proceed to <placeName reg="France" key="tgn,1000070">France</placeName> and <placeName reg="United Kingdom" key="tgn,7002445">England</placeName> to inquire into the military and naval organization of those <num value="2">two</num> countries, and make a report to the commission formed at <placeName reg="Athens, Clarke, Georgia" key="tgn,7013329">Athens</placeName> for the re-organization of those services in <placeName key="tgn,1000074" n="1.000 48" reg="ellas">Greece</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="282"/> &#x0022;<persName><foreName>Peter</foreName></persName>'s Pence,&#x0022; at <placeName reg="Rome, Floyd, Georgia" key="tgn,2024102">Rome</placeName>, produces less and less.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="283"/>At the commencement the produce was about <num value="4000">four thousand</num> <rs n="Roman" type="ethnic">Roman</rs> crowns a month, it afterwards fell to <num value="2000">two thousand</num>, and goes on decreasing.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="284"/><dateStruct value="-11-"><month reg="11">November</month></dateStruct> only gave <num value="700">seven hundred</num>, including offerings from <placeName key="tgn,7009760" n="1.000 8" reg="toscana">Tuscany</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="285"/> From official returns just published, it appears that the population of <placeName key="tgn,7007868" n="1.000 1" reg="bruxelles,bruxelles,belgie,europe">Brussels</placeName> on the <date value="01-01">1st of January</date> last, amounted to <num value="184932">184,932</num>, of whom <num value="89971">89,971</num> were males and <num value="94961">94,961</num> females. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="286"/> The <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> iron-plated vessel for the <rs>Brazilian</rs> navy was lately launched at the <rs type="place">Seine building</rs>- yard, near <placeName reg="Toulon, Var, Provence-Alpes-Cote d'Azur" key="tgn,7008794">Toulon</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="287"/>She is a corvette, and named the <rs>Don Pedro</rs> <num value="2">II</num>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="288"/> <num value="291000000">Two hundred and ninety-one million</num>, <num value="597000">five hundred and ninety-seven thousand</num>, <num value="240">two hundred and forty</num> eggs have been imported into <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName> in the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> <measure n="10months" type="date">ten months</measure> of the present year. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="289"/> The <rs n="Swedish" type="political">Swedish</rs> census, taken <date value="1863-12-31">December 31, 1863,</date> is published.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="290"/>The total population of <placeName key="tgn,1000097" n="1.000 73" reg="sverige">Sweden</placeName> is <num value="4022564">4,022,564</num>, and there are <num value="105940">105,940</num> more women than men. The increase of population during the last quinquennial period has been <num value="1">1</num>-<num value="0.02">2 per cent.</num> About <num value="3.5">three and a half</num> <num value="1000000">millions</num> live in the country, and the rest in the towns, <placeName key="tgn,7009861" n="1.000 6" reg="stockholm,stockholm,sverige,europe">Stockholm</placeName> containing nearly <num value="350000">350,000</num> inhabitants.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="291"/>The population of <placeName reg="Norge, Europe, " key="tgn,1000088">Norway</placeName> is about <num value="1500000">1,500,000</num>, which would give the united kingdom about <num value="5.5">five and a half</num> <num value="1000000">millions</num> of inhabitants. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="292"/> The <placeName key="tgn,7005025" n="1.000 1" reg="bergamo,bergamo,lombardia,italia,europe">Bergamo</placeName> <hi rend="italics">Gazette</hi> announces the discovery of the skeleton of a mastodon, or <hi rend="italics">elephas primigenius,</hi> in the lignite beds of Leffe.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="293"/><persName n="Ferrero,Professor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00182" reg="mostcommon:Ferrero,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Professor">Professor</roleName> <surname>Ferrero</surname></persName> states that its tusks are <num value="2">two</num> metres in length.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="294"/>The works at the pit have been suspended in order to enable some <rs n="Italian" type="group">Italian</rs> geolegists to take a survey of the place. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="295"/> The <hi rend="italics"><persName n="Correspondence,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00183" reg="mostcommon:Correspondence,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Correspondence</surname></persName></hi> of <placeName reg="Vienna, Fairfax, Virginia" key="tgn,2114749">Vienna</placeName> states that a percussion cap burst on the carriage of the <rs>Emperor</rs> of <placeName key="tgn,1000062" n="1.000 128" reg="austria">Austria</placeName> as he was returning from Sch&#x0153;nbrunn on the morning of the <date value="12-01">1st of December.</date> The care which the ministerial journal takes to state that no person was wounded would almost lead <num value="1">one</num> to suppose that the affair was not that of a mere harmless cap, but of some kind of projectile. </p> </div4> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="296"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> <milestone unit="column" n="6"/> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="morning"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head rend="italics">Salaries of Government clerks.</head> 
<div4 type="letter" n="1"> 
<head></head> <opener> <salute>To the <rs>Editor</rs> of the <orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>:</salute> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="297"/> The clamor for putting into service the able-bodied clerks of the various Departments having been complied with, and as the balance are now composed of exempts, does it not become the <rs>Government</rs> to allow them to obtain, from some source, that which keeps &#x0022; <hi rend="italics">body and soul</hi>&#x0022; together?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="298"/>The soldiers in the field are cared for, and why not this class of public servants?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="299"/>Their services are invaluable and could not be dispensed with.--The present salary of a Department clerk is <measure n="333.33dollars" type="currency">three hundred and thirty- three dollars and thirty-three cents</measure> per month.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="300"/>That amount, so Congress thinks, (judging from their humane silence,) is sufficient to meet their wants for <hi rend="italics"><num value="1">one</num> month.</hi> It would be proper to add that a certain member of the <rs type="place">House</rs> remarked, a few days since, &#x0022;that his daily expenses for himself alone, by using the strictest economy, were over <measure n="150dollars" type="currency">one hundred and fifty dollars</measure>.&#x0022; The clerks receive <measure n="13dollars" type="currency">thirteen dollars</measure>. Farther comment is unnecessary, but before closing it would not be amiss to suggest to the proper authorities to be on the <hi rend="italics">qui vice</hi> for a new set of clerks generally, as the present Department clerks cannot, physically or mentally, perform their laborious duties under the circumstances. </p> <closer> <signed>Reason.</signed> </closer> </div4> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="announcements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="married" n="1"> 
<head>Married.</head> 
<div4 type="wed" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="301"/> On <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> <time>evening</time>, the <dateStruct value="--24"><day reg="24">24th instant</day></dateStruct>, at the residence of the bride's father, <persName n="Peay,,James,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00184" reg="default:Peay,James,H.,,"><foreName>James</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Peay</surname></persName>, <rs type="role">Esq.</rs>, by <persName n="Edwards,Reverend,J.,E.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00185" reg="expanded:Edwards,Jane,E.,,"><roleName n="Reverend">the Rev.</roleName> <foreName>J.</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>Edwards</surname></persName>. <persName n="Duesberry,,R.,Henry,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00186" reg="default:Duesberry,R.,Henry,,"><foreName>R.</foreName> <foreName>Henry</foreName> <surname>Duesberry</surname></persName>, of this city, to <persName n="Pollock,,Sally,F.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00187" reg="default:Pollock,Sally,F.,,"><foreName>Sally</foreName> <foreName>F.</foreName> <surname>Pollock</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="302"/>of <placeName reg="Henrico, Virginia" key="tgn,1002467">Henrico county</placeName>. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="wed" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="303"/> On <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Thursday</day></dateStruct> <time>evening</time>, <dateStruct value="-01-19"><month reg="01">January</month> <day reg="19">19th</day></dateStruct>, at <orgName n="Trinity Church" type="church">Trinity Church</orgName>, by <persName n="Edwards,Reverend,J.,E.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00188" reg="expanded:Edwards,Jane,E.,,"><roleName n="Reverend">the Rev.</roleName> <foreName>J.</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>Edwards</surname></persName>, <persName n="Stratton,,William,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00189" reg="default:Stratton,William,H.,,"><foreName>William</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Stratton</surname></persName> to <persName n="Sedgwick,,M.,Jennie,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00190" reg="default:Sedgwick,M.,Jennie,,"><foreName>M.</foreName> <foreName>Jennie</foreName> <surname>Sedgwick</surname></persName>, both of this city. </p> </div4> </div3> 
<div3 type="death" n="2"> 
<head>Died.</head> 
<div4 type="obit" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="304"/> On <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> <time>morning</time>, at <time value="8oclock">8 o'clock</time>, Dolphus, the youngest <persName n="George,IsFather,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00191" reg="mostcommon:George,nomatch:0"><roleName n="IsFather">son of</roleName> <surname>George</surname></persName> and <persName n="Frank,,Mary,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00192" reg="default:Frank,Mary,,,"><foreName>Mary</foreName> <surname>Frank</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="305"/> <cit><q> <lg type="stanza"> <l>Dearest Dolphus, thou hast left us, </l><l>And thy loss we deeply feel; </l><l>But 'tis <name n="God" type="God">God</name> that hast bereft us-- </l><l>He can all our sorrows heal.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="306"/></l> </lg> </q><bibl></bibl></cit> </p> 
<p> The friends of the family are invited to attend his funeral, which will take place from <placeName reg="St. John's Church">St. John's Church</placeName>, on <address><street n="5 Street">Fifth street</street></address>, on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct> <time>morning</time> at <time value="10oclock">10 o'clock</time>. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="307"/> At <placeName reg="Keswick, Cumbria, England" key="tgn,7010161">Keswick</placeName>, <rs n="Powhatan" type="nativeamerican">Powhatan</rs> county, on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time>, the <dateStruct value="--27"><day reg="27">27th instant</day></dateStruct>, at <time value="11.5oclock">11&#x00BD; o'clock</time>, <persName n="Selden,Doctor,William,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00193" reg="default:Selden,William,A.,,"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <foreName>William</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName> <surname>Selden</surname></persName>, <rs type="role">Surgeon</rs> <orgName n="Provisional Army" type="misc">Provisional Army</orgName> <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="308"/> His funeral will take place from his late residence (<placeName reg="Keswick, Cumbria, England" key="tgn,7010161">Keswick</placeName>) on <date>Monday</date>, the <dateStruct value="--20"><day reg="20">20th instant</day></dateStruct>, at <time value="12mid">12 o'clock M.</time> His friends and acquaintances are invited to attend without further notice. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="309"/> In the town of <placeName reg="Fulton, Oswego, New York" key="tgn,2069306">Fulton</placeName>, at the residence of his father, of croup, on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Sunday</day></dateStruct> <time>morning</time>, the <dateStruct value="--29"><day reg="29">29th instant</day></dateStruct>, at <time value="4:30oclock">half-past 4 o'clock</time>, <persName n="Sandford,,Lewis,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00194" reg="default:Sandford,Lewis,,,"><foreName>Lewis</foreName> <surname>Sandford</surname></persName>, youngest <persName n="Maria,IsFather,Ann,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00195" reg="default:Maria,Ann,,,"><roleName n="IsFather">son of</roleName> <foreName>Ann</foreName> <surname>Maria</surname></persName> and Gustavus Seal, aged <num value="1">one</num> year and <measure n="5months" type="date">five months</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="310"/> The funeral will take place at his father's residence this evening at <time value="3oclock">3 o'clock</time>. The friends of the family are respectfully invited to attend. * </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="311"/> Of typhoid pneumonia, on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Sunday</day></dateStruct> <time>afternoon</time>, the <dateStruct value="--29"><day reg="29">29th instant</day></dateStruct>, in the <num value="35" type="ordinal">thirty-fifth</num> year of her age, <persName><foreName>Mary</foreName></persName>, wife of <persName n="Bevill,Mister,William,J.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00196" reg="default:Bevill,William,J.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>William</foreName> <foreName>J.</foreName> <surname>Bevill</surname></persName>, of this city, leaving <num value="6">six</num> small children to mourn their irreparable loss. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="312"/> The funeral services will take place at <orgName n="Centenary Church" type="church">Centenary Church</orgName>, on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> <time>Afternoon</time>, the <dateStruct value="--31"><day reg="31">31st instant</day></dateStruct>, at <time value="3oclock">3 o'clock</time>. The friends and acquaintances of the family, and those of her brother, <persName n="McFarland,Mister,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00197" reg="default:McFarland,John,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>John</foreName> <surname>McFarland</surname></persName>, are requited to attend without further notice. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="313"/> <term type="printrun">ja 30--2t*</term> </p> </div4> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="military"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="orders" n="1"> 
<head><hi rend="smallcaps">[Extract.]</hi><lb/><orgName n="Adjutant and Inspector General Office" type="government">Adjutant and Inspector-General's Office</orgName>,<lb/><hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 11" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName>,</hi> <dateStruct value="1865-01-28"><month reg="01">January</month> <day reg="28">28</day>, <year reg="1865">1865</year></dateStruct>.<lb/>Special Orders, <num value="23">no. 23</num>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="314"/><num value="57">LVII</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="315"/>Furloughs until <dateStruct value="1865-03-01"><month reg="03">March</month> <day reg="1">1</day>, <year reg="1865">1865</year></dateStruct>, are allowed all detailed soldiers and conscripts now serving with the local defence brigade of this city who are to rejoin their regiments in the field, or to be assigned to the <rs n="General Service" type="misc">general service</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="316"/>To such conscripts is allowed the privilege of selecting the companies and regiments to which they shall be assigned, provided that the company selected has not the maximum prescribed by law. Furloughs thus allowed will be issued from Headquarters Local Defence Brigade, and will be respected by the officers of the <name>Conscription</name> service. </p> <closer> By command of <signed>the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>.</signed> <lb/> <signed><persName n="Withers,,Jonathan,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00198" reg="default:Withers,Jonathan,,,"><foreName n="Jonathan">Jno.</foreName>  <surname>Withers</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <signed><rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Adjutant General">Assistant Adjutant-General</rs>.</signed> <term type="printrun">ja 30--1w</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="317"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> <milestone unit="page" n="3"/> 
<div1 type="page-image"> 
<head></head> 
<p><figure entity="NW_RichTimesD_028_025_003"> <figDesc>Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume <num value="28">28</num>, <num value="25">Number 25</num>, <ref n="page 3">page 3</ref>. </figDesc> </figure></p> </div1> <milestone unit="column" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="318"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.</head> 
<div2 type="morning"> 
<head><date value="1865-01-30">Monday morning...January 30, 1865.</date></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head rend="italics">The news.</head> 
<div4 type="entry" n="1"> 
<head>Peace Commissioners sent to <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="319"/> There was no war news yesterday, but, in lieu thereof, peace rumors were as plentiful as blackberries.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="320"/>These were of every variety of shade and color, and owed their origin chiefly to the fact that <persName n="Davis,President,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00199" reg="nearbymention:Davis,Jefferson,,,"><roleName n="President">President</roleName> <surname>Davis</surname></persName> had appointed <num value="3">three</num> peace commissioners to proceed to <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="321"/>This fact became publicly known, and at once the flood of rumors was let loose.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="322"/>It were idle to attempt to recapitulate them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="323"/>All that is known regarding these peace commissioners is, that <persName n="Stephens,Vice-President,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00200" reg="mostcommon:Stephens,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Vice-President">Vice President</roleName> <surname>Stephens</surname></persName>, <persName n="Campbell,Assistant-Secretary of War,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00201" reg="mostcommon:Campbell,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Assistant-Secretary of War">Assistant Secretary of War</roleName> <surname>Campbell</surname></persName> and <persName n="Hunter,Senator,R.,M.,T.," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00202" reg="default:Hunter,R.,M.,T.,"><roleName n="Senator">Senator</roleName> <foreName>R.</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <foreName>T.</foreName> <surname>Hunter</surname></persName>, having, pursuant to an understanding come to with <persName n="Blair,Mister,Francis,P.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00203" reg="default:Blair,Francis,P.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>Francis</foreName> <foreName>P.</foreName> <surname>Blair</surname></persName>, been appointed by <persName n="Davis,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00204" reg="nearbymention:Davis,Jefferson,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Davis</surname></persName> as peace commissioners, left this city by the <rs>Petersburg</rs> train yesterday morning at <time value="10oclock">10 o'clock</time> <hi rend="italics">en route</hi> for <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="324"/>From <placeName reg="Petersburg, Petersburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7014404">Petersburg</placeName> they have, by this time, gone by <persName n="Grant,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00205" reg="mostcommon:Grant,nomatch:0"><surname>Grant</surname></persName>'s military railroad to <placeName reg="City Point, Virginia, Virginia" key="tgn,2240477">City Point</placeName>, whence they will proceed to <placeName reg="Baltimore, Baltimore Independent City, Maryland" key="tgn,7013352">Baltimore</placeName> or <placeName key="tgn,7013303" n="1.000 493" reg="annapolis, anne arundel, maryland">Annapolis</placeName> by steamer.--It is feared that the cold weather, by obstructing navigation, will retard them in their trip.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="325"/>Nothing is known here as to the powers with which these commissioners are clothed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="326"/>There are a <num value="1000">thousand</num> speculations and theories on the subject; all of which, being based on no known fact, are worthless.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="327"/>About half of our people think that peace is some how to come out of this commission, while the other half hope nothing better from it than that our whole people, being convinced there is no prospect of an honorable peace, will be united as <num value="1">one</num> man in the determination to prosecute the war with increased vigor.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="328"/>The failure of the commission must have this effect; for there can be no question that, in their various sentiments, they fully represent all classes of the loyal people of the <rs>Southern States</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="329"/> The sensation produced in <placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 11" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName> by <persName n="Blair,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00206" reg="nearbymention:Blair,Francis,P.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Blair</surname></persName>'s <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> visit was a ripple on the waters compared with the maelstrom of excitement into which the cities of the <rs>North</rs> will be thrown by the advent of the &#x0022;Rebel Peace Commissioners.&#x0022; Already New York is in a commotion over the news of their coming, which has been flashed over the wires.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="330"/>The reporters of the great newspapers are already on the track of the <num value="3">three</num> gentlemen, and to-morrow morning the papers will be filled with their accounts.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="331"/>The <hi rend="italics">Herald</hi> will have a dozen columns of &#x0022;The Rebel Peace Commissioners&#x0022;--&#x0022;Their Powers&#x0022; --&#x0022;How they Look&#x0022;--&#x0022;What they Say&#x0022;--&#x0022;What they Eat,&#x0022; etc., etc. The illustrated papers will contain their photographs &mdash; how they looked before the war and how they look now. In short the &#x0022;Rebel Commissioners&#x0022; will be a <num value="9">nine</num> day's wonder to the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> nation, and as such, and coming in just in the nick of time to break the dreary monotony of the winter campaign, will be hailed with delight. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="2"> 
<head>More Commissioners.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="332"/> Surely now is the season of &#x0022;Commissioners.&#x0022; It was currently reported in the city <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> <time>evening</time> that a commissioner from the <rs>French Government</rs> had arrived.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="333"/>We have not seen any such gentleman.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="334"/>When <persName n="Stephens,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00207" reg="mostcommon:Stephens,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Stephens</surname></persName> and party went into <persName n="Grant,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00208" reg="mostcommon:Grant,nomatch:0"><surname>Grant</surname></persName>'s lines, at <placeName reg="Petersburg, Petersburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7014404">Petersburg</placeName>, yesterday morning, on the return of our flag of truce there came into our lines a gentleman from <placeName key="tgn,7007251" n="1.000 2052" reg="illinois">Illinois</placeName>, named <persName n="Grant,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00209" reg="mostcommon:Grant,nomatch:0"><surname>Grant</surname></persName>, who is also said to be a peace commissioner. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="335"/> We may mention, in connection with the reported arrival here of a French commissioner, that the rumor is brought down from <placeName reg="Virginia" key="tgn,7007919"><rs type="direction">Northern</rs> Virginia</placeName> that the <rs>French</rs> minister at <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName> has, for some cause which has not yet transpired, demanded his passports.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="336"/>We have no means of deciding upon the truth of this rumor.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="337"/>Our latest Northern papers are of the evening of the <dateStruct value="--23"><day reg="23">23d instant</day></dateStruct>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="338"/>It being apparently an accepted theory of our Government that the people have no interest either in the war or the peace which must at some time follow, no pains is taken to put the press in possession of authentic intelligence concerning great public events, frequently only known to the <rs>Government</rs>, and thereby enable them to give the facts to the country, or correct false and pernicious reports.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="339"/>We make this remark <milestone unit="column" n="2"/> generally, not being especially excited thereto by the report about the <rs>French</rs> minister. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="3"> 
<head><persName n="Breckinridge,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00210" reg="mostcommon:Breckinridge,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Breckinridge</surname></persName> <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>--the coming tax bill.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="340"/> We think it certain that <persName n="Breckinridge,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00211" reg="mostcommon:Breckinridge,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Breckinridge</surname></persName> has been appointed <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>, though his appointment has not yet been presented to the <name>Senate</name> for its approval.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="341"/>It is said that <persName n="Bruce,Mister,E.,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00212" reg="default:Bruce,E.,M.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Bruce</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName>, is to be <rs type="role" reg="Commissary-General">Commissary-General</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="342"/>He is spoken of as possessing peculiar fitness for the office.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="343"/>But the truth is, should Congress, as it probably will, pass a law giving market value for all property taken for Government use, the labors of the <orgName n="Commissary Department" type="department">Commissary Department</orgName> will be immeasurably decreased.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="344"/>There will be then no necessity for impressments.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="345"/>It being once known that the <rs>Government</rs> is giving the highest market price, the hidden stores of the country will be crowded into market.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="346"/>In this connection, we may mention that the <rs type="place">House</rs> <orgName n="Finance Committee" type="committee">Finance Committee</orgName> are now perfecting a sweeping tax bill, which will be ready to take the redundancy of the currency that would otherwise be created by the immense sums necessarily disbursed by Government if it pays market price for property taken for public use. The tax bill will raise <measure n="700000000dollars" type="currency">seven hundred million dollars</measure>, and a discount of <num value="0.15">fifteen percent.</num> is to be allowed for prompt payment. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="4"> 
<head>Gold.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="347"/>Gold on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> <time>morning</time> opened at <num value="47">forty-seven</num>, and ran up as high as <num value="52">fifty-two</num>; but the news of the appointment of the peace commissioners sent it down rapidly, and considerable amounts were sold as low as <num value="42">forty-two</num>. </p> </div4> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="amusements"> 
<head>Amusements.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="348"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="3"/> 
<div2 type="runaways"> 
<head>Runaways.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head><measure n="60dollars" type="currency">Sixty dollars</measure> reward.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="349"/> --Ran away, on the <dateStruct value="1865-01-22"><day reg="22">22d</day> of <month reg="01">January</month>, <year>1865</year>,</dateStruct> from the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName> Nitre Works, <placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 11" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName>, <persName n="Harris,,Lewis,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00213" reg="default:Harris,Lewis,,,"><foreName>Lewis</foreName> <surname>Harris</surname></persName> and <persName n="Valentine,,Sam,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00214" reg="default:Valentine,Sam,,,"><foreName>Sam</foreName> <surname>Valentine</surname></persName>, free negroes.--They live in <placeName key="tgn,7014021" n="1.000 1" reg="mecklenburg, north carolina, united states">Mecklenburg</placeName>, and may have hired themselves to the <orgName n="Richmond and Danville Railroad" type="railroad">Richmond and Danville Railroad</orgName> Company, to be employed at <placeName key="tgn,2112496" n="1.000 4" reg="keysville, charlotte, virginia">Keysville</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="350"/>Deliver them to any jail and notify. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Harrison,,E.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00215" reg="default:Harrison,E.,,,"><foreName>E.</foreName>  <surname>Harrison</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Va.</placeName> <term type="printrun">ja 27--6t</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head><measure n="30dollars" type="currency">Thirty dollars</measure> reward.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="351"/> --Catch <persName><foreName>Albert</foreName></persName>, a square-built, reddish-yellow Negro, with whiskers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="352"/>He ran away from the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName> Nitre Works on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Wednesday</day></dateStruct> <time>morning</time>, <dateStruct value="-01-25"><month reg="01">January</month> <day reg="25">25th</day></dateStruct>, and may make for <placeName reg="Amelia, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002139">Amelia county</placeName>, as he was hired from <persName n="Eggleston,,Edward,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00216" reg="default:Eggleston,Edward,,,"><foreName>Edward</foreName> <surname>Eggleston</surname></persName>, of that county.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="353"/>Deliver him to any jail and notify. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Harrison,,E.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00217" reg="default:Harrison,E.,,,"><foreName>E.</foreName>  <surname>Harrison</surname></persName>,</signed> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Va.</placeName> <term type="printrun">ja 27--6t</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head><measure n="500dollars" type="currency">Five hundred dollars</measure> reward.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="354"/> --Ran away from the subscriber, at <placeName reg="Dinwiddie Courthouse">Dinwiddie Courthouse</placeName>, on the <dateStruct value="--8"><day reg="8">8th instant</day></dateStruct>, my Negro Woman, <persName n="Hannah,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00218" reg="mostcommon:Hannah,nomatch:0"><surname>Hannah</surname></persName>; very likely; <measure n="19years" type="date">nineteen years</measure> old; stammers when excited.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="355"/>I suppose she is trying to get to the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="356"/>The above reward will be paid for the apprehension of said slave. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Barner,,Drewry,J.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00219" reg="default:Barner,Drewry,J.,,"><foreName>Drewry</foreName> <foreName>J.</foreName>  <surname>Barner</surname></persName>.</signed> <term type="printrun">ja 26--5t*</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="for rent"> 
<head>For rent.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="357"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="administrators"> 
<head>Administrators' Notices.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="358"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="4"/> 
<div2 type="special"> 
<head>Special Notices.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="359"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="5"/> 
<div2 type="wanted"> 
<head>Wanted.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>Wanted,</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="360"/> a Teacher, (a male teacher preferred), to go above <placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 11" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName>, on the south side of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">James river</placeName>, to teach my children.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="361"/>Must be fully competent to teach <persName n="French,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00220" reg="mostcommon:French,nomatch:0"><surname>French</surname></persName>, Mathematics and the <rs>English</rs> branched.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="362"/>References, as well as the amount of wages, to accompany answers to this advertisement, respectfully asked.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="363"/>Fore a suitable teacher, I will offer a pleasant home and good wage.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="364"/>Address A. B., <measure value="box 891" type="box">box 891</measure>, <placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 11" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="365"/> <term type="printrun">ja 30--eod3t</term> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="366"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="announcements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>Wanted to hire,</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="367"/> a Wagon, Team and Driver, for which will be given feed and liberal wages.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="368"/>Apply at </p> <closer> <signed><placeName><persName n="Cary,Major,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00221" reg="mostcommon:Cary,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <surname>Cary</surname></persName>'s office</placeName>,</signed> <lb/> <address><street n="Bank street">Bank street</street></address>, between <address><street n="11 Street">Eleventh</street></address> and <address><street n="12 Street">Twelfth</street></address>. <term type="printrun">ja 30--2t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head>Wanted,</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="369"/> Immediately, a Furnished Room, with gas, fires and use of a servant until close of session of Legislation, convenient to capitol.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="370"/>For the use of which, Provisions will be exchanged on fair terms if desired.--Address <measure value="box 1588" type="box">box 1,588</measure>, <orgName n="Post Office" type="office">post-office</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="371"/> <term type="printrun">ja 30--1t*</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head>Wanted to hire,</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="372"/> by the month, for a small family, a good Washer and Ironer and plain <persName n="Cook,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00222" reg="mostcommon:Cook,nomatch:0"><surname>Cook</surname></persName>, without encumbrance.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="373"/>Apply at the corner of <address><street n="5 Street">Fifth</street></address> and <address><street n="Canal Street">Canal streets</street></address>. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Mitchell,,J.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00223" reg="default:Mitchell,J.,,,"><foreName>J.</foreName>  <surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>.</signed> <term type="printrun">ja 30--6t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head>Wanted,</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="374"/> a <rs type="color">white</rs> or <rs type="color">colored Cook</rs>, for a general of cavalry in the field.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="375"/>Good wages will be given and permanent employment.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="376"/>Inquire at this office. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="377"/> <term type="printrun">ja 30--3t</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head>Wanted,</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="378"/> a Lady, to attend in a confectionary store.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="379"/>Apply at <address><street n="Broad Street 165">165 Broad street</street></address>, between <address><street n="6 Street">Sixth</street></address> and <address><street n="7 Street">Seventh</street></address> streets. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="380"/> <term type="printrun">ja 30--1t*</term> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="381"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="negroes"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>Wanted, <num value="2">two</num> servants; a <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num>-rate plain <persName n="Cook,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00224" reg="mostcommon:Cook,nomatch:0"><surname>Cook</surname></persName> (especially a good bread-maker) and a Nurse and House Servant.--No objection to a middle-aged woman as nurse.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="382"/>A good home and fair wages will be given.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="383"/>Call at my residence, on <address><street n="6 Street">Sixth street</street></address>, between <address><street n="Clay street">Clay</street></address> and <address><street n="Leigh street">Leigh</street></address>, east side. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Hester,,J.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00225" reg="default:Hester,J.,W.,,"><foreName>J.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName>  <surname>Hester</surname></persName>.</signed> <term type="printrun">[ja 28--2t*]</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head>Wanted, Shoemakers,</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="384"/> both on ladies' and gentlemen's work.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="385"/><num value="6">Six</num> or <num value="8">eight</num> good hands can find constant employment and good wages by applying to </p> <closer> <signed><orgName><persName n="Johnson,,W.,E.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00226" reg="default:Johnson,W.,E.,,"><foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName>  <surname>Johnson</surname></persName> &#x0026; Co.</orgName>,</signed> <lb/> <address><street n="Main Street 127">127 Main street</street></address>, <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Virginia</placeName>. <term type="printrun">ja 23--3t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head>Wanted, a Situation</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="386"/> --A young man, exempt from military duty, who has had about <measure n="10years" type="date">ten years</measure> experience in the <rs n="dry goods" type="product">Dry Goods</rs> business, desires a Situation.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="387"/>Would not object to any other employment.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="388"/>Best of references given.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="389"/>Address H, box <num value="624">No. 624</num>, city <orgName n="Post Office" type="office">post-office</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="390"/> ja <num value="28">28</num>--6t* </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head>Wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="391"/> I wish to employ a Female Teacher, to take charge of a small school--<num value="1">one</num> that is qualified to recommended.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="392"/>Address <persName n="Justis,,William,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00227" reg="default:Justis,William,W.,,"><foreName>William</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Justis</surname></persName>, Hallsboro, <placeName reg="Chesterfield, Chesterfield, Virginia" key="tgn,2111165">Chesterfield</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="393"/> <term type="printrun">ja 28--5t*</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head>Wanted,</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="394"/> immediately, a Situation, by a Young <rs type="role2">Lady</rs>, as Saleswoman in some store.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="395"/>References given and required.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="396"/>Address <rs type="role2">Miss</rs> N. M., <orgName n="Dispatch office" type="office">Dispatch office</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="397"/> <term type="printrun">ja 23--3t*</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head>Wanted,</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="398"/> <num value="2">two</num> <rs n="counter scales" type="product">Counter Scales</rs>, for which the highest price will be paid.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="399"/>Apply at <address><street n="Franklin Street 4">No. 4 Franklin street</street></address>, <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> door from the <rs type="place">Old Market</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="400"/> <term type="printrun">ja 28--1t*</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="7"> 
<head>Wanted,</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="401"/> a Mailing Clerk, at the <orgName n="Examiner office" type="office">Examiner Office</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="402"/>Apply to the <rs>Manager</rs> at once. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="403"/> <term type="printrun">ja 27--</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="8"> 
<head>Wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="404"/> The advertiser wishes to rent a Piano &mdash; a fine instrument.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="405"/>Special care will be taken of it. Address Piano, <measure value="box 782" type="box">box 782</measure>, <placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 11" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName>, stating terms. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="406"/> <term type="printrun">ja 27--3t*</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="9"> 
<head>Teacher Wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="407"/> --I wish to employ <persName n="Teacher,Lady,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00228" reg="mostcommon:Teacher,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lady">a Lady</roleName> <surname>Teacher</surname></persName> in my family, who can teach the higher branches of <name>English</name>, <name>French</name> and Music. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Ellett,,S.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00229" reg="default:Ellett,S.,,,"><foreName>S.</foreName>  <surname>Ellett</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> near <placeName reg="Ashland, Hanover, Virginia" key="tgn,2110477">Ashland</placeName>, <placeName reg="Hanover, Hanover, Virginia" key="tgn,2112147">Hanover</placeName>. <term type="printrun">ja 27--4t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="10"> 
<head>Wanted,</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="408"/> by a lady who is qualified to teach the higher <name>English</name> branches, Music on the <name>Piano</name> and the rudiments of <persName n="French,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00230" reg="mostcommon:French,nomatch:0"><surname>French</surname></persName>, a Situation as Teacher.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="409"/>Address <persName n="Ada,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00231" reg="mostcommon:Ada,nomatch:0"><surname>Ada</surname></persName>, Dixie <orgName n="Post Office" type="office">post-office</orgName>, <placeName reg="Fluvanna, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002159">Fluvanna county, Virginia</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="410"/> <term type="printrun">ja 27--6t*</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="11"> 
<head><hi rend="smallcaps">Clearance Lock,<lb/><placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">James River</placeName> and <placeName reg="Kanawha Canal">Kanawha Canal</placeName>,</hi><lb/><dateStruct value="1865-01-25"><month reg="01">January</month> <day reg="25">25</day>, <year reg="1865">1865</year></dateStruct></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="411"/>Wanted to Employ, a good, reliable white man, to assist in the duties of this office, viz: To examine and clear the boats and to assist in working the lock.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="412"/>Apply to the undersigned, at the <rs type="place">Clearance Office</rs>, on the canal <measure n="3miles" type="distance">three miles</measure> above the city. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Hopkins,,John,N.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00232" reg="default:Hopkins,John,N.,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>N.</foreName>  <surname>Hopkins</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <signed><persName n="Lock,,Clearance,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00233" reg="default:Lock,Clearance,,,"><foreName>Clearance</foreName>  <surname>Lock</surname></persName>-keeper,</signed> <lb/> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">James River</placeName> and <placeName reg="Kanawha Canal">Kanawha Canal</placeName>. <term type="printrun">ja 20--4t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="12"> 
<head>Shoemakers Wanted</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="413"/> at <num value="167">167</num>, <placeName reg="Ladies' Cheap Shoe Store">Ladies' Cheap Shoe Store</placeName>, for which the highest price will be paid. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Dunham,,C.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00234" reg="default:Dunham,C.,,,"><foreName>C.</foreName>  <surname>Dunham</surname></persName>.</signed> <term type="printrun">[ja 26--6t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="13"> 
<head>Wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="414"/> --I wish to hire, for this year, a Servant Woman, of good character and without encumbrance, to cook, wash and iron for my family.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="415"/>For <num value="1">one</num> well recommended I am willing to pay a high price. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Gibson,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00235" reg="default:Gibson,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName>  <surname>Gibson</surname></persName>,</signed> of J. &#x0026; <persName n="Gibson,,G.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00236" reg="default:Gibson,G.,,,"><foreName>G.</foreName> <surname>Gibson</surname></persName>, <lb/> corner <address><street n="Cary Street">Cary</street></address> and <address><street n="6 Street">Sixth streets</street></address>. <term type="printrun">ja 24--6t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="14"> 
<head>Wanted,</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="416"/> <persName n="Teacher,Lady,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00237" reg="mostcommon:Teacher,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lady">a lady</roleName> <surname>Teacher</surname></persName>, who can teach the higher branches of <name>English</name>, <name>French</name> and Music, for <num value="3">three</num> children, in a pleasant locality in the country.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="417"/>References given and required.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="418"/>Address T. J. C., <measure value="box 149" type="box">box 149</measure>, <placeName reg="Charlottesville, Charlottesville, Virginia" key="tgn,7013585">Charlottesville, Virginia</placeName>, stating terms, &#x0026;c. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="419"/> <term type="printrun">ja 15--10t*</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="15"> 
<head>Wanted,</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="420"/> at the <orgName n="Manassas Gap Railroad" type="railroad">Manassas Gap Railroad</orgName> Shops, <placeName reg="Greensboro, Guilford, North Carolina" key="tgn,7014135">Greensboro', North Carolina</placeName>, <lb/> Boilermakers, <measure n="25dollars" type="currency">$25</measure> a day; <lb/> Machinists, <measure n="20dollars" type="currency">$20</measure> a day. <lb/> Board, <measure n="200dollars" type="currency">$200</measure> a month. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="421"/> <term type="printrun">ja 21--2w*</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="16"> 
<head>Wanted,</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="422"/> a <num value="1">No. 1</num> <persName n="Cook,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00238" reg="mostcommon:Cook,nomatch:0"><surname>Cook</surname></persName>, Washer and Ironer, which I will buy or hire, and pay an extra price.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="423"/>Apply to <persName n="Marbey,,J.,D.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00239" reg="default:Marbey,J.,D.,,"><foreName>J.</foreName> <foreName>D.</foreName> <surname>Marbey</surname></persName>, under Tobacco Exchange, <address><street n="Virginia street">Virginia street</street></address>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="424"/> <term type="printrun">ja 19--2w</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="17"> 
<head>Wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="425"/> --I wish to engage the services of a Lady who is competent to teach thoroughly all the branches of an English education, Mathematics, Latin, <persName n="French,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00240" reg="mostcommon:French,nomatch:0"><surname>French</surname></persName>, and Music on the piano, to take charge of a small school in my family, which will be limited to <num value="6">six</num> pupils.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="426"/>References required.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="427"/>State terms and address the undersigned, <unclear><placeName reg="Goochland, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002163">Goochland</placeName></unclear> Courthouse, <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Michaux,,T.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00241" reg="default:Michaux,T.,,,"><foreName>T.</foreName>  <surname>Michaux</surname></persName>.</signed> <term type="printrun">ja 18--2tawlw*</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="428"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="6"/> 
<div2 type="lost"> 
<head>Lost, Strayed and stolen.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="429"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="negroes"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head><measure n="200dollars" type="currency">Two hundred dollars</measure> reward.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="430"/> --Ran away from <placeName><persName n="Green,,B.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00242" reg="default:Green,B.,W.,,"><foreName>B.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Green</surname></persName>'s farm</placeName>, about the last of <dateStruct value="-11-"><month reg="11">November</month></dateStruct>, a Negro man, named <persName><foreName>Isaac</foreName></persName>, belonging to <persName n="Bagby,Miss,Frances,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00243" reg="default:Bagby,Frances,,,"><roleName n="Miss">Miss.</roleName> <foreName>Frances</foreName> <surname>Bagby</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="431"/>He is about <measure n="30years" type="date">thirty years</measure> of age; tall; stoutly built, and very black; speaks rather slow, and wore side whiskers when last seen.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="432"/>He was seen a short time since several miles below <placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 11" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName> with a forged pass.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="433"/>The above reward will be paid on his delivery to <persName n="Clopton,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00244" reg="mostcommon:Clopton,nomatch:0"><surname>Clopton</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="Lyne,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00245" reg="mostcommon:Lyne,nomatch:0"><surname>Lyne</surname></persName>, or to the undersigned. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Bagby,,George,R.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00246" reg="default:Bagby,George,R.,,"><foreName n="George">Geo.</foreName> <foreName>R.</foreName>  <surname>Bagby</surname></persName>,</signed> <address><street n="Main Street 130">130 Main street</street></address>. <term type="printrun">ja 28--2t*</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="434"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="negroes"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>In <orgName n="Henrico County Court" type="court">Henrico county Court</orgName>, <dateStruct value="1865-01-25"><month reg="01">January</month> <day reg="25">25</day>, <year reg="1865">1865</year></dateStruct>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="435"/> --The <rs type="place">Court</rs> having again attended to-day, pursuant to their adjournment on <dateStruct><day type="name">Wednesday</day></dateStruct> last, to further consider the requisition of the <rs>Governor</rs> for slaves from this county to labor on the fortifications and other works necessary for the public defence, made pursuant to law, and <num value="6">six</num> of the <rs>Justices</rs> being present, doth order that the following slaveholders, hirers and public hospitals produce to the <rs>Sheriff</rs> of this county, at the <rs type="place">Court-house</rs> thereof, on <dateStruct><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct>, the <num value="30" type="ordinal">30th</num> day of the present month (<dateStruct value="-01-"><month reg="01">January</month></dateStruct>), by <time value="12mid">12 o'clock M.</time> of that day, the number of slaves, between the ages of <num value="18">eighteen</num> and <measure n="55years" type="date">fifty-five years</measure>, annexed to their names in the subjoined list, to labor as above indicated; on which day the <rs type="place">Court</rs> will proceed finally to dispose of the whole matter, and to direct the <rs>Sheriff</rs> to take into possession the slaves of all such holders, hirers and hospitals, who, on that day, are not excused or otherwise exempted, and ordered the same to be published in the <orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond <hi rend="italics">Dispatch</hi></orgName> until that day. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="436"/> The following is the list, viz: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="437"/> 
<table rows="41" cols="2"> 
<head></head> 
<row><cell><persName n="Allen,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00247" reg="mostcommon:Allen,nomatch:0"><surname>Allen</surname></persName>, W. C.</cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell>Ball, <persName n="Dandridge,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00248" reg="mostcommon:Dandridge,nomatch:0"><surname>Dandridge</surname></persName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Cosby,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00249" reg="mostcommon:Cosby,nomatch:0"><surname>Cosby</surname></persName>, J. W.</cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Carrington,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00250" reg="mostcommon:Carrington,nomatch:0"><surname>Carrington</surname>, <roleName n="Colonel">Colonel</roleName></persName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Cohn,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00251" reg="mostcommon:Cohn,nomatch:0"><surname>Cohn</surname></persName>, <persName><foreName>Jacob</foreName></persName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Christian,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00252" reg="mostcommon:Christian,nomatch:0"><surname>Christian</surname></persName>, <address><street n="Ann street">Ann</street></address></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Duval,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00253" reg="mostcommon:Duval,nomatch:0"><surname>Duval</surname></persName>, <persName><foreName>Samuel</foreName></persName> S.</cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Duval,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00254" reg="mostcommon:Duval,nomatch:0"><surname>Duval</surname></persName>, Miles</cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Dickinson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00255" reg="mostcommon:Dickinson,nomatch:0"><surname>Dickinson</surname></persName>, B. F.</cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Ellett,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00256" reg="nearbymention:Ellett,S.,,,"><surname>Ellett</surname></persName>, A. L.</cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Edmunds,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00257" reg="mostcommon:Edmunds,nomatch:0"><surname>Edmunds</surname></persName>, <persName><foreName>Robert</foreName></persName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell>friend, <persName><foreName>John</foreName></persName> E.</cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName><foreName>Francis</foreName></persName>, <persName n="James,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00258" reg="mostcommon:James,nomatch:0"><surname>James</surname></persName> G.</cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Ford,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00259" reg="mostcommon:Ford,nomatch:0"><surname>Ford</surname></persName>, A. J.</cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Garnett,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00260" reg="mostcommon:Garnett,nomatch:0"><surname>Garnett</surname></persName>, <persName><foreName>William</foreName></persName> F. G.</cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Green,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00261" reg="nearbymention:Green,B.,W.,,"><surname>Green</surname></persName>, B. W. &#x0026; Sons</cell><cell><num value="2">2</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Haxall,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00262" reg="mostcommon:Haxall,nomatch:0"><surname>Haxall</surname></persName>, <persName n="Boling,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00263" reg="mostcommon:Boling,nomatch:0"><surname>Boling</surname></persName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell>Heckler, V.</cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Hughes,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00264" reg="mostcommon:Hughes,nomatch:0"><surname>Hughes</surname></persName>, <persName><foreName>John</foreName></persName> C.</cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Higginbotham,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00265" reg="mostcommon:Higginbotham,nomatch:0"><surname>Higginbotham</surname></persName>, E. J.</cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Johnston,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00266" reg="mostcommon:Johnston,nomatch:0"><surname>Johnston</surname></persName>, <persName n="Thomas,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00267" reg="mostcommon:Thomas,nomatch:0"><surname>Thomas</surname></persName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Kerr,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00268" reg="mostcommon:Kerr,nomatch:0"><surname>Kerr</surname></persName>, <rs type="role">Mrs</rs> &#x0026; <persName n="Maxwell,,Robert,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00269" reg="default:Maxwell,Robert,,,"><foreName>Robert</foreName> <surname>Maxwell</surname></persName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Knight,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00270" reg="mostcommon:Knight,nomatch:0"><surname>Knight</surname></persName>, <persName><foreName>William</foreName></persName> C.</cell><cell><num value="2">2</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell>Lersner</cell><cell><num value="5">5</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Leake,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00271" reg="mostcommon:Leake,nomatch:0"><surname>Leake</surname></persName>, T. C.</cell><cell><num value="2">2</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Lawson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00272" reg="mostcommon:Lawson,Peter,,,:1"><surname>Lawson</surname></persName>, <persName><foreName>Peter</foreName></persName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Maynard,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00273" reg="mostcommon:Maynard,nomatch:0"><surname>Maynard</surname></persName>, J. C.</cell><cell><num value="4">4</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Omohundro,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00274" reg="mostcommon:Omohundro,nomatch:0"><surname>Omohundro</surname></persName>'s, <persName n="Estate,,S.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00275" reg="default:Estate,S.,,,"><foreName>S.</foreName> <surname>Estate</surname></persName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Poe,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00276" reg="mostcommon:Poe,nomatch:0"><surname>Poe</surname></persName>, <persName><foreName>John</foreName></persName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Payne,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00277" reg="mostcommon:Payne,nomatch:0"><surname>Payne</surname></persName>, <persName><foreName>Robert</foreName></persName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Randolph,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00278" reg="mostcommon:Randolph,nomatch:0"><surname>Randolph</surname></persName>, <persName><foreName>William</foreName></persName> B.</cell><cell><num value="2">2</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Shields,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00279" reg="mostcommon:Shields,nomatch:0"><surname>Shields</surname></persName>, <persName><foreName>John</foreName></persName> C</cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell>Schutte, <persName><foreName>Richard</foreName></persName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Sheppard,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00280" reg="mostcommon:Sheppard,nomatch:0"><surname>Sheppard</surname></persName>, <persName n="Lavinia,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00281" reg="mostcommon:Lavinia,nomatch:0"><surname>Lavinia</surname></persName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Stearns,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00282" reg="mostcommon:Stearns,Franklin,,,:1"><surname>Stearns</surname></persName>, <persName><foreName>Frank</foreName></persName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Taliaferro,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00283" reg="mostcommon:Taliaferro,nomatch:0"><surname>Taliaferro</surname></persName>, <persName><foreName>William</foreName></persName> C.</cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Taylor,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00284" reg="mostcommon:Taylor,James,,,:1"><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>, M. S.</cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Tinsley,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00285" reg="mostcommon:Tinsley,nomatch:0"><surname>Tinsley</surname></persName>, <persName n="Reeves,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00286" reg="mostcommon:Reeves,nomatch:0"><surname>Reeves</surname></persName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Winston,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00287" reg="mostcommon:Winston,nomatch:0"><surname>Winston</surname></persName>, <persName n="James,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00288" reg="mostcommon:James,nomatch:0"><surname>James</surname></persName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><persName n="Werth,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00289" reg="mostcommon:Werth,nomatch:0"><surname>Werth</surname></persName>, <persName><foreName>John</foreName></persName> J., agent</cell><cell><num value="5">5</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell>Weatham Iron Works</cell><cell><num value="13">13</num></cell></row> </table></p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="438"/> 
<table rows="7" cols="2"> 
<head>hospitals.</head> 
<row><cell><placeName reg="Louisiana Hospital">Louisiana Hospital</placeName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><placeName reg="Camp Lee">Camp Lee</placeName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><placeName reg="Camp Winder Hospital">Camp Winder Hospital</placeName></cell><cell><num value="11">11</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><placeName reg="Camp Jackson Hospital">Camp Jackson Hospital</placeName></cell><cell><num value="8">8</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><placeName reg="Howard Grove Hospital">Howard Grove Hospital</placeName></cell><cell><num value="4">4</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><placeName reg="Chimborazo Hospital">Chimborazo Hospital</placeName></cell><cell><num value="10">10</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell><placeName reg="Stuart Hospital">Stuart Hospital</placeName></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num></cell></row> </table></p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="439"/> A copy &mdash; Teste: </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Folkes,,William,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00290" reg="default:Folkes,William,,,"><foreName>William</foreName>  <surname>Folkes</surname></persName>. C. H. C.</signed> <term type="printrun">ja 26--5t</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="440"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> <milestone unit="page" n="4"/> 
<div1 type="page-image"> 
<head></head> 
<p><figure entity="NW_RichTimesD_028_025_004"> <figDesc>Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume <num value="28">28</num>, <num value="25">Number 25</num>, <ref n="page 4">page 4</ref>. </figDesc> </figure></p> </div1> <milestone unit="column" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="441"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.</head> 
<div2 type="morning"> 
<head><date value="1865-01-30">Monday morning...January 30, 1865.</date></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>Local matters.<lb/><hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName> <orgName n="District Court" type="court">District Court</orgName>.</hi></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="442"/> <persName n="Halyburton,Judge,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00291" reg="mostcommon:Halyburton,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Judge">Judge</roleName> <surname>Halyburton</surname></persName> held a short session on <dateStruct><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="443"/> In the <hi rend="italics">habeas corpus</hi> case of <persName n="Serveary,,Louis,F.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00292" reg="default:Serveary,Louis,F.,,"><foreName>Louis</foreName> <foreName>F.</foreName> <surname>Serveary</surname></persName>, claiming exemption from military service on the ground of being an undomiciled foreigner, the <rs>Judge</rs> delivered his opinion, which was adverse to give petitioner; whereupon he was remanded to the custody of <persName n="Green,Captain,C.,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00293" reg="default:Green,C.,A.,,"><roleName n="Captain">Captain</roleName> <foreName>C.</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName> <surname>Green</surname></persName>; the commander of the company to which he is attached. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="444"/> The court adjourned till <time value="11oclock">11 o'clock</time> this morning. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 11" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName> <orgName n="Circuit Court" type="court">Circuit Court</orgName>, <dateStruct><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="445"/> In the matter of petitions for writs of <hi rend="italics">habeas corpus</hi> of <persName><foreName>Jacob</foreName></persName> M&#x0153;bus and <persName n="Gangert,,Michael,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00294" reg="default:Gangert,Michael,,,"><foreName>Michael</foreName> <surname>Gangert</surname></persName>, members of <orgName n="regiment"><persName n="Danforth,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00295" reg="mostcommon:Danforth,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Colonel</roleName> <surname>Danforth</surname></persName>'s regiment</orgName> <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num>-class militia, the parties were this day brought into court, and bailed until the <date value="02-04">4th of February</date> ensuing, to await the decision of the <orgName n="Appeals Court" type="court">Court of Appeals</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="446"/> A writ was awarded <persName n="Beretel,,Adolph,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00296" reg="default:Beretel,Adolph,,,"><foreName>Adolph</foreName> <surname>Beretel</surname></persName>, a member of the same regiment, returnable on <dateStruct><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct> next at <time value="11oclock">11 o'clock</time>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="Mayor's Court">Mayor's Court</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="447"/> --The following cases were disposed of by the <rs>Mayor</rs> on <dateStruct><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct>: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="448"/> <persName n="Pryor,,Charles,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00297" reg="default:Pryor,Charles,,,"><foreName>Charles</foreName> <surname>Pryor</surname></persName>, a free negro of bad repute, charged with living in the city without a register, contrary to law, was remanded to the enrolling officer. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="449"/> The case of <persName n="Carter,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00298" reg="mostcommon:Carter,nomatch:0"><surname>Carter</surname></persName>, slave of <persName n="Stearns,,Franklin,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00299" reg="default:Stearns,Franklin,,,"><foreName>Franklin</foreName> <surname>Stearns</surname></persName>, charged with stealing a box of tobacco, valued at <measure n="600dollars" type="currency">six hundred dollars</measure>, the property of <persName n="Christian,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00300" reg="mostcommon:Christian,nomatch:0"><surname>Christian</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="Lea,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00301" reg="mostcommon:Lea,nomatch:0"><surname>Lea</surname></persName>, was continued till to-day. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="450"/> <persName><foreName>Jesse</foreName></persName>, slave of <persName n="Jones,,William,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00302" reg="default:Jones,William,H.,,"><foreName>William</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Jones</surname></persName>, charged with stealing a parcel of meat, was discharged, there being no evidence to convict him of the offence. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="451"/> <persName n="Willis,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00303" reg="nearbymention:Willis,T.,T.,,"><surname>Willis</surname></persName>, slave of <persName n="Taylor,,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00304" reg="default:Taylor,James,,,"><foreName>James</foreName> <surname>Taylor</surname></persName>, was committed for going at large. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="452"/> <persName n="Porter,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00305" reg="mostcommon:Porter,nomatch:0"><surname>Porter</surname></persName>, <hi rend="italics">alias</hi> <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName>, slave of <persName n="Green,,Benjamin,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00306" reg="default:Green,Benjamin,,,"><foreName>Benjamin</foreName> <surname>Green</surname></persName>, charged with stealing a pair of shoes from a negro girl in the employ of <persName n="McCarthy,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00307" reg="mostcommon:McCarthy,James,C.,,:1"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>McCarthy</surname></persName>, was ordered to be whipped. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="453"/> A fine of <measure n="50dollars" type="currency">fifty dollars</measure> was imposed upon <persName n="Bruggomat,,H.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00308" reg="default:Bruggomat,H.,,,"><foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Bruggomat</surname></persName> for permitting his servant, <persName><foreName>Mary</foreName></persName>, to go at large. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="454"/> <persName n="Schuyler,,Samuel,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00309" reg="default:Schuyler,Samuel,,,"><foreName>Samuel</foreName> <surname>Schuyler</surname></persName> was fined <measure n="20dollars" type="currency">twenty dollars</measure> upon a similar charge. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="455"/> <persName n="Lawson,,Peter,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00310" reg="default:Lawson,Peter,,,"><foreName>Peter</foreName> <surname>Lawson</surname></persName> was summoned to show cause why he should not be fined for selling light weight at his stall in the <rs>Second Market</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="456"/>On <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> <time>morning</time>, a gentleman, named <persName n="Smith,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00311" reg="nearbymention:Smith,W.,E.,,"><surname>Smith</surname></persName>, asked for a pound and <num value="0.5">a half</num> of meat at this stall, for which he paid <measure n="9dollars" type="currency">nine dollars</measure>. When the meat was handed to him, <persName n="Smith,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00312" reg="nearbymention:Smith,W.,E.,,"><surname>Smith</surname></persName> thought it looked quite small for the amount, and called attention to the matter, whereupon another small piece was thrown into his basket.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="457"/>On going to a grocery store soon afterwards, <persName n="Smith,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00313" reg="nearbymention:Smith,W.,E.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Smith</surname></persName> put the meat, including the extra piece, on a pair of scales, and found that all together lacked <num value="2">two</num> ounces of being a pound and <num value="0.5">a half</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="458"/><persName n="Lawson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00314" reg="nearbymention:Lawson,Peter,,,"><surname>Lawson</surname></persName> denied all knowledge of the transaction himself &mdash; the meat was sold by <persName n="Webster,,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00315" reg="default:Webster,James,,,"><foreName>James</foreName> <surname>Webster</surname></persName>, an employee at his stall.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="459"/>The <rs>Mayor</rs> continued the case till this morning, in order to procure the attendance of <persName n="Webster,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00316" reg="nearbymention:Webster,James,,,"><surname>Webster</surname></persName>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Police arrests.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="460"/> --The city police, during <dateStruct><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> and <dateStruct><day type="name">Sunday</day></dateStruct>, made the following arrests: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="461"/> <persName><foreName>Sarah</foreName></persName>, slave of <persName n="Bailey,Mrs.,Georgiana,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00317" reg="default:Bailey,Georgiana,,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <foreName>Georgiana</foreName> <surname>Bailey</surname></persName>, charged with stealing meat from <persName n="Cullingsworth,,William,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00318" reg="default:Cullingsworth,William,,,"><foreName>William</foreName> <surname>Cullingsworth</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="462"/>She was ordered to be whipped by <persName n="William,Justice,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00319" reg="mostcommon:William,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Justice">Justice</roleName> <surname>William</surname></persName>, <persName n="Taylor,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00320" reg="nearbymention:Taylor,James,,,"><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>, and discharged. </p> </q><bibl n="The city police"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="463"/> <persName n="Beswell,,Joseph,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00321" reg="default:Beswell,Joseph,,,"><foreName>Joseph</foreName> <surname>Beswell</surname></persName>, free, for assaulting and beating <persName n="Larman,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00322" reg="mostcommon:Larman,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Larman</surname></persName>, a white woman. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="464"/> <persName n="Kenneday,,Charles,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00323" reg="default:Kenneday,Charles,,,"><foreName>Charles</foreName> <surname>Kenneday</surname></persName>, white, charged with trespassing on the premises of <persName n="Edwards,Miss,Jane,E.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00324" reg="default:Edwards,Jane,E.,,"><roleName n="Miss">Miss.</roleName> <foreName>Jane</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>Edwards</surname></persName> and breaking up her furniture.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="465"/>Kenneday was subsequently held to security by <persName n="McCarthy,Justice,James,C.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00325" reg="default:McCarthy,James,C.,,"><roleName n="Justice">Justice</roleName> <foreName>James</foreName> <foreName>C.</foreName> <surname>McCarthy</surname></persName>, in the sum of <measure n="300dollars" type="currency">three hundred dollars</measure>, to keep the peace and be of good behavior for <measure n="12months" type="date">twelve months</measure>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Accident.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="466"/> --A youth, named <persName n="Norwood,,James,C.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00326" reg="default:Norwood,James,C.,,"><foreName>James</foreName> <foreName>C.</foreName> <surname>Norwood</surname></persName>, while sliding on the ice on <address><street n="Main street">Main street</street></address>, near <num value="21" type="ordinal">Twenty- first</num>, on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> <time>afternoon</time>, fell down and broke <num value="1">one</num> of his legs.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="467"/>He was taken to his mother's residence, near by, where <persName n="Walker,Doctor,Robert,S.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00327" reg="default:Walker,Robert,S.,,"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <foreName>Robert</foreName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <surname>Walker</surname></persName> attended him and reset the limb.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="468"/>Yesterday evening the wounded boy was improving. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Fulfilling a bargain.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="469"/> --Some time since, <num value="2">two</num> employing painters of this city, exempts from military service, finding their business slacking off, in their hours of idleness made a bargain that each should exercise his professional skill upon the features of the other whenever he was caught drunk.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="470"/>Since the arrangement, both of the contracting parties have taken particular pains to shun each other whenever they would go to take a drink; but, finally, in an unguarded moment, <num value="1">one</num> of them got rather too much on board, and being caught in this condition by his friend, he was painted as black as paint of that color could make him. Upon sobering off, and finding that the bargain had been fulfilled as far as he was concerned, the unfortunate victim determined that the advantage should not always be against him, so he set to work keeping a stricter <milestone unit="column" n="2"/> watch upon his colleague in business, that he might find him in a similar situation, when he would perform the same operation upon him. He had not long to wait either; for, in less than <measure n="3days" type="date">three days</measure> afterwards, the <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> party to the bargain got drunker than the other, and was thereupon subjected to a thicker coat of paint, and blacker, too, if possible.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="471"/>Nor was this all, in the case of the latter; when night came on, he ventured out in the street in his disguised condition, was gobbled up by the guard, and taken to the guard-house, where he remained all night, locked up in the cell, and, being too drunk to make the explanation, was registered as a negro, whose name was unknown.--The next morning he gave his name, related the story, and was permitted to depart without any further publicity being given to the affair. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="7"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Robbery.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="472"/> --On <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time> the residence of <persName n="Royster,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00328" reg="mostcommon:Royster,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Royster</surname></persName>, on the corner of <address><street n="Franklin Street">Franklin</street></address> and <address><street n="26 Street">Twenty- sixth streets</street></address>, was broken into, and a lot of <rs n="wearing apparel" type="product">wearing apparel</rs>, jewelry, etc., belonging to a lady living in the house, was stolen.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="473"/>During the operations of the thieves their presence was discovered, but before assistance could be obtained, they became alarmed and made good their escape. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="8"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><measure n="2" type="prisoners">Two prisoners</measure>,</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="474"/> committed to <placeName reg="Castle Thunder">Castle Thunder</placeName> on <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct>, giving their names as members of the <orgName type="regiment" key="1Company">First company</orgName> Richmond Howitzers, were not connected with that company. </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> </body> <back> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="475"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="proclamation"> 
<head>Proclamation</head> 
<div3 type="orders" n="1"> 
<head>By the <rs>President</rs>, appointing a day of fasting, humiliation and Prayer, with thanksgiving.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="476"/> --The <orgName n="Confederate States Congress" type="congress">Congress of the Confederate States</orgName> have, by a joint resolution, invited me to appoint a day of public fasting, humiliation and prayer, with thanksgiving to Almighty <name n="God" type="God">God</name>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="477"/> It is our solemn duty, at all times, and more especially in a season of public trial and adversity, to acknowledge our dependence on His mercy, and to bow in humble submission before His footstool, confessing our manifold sins, supplicating His gracious pardon, imploring His Divine help, and devoutly rendering thanks for the many and great blessings which He has vouchsafed to us. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="478"/> Let the hearts of our people turn contritely and trustfully unto <name n="God" type="God">God</name>; let us recognize in His chastening hand the correction of a Father, and submissively pray that the trials and sufferings which have so long borne heavily upon us may be turned away by His merciful love; that His sustaining grace be given to our people, and His divine wisdom imparted to our rulers; that the <name n="God" type="God"><rs type="role" reg="Lord">Lord</rs> of Hosts</name> will be with our armies, and fight for us against our enemies; and that He will graciously take our cause into His own hand and mercifully establish for us a lasting, just and honorable peace and independence. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="479"/> And let us not forget to render unto His holy name the thanks and praise which are so justly due for His great goodness, and for the many mercies which He has extended to us amid the trials and sufferings of protracted and bloody war. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="480"/> Now, therefore, I, <persName n="Davis,,Jefferson,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00329" reg="default:Davis,Jefferson,,,"><foreName>Jefferson</foreName> <surname>Davis</surname></persName>, <rs type="role" reg="President">President</rs> of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States of America</placeName>, do issue this my proclamation, appointing <date>Friday</date>, the <dateStruct value="-03-10"><day reg="10">10th</day> day of <month reg="03">March</month></dateStruct> next, as a day of public fasting, humiliation and prayer, (with thanksgiving,) for &#x0022;invoking the favor and guidance of Almighty <name n="God" type="God">God</name>;&#x0022; and I do earnestly invite all soldiers and citizens to observe the same in a spirit of reverence penitence and prayer. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="481"/> Given under my hand and the seal of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName>, at <placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 11" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName>, this <dateStruct value="-01-25"><day reg="25">twenty-fifth</day> day of <month reg="01">January</month></dateStruct>, <dateStruct value="1865--">in the year of our Lord <year reg="1865">one thousand eight hundred and sixty-five</year></dateStruct>. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Davis,,Jefferson,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00330" reg="default:Davis,Jefferson,,,"><foreName>Jefferson</foreName>  <surname>Davis</surname></persName>.</signed> <lb/> By <signed>the <rs>President</rs>:</signed> <lb/> <signed><persName n="Benjamin,,J.,P.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00331" reg="default:Benjamin,J.,P.,,"><foreName>J.</foreName> <foreName>P.</foreName>  <surname>Benjamin</surname></persName>, <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of State">Secretary of State</rs>.</signed> <term type="printrun">ja 26--3tawtd</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="482"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="3"/> 
<div2 type="auction"> 
<head><rs n="auction sales" type="product">Auction sales</rs>.<lb/>future day.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="483"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="4"/> 
<div2 type="auction"> 
<head><rs n="auction sales" type="product">Auction sales</rs>.<lb/>this day.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="484"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="real estate for sale"> 
<head><rs n="real estate" type="product">Real estate</rs> for sale.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="485"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="educational"> 
<head>Educational.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="486"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="5"/> 
<div2 type="auction"> 
<head><rs n="auction sales" type="product">Auction sales</rs>.<lb/>future day.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="487"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="6"/> 
<div2 type="official"> 
<head>Official.</head> 
<div3 type="orders" n="1"> 
<head><hi rend="smallcaps"><orgName n="Treasury Department" type="department">Treasury Department</orgName>,</hi><lb/><hi rend="smallcaps">Confederate State of <placeName reg="America, Walker, Alabama" key="tgn,2002460">America</placeName>,</hi><lb/><placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 11" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName>, <dateStruct value="1864-08-08"><month reg="08">August</month> <day reg="8">8</day>, <year reg="1864">1864</year></dateStruct>.<lb/>Certificates of Indebtedness bearing <num value="0.06">Six Per Cent.</num> Per annum interest and free from taxation.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="488"/> --By the <orgName type="regiment" key="14Section">fourteenth section</orgName> of the act to reduce the currency, approved <dateStruct value="1864-02-17"><month reg="02">February</month> <day reg="17">17</day>, <year reg="1864">1864</year></dateStruct>, the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of the Treasury">Secretary of the Treasury</rs> is authorized to issue the above certificates, payable <measure n="2years" type="date">two years</measure> after the ratification of a treaty of peace with the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="489"/>They cannot be sold, but are only to be issued to such creditors of the <rs>Government</rs> as are willing to receive the same in payment of their demands.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="490"/>They must also be given at par, though free from taxation. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="491"/> The attention of purchasing agents and disbursing officers of the <rs>Government</rs> is called to this class of public securities as offering peculiar advantages to those from whom the supplies of the <rs>Government</rs> are bought; and to facilitate the use of them, checks drawn by disbursing officers upon the depositaries holding these funds, and marked across the face &#x0022;payable in certificates of indebtedness,&#x0022; will paid in conformity therewith. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="492"/> Depositaries are hereby authorized and required to comply with this regulation, and to make application to the <name>Register</name> for supplies of certificates as required. </p> <closer> [Signed] <signed><persName n="Trenholm,,G.,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00332" reg="default:Trenholm,G.,A.,,"><foreName>G.</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName>  <surname>Trenholm</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <signed><rs type="role" reg="Secretary of the Treasury">Secretary of Treasury</rs>.</signed> <term type="printrun">ja 2--ts</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="2"> 
<head><hi rend="smallcaps"><orgName n="Treasury Department" type="department">Treasury Department</orgName>,</hi><lb/><hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States of America</placeName>,</hi><lb/><placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Va.</placeName>, <dateStruct value="1864-08-26"><month reg="08">August</month> <day reg="26">26</day>, <year reg="1864">1864</year></dateStruct>.<lb/>regulations for carrying into effect the act of Congress approved <dateStruct value="1864-06-13"><month reg="06">June</month> <day reg="13">13</day>, <year reg="1864">1864</year></dateStruct>, Authorizing Owners of registered <num value="0.08">eight Per Cent.</num> Bonds, issued under the <name>Provisions</name> of the act approved may <num value="16">16</num>, <dateStruct value="1861--"><year reg="1861">1861</year></dateStruct>, to Exchange the same for <rs n="coupon bond" type="product">Coupon bonds</rs>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="493"/> --Parties owning registered <num value="0.08">eight per cent.</num> bonds under the act of <dateStruct value="1861-05-16"><month reg="05">May</month> <day reg="16">16</day>, <year reg="1861">1861</year></dateStruct>, desiring to exchange them for <rs n="coupon bond" type="product">coupon bonds</rs>, will assign them, in the manner pointed out in the printed endorsement on the back of the certificate, to the &#x0022;<placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States of America</placeName>, in exchange for <rs n="coupon bond" type="product">coupon bonds</rs>,&#x0022; and cause them to be presented to the <name>Register</name> of the <orgName n="Treasury Department" type="department">Treasury Department</orgName>, who will thereupon, in compliance with the provisions of the act of <dateStruct value="1864-06-13"><month reg="06">June</month> <day reg="13">13</day>, <year reg="1864">1864</year></dateStruct>, issue <rs n="coupon bond" type="product">coupon bonds</rs> for the amount specified in the <rs n="registered bond" type="product">registered bonds</rs> so assigned. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Trenholm,,G.,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00333" reg="default:Trenholm,G.,A.,,"><foreName>G.</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName>  <surname>Trenholm</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <signed><rs type="role" reg="Secretary of the Treasury">Secretary of the Treasury</rs>.</signed> <term type="printrun">ja 2--ts</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="3"> 
<head><hi rend="smallcaps"><orgName n="Treasury Department" type="department">Treasury Department</orgName>,</hi><lb/>Confederate State of <placeName reg="America, Walker, Alabama" key="tgn,2002460">America</placeName>,<lb/><hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 11" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName>,</hi> <dateStruct value="1864-10-12"><month reg="10">October</month> <day reg="12">12</day>, <year reg="1864">1864</year></dateStruct>.<lb/>non-taxable bonds, <num value="500000000">five hundred-million</num> loan.--sale continued.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="494"/> --Numerous applications having been made for bonds at the established price of <measure n="135dollars" type="currency">one hundred and thirty-five dollars</measure> and interest, under circumstances that entitle them to favorable consideration, it has been determined to continue the sale at the above price until further notice. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="495"/> Agents for the salve of these Bonds are instructed to act in accordance with this order; and the attention of disbursing officers of the <rs>Government</rs> is particularly called to it. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Trenholm,,G.,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00334" reg="default:Trenholm,G.,A.,,"><foreName>G.</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName>  <surname>Trenholm</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <signed><rs type="role" reg="Secretary of the Treasury">Secretary of the Treasury</rs>.</signed> <term type="printrun">ja 2--ts</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="4"> 
<head><hi rend="smallcaps"><orgName n="Treasury Department" type="department">Treasury Department</orgName>,</hi><lb/><hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States of America</placeName>,</hi><lb/>loans on the security of the <num value="5000000.06">five hundred million Six Per Cent</num>, non-taxable bonds, under the <orgName type="regiment" key="7Section">Seventh section</orgName> of the currency law.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="496"/> --Deposits on call will be received by the <rs>Treasurer</rs> in this city, <rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Treasurer">Assistant Treasurers</rs> at <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName> and <placeName reg="Mobile, Mobile, Alabama" key="tgn,7017444">Mobile</placeName>, and the <name>Depositaries</name> at <placeName reg="Wilmington, New Hanover, North Carolina" key="tgn,7014631">Wilmington</placeName>, <placeName reg="Raleigh, Wake, North Carolina" key="tgn,7013949">Raleigh</placeName>, <placeName reg="Columbia, Richland, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013641">Columbia</placeName>, <placeName reg="Augusta, Richmond, Georgia" key="tgn,7017498">Augusta</placeName>, <placeName reg="Savannah, Chatham, Georgia" key="tgn,7014487">Savannah</placeName> and <persName n="Montgomery,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00335" reg="mostcommon:Montgomery,nomatch:0"><surname>Montgomery</surname></persName>, and certificates will be issued for the same, bearing interest at the rate of <num value="0.04">four per cent.</num> per annum, and secured by the hypothecation of an amount of the above bonds equal to the sum of these loans.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="497"/>The bonds to be set apart by the <rs>Treasurer</rs>, and the proceeds, when sold, applied exclusively to the payment of the said certificates. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="498"/> The security and convenience afforded to banks and other corporations, and to the public generally, by this mode of temporary investment, and the effect of the measure, if generally adopted, in keeping the currency within moderate bounds, it is hoped will commend it to the favorable consideration of the community and secure their prompt co-operation in carrying unto effect. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Trenholm,,G.,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00336" reg="default:Trenholm,G.,A.,,"><foreName>G.</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName>  <surname>Trenholm</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <signed><rs type="role" reg="Secretary of the Treasury">Secretary of the Treasury</rs>.</signed> <term type="printrun">ja 2--ts</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="5"> 
<head><hi rend="smallcaps"><orgName n="Treasury Department" type="department">Treasury Department</orgName>,</hi><lb/><hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States of America</placeName>,</hi><lb/><placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 11" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName>, <dateStruct value="1864-07-28"><month reg="07">July</month> <day reg="28">28</day>, <year reg="1864">1864</year></dateStruct>.<lb/>Taxed Treasury notes.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="499"/> --In order to promote, as far as practicable, the early liquidation by the <name>Treasury</name> of the <rs>Outstanding Taxed</rs> notes, the <rs>Treasurer</rs>, <rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Treasurer">Assistant Treasurer</rs>, and Pay Depositaries in the different States, are hereby authorized to receive the said notes, except the <measure n="100dollars" type="currency">$100</measure> notes, at <num value="66">66</num> &#x2154; per centum, on deposit, issuing for same certificates of loan, upon hypothecation of non-taxable bonds.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="500"/>The said certificates to be payable on demand after the expiration of <measure n="90days" type="date">ninety days</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="501"/> And all agents for the sale of the above bonds are hereby authorized to receive the taxed notes, with the exception above named, in payment of bonds, when sold, at the rate of <num value="66">66</num> &#x2154; per centum. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Trenholm,,G.,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00337" reg="default:Trenholm,G.,A.,,"><foreName>G.</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName>  <surname>Trenholm</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <signed><rs type="role" reg="Secretary of the Treasury">Secretary of the Treasury</rs>.</signed> <term type="printrun">ja 2--ts</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="6"> 
<head><hi rend="smallcaps"><orgName n="Treasury Department" type="department">Treasury Department</orgName>,</hi><lb/>Confederate State of <placeName reg="America, Walker, Alabama" key="tgn,2002460">America</placeName>,<lb/><hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 11" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName>,</hi> <dateStruct value="1864-12-01"><month reg="12">December</month> <day reg="1">1</day>, <year reg="1864">1864</year></dateStruct>.<lb/><num value="7">seven</num>-<num value="30">thirty</num> Treasury notes.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="502"/> --In pursuance of an act of Congress, approved <dateStruct value="1864-11-28"><month reg="11">November</month> <day reg="28">28</day>, <year reg="1864">1864</year></dateStruct>, entitled &#x0022;An act to authorize the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of the Treasury">Secretary of the Treasury</rs> to exchange <rs n="coupon bond" type="product">coupon bonds</rs> for <num value="7">seven</num>-<num value="30">thirty</num> treasury notes,&#x0022; holders of such notes are hereby notified that after the payment of the annual interest due thereon on the <dateStruct value="1865-01-1"><day reg="1">first</day> day of <month reg="01">January</month>, <year>1865</year>,</dateStruct> upon presentation of the same, the <rs>Treasurer</rs>, <rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Treasurer">Assistant Treasurers</rs> and Pay Depositaries (as designated at foot) will issue certificates therefore, which will entitle the holders to <rs n="coupon bond" type="product">coupon bonds</rs> payable <measure n="30years" type="date">thirty years</measure> after the <dateStruct value="1865-01-1"><day reg="1">first</day> day of <month reg="01">January</month>, <year>1865</year>,</dateStruct> bearing <num value="0.06">six per cent.</num> interest from the said <dateStruct value="1864-01-1"><day reg="1">first</day> of <month reg="01">January</month>, <year>1864</year>,</dateStruct> payable on the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> days of <dateStruct value="-01-"><month reg="01">January</month></dateStruct> and <dateStruct value="-07-"><month reg="07">July</month></dateStruct> in each year.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="503"/>The Treasurer, <rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Treasurer">Assistant Treasurers</rs> and Depositaries will make weekly reports to the <name>Register</name> of the <name>Treasury</name> of such certificates issued at their offices, whereupon bonds will be sent forward in satisfaction of same.--The notes will be cancelled in the usual manner and forwarded to the <num value="1" type="ordinal">First</num> Auditor. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Trenholm,,G.,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00338" reg="default:Trenholm,G.,A.,,"><foreName>G.</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName>  <surname>Trenholm</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <signed><rs type="role" reg="Secretary of the Treasury">Secretary of Treasury</rs>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>Treasurer at <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Virginia</placeName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed><rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Treasurer">Assistant Treasurers</rs> at <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName> and <placeName reg="Mobile, Mobile, Alabama" key="tgn,7017444">Mobile</placeName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>Depositaries at <placeName reg="Raleigh, Wake, North Carolina" key="tgn,7013949">Raleigh</placeName> and <placeName reg="Wilmington, New Hanover, North Carolina" key="tgn,7014631">Wilmington, North Carolina</placeName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>Depositaries at <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName> and <placeName reg="Columbia, Richland, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013641">Columbia, South Carolina</placeName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>Depositaries at <placeName reg="Savannah, Chatham, Georgia" key="tgn,7014487">Savannah</placeName> and <persName n="Georgia,,Augusta,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00339" reg="default:Georgia,Augusta,,,"><foreName>Augusta</foreName> <surname>Georgia</surname></persName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>Depositaries at <placeName reg="Tallahassee, Leon, Florida" key="tgn,7013938">Tallahassee, Florida</placeName>, and <placeName reg="Montgomery, Montgomery, Alabama" key="tgn,7013928">Montgomery, Alabama</placeName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>Depositaries at <placeName reg="Columbus, Lowndes, Mississippi" key="tgn,2056204">Columbus, Mississippi</placeName>, and <placeName reg="Houston, Harris, Texas" key="tgn,7013727">Houston</placeName> and <placeName reg="Marshall, Harrison, Texas" key="tgn,2105926">Marshall, Texas</placeName>.</signed> <term type="printrun">ja 2--ts</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="military"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="orders" n="1"> 
<head><hi rend="smallcaps"><orgName n="Navy Department" type="department">Navy Department</orgName>,</hi><lb/><hi rend="smallcaps">Office Special service.</hi><lb/><hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Va.</placeName>,</hi><dateStruct value="1864-09-19"><month reg="09">September</month> <day reg="19">19</day>, <year reg="1864">1864</year></dateStruct></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="504"/>Notice.--From and after Monday Next, the <dateStruct value="--26"><day reg="26">26th instant</day></dateStruct>, the <term type="ship">Steamer</term> <rs type="ship">Shrapnel</rs> will leave the wharf at <placeName key="tgn,2625188" n="1.000 10" reg="Rocketts, Henrico, Virginia">Rocketts</placeName> for the <orgName n="James River Squadron" type="squadron">James River Squadron</orgName> daily at <time value="7am">7 o'clock A. M.</time> and <time value="3pm">3 o'clock P. M.</time>, touching at all the principal landings on the river. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Parker,,John,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00340" reg="expanded:Parker,"><foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName>  <surname>Parker</surname></persName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed><rs type="role2">Lieutenant</rs> in charge.</signed> <term type="printrun">oc 20--ts</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="505"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> </back> </text> </TEI.2>
