<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> <!DOCTYPE TEI.2 PUBLIC "-//TEI P4//DTD Main DTD Driver File//EN" "http://www.tei-c.org/Guidelines/DTD/tei2.dtd" [ <!ENTITY % TEI.XML "INCLUDE"> <!ENTITY % PersProse PUBLIC "-//Perseus P4//DTD Perseus Prose//EN" "http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/DTD/1.0/PersProse.dtd" > %PersProse; <!NOTATION jpg SYSTEM "JPEG"> <!ENTITY NW_RichTimesD_025_059_001 SYSTEM "NW_RichTimesD_025_059_001.jpg" NDATA jpg> <!ENTITY NW_RichTimesD_025_059_002 SYSTEM "NW_RichTimesD_025_059_002.jpg" NDATA jpg> ]> <TEI.2 id="NW_RichTimesD_025_059"> <teiHeader type="aacr2"> <fileDesc> <titleStmt> <title type="245">The Daily Dispatch: September 8, 1863. </title> <title type="gmd">[Electronic resource] </title> <funder> Institute of Museum and Library Services National Leadership Grant </funder> <respStmt> <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> <resp>Creation of digital images: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> <resp>Conversion to Tei.2-conformant markup: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> </respStmt> </titleStmt> <extent>ca. <num value="30">XXX</num> kilobytes </extent> <publicationStmt> <publisher>University of <orgName n="Richmond Library" type="library">Richmond Library</orgName> </publisher> <pubPlace>Richmond, Virginia </pubPlace> <idno type="Url">Nw_richtimesd_025_059</idno> <availability> 
<p>&#x00A9; 2004 by the University of Richmond. </p> 
<p>Url: http://oncampus.Richmond.edu/academics/Library/digital/ </p> </availability> <date> </date> </publicationStmt> <seriesStmt> 
<p>Institute of Museum and Library Services Civil War Newspaper Project </p> </seriesStmt> <notesStmt> <note>page images have been included from the microfilm version. </note> <note>images were scanned with a Sunrise 2000 scanner from microfilm, at 14x reduction ratio at 400 dpi Optical Resolution. Creation Software: Pixel Translations. Pixtiff version 1.135. </note> <note>Ddd note: shipped: 2005_04_01_ddd_url. </note> </notesStmt> <sourceDesc> <biblFull> <titleStmt> <title type="245">The Daily Dispatch: September 8, 1863. </title> <title type="246"><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName> </title> <respStmt> <resp> </resp> <name> </name> </respStmt> </titleStmt> <editionStmt> 
<p> </p> </editionStmt> <extent>2 pages. </extent> <publicationStmt> <publisher>by Cowardin &#x0026; Hammersley. </publisher> <pubPlace>Richmond </pubPlace> <date value="1863-09-08">September 8, 1863</date><idno type="vol">25.59</idno> </publicationStmt> <seriesStmt> <title> </title> </seriesStmt> <notesStmt> <note>microfilm. Ann Arbor, Mi : Proquest. 1 microfilm reel ; 35 mm. </note> </notesStmt> </biblFull> </sourceDesc> </fileDesc> <encodingDesc> <projectDesc> 
<p>Imls Civil War Newspaper Project. </p> </projectDesc> <editorialDecl> 
<p>the images exist as archival Tiff images, with Jpeg versions for internet access. </p> </editorialDecl> <refsDecl> <state unit="article" /> </refsDecl> <classDecl> <taxonomy id="lcsh"> <bibl> <title>Library of Congress subject Headings, </title> <edition>21st edition, 1998</edition> </bibl> </taxonomy> </classDecl> </encodingDesc> <profileDesc> <creation> <date value="1863">1863 </date> </creation> <langUsage> <language id="eng">English </language> </langUsage> 
<textClass> <keywords scheme="lcsh"> 
<list type="simple"> 
<item>Newspapers -- Virginia -- Richmond</item> </list> </keywords> </textClass> </profileDesc> <revisionDesc> <change> <date>September, 2005 </date> <respStmt> <resp>Checker </resp> <name>Grant Dickie, of the University of <orgName n="Richmond Library" type="library">Richmond Library</orgName> </name> </respStmt> 
<item>File checked, not corrected: DO NOT return to vendor. </item> </change> </revisionDesc> </teiHeader> 
<text id="NW_RichTimesD_025_059T"> <front> <milestone unit="page" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="page-image"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="1"/><figure entity="NW_RichTimesD_025_059_001"> <figDesc>Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume <num value="25">25</num>, <num value="59">Number 59</num>, <ref n="page 1">page 1</ref>. </figDesc> </figure></p> </div1> <titlePage> <docTitle><titlePart type="main"> Daily Dispatch </titlePart> </docTitle> <docImprint> Vol. Xxv &mdash; no.<num value="59">59</num> <pubPlace> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Va.</placeName> </pubPlace> <date value="1863-09-08">Tuesday, September 8, 1863</date> <persName n="Price,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00001" reg="mostcommon:Price,nomatch:0"><surname>Price</surname></persName> <num value="1">one</num> cent </docImprint> </titlePage> 
<div1 type="subscription"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName><lb/> by <persName n="Cowardin,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00002" reg="mostcommon:Cowardin,nomatch:0"><surname>Cowardin</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="Hammersley,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00003" reg="mostcommon:Hammersley,nomatch:0"><surname>Hammersley</surname></persName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="2"/>the <rs>Daily Dispatch</rs> is served to subscribers at <measure n="6.25cents" type="currency">six and A Quarter cents</measure> per Week, payable to the <name>Carrier</name> weekly.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="3"/><persName n="Price,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00004" reg="mostcommon:Price,nomatch:0"><surname>Price</surname></persName> for mailing, <measure n="4dollars" type="currency">$4</measure> a year, or <measure n="2.50dollars" type="currency">$2.50</measure> for <measure n="6months" type="date">six months</measure>, in advance.</p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="4"/>the <rs>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</rs> is issued every <dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> and <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> at <measure n="2.00dollars" type="currency">$2.00</measure>, in advance.</p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="5"/>the <rs>Weekly Dispatch</rs> is issued every <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct>, and mailed to subscribers at <measure n="1dollars" type="currency">$1</measure> per annum.</p> </div1> 
<div1 type="advertising"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="6"/> 
<table rows="4" cols="4"> 
<head rend="italics">Terms of Advertising.</head> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <num value="1">1</num> day,</cell><cell><measure n="0.50dollars" type="currency">$0.50</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="5days" type="date">5 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="1.50dollars" type="currency">$1.50</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="2days" type="date">2 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="0.75dollars" type="currency">$0.75</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="5days" type="date">5 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="1.75dollars" type="currency">$1.75</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square <measure n="3days" type="date">3 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="1.00dollars" type="currency">$1.00</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="12days" type="date">12 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="3.00dollars" type="currency">$3.00</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square <measure n="4days" type="date">4 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="1.25dollars" type="currency">$1.25</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <dateStruct value="-1-"><month reg="1">1 month</month></dateStruct>,</cell><cell><measure n="5.00dollars" type="currency">$5.00</measure></cell></row> </table></p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="7"/><hi rend="italics">Larger advertisements in exact properties.</hi></p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="8"/>Advertisements published until forbid, will be charged <measure n="50cents" type="currency">50 cents</measure> per square of <num value="8">eight</num> lines for the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> insertion, and <measure n="25cents" type="currency">25 cents</measure> for each continuance</p> </div1> </front> <body> <milestone unit="column" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.</head> 
<div2 type="morning"> 
<head><date value="1863-09-08">Tuesday morning..September 8, 1863.</date></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>Governor's Message.</head> <opener> <dateline> <orgName n="Department of the Executive" type="government">Executive Department</orgName>,<lb/><placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Va.</placeName>, <dateStruct value="1863-09-07"><month reg="09">Sept.</month> <day reg="7">7</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="9"/> <hi rend="italics">Gentlemen of the <name>Senate</name><lb/>and <orgName n="House of Delegates" type="government">House of Delegates</orgName>.</hi> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="10"/> In this crisis I have deemed it advisable to convene you in extraordinary session, in order that the freshly chosen representatives of the people may consult and devise such measures as will be calculated to meet the existing emergency in public affairs.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="11"/>The war has now been in progress for more than <measure n="2.5years" type="date">two years and a half</measure>, and has been presented against us with a ferocity unparallel in all past struggles between contending parties.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="12"/>It has been conducted upon the avowed principle of subjugating in either by force of arms or by visiting upon our people the horrors of famine, Hence it is that foiled and defeated again and again upon the field of battle, they have adopted the policy of desolating our farms, destroying our crops, burning our dwellings, stealing and carrying away our property, leaving our wives and children to perish by the slow torture of starvation.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="13"/>It is no longer a war for the preservation of the old Union, as it was originally proclaimed to be, but it has degenerated into a war-for the emancipation of our slaves; and this purpose the <name>Administration</name> at <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName> propose to accomplish even if the extermination of the white race, of all ages, sexes, and conditions; of the <orgName n="Southern Confederacy" type="newspaper">Southern Confederacy</orgName>, shall be the result.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="14"/>We have no alter native, therefore, but to defend ourselves with all the power, energy, and ability, we can command.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="15"/>We must succeed, if we would be a free and independent people, worthy of the illustrious ancestry from which we descended.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="16"/>To succeed, we must have union, harmony, concert, conciliation, courage, energy, and determined resolution on the part of rulers and people.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="17"/>We must cultivate <num value="1">one</num> to wards another the noble virtues of prudence, toleration, charity, and forbearance. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="18"/> With these <rs n="General Remarks" type="misc">general remarks</rs> I proceed to the consideration of such subjects as are of special interest at this time, and in my judgment demand legislative action. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="19"/> The subject <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> in importance, so far as the <rs>Commonwealth</rs> is concerned, is the best means of providing and adequate force for the local defence of the <rs>State</rs> against invasion or raids, and for the execution of the laws in case a resort to force shall at any time become necessary The entire military force of the <rs>State</rs> has been absorbed by the conscription law, and we are thus left, in a time of greatest peril, with no militia organization for the defence of the <rs>Commonwealth</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="20"/>This want can be and must be supplied with as little delay as practicable. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="21"/> As to the plan of raising this force I an aware there is much diversity of opinion.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="22"/>The difference, however, is reconcilable if the subject is considered and discussed in a patriotic spirit. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="23"/> Let a force, to consist of all able-bodied persons between the ages of <num value="16">sixteen</num> and <num value="60">sixty</num>, not in the <rs>Confederate</rs> service, be organized, corresponding with the force now organized in the cities of <placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 6" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName>, <placeName reg="Petersburg, Petersburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7014404">Petersburg</placeName> and <placeName reg="Lynchburg, Lynchburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013981">Lynchburg</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="24"/>Let them be regularly enrolled, formed into companies, battalions, and regiments, and officered in such manner as will be most likely to secure efficient, intelligent, and energetic men. They should be drilled at proper intervals, so as to be well instructed in the evolutions and the manual, and prepared for efficient service whenever the necessity shall arise.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="25"/>The act should also define what is local defence, as there is much contrariety of opinion in regard to it. Some think local defence consists in remaining at home, and under no circumstances to be taken out of the city or county in which the company is organized.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="26"/>This, in my view, is a most mistaken nation of the meaning of the term &#x0022;local defence,&#x0022; and if it is to prevail will work great mischief and render the organization of little value in giving protection to our people.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="27"/>My opinion is that if the city of <placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 6" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName> can be defended more certainly <measure n="50miles" type="distance">fifty miles</measure> from it than immediately around it or in it, that locality is the proper place for its defence, and the local militia should be required to make the defence there.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="28"/>The officer charged with the defence of any particular locality is presumed to be better acquainted with the mode of defending it, and the best point of defending it successfully, and he should direct all troops so as best to secure the end desired. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="29"/> The object of such organizations should be to give adequate protection to all parts of the <rs>Commonwealth</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="30"/>We must not only provide for the defence of the counties, cities and towns, by the local forces in and immediately around them, but we must, under the law which is proposed to be passed, have authority to order others from contiguous counties to their all and support.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="31"/>A force, whose operations is to be confined by county, city or town boundaries, can prove of but little value in checking raids, or in executing and enforcing obedience to the laws. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="32"/> This organization should be made to embrace the foreign population who are located amongst us. This foreign population may be said to consist of <num value="3">three</num> classes: <num value="1" type="ordinal">First</num>, those who have been regularly naturalized, and who are therefore citizens embraced by our laws relating to the public defence.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="33"/><num value="2" type="ordinal">Second</num>, those who are domiciliated amongst us, and have been living in our midst and prosecuting various branches of business, and left their native land with no purpose or intention of returning to it; and lastly, those who are temporarily sojourning amongst us. The <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> class are in service under our militia laws, and the <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> class should be required to go into service for public defence of the soil on which they reside.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="34"/>The latter class, who are sojourners, engaged in no regular business, should be exempt.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="35"/>I recommend, therefore, that in your legislation upon this subject, the <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> class above referred to shall be clearly and distinctly embraced. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="36"/> On this subject I desire to present another recommendation, in regard to the act passed by your predecessors on the <dateStruct value="1862-11-20"><day reg="20">20th</day> day of <month reg="11">November</month>, <year>1862</year>,</dateStruct> authorizing persons of certain religious denominations in the <rs>State</rs> to exempt themselves from military service in the war, by the payment of <measure n="500dollars" type="currency">five hundred dollars</measure> each, Subsequently Congress passed an act of like character; and these persons availed themselves of it, and were discharged from liability to all military service in the <milestone unit="column" n="2"/> <orgName n="Confederate Army" type="org">Confederate army</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="37"/>I regard this provision as substantially a violation of the <rs>Constitution</rs>, inasmuch as it grants exemptions to certain classes of persons, which are not granted to others. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="38"/> In this war all classes who reside amongst us should be required to perform duty of some sort, if they are with in the military age. If they are unwilling to bear arms, there are various other duties connected with the army and the general defence which they can perform, and which they should be required to perform.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="39"/>They are citizens, property holders to a large extent, interested therefore in all that concerns other citizens, and should be required to perform their part.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="40"/>In some countries this class or persons are required to aid in the construction of fortifications, and I see no just reason why they should not be required to do so here.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="41"/>This branch of defence must be maintained by somebody; and if their religious convictions will not allow them to go into the ranks for the defence and maintenance of the common cause, why cannot they do this? </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="42"/> It will not do to say that they are opposed to war, and can do nothing that will tend to its prosecution.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="43"/>The law is based upon the principle that they are bound to do something &mdash; otherwise they would not be taxed the sum of <measure n="500dollars" type="currency">$500</measure> each.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="44"/>That money goes into the <name>Treasury</name>, and is drawn therefrom to defray the expenses of the war, and to this extent, at least, they are aiding and supporting it. If they can aid to the extent of <measure n="500dollars" type="currency">five hundred dollar</measure> in money, can they not aid by labor or other service? </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="45"/> A state of war imposes a personal obligation upon every citizen within the military age, and he should be required to discharge it. When the country is invaded, our dwellings burned, our lands laid waste, our property destroyed or carried away, our citizens imprisoned, it is their duty to step forward promptly and aid in repelling the invader.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="46"/>Ministers and members of other religious denominations, equally as conscientious, are in the field.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="47"/>I recommend; therefore, that this law be repealed. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="48"/> Besides these provisions, stringent regulations should be adopted to prevent desertion or struggling from service with out leave.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="49"/>It ought to be made the duty of the local militia to arrest any officer or soldier found abroad from his corps without a furlough, and cause him to be forthwith returned to his position or delivered to the nearest <rs type="role" reg="Provost Marshal">Provost Marshal</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="50"/>The officers in command in any city or county through which such persons might be passing or sojourning might be invested with like authority, and be clothed with power to detail a sufficient number of men to make the arrest effective, and to compel the parties in default to render the service to which they are liable.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="51"/>It might also with propriety be made the duty of company officers, at regular intervals, to report all persons who have not been exempted and who are liable to conscription, that our armies may be kept full and efficient, and at all times be prepared to meet and repel the enemy.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="52"/>Any act you may pass should provide for the speedy and certain punishment of all who fail or refuse to obey lawful orders, and prescribe some mode for the removal of incompetent or unfaithful officers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="53"/>The experience of the last <measure n="2years" type="date">two years</measure> renders legislation upon this subject necessary. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="54"/> The time has come when it is absolutely indispensable that we should omit nothing which promises protection to our people and success to our cause.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="55"/>An unscrupulous enemy is pursuing us with a spirit of malignity and vindictiveness that respects neither the rights of persons nor of property.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="56"/>We must be active and untiring in our efforts to repel him; and to accomplish this we must call forth all our able-bodied men, and prepare them for the most efficient service. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="57"/> No army can expect a continued current of success.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="58"/>We may &mdash; nay, we must expect to meet with reverses, and we must be prepared for them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="59"/>Instead of discouraging, they should only stimulate us to increased efforts &mdash; should call forth redoubled energy &mdash; should bind us more closely together, and inspire us with a more determined spirit and courage.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="60"/>If our forefathers had permitted reverses to crush their spirit or paralyze their energies and efforts, the <rs n="American" type="group">American</rs> Revolution never would have proved a success, and the independence of our country would never have been achieved.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="61"/>They passed through storms and trials far greater than any that have fallen to us in this contest.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="62"/>The men, old and young, sustained and supported the cause with hearty good will; and as the clouds gathered and the prospect of success seemed to grow more desperate and hopeless, they became more and more resolved and determined.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="63"/>The noble women of that day, while their fathers, husbands, and sons were engaged in fighting the battles and driving back the invader, planted and gathered the crops by which the army was sustained.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="64"/>We have not been reduced to such straits yet, nor is it probable we shall be. But the women of the present day have shown a self-sacrificing spirit, inducing them incessantly to work, and showing that they are ready to emulate such an example.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="65"/>They have displayed a generous devotion, which should awake the sluggards and animate and cheer the gloomy and desponding. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="66"/> There are in all communities some people whose eyes always fall on the dark side of every picture, and who are disposed to succumb at even the indications of disaster.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="67"/>It would be remarkable if we had not some such amongst us; but it is gratifying to know that the number is very small, even in those portions of our State which have been overrun by the enemy.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="68"/>The spirit and courage of the large mass of the people has never flagged.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="69"/>Each new wrong has inspired new resolution.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="70"/><persName n="Bach,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00005" reg="mostcommon:Bach,nomatch:0"><surname>Bach</surname></persName> new out rage has but nerved them for a more determined and desperate struggle in behalf of the cause.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="71"/><placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> went into this contest after the most serious and calm consideration, with a firm resolve to do her whole duty to herself and her confederate sisters &mdash; to take all the consequences, however horrible they might be. Her people have never quailed &mdash; nor have they murmured under the repeated wrongs and aggressions they have suffered.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="72"/>She was not the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> to enter this struggle, nor will she be the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> to sue for peace, unless that peace shall be accompanied by an unqualified recognition of the independence of the <orgName n="Southern Confederacy" type="newspaper">Southern Confederacy</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="73"/> The report of the <rs type="role" reg="Adjutant General">Adjutant General</rs>, <milestone unit="column" n="3"/> accompanied by a bill, is herewith submitted, and to it your attention is respectfully invited.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="74"/><persName n="Richardson,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00006" reg="mostcommon:Richardson,A.,W.,,:1"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Richardson</surname></persName>'s intelligence and experience in all military matters entitle his views to great respect, and I confidently commend them to your favorable consideration. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="75"/> The <orgName n="General Assembly" type="misc">General Assembly</orgName>, at its last session, prescribed that no Confederate issues of a date anterior to <date value="1863-04-06">April 6th, 1863</date> should be received in payment of State taxes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="76"/>I am unable to comprehend either the wisdom or policy of this legislation.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="77"/>It is calculated to impair confidence in the currency of the <orgName n="Confederate Government" type="org">Confederate Government</orgName>, and, indeed, in almost the only currency in circulation in the greater portion of the <rs>State</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="78"/>If these issues are not to be receivable in payment of State taxes it is inferable, at least by those who are not fully informed in regard to such questions, that it is because those issues are not as valuable as subsequent issues by the <rs>Government</rs>, or for some cause or other they have not been considered a safe or reliable circulating medium.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="79"/>No matter what caused the exclusion, it is perfectly plain that the effect has been to depredate the currency and to arouse in the public mind the suspicion that it will not ultimately be redeemed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="80"/>Very few persons in ordinary business transactions stop to examine the particular date of a note which they are about to receive.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="81"/>Very few can remember the particular date of the note discredited by the law. The consequence is, as soon as they ascertain that notes of some dates are not receivable in payment of taxes, and they do not know which, they become shy of receiving any, and all are discredited.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="82"/>When they are told that some of the banks will not receive them on deposit, and that some of the railroad and other transportation companies will not receive them for fare or freight, they of course refuse to receive them, and a general depreciation ensues, which it will be found next to impossible thereafter to prevent. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="83"/> In very many cases this money has been paid to our soldiers, and by them sent home to pay their taxes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="84"/>Some such cases have been brought to my knowledge; and the persons who were in this situation, on finding that it was not receivable in payment of State taxes, have very naturally complained.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="85"/>If the money was good enough to pay the soldier, who receives but <measure n="11dollars" type="currency">eleven dollars</measure> per month, why is it not good enough to satisfy the claim of the <rs>State</rs> when her agent applies for State dues?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="86"/>We have no <orgName n="State Bank" type="bank">State bank</orgName> circulation, we have no State Treasury note circulation; both of these descriptions of notes having been hoarded as fast as they could be collected by moneyed men. The consequence, therefore, is, that the holders of the repudiated Confederate issues are driven to the necessity of shaving off those they have, in order to procure such as will enable them to meet the demands of the <rs>State</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="87"/>While it was not the intention of the <name>Legislature</name> to place the tax-payers in this condition such is inevitably its effect. --They must have such money as will answer the purpose, and to obtain it they must apply to such persons as have it, and must pay them such price in these rejected Confederate issues as will command it. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="88"/> The only reason I have ever heard assigned in justification of this legislation is, that it was designed to force persons holding this currency to fund in Confederate bonds, and thus retire it from circulation.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="89"/>This would all be very well if every man who had these issues in hand had no use for them either for the support of his family or the payment of debts.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="90"/>It unfortunately happens, however, for this theory, that <num value="4">four</num> <num value=".2">fifths</num> of the community have no money to invest.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="91"/>All they receive they have present and pressing use for, to relieve their daily wants and the wants of those dependent upon them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="92"/>Funding, with all such, is therefore an impossibility, and the circulation thus rejected cannot be retired in this way. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="93"/> Congress, feeling the difficulty, and desirous to compel the funding, passed an act which provides that all notes of issues previous to <date value="1862-12-01">December 1st, 1862, </date> should be fundable in <num value="0.08">eight per cent</num> bonds, if presented by the <date value="1863-04- 22">22d day of April, 1863,</date> if not presented by that day, but presented before the <date value="1863-08-01">1st of August, 1863,</date> they were then fundable in <num value="0.07">seven per cent</num> bonds; and these issues are not fundable at all after the <date value="08-01">1st of August.</date> Notes issued after <date value="1862-12-01">December 1st, 1862,</date> are fundable in <num value="0.07">seven per cent</num> bonds until <date value="1863-08-01">August 1st, 1863,</date> and after that date in <num value="0.04">four per cent</num> bonds.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="94"/>Notes issued after <date value="1863-04-01">April 1st, 1863,</date> are fundable in <num value="0.06">six per cent.</num> bonds if presented in <measure n="12months" type="date">twelve months</measure> from their is she; but if not so presented, they are fundable in <num value="0.04">four per cent.</num> bonds.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="95"/>This looks to me very much like a repudiation to some extent of the obligations assumed by the <rs>Government</rs>; and it is not, therefore, surprising that such legislation should have created uneasiness in the public mind, and aided in bringing about depreciation, and a want of confidence in the ultimate payment of these obligations. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="96"/> Other legislation on the part of Congress has tended strongly to produce the same conclusion in the public mind.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="97"/>The mode in which taxes are to be assessed upon credits in certain contingencies, may be mentioned as <num value="1">one</num> that tends directly to the discredit of the currency Better far would it have been to make these issues a legal tender in payment of debts than to resort to a compulsory process like this to force its reception by the creditor; and while this is being done our Legislature is urged to reject the same paper issues in payment of State taxes! </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="98"/> When the <rs>Government</rs> casts suspicion upon its currency, and the <rs>State Governments</rs>, and the <name>Banks</name>, and Railroad Companies do the same thing, then the people may well become alarmed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="99"/>The consequences cannot fail to be most disastrous.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="100"/>We cannot change the action of Congress, but we can remedy the errors of our own legislation, and thus show that we are disposed to uphold the credit and currency of the <rs>Confederacy</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="101"/> The appropriation for the support of the convicts in the <name>Penitentiary</name> is exhausted, and it is necessary that further provision be made at the earliest moment for their maintenance during the year.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="102"/>This is owing to the fact that the prices of all articles necessary for the convicts have greatly increased, and are still advancing.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="103"/>The condition of the country must be kept steadily in view when legislating on subjects of this kind, and we must, <unclear></unclear> regulating appropriations, bear in mind that all articles of prime necessity have increased, and will continue to increase, unless some speedy measures are adopted to reduce the redundancy of the currency.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="104"/>Besides, the convicts are increasing, and the experience of the last <measure n="6months" type="date">six months</measure> warrants the conclusion that the number will be uncommonly large before the close of the year.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="105"/>The legitimate offspring of a state of war are lawlessness and crime, and during its continuance, therefore, we may reasonably calculate upon an unusual increase of convicts.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="106"/>There are now nearly <num value="350">three hundred and fifty</num> confined in a prison intended originally to accommodate <dateStruct value="250"><year reg="250">two hundred and fifty</year></dateStruct>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="107"/> In previous messages I have earnestly invited the attention of the <name>Legislature</name> to the affairs of the <name>Penitentiary</name>, and the management of the institution and the convicts.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="108"/>I have always believed, and still think, that with prudent, judicious, and energetic management, the labor of the convicts would support the institution, and pay a handsome revenue into the <name>Treasury</name> annually.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="109"/>I take pleasure in saying that under the present Superintendent the discipline and management is greatly improved.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="110"/>I have heretofore submitted various recommendations in my communications to the two Houses; and <milestone unit="column" n="4"/> without repeating those recommendation I will content myself with calling attention to them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="111"/>They are accessible to all having been published in the documents of the past <measure n="3years" type="date">three years</measure>. In this connection, I also invite your attention to the very able report on this subject prepared by <persName n="Haymond,Commissioner,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00007" reg="mostcommon:Haymond,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Commissioner">Commissioners</roleName> <surname>Haymond</surname></persName>, <persName n="Johnston,Commissioner,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00008" reg="mostcommon:Johnston,S.,V.,,:1"><roleName n="Commissioner"></roleName><surname>Johnston</surname></persName>, and <persName n="Campbell,Commissioner,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00009" reg="mostcommon:Campbell,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Commissioner"></roleName><surname>Campbell</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="112"/>This report contains recommendations and suggestions of much value and importance, and I commend them to your favorable consideration. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="113"/> This is a matter of practical importance, and requires early attention.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="114"/>The interests of the <rs>State</rs> demand that the reforming hand of the <name>Legislature</name> should be applied to it.--With a regular supply of raw material, so as to keep the convicts constantly employed, and with an intelligent and judicious application of their labor, we may reasonably <unclear></unclear> that the institution will be self sustaining, it no more. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="115"/> I submit the report of <persName n="Edward,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00010" reg="mostcommon:Edward,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Capt.</roleName> <surname>Edward</surname></persName>. <persName n="Fitzhugh,,H.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00011" reg="default:Fitzhugh,H.,,,"><foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Fitzhugh</surname></persName>, now in charge of the <orgName><rs type="role" reg="Quartermaster-General">Quartermaster General</rs>'s office</orgName>, to which I invite your attention.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="116"/>It presents a clear and succinct statement of the condition of affairs in that office from the organization of the <rs>State</rs> line forces to the present time, and will doubtless be read with great interest, especially when it is recollected that just before the <placeName reg="State">State</placeName> Line troops were disbarred it was quite currently charged that the entire appropriation had been expended.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="117"/>This report shows that the sum of <num value="1000002">one million two</num> <unclear></unclear> <measure n="25000dollars" type="currency">twenty-five thousand dollars</measure> had been drawn from the treasury for that department, and that since the force was disbanded <num value="616">six hundred and sixteen</num> <unclear></unclear> <num value="517">five hundred and seventeen</num> dollars<unclear>..</unclear> <measure n="92cents" type="currency">ninety-two cents</measure> had been refunded, leaving the actual cost of the <rs>State</rs> line forces so far as that department is concerned, <measure n="608482.08dollars" type="currency">six hundred and eight thousand four hundred and eighty two dollars and eight cents</measure>. Other property now being collected, and which will be turned over to the <orgName n="Confederate Government" type="org">Confederate Government</orgName>, will further reduce the cost.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="118"/>No report has been received from the <rs type="role" reg="Paymaster-General">Paymaster General</rs>'s department. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="119"/> In this connection it is appropriate and becoming that should refers to the distinguished commander of the <placeName reg="State">State</placeName> Line, whose race is run, whose labors are ended, and who now quietly sleeps with the dead.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="120"/><persName n="Floyd,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00012" reg="mostcommon:Floyd,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Floyd</surname></persName> was no ordinary man. He was blessed with rare intellectual endowments.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="121"/>He possessed uncommon energy and great physical endurance.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="122"/>His information was varied, extensive, and valuable.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="123"/>As an orator, he had few superiors &mdash; as a statesman, he was equal to any of the men of his day &mdash; and as a patriot, devoted to his country and his country's cause, his services in this war best attest his merits.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="124"/>He was equal to every position to which he was called &mdash; as Delegate in the <orgName n="General Assembly" type="misc">General Assembly</orgName>, as <rs type="role" reg="Governor">Governor</rs> of this State, as <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs> under the old Government, as <rs type="role" reg="Brigadier-General">Brigadier General</rs> commanding the <rs>Confederate</rs> troops, or as <rs type="role2">Major</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="125"/>General commanding the <placeName reg="State">State</placeName> Line.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="126"/>When the news of his death reached this city I caused the <rs>State</rs> flag to be displayed at half must, and the offices to be closed for the day, in taken of respect for his memory. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="127"/> On the <dateStruct value="-08-29"><day reg="29">29th</day> day of <month reg="08">August</month></dateStruct> last a requisition was made upon me by the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs> for <num value="5340">5,340</num> slaves, to work upon the fortifications around <placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 6" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="128"/>Copies of the papers are herewith submitted to your consideration, and I particularly invite your attention to the draft made upon the several counties.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="129"/>The apportionment upon the counties seems to be entirely arbitrary, and bears very unequally.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="130"/>In some cases <num value="0.05">five per cent.</num> of the slaves is called for, and in other cases less than <num value="0.01">one per cent.</num> Thus, <placeName reg="Amelia Court House, Amelia, Virginia" key="tgn,2110319">Amelia</placeName>, with upwards of <num value="7000">7,000</num> slaves assessed with taxes in <dateStruct value="1862--"><year reg="1862">1862</year></dateStruct>, is required to furnish <num value="50">50</num>, while <placeName reg="Alleghany, Alleghany, Virginia" key="tgn,2110294">Alleghany</placeName>, with less than <num value="700">700</num>, is required to furnish <num value="30">30</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="131"/>The <placeName reg="Albemarle, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002137">county of Albemarle</placeName>, with <num value="12681">12,681</num>, is called upon for <num value="200">200</num>, while <placeName reg="Brunswick, Cumberland, Maine" key="tgn,7015802">Brunswick</placeName>, with <num value="9212">9,212</num>, is called upon for <num value="250">250</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="132"/>The <placeName reg="Augusta, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002142">county of Augusta</placeName>, with <num value="4460">4,460</num> is called upon for <num value="80">80</num>, while the county of <placeName reg="Rockingham, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002187">Rockingham</placeName>, with <num value="2164">2,164</num> is called upon for <num value="100">100</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="133"/><placeName reg="Hanover, Hanover, Virginia" key="tgn,2112147">Hanover</placeName>, with <num value="8621">8,621</num>, is called upon for <num value="80">80</num>, while <persName><roleName n="Prince">Prince</roleName> <foreName>Edward</foreName></persName>, with <num value="6998">6,998</num>, is called upon for <num value="150">150</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="134"/>These examples will suffice to show how unequally this burden is distributed; and I trust that some amendment will be made to the law, which will afford protection against such inequality. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="135"/> The law requires that &#x0022;the value of such slaves as may escape from the <rs>Confederate</rs> authorities and not return to their owners, or be seized, or killed by the public enemy, or may, by want of due diligence on the part of the authorities of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName>, in any manner be lost to the owners of such slaves; and in like manner compensation shall be made for any injury to slaves arising from the want of due diligence on the part of the authorities of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName>.&#x0022;Many cases of peculiar hardship, arising from the loss of slaves, have been brought to my attention, and much complaint has been made by the owners, in consequence of the fact that they have not received the value as provided for in this act. In several cases the only slave capable of field labor that the owner possessed has been lost, and compensation not having been made, he has been unable to supply his place.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="136"/>If the value had been promptly paid, the hardship in such cases would have been greatly relieved.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="137"/>I invoke your early attention to this subject, of so much importance to our common constituents. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="138"/> In my last message I recommended an in crease of the salaries at the officers and employees of the <rs>Government</rs>, and assigned the reasons which prompted the recommendation.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="139"/>Subsequent experience has greatly strengthened those reasons; and I now, therefore, without repeating them, renew the recommendation, in the earnest hope that it will meet your approval. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="140"/> I have received a communication from the <rs>President</rs> of the <orgName n="Central Railroad" type="railroad">Central railroad</orgName>, enclosing a report made to him by the <rs>Superintendent</rs>, on a subject of great importance to the road, and not less to the <rs>State</rs> and the <rs>Confederacy</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="141"/>The demands for the transportation of passengers and freight over this and the other railroads of the <rs>State</rs> have been very great, and the roads have been severely taxed to meet them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="142"/>So far they have fully met the demands, but it is apparent to any person that will pass over them that extensive repairs are now much needed, and must be made, or they will be broken down and rendered useless.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="143"/>Besides great difficulty is experienced in procuring cross ties and the necessary supply of wood for fuel.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="144"/>Labor is indispensably necessary to relieve them, and so far as legislation can aid them I am satisfied it will be cheerfully extended. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="145"/> The Central, <placeName reg="Orange, Orange, Virginia" key="tgn,7014299">Orange</placeName> and <placeName reg="Alexandria, Alexandria, Virginia" key="tgn,7013269">Alexandria</placeName>, are the <rs type="place">Virginia</rs> and <address><street n="Tennessee road">Tennessee roads</street></address> have more to apprehend from raids than any of the other roads in the <rs>State</rs>, and this apprehension makes it difficult to procure labor on reasonable, or indeed on any terms.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="146"/>The owners of slaves are unwilling to hire them on these lines, lost they may be seized and carried off, or may be induced to abscond.--Under these circumstances they very properly desire that the subject shall be brought to your attention.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="147"/>The papers are herewith submitted, and I trust your wisdom will enable you to devise some measure of relief. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="148"/> I communicate herewith the reports of the <orgName n="Visitors Board" type="board">Board of Visitors</orgName>, the <rs>Superintendent</rs>, and the <rs>Surgeon</rs> of the <orgName n="Virginia Military Institute" type="institute">Virginia Military Institute</orgName>, and I commend them to your consideration.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="149"/>They are deeply interesting, and, not withstanding the embarrassments of the times, they show that the institution is in a very flourishing condition.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="150"/>When the institution was re-opened it was seriously apprehended that it would be difficult, if not impossible, to procure the requisite supplies for clothing and feeding the cadets; but I take pleasure in saying that the judgment and energy of the <rs>Superintendent</rs> have over come all difficulties, and the operations of the school have been regularly kept up. The <rs type="place">Institute</rs> has strongly commended itself to the fostering care of the <orgName n="General Assembly" type="misc">General Assembly</orgName> and the people of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>, and I cannot too earnestly press its claims upon your support and favor.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="151"/>I trust it will be your pleasure to adopt the recommendations made in the reports, and thus place it upon a firm and enduring basis, and enable it gradually to extend the sphere of its usefulness. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="152"/> Since the commencement of this war <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> has been called upon to month over the loss of many of her gallant sons; but of all her jewels, the most brilliant was the if insidious <persName n="Jackson,Lieutenant-General,Thomas,J.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00013" reg="default:Jackson,Thomas,J.,,"><roleName n="Lieutenant-General">Lieutenant General</roleName> <foreName>Thomas</foreName> <foreName>J.</foreName> <surname>Jackson</surname></persName>--a graduate of <placeName reg="West Point, King William, Virginia" key="tgn,2114999">West Point</placeName> &mdash; highly distinguished in the <rs n="Mexican" type="group">Mexican</rs> war, and at the opening of the present war a quiet and unpretending professor in our State <orgName n="Military Institute" type="institute">Military institute</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="153"/>He was called from the professor's chair to the field, and his sagacity, his <milestone unit="column" n="5"/> energy, and the unparalleled success which crowned his efforts, won for him a reputation that made him the pride of his own State, endeared him to the people of the <rs>Confederacy</rs>, attracted to him the attention of the nations of the earth, and compelled the respect and admiration even of those heartless enemies who have drenched our land in blood, and brought wailing and lamentation to the firesides of <num value="1000">thousands</num> of their own misguided people.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="154"/>For decision of character, for stern and unbending resolution, for pure and elevated patriotism, for sound and inflexible integrity, and for prompt and energetic action, he was supposed by no man of his times.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="155"/>The record of his achievements will constitute some of the brightest pages in the history of the war when that history shall have been written.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="156"/>His regulation as a military leader of the highest ability and merit has been fairly and firmly established in the judgment of the army and the country, and his name will be honored and his fame will be cherished &#x0022;While the earth bears a plant or the <unclear>..</unclear> a wave.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="157"/> <persName n="Jackson,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00014" reg="nearbymention:Jackson,Thomas,J.,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Jackson</surname></persName> was not only a great man, but he was emphatically a good man. He was pure and upright, earnest and honest, conscientious and true in his intercourse with the world.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="158"/>In all the relations of life, as a son, a husband, a father and a citizen, he was faithful and reliable.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="159"/>As a member of the <orgName n="Presbyterian Church" type="church">Presbyterian Church</orgName>, his &#x0022;walk and conversation&#x0022; attested the sincerity of his profession.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="160"/>The death of such a man, and at such a time, could not fall to produce the most profound sensation throughout the <rs>Confederacy</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="161"/>He had won the confidence of the people of all classes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="162"/>Their affections were out wined around him &mdash; their hopes centered in him &mdash; and they looked to him as <num value="1">one</num> of the great instruments provided by an all wise Providence for their deliverance, and for the establishment of their independence upon a new basis.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="163"/>His death was regarded as a national calamity, and it was succeeded by manifestations of the most heartfelt grief and the most sincere sorrow. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="164"/> He has passed from life, but his example is still left to encourage and stimulate us to greater exertions in the noble cause in which we are engaged.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="165"/>That example cannot fail to exert a most powerful influence in awaking our dormant energies &mdash; in rousing us up to great efforts &mdash; in inspiring us with greater zeal, and in animating us with a nobler spirit and a more determined courage.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="166"/>His whole soul was in the cause, and he performed his duty cheerfully and with the most scrupulous fidelity.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="167"/>The redemption of the people from the yoke of <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> tyranny was the object nearest his heart, and to its accomplishment he directed his efforts.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="168"/>The cheeks of the deserters and stragglers and laggards should burn with shame when contemplating his devotion and self sacrificing spirit.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="169"/>They should appreciate such an example, and should resolve at once to emulate it, and should return to the path of duty with a fixed purpose to relieve their land from the tread of the invader, or, as he did, sacrifice their lives in the effort.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="170"/>If such shall be the result, he will not have died in vain.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="171"/>The sacrifice, great as it was, will impress upon the country an invaluable lesson for the instruction of the present and future generations. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="172"/> The extortioner is still pursuing his heart less traffic and amassing his gains.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="173"/>The war to him is a <name n="God" type="God">God</name> send, and he would not have it terminated for any earthly consideration.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="174"/>He shares none of its hardships &mdash; he suffers none of its dangers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="175"/>He has perhaps hired a substitute, who, for a pecuniary consideration, agreed to be shot at in his place.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="176"/>Such men are found everywhere throughout the <rs>Confederacy</rs>, and it is time something were done to put an end to their money making business. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="177"/> I have been investigating this subject in the hope that I would be able to make some practical recommendation that would check if it did not eradicate this evil.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="178"/>In the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> volume of the <rs>Revised Code</rs> of <dateStruct value="1819--"><year reg="1819">1819</year></dateStruct>, <ref n="page 551">page 551</ref>, I find an act which was passed in <dateStruct value="1777--"><year reg="1777">1777</year></dateStruct>, entitled &#x0022;an act to prevent forestalling, regrafting, engrossing, and public vendues,&#x0022; which, with very slight amendments, would, if re-enacted, check in a great measure this growing evil.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="179"/>I invite your attention to it, and recommend that some similar act be passed at this session. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="180"/> The finances of the <rs>State</rs> are in a highly prosperous condition &mdash; much more prosperous indeed than could have been anticipated under the circumstances which surround us. The enormous demands made upon the treasury have been promptly met and satisfied.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="181"/>Our revenue is increasing, and the people, with that noble spirit which has ever characterized Virginias, cheerfully pay their taxes, and thus maintain the credit and uphold the character of the <rs>Commonwealth</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="182"/> I suggest whether it would not be wise to dispose of the interest which the <rs>State</rs> holds in our various internal improvement companies, under such restrictions as may be deemed proper, and apply the proceeds arising therefrom to the payment of the <rs>State</rs> debt.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="183"/>We could at this time dispose of these stocks to great advantage; and such an application of the proceeds would reduce the debt to a comparatively small sum. It is the part of wisdom to extinguish our debt as rapidly as possible, and any measure which will produce this result will greatly increase public confidence. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="184"/> 
<table rows="12" cols="2"> 
<head></head> 
<row><cell>The total permanent debt of the <rs>State</rs> is reported to be</cell><cell><measure n="34399.850.30dollars" type="currency">$34,399.850.30</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell>This sent includes ruter est on the public debt uncalled for the greater portion of which is due to the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> and her citizens</cell><cell><measure n="2730.894.01dollars" type="currency">$2,730.894.01</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell>it includes, also, the sum borrowed by us to aid in the prevention of the war, and which, by agreement, is to be refounded by the <orgName n="Confederate Government" type="org">Confederate Government</orgName>, amounting to</cell><cell><num value="8600000">8,600,000 00</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell></cell><cell><num value="11230894">11,230,894</num> <num value="61">61</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell>These sums, making</cell><cell><measure n="11230.894dollars" type="currency">$11,230.894</measure> <num value="61">61</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell>State debt the sum of</cell><cell><num value="23168788">23,168,788</num> <num value="09">09</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell>Deduct debt purporting to be due to the <name>Literacy</name> fund, which belongs to the <rs>State</rs> and is a debt by move nation of law</cell><cell><num value="2662694">2,662,694</num> <num value="38">38</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell></cell><cell><num value="20806097">20,806,097</num> <num value="31">31</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell>To pay which, we have available bank stocks belonging to the <orgName n="Library Fund" type="fund">Library fund</orgName>, railroad and other stocks belonging to the internal improvement land, worth in the market, and from which can be realized at any time the <rs>State</rs> may direct, the sum of</cell><cell><num value="16613065">16,613,065</num> <num value="24">24</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell></cell><cell><num value="3963042">3,963,042</num> <num value="00">00</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell>in addition, the <rs>Commonwealth</rs> owns <measure n="2340dollars" type="currency">$2,340</measure> <num value="600">600</num> worth of bank stock, which will readily command in the market the sum of</cell><cell><num value="3019125">3,019,125</num> <num value="00">00</num></cell></row> 
<row><cell>leaving only to by <unclear>..</unclear></cell><cell><measure n="943917dollars" type="currency">$943,917</measure> <num value="00">00</num></cell></row> </table></p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="185"/> This statement <unclear></unclear> with great care, after <unclear></unclear> with our Auditors, and will, I believe, be found accurate and reliable. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="186"/> I have thus brought to your attention such matters as are deserving of consideration at this session of the <orgName n="General Assembly" type="misc">General Assembly</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="187"/>I have only to add, in conclusion, that I hope harmony and unity will attend your deliberations; that wisdom will dictate your measures, and that they will promote the honor, interests and prosperity of the <rs>Commonwealth</rs> and the <rs>Confederacy</rs>. </p> <closer> <salute>Respectfully,</salute> <lb/> <signed><persName n="Letcher,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00015" reg="default:Letcher,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName>  <surname>Letcher</surname></persName></signed> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="local"> 
<head>Local matters.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Change of Base.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="188"/> --It is stated that the point for the future exchange of prisoners in <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> is shortly to be transferred from <placeName reg="City Point, Virginia, Virginia" key="tgn,2240477">City Point</placeName> to <placeName reg="Port Walthall">Port Walthall</placeName>, on the <rs>Appomattox</rs>, or some other place equally as convenient.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="189"/>From <placeName reg="Port Walthall">Port Walthall</placeName>, if that should be the future scene of operation, there is a continuous line of rail to <placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 6" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName>, the point where the prisoners are all congregated, and independent of other reasons, the delay and expose attendant upon <num value="2">two</num> roads would be obviated. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">The cage.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="190"/> --At the cage yesterday, <persName n="Whiteside,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00016" reg="default:Whiteside,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Whiteside</surname></persName> was committed on the charge of stealing a pair of shoes valued at <measure n="40dollars" type="currency">$40</measure>, the property of <persName n="Bird,,A.,S.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00017" reg="default:Bird,A.,S.,,"><foreName>A.</foreName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <surname>Bird</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="191"/><persName n="Rickers,,Edward,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00018" reg="default:Rickers,Edward,,,"><foreName>Edward</foreName> <surname>Rickers</surname></persName> was also committed on the charge of threatening personal violence to the said <rs>Bird</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="192"/>The latter was afterwards balled out. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">The prisons.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="193"/> --At the <rs>Confederate</rs> prisons in this city nothing was done yesterday.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="194"/>The books of the <rs type="place">Castle and Libby Prison</rs> presented a meagre record &mdash; showing un cases of interest. </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="6"/> 
<div2 type="latest"> 
<head>Latest from the <rs>North</rs>.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="195"/> We have received, through the courtesy of the officers of the <rs type="place">Exchange Bureau</rs>, Northern papers of Saturday the <dateStruct value="--5"><day reg="5">5th inst.</day></dateStruct> We condense the news from them into a short space, in view of the crowded condition of our columns.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="196"/>The <orgName n="Baltimore American" type="newspaper">Baltimore <hi rend="italics">American</hi></orgName> has the following summary of the contents of its <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName> correspondence, which is as late as last <dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct>: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="197"/> The shelling of <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName> was resumed from the <placeName reg="Marsh, Gem, Idaho" key="tgn,2493449">Marsh</placeName> Battery on <dateStruct><day type="name">Sunday</day></dateStruct> week, and a few shells were thrown into <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="198"/><num value="2">Two</num> seacoast mortars bearing on the city are being mounted by <persName n="Gill,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00019" reg="mostcommon:Gill,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Gill</surname></persName> more.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="199"/>Deserters from the rebels say the shells thrown into <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName> caused a great conflagration, <num value="1">one</num> of them setting fire to a warehouse stored with cotton.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="200"/>They also report a number of persons killed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="201"/><orgName n="Battery Wagner" type="battery">Battery Wagner</orgName> is undermined, and its speedy fall looked for. On <dateStruct><day type="name">Wednesday</day></dateStruct> <persName n="Gillatore,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00020" reg="mostcommon:Gillatore,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Gillatore</surname></persName> advanced his lines <measure n="100yards" type="distance">one hundred yards</measure> scaper this work, taking possession of the enemy's a rifle pits and capturing several prisoners. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="202"/> During the affair the rebel batteries on <placeName reg="James Island, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,2418933">James Island</placeName> created great have among their own men, killing and wounding a number.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="203"/><placeName key="tgn,7013582" n="1.000 46" reg="charleston, charleston, south carolina">Sumter</placeName> is a useless <unclear></unclear> of <unclear>..</unclear> shot is fired <unclear>..</unclear> pounder <persName n="Parrott,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00021" reg="mostcommon:Parrott,nomatch:0"><surname>Parrott</surname></persName>, that gan having been found as good as ever, the only <unclear></unclear> it sustained being the loss of a portion of its muzzle.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="204"/>The rebels succeeded in remounting a gun in <num value="1">one</num> corner of the work on <dateStruct><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> last, but a few well directed shots from the <orgName n="Naval Battery" type="battery">naval battery</orgName> caused its disappearance.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="205"/>The rebel flag still floats over the ruins, a sufficient force being kept there to replace it whenever it is shot away.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="206"/><orgName n="Battery Gregg" type="battery">Battery Gregg</orgName> had received a sharp bombardment from <num value="1">one</num> of the monitors, the shot passing through the fort.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="207"/>A very important movement of <persName n="Dahlgren,Admiral,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00022" reg="mostcommon:Dahlgren,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Admiral">Admiral</roleName> <surname>Dahlgren</surname></persName>'s fleet on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time> last was prevented by the setting in of a heavy storm of wind and rain; which continued at intervals up to the time the <rs>Spaulding</rs> left, thus hindering the prosecution of this important enterprise up to that time.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="208"/>All that is wanting for the success of this expedition is good weather, and the issue forced upon the rebels will be the destruction or the occupation of the city of <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="209"/>The <term type="ship">monitor</term> <rs type="ship">Lehigh</rs> had arrived in safety.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="210"/>No disasters had occurred among any of the vessels of the fleet during the storm, all being safely at anchor inside the bar. The <term type="ship">steamer</term> <rs type="ship">Home</rs>, fitted out by the <orgName n="Navy Department" type="department">Navy Department</orgName> as a resort for the officers and crews of the monitors in which to recuperate and rest, had also arrived.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="211"/>Both <persName n="Dahlgren,Admiral,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00023" reg="mostcommon:Dahlgren,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Admiral">Admiral</roleName> <surname>Dahlgren</surname></persName> and <persName n="Gillmore,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00024" reg="mostcommon:Gillmore,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Gillmore</surname></persName> are in good health and fine spirits, perfectly confident in the final success of their effort to humble the cradle of treason, and to &#x0022;repossess and reoccupy the forts and other public property of the <name>United State</name>&#x0022; in <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName> and its vicinity. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="212"/> The <term type="ship">steamship</term> <rs type="ship">Fulton</rs> arrived at New York yesterday, having left <placeName reg="Charleston Harbor, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,2233245">Charleston harbor</placeName> on <dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="213"/>She brings but little additional crews.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="214"/><persName n="Gillmore,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00025" reg="mostcommon:Gillmore,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Gillmore</surname></persName> has succeeded in running a parallel up to <placeName key="tgn,2525074" n="1.000 107" reg="morris island, charleston, south carolina">Fort Wagner</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="215"/>The monitors, it is said, had been with drawn from the attack on Forth <placeName key="tgn,2335409" n="1.000 25" reg="fort moultrie, charleston, south carolina">Moultrie</placeName>, but we think there is some error in this statement as they had not yet attacked that fort.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="216"/>Everything is represented as progressing favorably. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="217"/> The same paper contains the following summary of general news: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="218"/> From <placeName reg="Lexington, Lexington, Virginia" key="tgn,7013889">Lexington, Ky</placeName>, we learn that <persName n="Burnside,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00026" reg="mostcommon:Burnside,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Burnside</surname></persName> had passed through the gaps in the <rs type="place">Cumberland mountains</rs>, and was pushing on to <placeName reg="Kingston, Bartow, Georgia" key="tgn,2023318">Kingston</placeName>, in <placeName reg="Roase county">Roase county</placeName>, adjoining Know, and some <placeName><distance reg="40miles">forty miles</distance> from Knoxville</placeName> At <placeName reg="Kingston, Bartow, Georgia" key="tgn,2023318">Kingston</placeName> he will have possession of the <orgName n="Virginia and Tennessee Railroad" type="railroad">Virginia and Tennessee Railroad</orgName>, thus cutting off the retreat of the rebels toward the <rs>West</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="219"/>A mounted force had gone eastward of <placeName reg="Cumberland, Allegany, Maryland" key="tgn,2046811">Cumberland</placeName> Gen. and would interfere with a retreat of the enemy in that direction it is thought that the hero of <placeName reg="Roanoke Island, Dare, North Carolina" key="tgn,7014345">Roanoke island</placeName> will be in <placeName reg="Knoxville, Knox, Tennessee" key="tgn,7013841">Knoxville</placeName> in a very short period of time, the rebels not being prepared to make any serious resistance </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="220"/> Later dispatches from <orgName n="army"><persName n="Burnside,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00027" reg="mostcommon:Burnside,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Burnside</surname></persName>'s army</orgName> confirm the successes of his movements.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="221"/>He has occupied <placeName reg="Kingston, Roane, Tennessee" key="tgn,2099865">Kingston, Tenn</placeName>; the rebels offering little serious opposition.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="222"/>All of <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825"><rs type="direction">East</rs> Tennessee</placeName> except the <placeName reg="Chattanooga, Hamilton, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017496">Chattanooga</placeName> region has been evacuated by the rebels and is now free.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="223"/><placeName reg="Kingston, Bartow, Georgia" key="tgn,2023318">Kingston</placeName> is on the <placeName reg="Church river">Church river</placeName>, and also on the line of the <orgName n="Tennessee Railroad" type="railroad">Tennessee Railroad</orgName>. <orgName n="army"><persName n="Rosecrans,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00028" reg="mostcommon:Rosecrans,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Rosecrans</surname></persName>'s army</orgName> is also successfully operating, and will shortly surmount the difficulties opposing the advance on <placeName reg="Chattanooga, Hamilton, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017496">Chattanooga</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="224"/>General <unclear></unclear> doubt occupied <placeName reg="Knoxville, Knox, Tennessee" key="tgn,7013841">Knoxville</placeName> by this time. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="225"/> The following telegrams has been received in <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="226"/> For a <hi rend="smallcaps">Miles South of <placeName reg="Bridgeport, Cocke, Tennessee" key="tgn,2098103">Bridgeport</placeName></hi> <date value="09-02">September 2. </date>--The army is well across the <rs>Tennessee</rs>, and occupies a strong position several miles South of the river.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="227"/>No resistance was made <unclear></unclear> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="228"/> Reconnaissances have been made to <placeName reg="Trenton, Dade, Georgia" key="tgn,2024539">Trenton, Georgia</placeName>, without finding the enemy in force.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="229"/>He is said to be intrenched East of <placeName reg="Chattanooga, Hamilton, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017496">Chattanooga</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="230"/> The trestle bridge at <placeName reg="Bridgeport, Cocke, Tennessee" key="tgn,2098103">Bridgeport</placeName>, inst completed this morning, gave way this afternoon while the train of the <orgName type="regiment" key="4MIBattery">4th Michigan battery</orgName> was crossing.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="231"/><num value="1">One</num> male only was drowned, the water not being over <measure n="4feet" type="distance">four feet</measure> deep.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="232"/>Several brigades of infantry and batteries had just preceded the train.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="233"/>The bridge will be replaced by to morrow.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="234"/>There are several more at different points.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="235"/><persName n="Rosecrans,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00029" reg="mostcommon:Rosecrans,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Rosecrans</surname></persName> and staff crossed this afternoon. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="236"/> A Washington Dispatch to the <orgName n="New York Times" type="newspaper">New York <hi rend="italics">Times</hi></orgName> says: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="237"/> A distinguished officer in the <orgName n="Army of the Potomac" type="army">Army of the Potomac</orgName> has sent in word that <persName n="Lee,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00030" reg="mostcommon:Lee,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Lee</surname></persName> has not given the slightest evidence of a purpose to move his forces.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="238"/>On the other hand; he is waiting for the result of the operations of <persName n="Rosecrans,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00031" reg="mostcommon:Rosecrans,nomatch:0"><surname>Rosecrans</surname></persName>, <persName n="Gillmore,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00032" reg="mostcommon:Gillmore,nomatch:0"><surname>Gillmore</surname></persName>, and <persName n="Burnside,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00033" reg="mostcommon:Burnside,nomatch:0"><surname>Burnside</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="239"/>The opinion prevails among the most intelligent of our officers at headquarters that if those operations are successful <persName n="Lee,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00034" reg="mostcommon:Lee,nomatch:0"><surname>Lee</surname></persName> will propose terms of surrender, and endeavor to bring the war to a close. </p> </q><bibl n="New York Times"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="240"/> Information has been received at <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName> from the <orgName type="corps" n="corps 3">3d army corps</orgName> that <persName n="Kilpatrick,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00035" reg="mostcommon:Kilpatrick,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Colonel</roleName> <surname>Kilpatrick</surname></persName> on Wednesday succeeded in sinking, on the <rs>Rappahannock</rs>, <placeName><distance reg="12miles">twelve miles</distance> below <placeName reg="Fredericksburg, Fredericksburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013943">Fredericksburg</placeName></placeName>, the <term type="ship">gunboats</term> <rs type="ship">Satellite</rs> and <rs type="ship">Reliance</rs>, captured by the rebels a few days since.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="241"/>This he accomplished with <num value="1">one</num> of his field batteries, supported by cavalry.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="242"/>An expedition previously sent up the river to capture them failed to do so on account of <unclear></unclear> water.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="243"/>[The readers of the <unclear><hi rend="italics">Dis</hi></unclear> know the falsity of the above] </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="244"/> <unclear>T</unclear> announcement Union victory at the polls in <placeName reg="California" key="tgn,7007157">California</placeName> <unclear></unclear> Union candidate for Governor will have probably <num value="20000">twenty thousand</num> majority, and the <name>Congressional</name> delegation will no doubt be a unit.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="245"/>The elections in <placeName reg="Vermont" key="tgn,7007828">Vermont</placeName> and <placeName reg="California" key="tgn,7007157">California</placeName> have settled beyond all doubt the complexion of the next <orgName n="House of Representatives" type="government">House of Representatives</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="246"/> A Memphis dispatch furnishes New Orleans dates to the <dateStruct value="--28"><day reg="28">28th ult.</day></dateStruct> An expedition for some point in the <rs type="place">Gulf</rs> was nearly ready and would start in a few days.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="247"/><persName n="Grant,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00036" reg="mostcommon:Grant,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Grant</surname></persName> was to leave <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName> on the <num value="31" type="ordinal">31st</num> for New Orleans. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="248"/> The <term type="ship">steamer</term> <rs type="ship">Warrior</rs>, <persName n="Henry,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00037" reg="mostcommon:Henry,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Capt</roleName> <surname>Henry</surname></persName> Wold., was captured <measure n="60miles" type="distance">sixty miles</measure> north of Tortugas She was from <placeName reg="Montour Falls, Schuyler, New York" key="tgn,2070618">Havana</placeName>, bound to <placeName reg="Apalachicola, Franklin, Florida" key="tgn,2018463">Apalachicola</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="249"/>She had on board, when captured, an assorted cargo, valued at about <num value="150000">one hundred and fifty thousand</num> and dollars. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="250"/> <rs type="role2">Private</rs> dispatches received in <placeName key="tgn,7014620" n="1.000 73" reg="wheeling, ohio, west virginia">Wheeling</placeName> announce the return to <placeName key="tgn,2118671" n="1.000 14" reg="huntersville, pocahontas, west virginia">Huntersville</placeName>, <placeName reg="Randolph county, West Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002291">Randolph county</placeName>, of the expedition under <persName n="Averill,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00038" reg="mostcommon:Averill,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Averill</surname></persName>?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="251"/>recently sent out by <persName n="Kelley,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00039" reg="mostcommon:Kelley,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Kelley</surname></persName>.--<persName n="Averill,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00040" reg="mostcommon:Averill,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Averill</surname></persName> route extended through the counties of <placeName reg="Sturdy county">Sturdy</placeName>, <placeName key="tgn,7014398" n="1.000 2" reg="pendleton, west virginia, united states">Pendleton</placeName>, <placeName reg="Highland, Virginia, Virginia" key="tgn,2002168">Highland</placeName>, <placeName key="tgn,2002287" n="1.000 3" reg="pocahontas, west virginia, united states">Pocahontas</placeName>, and <placeName key="tgn,2002264" n="1.000 25" reg="greenbrier, west virginia, united states">Greenbrier</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="252"/>He destroyed the saltpetre works in <placeName reg="Pendleton, Pickens, South Carolina" key="tgn,7014397">Pendleton</placeName>, and drove <persName n="Jackson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00041" reg="nearbymention:Jackson,Thomas,J.,,"><surname>Jackson</surname></persName> out of <placeName reg="Pocahontas, Coffee, Tennessee" key="tgn,2101068">Pocahontas</placeName> pursuing him to <placeName reg="Greenbrier, West Virginia, United States" key="tgn,1124364">Greenbrier</placeName>, near the <rs type="place">White Sulphur Springs</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="253"/>At <placeName reg="Rocky Gap, Fannin, Georgia" key="tgn,2626391">Rocky Gap</placeName> he encountered the forces of <persName n="Jones,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00042" reg="mostcommon:Jones,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Jones</surname></persName> and <persName n="Patton,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00043" reg="mostcommon:Patton,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Patton</surname></persName>, and had a severe action, in which he lost about <num value="100">one hundred</num> men in killed and wounded, including several officers. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="254"/> Writs of election, dated <date value="08-026">August 26,</date> for a Judge of the <orgName n="Judicial District 1" type="district">First Judicial District of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName></orgName>, composed of the counties of <persName><roleName n="Princess">Princess</roleName> <foreName>Anne</foreName></persName>, <persName n="Norfolk,Princess,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00044" reg="mostcommon:Norfolk,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Princess"></roleName><surname>Norfolk</surname></persName>, <persName n="Nansemond,Princess,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00045" reg="mostcommon:Nansemond,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Princess"></roleName><surname>Nansemond</surname></persName>, <persName n="Isle,Princess,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00046" reg="mostcommon:Isle,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Princess"></roleName><surname>Isle</surname></persName> of <persName n="Wight,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00047" reg="mostcommon:Wight,nomatch:0"><surname>Wight</surname></persName>, &#x0026;c., have been forwarded to the <name>Sheriffs</name> of the different counties in said district, for an election to be held on <dateStruct><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct>, <date value="09-28">September 28,</date> to supply the place of <persName n="Baker,,Richard,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00048" reg="default:Baker,Richard,H.,,"><foreName>Richard</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Baker</surname></persName>, <milestone unit="column" n="7"/> who has failed to take the oath of allegiance to the <orgName n="U. S. Government" type="org">United States Government</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="255"/> The St. Louis <hi rend="italics">Union</hi> states that the force now advancing on <placeName reg="Little Rock, Pulaski, Arkansas" key="tgn,7013897">Little Rock</placeName> consists of about <num value="20000">20,000</num> infantry and <num value="10000">10,000</num> cavalry &mdash; the cavalry under <persName n="Davidson,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00049" reg="mostcommon:Davidson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Davidson</surname></persName>, and the whole expediting under command of <persName n="Steels,Major-General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00050" reg="mostcommon:Steels,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major-General">Major General</roleName> <surname>Steels</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="256"/> The utmost consternation and alarm prevail in the border counties of <placeName reg="Missouri" key="tgn,7007523">Missouri</placeName>, in consequence of the orders of <persName n="Ewing,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00051" reg="mostcommon:Ewing,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Ewing</surname></persName> and the threatened invasion from <placeName reg="Kansas" key="tgn,7007254">Kansas</placeName>. <persName n="Ewing,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00052" reg="mostcommon:Ewing,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Ewing</surname></persName>'s order required the inhabitant in <placeName reg="Jackson county, West Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002268">Jackson</placeName>, <placeName reg="Bartow, Georgia, United States" key="tgn,2000299">Cass</placeName> and <placeName reg="Bates, Missouri, United States" key="tgn,2001172">Bates counties</placeName> to abandon their homes and assemble at certain Specified posts by the <date value="09-09">9th of September,</date> and directed that all hay left in those counties should be furnished.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="257"/>At the same time it is announced that <persName n="Laue,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00053" reg="mostcommon:Laue,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Laue</surname></persName> will enter <placeName reg="Missouri" key="tgn,7007523">Missouri</placeName> <unclear></unclear> force on the <date value="09-09">9th of September,</date> There is a general conviction that independence the most important town in <placeName reg="Jackson county, West Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002268">Jackson county</placeName>, is to be plundered and reduced to ashes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="258"/>The moneys of the bank at that place have been removed to <placeName reg="Saint Louis, Saint Louis City, Missouri" key="tgn,7014444">St. Louis</placeName> for safety The records of the <num value="3">three</num> counties &mdash; <persName n="Jackson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00054" reg="nearbymention:Jackson,Thomas,J.,,"><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>, <persName n="Bates,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00055" reg="mostcommon:Bates,nomatch:0"><surname>Bates</surname></persName>, and <persName n="Cass,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00056" reg="mostcommon:Cass,nomatch:0"><surname>Cass</surname></persName> &mdash; have also been removed to prevent their destruction.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="259"/><persName n="Schofield,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00057" reg="mostcommon:Schofield,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Schofield</surname></persName>, with his staff, left <placeName reg="Saint Louis, Saint Louis City, Missouri" key="tgn,7014444">St. Louis</placeName> on Monday for the bounder, to give his personal attention to affairs there and to inaugurate energetic <unclear></unclear> for ridding that region of the brigands under <persName n="Quantrell,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00058" reg="mostcommon:Quantrell,nomatch:0"><surname>Quantrell</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="260"/> The funeral of <persName n="Collamove,,J.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00059" reg="default:Collamove,J.,W.,,"><foreName>J.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Collamove</surname></persName>, late <rs type="role" reg="Mayor">Mayor</rs> or <unclear>..</unclear> took <unclear>..</unclear> <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Thursday</day></dateStruct> <time>afternoon</time>, <unclear></unclear> <persName n="Garnett,Doctor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00060" reg="mostcommon:Garnett,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <surname>Garnett</surname></persName> <unclear></unclear> in <placeName reg="Boston, Suffolk, Massachusetts" key="tgn,7013445">Boston</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="261"/> The <term type="ship">schooner</term> <rs type="ship">Ella</rs>, recently arrived at New York from <placeName key="tgn,2535807;tgn,7006630" n="0.380 000000.7603	placename;tgn,2535807;nassau river, florida, florida,Florida,United States,North and Central America;0.006 000000.0124	placename;tgn,7006630;nassau,new providence,bahamas,north and central america,New Providence,Bahamas,North and Central America" reg="nassau river, florida, florida,Florida,United States,North and Central America;nassau,new providence,bahamas,north and central america,New Providence,Bahamas,North and Central America">Nassau</placeName> with a cargo of trait, has been discovered to be the same vessel which, under the name of the <rs>Retribution</rs>, the rebels used for some time as a privateer.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="262"/>She has been seized by the authorities. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="263"/> <persName n="Thompson,General,Jefferson,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00061" reg="default:Thompson,Jefferson,,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <foreName n="Jefferson">Jeff.</foreName> <surname>Thompson</surname></persName> and <persName n="Hay,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00062" reg="mostcommon:Hay,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Capt.</roleName> <surname>Hay</surname></persName> his <rs type="role" reg="Adjutant General">Adjutant General</rs>, have been committed to the military prison in <placeName reg="Saint Louis, Saint Louis City, Missouri" key="tgn,7014444">St. Louis</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="264"/>He managed to destroy all his important papers before the <rs>Federal</rs> officer captured him. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="265"/> The New York gold market was highly excited <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct>, opening at <num value="134.5">134&#x00BD;</num> and closing at <num value="133.5">133 &#x00BD;</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="266"/>On <dateStruct><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct>, at the morning board it was quoted at <num value="131">131</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="267"/>In Baltimore Saturday gold was quoted at <num value="134">134</num>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head>The <rs>Florida</rs> off <placeName reg="Liverpool, Yazoo, Mississippi" key="tgn,2463110">Liverpool</placeName> &mdash; excitement among the <name>Merchants</name> &mdash; the <rs>Alabama</rs>.</head> 
<div4 type="entry" n="1"> 
<head>[from the <name>Liverpool</name> times, <date value="08-21">Aug. 21.]</date></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="268"/> There has been a good deal of excitement on Change yesterday in connection with the movements of this vessel.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="269"/>It was at <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> reported that <num value="75804">75,804</num> couces of silver, a portion of the prize money from a capture by the <rs>Florida</rs>, had been placed on board the <term type="ship">ship</term> <rs type="ship">Eagle</rs>, <persName n="Norfolk,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00063" reg="mostcommon:Norfolk,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Capt.</roleName> <surname>Norfolk</surname></persName>, which arrived at Liver pool yesterday morning, and the agents of the <rs>Federal Government</rs> in the town were exceedingly anxious to take any measures which were available for the recovery of the treasure.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="270"/>They consulted an eminent legal firm upon the subject, and as their interiors became known there was a manifest desire on the part of the <name>Southerners</name> to make come counter demonstration. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="271"/> <hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="Roches Point,Northwest Territories,Canada,North and Central America" key="tgn,4009350">Roche's Point</placeName>,</hi> <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Thursday</day></dateStruct> <time>Evening</time>.--The Confederate armed steamer <placeName reg="Florida, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007240">Florida</placeName> was again seen off the harbor this morning, steering to the S. S. W., bark rigged, and subsequently seen steering to the E. N. E., bark rigged. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="272"/> This question, however, was overshadowed in importance by an announcement which was made later in the day, viz.: That The <rs>Florida</rs> was <num value="2">two</num> and a ball miles from Tuskar, waiting for &#x0022;something.&#x0022; and that a large <rs n="American" type="group">American</rs> ship, under full-scale, was leaving that point.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="273"/>Underwriters immediately began to look very gloomy, as they expected in a few hours to hear of the destruction of the ship. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="2"> 
<head>[from the <rs>Cork Herald</rs>, <date value="08-20">August 20.]</date></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="274"/> The <rs>Florida</rs> is a serow steamer of extraordinary swiftness, and is disguised in such a manner as to puzzle the keenest observer.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="275"/>Her bail is long and low; her sails look old and patched, and no external trace is visible of her bear strength and ponder.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="276"/><num value="3">Three</num> hands have been, in <num value="1">one</num> instance, seen struggling doll to take in a sail, to master which efficiently <num value="10">ten</num> would be necessary, while a visit to the deck would disclose to view a body of at least <num value="200">two hundred</num> men, scattered about in groups.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="277"/>The persons landed from the <rs>Florida</rs> are officers of the <orgName n="Confederate Navy" type="org">Confederate navy</orgName>, (<num value="1">one</num> of them a physician,) who avowed their profession and the service they belonged to but refused to tell the name of their ship.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="278"/>Their business in <placeName key="tgn,1000003" n="1.000 139" reg="europe,">Europe</placeName>, of course, can apply be conjectured. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="3"> 
<head>[from the <orgName n="London Times" type="newspaper">London times</orgName>, <date value="08-24">August 24.]</date></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="279"/> <name n="her Majesty" type="role">Her Majesty</name> a <term type="ship">ship</term> <rs type="ship">Ohio</rs>, on her passage home from <placeName reg="Rio">Rio</placeName>, about a week ago, came across the <rs>Alabama</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="280"/>On the evening of the <date value="07-20">20 July,</date> at <time value="7oclock">7 o'clock</time>, a fine was reported on the port how so the ship was immediately kept away for <unclear></unclear> and at <time value="9oclock">nine o'clock</time> a vessel was deserved to <unclear></unclear> counting towards us, and when within a mile and <num value="0.5">a half</num> official a blank gun, which beat once returned She then <unclear></unclear> wind and hope away in the opposite direction, so we thought we had done will her About <time value="10pm">ten P. M.</time> we came abroad of a large.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="281"/><rs n="American" type="group">American</rs> vessel on fire and almost burnt to the water's edger and a bark was also seen lying to close by her We burned a long light, in <unclear></unclear> any persons were <unclear></unclear> or required assistance, and at <time value="12:20mid">twenty minutes past 12 midnight</time> a vessel was reported coming after <unclear></unclear> under sail and steam, and fulling sail in very quick time under our stern, steamed up on our weather quarter, going apparently double our speed &mdash; viza <num value="7">seven</num> knots &mdash; with all her men at quarters, and clearing for action and commenced halling us as follows &#x0022;This is the <name n="Confederate States">Confederate</name> <term type="ship">war steamer</term> <rs type="ship">Alabama</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="282"/>Ship, ahoy?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="283"/>what ship is that?&#x0022; On being asked if they burned that ship, they said they did. The excitement on board among officers and men was very great, all being eager to catch a sight of the far famed vessel <placeName key="tgn,7002659" n="1.000 5060" reg="alabama">Alabama</placeName> over the bulwarks, or wherever a good view could be obtained. </p> </div4> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">From <placeName reg="Tennessee, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="284"/> --The <placeName reg="Chattanooga, Hamilton, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017496">Chattanooga</placeName> <hi rend="italics">Rebel,</hi> of <dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct>, says that <persName n="Rice,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00064" reg="mostcommon:Rice,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Captain</roleName> <surname>Rice</surname></persName>, who commanded the cavalry picket between that point and <placeName reg="Bridgeport, Fairfield, Connecticut" key="tgn,7013453">Bridgeport</placeName>, reports the enemy about <placeName><distance reg="12miles">twelve miles</distance> from <placeName reg="Chattanooga, Hamilton, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017496">Chattanooga</placeName></placeName>, on the south side of the river.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="285"/>The <hi rend="italics">Appeals</hi> <placeName reg="Dalton, Whitfield, Georgia" key="tgn,2022620">Dalton (Ga.)</placeName> correspondent, on <date value="09-01">September 1st,</date> writes: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="286"/> The news brought by the train from <persName n="Tennessee,,Kast,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00065" reg="default:Tennessee,Kast,,,"><foreName>Kast</foreName> <surname>Tennessee</surname></persName>, last night, is to the effect that a large Federal force has appeared at <persName n="Blythe,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00066" reg="mostcommon:Blythe,nomatch:0"><surname>Blythe</surname></persName>'s a Ferry, on the north side of the <rs>Tennessee</rs> opposite the month of the <rs>Hiwassee</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="287"/><persName n="Buckner,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00067" reg="mostcommon:Buckner,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Buckner</surname></persName> on yesterday evacuated <placeName reg="London, Madison, Ohio" key="tgn,2080432">London</placeName> and felt back with his whole force to <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName>, where the railroad crosses the <rs>Hiwassee</rs>, some <measure n="18mile" type="distance">eighteen mile distant</measure> from its month.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="288"/>The <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> force is reported to be some <num value="20000">20,000</num> strong, and <num value="1">one</num> report &mdash; not believed &mdash; has it that <num value="10000">ten thousand</num> had crossed to this side of the <rs>Tennessee</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="289"/> The <orgName n="Lynchburg Republican" type="newspaper">Lynchburg <hi rend="italics">Republican</hi></orgName> of yesterday learns from various sources entitled to credit, that. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="290"/> A force of the enemy, estimated at <num value="1400">1,400</num> cavalry, with military, are certainly at <placeName reg="Morristown, Hamblen, Tennessee" key="tgn,2100483">Morristown</placeName>, which is a depot on the <rs>East</rs> <orgName n="Tennessee and Virginia Railroad" type="railroad">Tennessee and Virginia railroad</orgName>, about <measure n="30miles" type="distance">thirty miles</measure> this side of <placeName reg="Knoxville, Knox, Tennessee" key="tgn,7013841">Knoxville</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="291"/>They are in possession of <num value="3">three</num> trains, <num value="1">one</num> of which they captured in <placeName reg="Knoxville, Knox, Tennessee" key="tgn,7013841">Knoxville</placeName>, the other <num value="2">two</num> were taken on route from <placeName reg="Bristol, Sullivan, Tennessee" key="tgn,2098111">Bristol</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="292"/>The train that left the latter place on Wednesday was captured on its arrival in <placeName reg="Knoxville, Knox, Tennessee" key="tgn,7013841">Knoxville</placeName>, but the conductor made his escape.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="293"/>They captured the telegraph operator at <placeName reg="Morristown, Hamblen, Tennessee" key="tgn,2100483">Morristown</placeName>, and <num value="1">one</num> report is that they got <num value="3">three</num> operatives, but this is doubtful. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="294"/> It is said that the force of the enemy operating in that region is not <orgName n="command"><persName n="Burnside,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00068" reg="mostcommon:Burnside,nomatch:0"><surname>Burnside</surname></persName>'s command</orgName>, but bushwhackers and sharpshooters under <persName n="Carter,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00069" reg="mostcommon:Carter,nomatch:0"><surname>Carter</surname></persName>, composed of Union men of <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825"><rs type="direction">East</rs> Tennessee</placeName>, and that <persName n="Buckner,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00070" reg="mostcommon:Buckner,nomatch:0"><surname>Buckner</surname></persName> with his command was absent from <placeName reg="Knoxville, Knox, Tennessee" key="tgn,7013841">Knoxville</placeName>, which being known to these gentry they took advantage of the situation to make a descent.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="295"/>upon that place.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="296"/><persName n="Burnside,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00071" reg="mostcommon:Burnside,nomatch:0"><surname>Burnside</surname></persName>, it is said in afraid to enter the country, feasting that <unclear></unclear> retreat will be cut off. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="297"/> <persName n="Robert,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00072" reg="mostcommon:Robert,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Robert</surname></persName> A Heart, wounded at <placeName reg="Helena, Phillips, Arkansas" key="tgn,2008470">Helena</placeName> on <date value="07-04">July 4th,</date> and carried to <unclear></unclear> as a prisoner, has died.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="298"/>He was at <num value="1">one</num> time inspector General on <persName n="Thudman,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00073" reg="mostcommon:Thudman,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Thudman</surname></persName>'s <unclear></unclear> and subsequently <rs type="role2">Colonel</rs> of <unclear></unclear> regiment. </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> <milestone unit="page" n="2"/> 
<div1 type="page-image"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="299"/><figure entity="NW_RichTimesD_025_059_002"> <figDesc>Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume <num value="25">25</num>, <num value="59">Number 59</num>, <ref n="page 2">page 2</ref>. </figDesc> </figure></p> </div1> <milestone unit="column" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.</head> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="300"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.</head> 
<div2 type="morning"> 
<head><date value="1863-09-08">Tuesday morning.....September 8, 1863.</date></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">The Governor's Message.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="301"/> --This is a plain, strong, business-like document, eminently characteristic of its author.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="302"/><persName n="Letcher,Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00074" reg="nearbymention:Letcher,John,,,"><roleName n="Governor">Governor</roleName> <surname>Letcher</surname></persName> evidently thinks that where a thing is to be done, the best way is to set about it in earnest and at once.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="303"/>His military recommendations are admirable.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="304"/>We hope a bill will be framed embracing them all. We hope it will be made the duty of all sheriffs and sheriffs' officers as well as of all officers of militia, to arrest stragglers from the army, or deserters, for that is the true name.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="305"/>It is time to begin to shoot these gentry, no matter what excuse they may make for their conduct, and they always have some pitiful tale to tell.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="306"/>Justice should be inexorable &mdash; listen to no apology &mdash; reject all defence &mdash; punish for the act, and let it be known that hereafter punishment will always be inflicted.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="307"/>Then desertions would cease, and until then it never will cease. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="308"/> <persName n="Letcher,Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00075" reg="nearbymention:Letcher,John,,,"><roleName n="Governor">Governor</roleName> <surname>Letcher</surname></persName> has several paragraphs full of pith and meaning upon the strange conduct of <persName n="Memminger,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00076" reg="mostcommon:Memminger,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Memminger</surname></persName> and Congress, in recommending the discredit, and actually discrediting their own notes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="309"/>The French Convention did that on <num value="1">one</num> occasion, but since the days of those madmen we do not imagine that any other body ever attempted it. Its effects have already been seen in the suspicion of the people with regard to Confederate money of every kind, and the loss and inconvenience to which taxpayers have been subjected.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="310"/>We hope the <name>Legislature</name> will wash their hands of the business.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="311"/>It was very weak in the last Legislature to lend themselves to the schemes of Congress and the <name>Treasury</name>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="312"/>We can only forgive them on the supposition that they knew not what they did. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="313"/> <persName n="Letcher,Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00077" reg="nearbymention:Letcher,John,,,"><roleName n="Governor">Governor</roleName> <surname>Letcher</surname></persName>, after calling attention to the condition of our railroads, (a most important subject,) passes a lofty eulogium upon <persName n="Jackson,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00078" reg="nearbymention:Jackson,Thomas,J.,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Jackson</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="314"/>We wish he had closed it with a recommendation to appropriate <measure n="200000dollars" type="currency">$200,000</measure> to the use of his wife and children.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="315"/>If ever the <rs>State</rs> was bound in honor and justice to take care of anybody whatever, it is thus bound to take care of those who were nearest and dearest to <persName n="Jackson,,Stonewall,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00079" reg="default:Jackson,Stonewall,,,"><foreName>Stonewall</foreName> <surname>Jackson</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="316"/> The Governor raises the old cry against extortioners, attributing to these men (whom we are not disposed to defend) the evils inevitably resulting from a depreciated currency.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="317"/>If he can only prevail on Congress to curtail the redundant currency, until it is cut down to the proper amount necessary to serve the country, he will get rid of &#x0022;extortioners, forestallers, regretters,&#x0022; and all that sort of cattle at once, without reviving the law of <dateStruct value="1777--"><year reg="1777">1777</year></dateStruct>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="318"/>If he cannot do this penal laws cannot do it. Improve the currency, and the extortioners will fall. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Latest Northern news.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="319"/> --The news from the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> which we publish to-day has <num value="2">two</num> points of interest.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="320"/><num value="1">One</num> is the news of the occupation of <placeName reg="New Matamoras, Washington, Ohio" key="tgn,2081017">Matamoras</placeName> in force by the <rs>French</rs>, and the other is the rise in the value of gold, which was so considerable and so sudden as to indicate the existence of some new source of anxiety to money dealers.--What this is we can only conjecture.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="321"/>It may be unfavorable accounts from <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName>; or it may be this occupation of <placeName reg="New Matamoras, Washington, Ohio" key="tgn,2081017">Matamoras</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="322"/>It may be neither of these, and something else may have produced the disturbance in <address><street n="Wall street">Wall street</street></address>. --The occupation of <placeName reg="New Matamoras, Washington, Ohio" key="tgn,2081017">Matamoras</placeName> by an efficient <name>French</name> force is, nevertheless, an important event, and must occasion uneasiness in <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="323"/>We suppose it is true.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="324"/>We hope it is. It is certainly as agreeable to us as it is disagreeable to the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> that such a force should occupy just that place on the southern bank of the <rs type="place">Rio Grande</rs>, across the border from <placeName reg="Texas" key="tgn,7007826">Texas</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="325"/>We take it that such a movement must be for the protection of <name>French</name> commerce, and that <name>French</name> ships will soon convey away cotton that has crossed the river from <placeName reg="Brownsville, Haywood, Tennessee" key="tgn,2098151">Brownsville</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="326"/>The <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> would like to prevent this traffic between our people and the <rs>French</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="327"/>We have no objection to their trying to do so. As strengthening the probability of the statement, we publish the following extract from the <rs>Paris</rs> correspondence of the <orgName n="London Times" type="newspaper">London <hi rend="italics">Times</hi></orgName>, of <date value="08-20">August 20th.</date> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="328"/> &#x0022;According to private letters received by the last mail, <placeName key="tgn,1018380" n="1.000 4" reg="tampico,tamaulipas,mexico,north and central america">Tampico</placeName> and Tuxpan were about to be occupied by the <rs>French</rs>, and it was expected <hi rend="italics">that <placeName reg="New Matamoras, Washington, Ohio" key="tgn,2081017">Matamoras</placeName> would also have to be held on account of the important cotton trade which might there be carried on.</hi> &#x0022; </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="329"/> --It was rumored yesterday that a dispatch had been received by <persName n="Cooper,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00080" reg="mostcommon:Cooper,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Cooper</surname></persName> announcing the withdrawal of the troops from <placeName key="tgn,2525074" n="1.000 107" reg="morris island, charleston, south carolina">Fort Wagner</placeName> and <placeName key="tgn,7013582" n="1.000 46" reg="charleston, charleston, south carolina">Fort Sumter</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="330"/>We think this highly probable, as a gentleman who left <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName> on Friday says the enemy were at that time within <placeName><distance reg="75yards">seventy- five yards</distance> of <placeName key="tgn,2525074" n="1.000 107" reg="morris island, charleston, south carolina">Fort Wagner</placeName></placeName>, and <placeName key="tgn,7013582" n="1.000 46" reg="charleston, charleston, south carolina">Sumter</placeName> is entirely in ruins.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="331"/>The same gentleman says the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> trouble have not yet commenced, nor will commence, until they get into the harbor.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="332"/>The universal belief at <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName> was that <placeName key="tgn,7013582" n="1.000 46" reg="charleston, charleston, south carolina">Sumter</placeName> and <persName n="Wagner,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00081" reg="mostcommon:Wagner,nomatch:0"><surname>Wagner</surname></persName> would be taken, but that <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName> would not be. Our informant expressed the opinion that the iron clads would never get <hi rend="italics">out</hi> of the harbor if they once got in. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><orgName n="Virginia Legislature" type="legislature">Virginia Legislature</orgName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="333"/> --In response to the proclamation of the <rs>Governor</rs>, the two Houses of the <orgName n="General Assembly" type="misc">General Assembly of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName></orgName> convened in extra session at the <rs>Capitol</rs> yesterday. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="334"/> The <hi rend="italics">Senate</hi> was called to order by <persName n="Montague,Lieutenant-Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00082" reg="mostcommon:Montague,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lieutenant-Governor">Lt. Governor</roleName> <surname>Montague</surname></persName>, and was afterwards organized by the election of the following officers: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="335"/> <persName n="Davis,Clerk,Shelton,C.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00083" reg="default:Davis,Shelton,C.,,"><roleName n="Clerk">Clerk</roleName> <foreName>Shelton</foreName> <foreName>C.</foreName> <surname>Davis</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond city</placeName>; Sergeant-at-Arms, <persName n="Jordan,,John,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00084" reg="default:Jordan,John,A.,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName> <surname>Jordan</surname></persName>, of late of <persName n="Wight,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00085" reg="mostcommon:Wight,nomatch:0"><surname>Wight</surname></persName>; Doorkeeper, <persName n="Sutton,,Francis,V.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00086" reg="default:Sutton,Francis,V.,,"><foreName>Francis</foreName> <foreName>V.</foreName> <surname>Sutton</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond city</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="336"/> After the organization of the <name>Senate</name> was effected the message of the <rs>Governor</rs> was read and the body adjourned. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="337"/> In the <hi rend="italics">House</hi> the old Clerk, <persName n="Gordon,,William,F.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00087" reg="default:Gordon,William,F.,,"><foreName n="William">Wm.</foreName> <foreName>F.</foreName> <surname>Gordon</surname></persName>, <rs type="role">Esq.</rs>, read the <name>Proclamation</name> of the <rs>Governor</rs> convening the <name>Legislature</name>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="338"/>An election for officers of the <rs type="place">House</rs> then took place, with the following result. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="339"/> <rs type="role" reg="Speaker">Speaker</rs>, <persName n="Sheffey,,Hugh,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00088" reg="default:Sheffey,Hugh,W.,,"><foreName>Hugh</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Sheffey</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Augusta, Richmond, Georgia" key="tgn,7017498">Augusta</placeName>; <persName n="Gordon,Clerk,William,F.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00089" reg="default:Gordon,William,F.,,"><roleName n="Clerk">Clerk</roleName>, <foreName n="William">Wm.</foreName> <foreName>F.</foreName> <surname>Gordon</surname></persName>, of <placeName key="tgn,2002137" n="1.000 2" reg="albemarle, virginia, united states">Albemarle</placeName>; Sergeant-at-Arms, <persName n="Burke,,Robert,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00090" reg="default:Burke,Robert,W.,,"><foreName>Robert</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Burke</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Augusta, Richmond, Georgia" key="tgn,7017498">Augusta</placeName>; <num value="1" type="ordinal">First</num> Doorkeeper, <persName n="Freeman,,Samuel,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00091" reg="default:Freeman,Samuel,,,"><foreName>Samuel</foreName> <surname>Freeman</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond city</placeName>; <num value="2" type="ordinal">Second</num> Doorkeeper, <persName n="Wilson,,George,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00092" reg="default:Wilson,George,W.,,"><foreName>George</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Wilson</surname></persName>, of <persName n="Botetourt,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00093" reg="mostcommon:Botetourt,nomatch:0"><surname>Botetourt</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="340"/> On assuming the duties of the <name>Chair</name> <persName n="Shelby,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00094" reg="mostcommon:Shelby,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Shelby</surname></persName> addressed the <rs type="place">House</rs> in eloquent and appropriate terms, after which the <name>Message</name> of the <rs>Governor</rs> was read. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="341"/> On motion of <persName n="Fleming,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00095" reg="mostcommon:Fleming,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Fleming</surname></persName>, of High <milestone unit="column" n="2"/> land, <num value="1200">1,200</num> copies of the <name>Message</name> were ordered to be printed for the use of the members of the <rs type="place">House</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="342"/> The remainder of the day was expended in the discussion of the rules of the <rs type="place">House</rs>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">From <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="343"/> --From intelligence received yesterday from <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName>, it is generally understood that <orgName n="Battery Wagner" type="battery">battery Wagner</orgName> has been evacuated by our forces, thus giving the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> possession of the whole of <placeName reg="Morris Island, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,2525074">Morris Island</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="344"/>What effect the undisputed occupation of this island is to have upon the future movements around that city remains to be seen; but we have the assurance of those who are familiar with the condition of affairs there that the safety of the city is in no wise involved, and not at all compromised by this evacuation. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Reported Russo-<rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> alliance.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="345"/> --The <placeName reg="Vienna, Fairfax, Virginia" key="tgn,2114749">Vienna</placeName> <hi rend="italics">Press,</hi> of <date value="08-19">August 19th,</date> has the following: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="346"/> We hear that communications have been received from an English source, according to which we must prepare-ourselves for the approaching ratification of an offensive and defensive alliance between <placeName reg="Saint Petersburg, Pinellas, Florida" key="tgn,7014446">St. Petersburg</placeName> and <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="347"/>This eventuality, should this somewhat speculative information be confirmed, would principally affect the bearings of the <rs n="Mexican" type="group">Mexican</rs> and Polish questions. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="7"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Latest from the <rs>North</rs>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="348"/> --Another new arrival <hi rend="smallcaps">This (<dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct>) Morning</hi> of late Northern papers at the <rs>Confederate Reading Room</rs> bringing dates up to last <date>Friday</date>, the <dateStruct value="--4"><day reg="4">4th inst.</day></dateStruct> Full files <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> Pistorlals &#x0026;c. Call and see. Also, all the city and Southern papers and periodicals.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="349"/>Paper, envelopes, &#x0026;c., for writing letters.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="350"/>Admission (good for all day) <measure n="20cents" type="currency">20 cents</measure>. </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="special"> 
<head rend="italics">Special Notices.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="351"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="amusements"> 
<head rend="italics">Amusements.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="352"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="military"> 
<head rend="italics">Military Notices.</head> 
<div3 type="orders" n="1"> 
<head>Notice.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="353"/> --I am authorized by the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs> to raise from those not now connected with the army, nor subject to conscription, a company of cavalry, to be attached to <orgName n="command"><persName n="Mosby,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00096" reg="mostcommon:Mosby,nomatch:0"><surname>Mosby</surname></persName>'s command</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="354"/>Any such persons desirous of service under that celebrated chieftain will call upon me at the office of the <num value="2" type="ordinal">Second</num> <rs type="role" reg="Auditor">Auditor</rs> of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Thomas,,John,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00097" reg="default:Thomas,John,H.,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName>  <surname>Thomas</surname></persName>.</signed> <term type="printrun">se 8--3t</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="355"/><measure n="70dollars" type="currency">Seventy Dollars</measure> Bounty to all youths between the ages of <num value="15">15</num> and <num value="18">18</num> who enlist in <persName n="Burit,Captain,H.,D.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00098" reg="default:Burit,H.,D.,,"><roleName n="Captain">Capt</roleName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <foreName>D.</foreName> <surname>Burit</surname></persName>'s <orgName n="company">company</orgName>, to master in <orgName n="battalion"><persName n="Munford,Major,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00099" reg="mostcommon:Munford,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <surname>Munford</surname></persName>'s battalion</orgName>, <unclear></unclear> special and local defence of the city of <placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 6" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="356"/>Apply at camp, near the old <placeName reg="Fair Grounds">Fair Grounds</placeName>. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Burr,,H.,D.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00100" reg="default:Burr,H.,D.,,"><foreName>H.</foreName> <foreName>D.</foreName>  <surname>Burr</surname></persName>, <rs type="role2">Capt</rs> com'g.</signed> <term type="printrun">se 8--6t</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="3"> 
<head>Henrico Mounted men.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="357"/> --The Henrico Mounted Men will meet at <placeName reg="Henrico Country Court-House">Henrico Country Court-House</placeName> on <dateStruct><day type="name">Thursday</day></dateStruct>, the <num value="10" type="ordinal">10th</num> inst, at <time value="12oclock">12 o'clock</time> M, punctually, on important business. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="358"/> <term type="printrun">se 8--1t</term> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="359"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> <milestone unit="column" n="3"/> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="telegraphic"> 
<head>Telegraphic news.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>From <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName>.</head> 
<argument> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="360"/> <hi rend="italics">evacuation of <placeName reg="Morris Island, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,2525074">Morris Island</placeName> &mdash; another demand for the surrender of <placeName key="tgn,7013582" n="1.000 46" reg="charleston, charleston, south carolina">Fort Sumter</placeName>--<persName n="Beauregard,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00101" reg="mostcommon:Beauregard,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Beauregard</surname></persName>'s reply &mdash; Furious bombardment.</hi> </p> </argument> 
<div4 type="entry" n="1"> 
<head></head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-09-7"><month reg="09">Sept.</month> <day reg="7">7</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="361"/> --The bombardment was kept up without intermission all day yesterday and far into the night.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="362"/>About <num value="150">one hundred and fifty</num> of our men were killed and wounded at <orgName n="Battery Wagner" type="battery">batteries Wagner</orgName> and <orgName n="Battery Gregg" type="battery">Gregg</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="363"/> The attempt to assault <persName n="Gregg,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00102" reg="mostcommon:Gregg,nomatch:0"><surname>Gregg</surname></persName> was repulsed before the enemy had completed their landing.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="364"/>Great havoc is supposed to have been played in enemy's boats by our grape and canister at dark. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="365"/> Yesterday afternoon, the enemy having advanced their sappers up to the very moat of <persName n="Wagner,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00103" reg="mostcommon:Wagner,nomatch:0"><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>, and it being impossible to hold the island longer, <persName n="Beauregard,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00104" reg="mostcommon:Beauregard,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Beauregard</surname></persName> ordered the evacuation, which was executed between <time value="8pm">8 P. M.</time> and <time value="1am">1 A. M.</time>, with success.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="366"/>We spiked the guns of <persName n="Wagner,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00105" reg="mostcommon:Wagner,nomatch:0"><surname>Wagner</surname></persName> and <persName n="Gregg,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00106" reg="mostcommon:Gregg,nomatch:0"><surname>Gregg</surname></persName>, and withdrew noiselessly in <num value="40">forty</num> barges.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="367"/>Only <num value="1">one</num> barge, containing <num value="12">twelve</num> men, was captured.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="368"/>The enemy now holds <placeName reg="Cummings Point, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,2271638">Cummings Point</placeName>, in full view of the city.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="369"/>All quiet this morning. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="2"> 
<head>[<num value="2" type="ordinal">Second</num> Dispatch.]</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-09-7"><month reg="09">Sept.</month> <day reg="7">7</day></dateStruct> </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="370"/> --Noon.--A dispatch from <persName n="Elliott,Major,Stephen,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00107" reg="default:Elliott,Stephen,,,"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <foreName>Stephen</foreName> <surname>Elliott</surname></persName>, commanding at <placeName key="tgn,7013582" n="1.000 46" reg="charleston, charleston, south carolina">Fort Sumter</placeName>, announces that a flag of truce, demanding the immediate surrender of that fort, has just been received from <persName n="Dahlgren,Admiral,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00108" reg="mostcommon:Dahlgren,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Admiral">Admiral</roleName> <surname>Dahlgren</surname></persName> by <persName n="Brown,Lieutenant,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00109" reg="mostcommon:Brown,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lieutenant">Lieut.</roleName> <surname>Brown</surname></persName>, of the <term type="ship">steamer</term> <rs type="ship">Palmetto State</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="371"/> <persName n="Beauregard,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00110" reg="mostcommon:Beauregard,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Beauregard</surname></persName> telegraphed to <persName n="Elliott,Major,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00111" reg="nearbymention:Elliott,Stephen,,,"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <surname>Elliott</surname></persName> to reply to <persName n="Dahlgren,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00112" reg="mostcommon:Dahlgren,nomatch:0"><surname>Dahlgren</surname></persName> that he can have <placeName key="tgn,7013582" n="1.000 46" reg="charleston, charleston, south carolina">Fort Sumter</placeName> when he takes it and holds it, and that in the meantime such demands are puerile and unbecoming. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="3"> 
<head>[<num value="3" type="ordinal">Third</num> Dispatch.]</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-09-7"><month reg="09">Sept.</month> <day reg="7">7</day></dateStruct>--<time value="8pm">8 P. M.</time> </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="372"/> --At <time value="6pm">6 o'clock P. M.</time> the iron-clads and monitors approached <placeName key="tgn,7013582" n="1.000 46" reg="charleston, charleston, south carolina">Fort Sumter</placeName>, closer than usual and opened a hot fire against it. Our batteries on <placeName reg="Sullivan's Island, Sullivan's Island, South Carolina" key="tgn,2096782">Sullivan's Island</placeName>, including <placeName key="tgn,2335409" n="1.000 25" reg="fort moultrie, charleston, south carolina">Fort Moultrie</placeName>, replied heavily; the firing still going on. </p> </div4> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head>From <placeName reg="Tennessee, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName>.</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Chattanooga, Hamilton, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017496">Chattanooga</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-09-6"><month reg="09">Sept.</month> <day reg="6">6</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="373"/> --With the exception of a few shells thrown at our pontoons yesterday, nothing occurred to break the monotony at this place.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="374"/>The enemy seems quite active, both above and below the place, but there is no further indication of an attack.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="375"/>The best informed persons think that no attack will be made here, but an effort will be made to flank us. <num value="2">Two</num> privates, <num value="4">four</num> regulars, and <num value="1">one</num> of <persName n="Rosecrans,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00113" reg="mostcommon:Rosecrans,nomatch:0"><surname>Rosecrans</surname></persName>'s telegraph operators were captured yesterday near <placeName reg="Running Water Bridge">Running Water Bridge</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="376"/> <hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="Atlanta, Fulton, Georgia" key="tgn,7013331">Atlanta</placeName>,</hi> <date value="09-07">Sept. 7.</date>--Passengers from <placeName reg="Chattanooga, Hamilton, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017496">Chattanooga</placeName> report a force of the enemy at <placeName key="tgn,2108378" n="1.000 6" reg="waxahachie, ellis, texas">Waxahachie</placeName> &mdash; number not stated.--We learn from <placeName reg="Rome, Floyd, Georgia" key="tgn,2024102">Rome</placeName> that another force is advancing on that point.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="377"/>All accounts concur in stating that the feeling and disposition of the army is <num value="1">one</num> of great desire to meet the enemy, and confidence in the result.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="378"/>From <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825"><rs type="direction">East</rs> Tennessee</placeName> no recent movement to report. </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="lost"> 
<head rend="italics">Lost, Strayed, &#x0026;c.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="379"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="rent"> 
<head rend="italics">For Rent and Sale.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="380"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="educational"> 
<head rend="italics">Educational.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="381"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="negroes"> 
<head rend="italics">Negroes for Sale and hire.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>For Sale</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="382"/> --To remain in the city or <unclear>vic</unclear>, a valuable Man Servant, (middle age.) For honesty, industry, and sobriety, his former life gives assurance.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="383"/>The owner consents to part with him that he may be near his wife.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="384"/>Apply at <num value="7">No. 7</num> <placeName reg="Belvin's Building">Belvin's Building</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="385"/> <term type="printrun">sc 8--2t</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head>Negroes for hire.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="386"/> --We have for hire, for the balance of the year, several able-bodied Men, and a good <persName n="Cook,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00114" reg="mostcommon:Cook,nomatch:0"><surname>Cook</surname></persName>, Washer and Ironer. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Clopton,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00115" reg="mostcommon:Clopton,nomatch:0"><surname>Clopton</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="Lyne,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00116" reg="mostcommon:Lyne,nomatch:0"><surname>Lyne</surname></persName>.</signed> <term type="printrun">se 7--2t</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="387"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="4"/> 
<div2 type="announcements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="died" n="1"> 
<head>Died.</head> 
<div4 type="obit" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="388"/> On <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct> <time>morning</time>, <num value="1" type="ordinal">1st</num> inst, at <num value="3">3</num>&#x00BC; o'clock, <persName><foreName>Mary</foreName></persName> R, infant <persName n="Wm,IsFather,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00117" reg="mostcommon:Wm,nomatch:0"><roleName n="IsFather">daughter of</roleName> <surname>Wm</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="389"/>M. and <persName n="Hope,,Virginia,F.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00118" reg="default:Hope,Virginia,F.,,"><foreName>Virginia</foreName> <foreName>F.</foreName> <surname>Hope</surname></persName> aged <measure n="20months" type="date">twenty months</measure>, late of <placeName reg="Portsmouth, Portsmouth, Virginia" key="tgn,7014278">Portsmouth</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="390"/> Sweet little Hady is an angel now, to beckon her loved ones to the skies.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="391"/>May He who alone can comfort the broken hearted sanctify this sad affliction to the good of her doting parents. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="392"/> The relatives and friends of the family are respectfully invited to attend her funeral, from the residence of her parents, on <persName n="Venable,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00119" reg="mostcommon:Venable,nomatch:0"><surname>Venable</surname></persName> and <num value="23" type="ordinal">23d</num> sts, this (<dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct>) morning at <time value="10oclock">10 o'clock</time>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="393"/> <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName> and <placeName reg="Portsmouth, Portsmouth, Virginia" key="tgn,7014278">Portsmouth</placeName>, Va, and Selms, <persName><foreName>Ala</foreName></persName>, papers please copy. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="394"/> On <dateStruct value="1863-09-07"><day type="name">Monday</day>, <month reg="09">Sept.</month> <day reg="7">7th</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>, at the residence of <persName n="Christian,Reverend,W.,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00120" reg="default:Christian,W.,H.,,"><roleName n="Reverend">Rev.</roleName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Christian</surname></persName>, in this city, of pulmonary affection, <persName n="Perkins,Miss,Ann,B.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00121" reg="default:Perkins,Ann,B.,,"><roleName n="Miss">Miss</roleName> <foreName>Ann</foreName> <foreName>B.</foreName> <surname>Perkins</surname></persName>, in the <num value="59" type="ordinal">59th</num> year of her age. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="395"/> Her friends, and those of her sister, <persName n="Richardson,Mrs.,A.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00122" reg="default:Richardson,A.,W.,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <foreName>A.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Richardson</surname></persName>, are invited to attend her funeral this (<dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct>) afternoon at <time value="4oclock">4 o'clock</time>, from <placeName reg="Union, Union, South Carolina" key="tgn,2096848">Union Station</placeName> <orgName n="Methodist Church" type="church">Methodist Church</orgName>. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="396"/> At his home, on <placeName key="possibilities=40" n="1.000 10" reg=",">Church Hill</placeName>, corner <num value="25" type="ordinal">25th</num> and Broad sts, on the afternoon of the <num value="7" type="ordinal">7th</num> inst, <persName n="Listern,,Joseph,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00123" reg="default:Listern,Joseph,,,"><foreName>Joseph</foreName> <surname>Listern</surname></persName>, youngest child of <rs type="role">Dr.</rs> W. O and <persName n="Snellings,,Mary,E.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00124" reg="default:Snellings,Mary,E.,,"><foreName>Mary</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>Snellings</surname></persName>, aged <measure n="2years" type="date">2 years</measure> and <measure n="5months" type="date">5 months</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="397"/> &#x0022;Suffer little children to come unto me, for of such is the kingdom of <name n="God" type="God">God</name>.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="398"/> The friends of the family are respectfully invited to attend the funeral this (<dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct>) morning, at <time value="11oclock">11 o'clock</time>. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="399"/> On <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct>, the <num value="4" type="ordinal">4th</num> inst, at <time value="10pm">10 o'clock P. M.</time>, after a short illness, <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> A Vaiden in the <num value="24" type="ordinal">24th</num> year of her age. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="400"/> Mother, sisters, and friends, let this case thy aching heart and wipe away thy mourning tears, that her days of weariness and nights of anguish are over; her poor afflicted body shall know no more pain; her worn and weary spirit shall no more sigh in exile from Heaven. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="401"/> <cit><q> <lg type="stanza"> <l>Calm on the bosom of thy <name n="God" type="God">God</name>. </l><l>Fair Spirit!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="402"/>rest thee low; </l><l>Even while with us thy footsteps trod, </l><l>His Seal was on thy brow, </l><l>Dust to its narrow house beneath, </l><l>Soul to its place on high!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="403"/></l><l>They that have seen thy look in death, </l><l>No more may fear to die. </l> </lg> </q><bibl n="F. T. J"></bibl></cit> </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="404"/> At the residence of her daughter, in this city, <persName n="Best,Mrs.,Harriet,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00125" reg="default:Best,Harriet,H.,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <foreName>Harriet</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Best</surname></persName>, in the <num value="52" type="ordinal">52d</num> year of her age. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="405"/> <cit><q> <lg type="stanza"> <l>Tears to my eyes are starting, </l><l>And sorrow shades my brow; </l><l>Ah!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="406"/>weary a was at parting, </l><l>I have no mother now. </l> </lg> </q><bibl></bibl></cit> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="407"/> <placeName reg="North Carolina" key="tgn,7007709">North Carolina</placeName> papers please copy. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="6"> 
<head>Obituary.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="408"/> Died, on the <num value="5" type="ordinal">5th</num> inst, <persName n="Bangs,Miss,Elizabeth,Guy,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00126" reg="default:Bangs,Elizabeth,Guy,,"><roleName n="Miss">Miss</roleName> <foreName>Elizabeth</foreName> <foreName>Guy</foreName> <surname>Bangs</surname></persName>, piece of <persName n="Guy,Captain,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00127" reg="default:Guy,James,,,"><roleName n="Captain">Capt</roleName> <foreName>James</foreName> <surname>Guy</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Alexandria, Alexandria, Virginia" key="tgn,7013269">Alexandria</placeName>, Va, and the adopted daughter of <persName n="Margaret,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00128" reg="mostcommon:Margaret,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Margaret</surname></persName> M <persName n="Bangs,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00129" reg="nearbymention:Bangs,Elizabeth,Guy,,"><surname>Bangs</surname></persName>, of the same city. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="409"/> Her funeral sermon was preached at the residence of her sister, <persName n="Johnston,Mrs.,S.,V.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00130" reg="default:Johnston,S.,V.,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <foreName>V.</foreName> <surname>Johnston</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="410"/> She died of consumption after a lingering illness of <measure n="15months" type="date">15 months</measure>, which she bore with <name>Christian</name> patience, in the cheering hope of a home in Heaven.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="411"/>Her remains was interred in <placeName key="tgn,2008520" n="1.000 1" reg="hollywood, clark, arkansas">Hollywood</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="412"/>She was <measure n="45years" type="date">45 years</measure> of age. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="413"/> <cit><q> <lg type="stanza"> <l>She was our <persName><foreName>Lizzie</foreName></persName>, thrice dear to us, </l><l>As daughter, sister, friend; </l><l>Performing each part with child-like duty, </l><l>Fraternal affection and unselfish devotion.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="414"/></l><l>It needed no blood of ours, </l><l>Swelling in her gentle veins, </l><l>To make her more dear to our heart, </l><l>For she was loved by us tenderly, </l><l>And is mourned as a lost treasure.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="415"/></l> </lg> </q><bibl></bibl></cit> </p> </div4> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="wants"> 
<head rend="italics">Wants.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="416"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="chancery"> 
<head rend="italics">Chancery Notices.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="417"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="5"/> 
<div2 type="auction"> 
<head><hi rend="italics"><rs n="auction sales" type="product">Auction Sales</rs></hi>--<hi rend="smallcaps">future days.</hi></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="418"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="real estate"> 
<head rend="italics"><rs n="real estate" type="product">Real Estate</rs> for Sale.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="419"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="6"/> 
<div2 type="auction"> 
<head><hi rend="italics"><rs n="auction sales" type="product">Auction Sales</rs></hi>--<hi rend="smallcaps">future days.</hi></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="420"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="7"/> 
<div2 type="auction"> 
<head><hi rend="italics"><rs n="auction sales" type="product">Auction Sales</rs></hi>--<hi rend="smallcaps">this day.</hi></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="421"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="runaways"> 
<head rend="italics">Runaways</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head><measure n="50dollars" type="currency">Fifty dollars</measure> reward.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="422"/> --Runaway from our farm, in <placeName reg="Nelson, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002175">Nelson county</placeName>, on the <dateStruct value="-08-17"><day reg="17">17th</day> of <month reg="08">August</month></dateStruct>, a negro woman named <persName><foreName>Eliza</foreName></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="423"/>She is about <measure n="23years" type="date">23 years</measure> old, likely, black, and above the average size.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="424"/>She is originally from <placeName reg="North Carolina" key="tgn,7007709">North Carolina</placeName>, was purchased by us in <placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 6" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName>, and lived with <num value="1">one</num> of us a short time at <placeName reg="Madison Court House">Madison Court House</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="425"/>She was apprehended and made her escape from <persName n="Marrin,Mister,Thomas,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00131" reg="default:Marrin,Thomas,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>Thomas</foreName> <surname>Marrin</surname></persName>'s, on the <orgName n="Orange and Alexandria Railroad" type="railroad">Orange and Alexandria Railroad</orgName>, near <placeName reg="Covesville, Albemarle, Virginia" key="tgn,2111339">Covesville, Albemarle county</placeName>, last week, and is doubtless making her way towards <placeName key="tgn,2111971" n="1.000 34" reg="gordonsville, orange, virginia">Gordonsville</placeName> or <placeName key="tgn,7013964" n="1.000 6" reg="richmond, richmond, virginia">Richmond</placeName>, or the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> lines.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="426"/><measure n="50dollars" type="currency">$50</measure> will be given for her apprehension and delivery to us, or <measure n="30dollars" type="currency">$30</measure> of secured in jail so that we get her. Address <placeName reg="Madison Court-House">Madison Court-House</placeName> or <placeName key="tgn,2112332" n="1.000 1" reg="howardsville, albemarle, virginia">Howardsville</placeName>. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Lewis,,Z.,R.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00132" reg="default:Lewis,Z.,R.,,"><foreName>Z.</foreName> <foreName>R.</foreName>  <surname>Lewis</surname></persName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed><persName n="Harisock,,D.,J.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00133" reg="default:Harisock,D.,J.,,"><foreName>D.</foreName> <foreName>J.</foreName>  <surname>Harisock</surname></persName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed><persName n="Blakey,,A.,R.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00134" reg="default:Blakey,A.,R.,,"><foreName>A.</foreName> <foreName>R.</foreName>  <surname>Blakey</surname></persName></signed> <term type="printrun">se 8--10t</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="427"/> I will pay <measure n="100dollars" type="currency">one hundred dollars</measure> for the delivery of my woman <persName n="Easter,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00135" reg="mostcommon:Easter,nomatch:0"><surname>Easter</surname></persName>, sometimes called <persName n="Hester,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00136" reg="mostcommon:Hester,nomatch:0"><surname>Hester</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="428"/>She is about <num value="40">40</num> or <measure n="45years" type="date">45 years</measure> old; brown skin; good teeth a little apart and project in front; is about <measure n="5feet" type="distance">5 feet</measure> high, cut very stout.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="429"/>Deliver her to <persName n="Lee,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00137" reg="mostcommon:Lee,nomatch:0"><surname>Lee</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="James,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00138" reg="mostcommon:James,nomatch:0"><surname>James</surname></persName>, Ane Coneers, <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Va.</placeName> </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Cocke,,H.,F.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00139" reg="default:Cocke,H.,F.,,"><foreName>H.</foreName> <foreName>F.</foreName>  <surname>Cocke</surname></persName>.</signed> <term type="printrun">se 8--eod3t</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head><measure n="20dollars" type="currency">Twenty dollars</measure> reward.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="430"/> --Will be given for the apprehension and delivery to me of my servant girl Rose, who ran away on the morning of the <dateStruct value="--7"><day reg="7">7th inst.</day></dateStruct> Rose is about <measure n="4feet" type="distance">4 feet</measure> <num value="6">6</num> or <measure n="8inches" type="distance">8 inches</measure> high, <num value="14">14</num> or <measure n="15years" type="date">15 years</measure> old, dark skin, and stoutly formed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="431"/>She had on a new dark blue homespun dress. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Brauer,,B.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00140" reg="default:Brauer,B.,,,"><foreName>B.</foreName>  <surname>Brauer</surname></persName>.</signed> <lb/> <rs n="Stall 25">Stall No. 25</rs>, 1st Market. <term type="printrun">se 8--3t</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head>Runaway--<measure n="350dollars" type="currency">$350</measure> reward.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="432"/> --Ran away from the subscriber, about the <dateStruct value="-07-25"><day reg="25">25th</day> of <month reg="07">July</month></dateStruct> last, a boy, named <rs type="role2">Major</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="433"/>He is a bright mulatto, about <measure n="21years" type="date">21 years</measure> old; <measure n="5feet" type="distance">5 feet</measure> <num value="8.5">8&#x00BD;</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="434"/>inches high, and is a very likely boy. He was raised near <placeName reg="Chesterfield Court House">Chesterfield C. H.</placeName> <placeName reg="Virginia" key="tgn,7007919">Va.</placeName>, and a supposed that he is now in that neighborhood, and probably harbored by some person.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="435"/>I will give a reward of <measure n="150dollars" type="currency">$150</measure> for his apprehension and confinement that I get him again, and <measure n="205dollars" type="currency">$205</measure> for the conviction of any person harboring him. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Roller,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00141" reg="expanded:Roller,"><foreName>John</foreName>  <surname>Roller</surname></persName>.</signed> <term type="printrun">se 1--cod4w.</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="436"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> </body> </text> </TEI.2>
 
