<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> <!DOCTYPE TEI.2 PUBLIC "-//TEI P4//DTD Main DTD Driver File//EN" "http://www.tei-c.org/Guidelines/DTD/tei2.dtd" [ <!ENTITY % TEI.XML "INCLUDE"> <!ENTITY % PersProse PUBLIC "-//Perseus P4//DTD Perseus Prose//EN" "http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/DTD/1.0/PersProse.dtd" > %PersProse; <!NOTATION jpg SYSTEM "JPEG"> <!ENTITY NW_RichTimesD_024_139_001 SYSTEM "NW_RichTimesD_024_139_001.jpg" NDATA jpg> <!ENTITY NW_RichTimesD_024_139_002 SYSTEM "NW_RichTimesD_024_139_002.jpg" NDATA jpg> ]> <TEI.2 id="NW_RichTimesD_024_139"> <teiHeader type="aacr2"> <fileDesc> <titleStmt> <title type="245">The Daily Dispatch: June 11, 1863. </title> <title type="gmd">[Electronic resource] </title> <funder> Institute of Museum and Library Services National Leadership Grant </funder> <respStmt> <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> <resp>Creation of digital images: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> <resp>Conversion to Tei.2-conformant markup: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> </respStmt> </titleStmt> <extent>ca. <num value="30">XXX</num> kilobytes </extent> <publicationStmt> <publisher>University of <orgName n="Richmond Library" type="library">Richmond Library</orgName> </publisher> <pubPlace>Richmond, Virginia </pubPlace> <idno type="Url">Nw_richtimesd_024_139</idno> <availability> 
<p>&#x00A9; 2004 by the University of Richmond. </p> 
<p>Url: http://oncampus.Richmond.edu/academics/Library/digital/ </p> </availability> <date> </date> </publicationStmt> <seriesStmt> 
<p>Institute of Museum and Library Services Civil War Newspaper Project </p> </seriesStmt> <notesStmt> <note>page images have been included from the microfilm version. </note> <note>images were scanned with a Sunrise 2000 scanner from microfilm, at 14x reduction ratio at 400 dpi Optical Resolution. Creation Software: Pixel Translations. Pixtiff version 1.135. </note> <note>Ddd note: shipped: 2005_03_18_ddd_url. </note> </notesStmt> <sourceDesc> <biblFull> <titleStmt> <title type="245">The Daily Dispatch: June 11, 1863. </title> <title type="246"><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName> </title> <respStmt> <resp> </resp> <name> </name> </respStmt> </titleStmt> <editionStmt> 
<p> </p> </editionStmt> <extent>2 pages. </extent> <publicationStmt> <publisher>by Cowardin &#x0026; Hammersley. </publisher> <pubPlace>Richmond </pubPlace> <date value="1863-06-11">June 11, 1863</date><idno type="vol">24.139</idno> </publicationStmt> <seriesStmt> <title> </title> </seriesStmt> <notesStmt> <note>microfilm. Ann Arbor, Mi : Proquest. 1 microfilm reel ; 35 mm. </note> </notesStmt> </biblFull> </sourceDesc> </fileDesc> <encodingDesc> <projectDesc> 
<p>Imls Civil War Newspaper Project. </p> </projectDesc> <editorialDecl> 
<p>the images exist as archival Tiff images, with Jpeg versions for internet access. </p> </editorialDecl> <refsDecl> <state unit="article" /> </refsDecl> <classDecl> <taxonomy id="lcsh"> <bibl> <title>Library of Congress subject Headings, </title> <edition>21st edition, 1998</edition> </bibl> </taxonomy> </classDecl> </encodingDesc> <profileDesc> <creation> <date value="1863">1863 </date> </creation> <langUsage> <language id="eng">English </language> <language id="fre">French </language> </langUsage> 
<textClass> <keywords scheme="lcsh"> 
<list type="simple"> 
<item>Newspapers -- Virginia -- Richmond</item> </list> </keywords> </textClass> </profileDesc> <revisionDesc> <change> <date>September, 2005 </date> <respStmt> <resp>Checker </resp> <name>Lesley Byrd, of the University of <orgName n="Richmond Library" type="library">Richmond Library</orgName> </name> </respStmt> 
<item>File checked, not corrected: DO NOT return to vendor. </item> </change> </revisionDesc> </teiHeader> 
<text id="NW_RichTimesD_024_139T"> <front> <milestone unit="page" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="page-image"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="1"/><figure entity="NW_RichTimesD_024_139_001"> <figDesc>Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume <num value="24">24</num>, <num value="139">Number 139</num>, <ref n="page 1">page 1</ref>. </figDesc> </figure></p> </div1> <titlePage> <docTitle><titlePart type="main"> Daily Dispatch </titlePart> </docTitle> <docImprint> Vol. Xxiv &mdash; no.<num value="139">139</num> <pubPlace> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Va.</placeName> </pubPlace> <date value="1863-06-11">Thursday, June 11, 1863</date> price <num value="1">one</num> cent </docImprint> </titlePage> 
<div1 type="subscription"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName><lb/> by <persName n="Cowardin,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00001" reg="mostcommon:Cowardin,nomatch:0"><surname>Cowardin</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="Hammersley,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00002" reg="mostcommon:Hammersley,nomatch:0"><surname>Hammersley</surname></persName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="2"/>the <rs>Daily Dispatch</rs> is served to subscribers at <num value="6.25">six and A Quarter</num> Cents per Week, payable to the <name>Carrier</name> weekly.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="3"/><persName n="Price,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00003" reg="mostcommon:Price,nomatch:0"><surname>Price</surname></persName> for mailing, <measure n="4dollars" type="currency">$4</measure> a year, or <measure n="2.50dollars" type="currency">$2.50</measure> for <measure n="6months" type="date">six months</measure>, in advance.</p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="4"/>the <rs>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</rs> is issued every <dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> and <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> at <measure n="2.00dollars" type="currency">$2.00</measure>, in advance.</p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="5"/>the <rs>Weekly Dispatch</rs> is issued every <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct>, and mailed to subscribers at <measure n="1dollars" type="currency">$1</measure> per annum.</p> </div1> 
<div1 type="advertising"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="6"/> 
<table rows="4" cols="4"> 
<head rend="italics">Terms of Advertising.</head> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <num value="1">1</num> day,</cell><cell><measure n="0.50dollars" type="currency">$0.50</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="5days" type="date">5 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="1.50dollars" type="currency">$1.50</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="2days" type="date">2 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="0.75dollars" type="currency">$0.75</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="5days" type="date">5 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="1.75dollars" type="currency">$1.75</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square <measure n="3days" type="date">3 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="1.00dollars" type="currency">$1.00</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="12days" type="date">12 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="3.00dollars" type="currency">$3.00</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square <measure n="4days" type="date">4 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="1.25dollars" type="currency">$1.25</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <dateStruct value="-1-"><month reg="1">1 month</month></dateStruct>,</cell><cell><measure n="5.00dollars" type="currency">$5.00</measure></cell></row> </table></p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="7"/><hi rend="italics">Larger advertisements in exact properties.</hi></p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="8"/>Advertisements published until forbid, will be charged <measure n="50cents" type="currency">50 cents</measure> per square of <num value="8">eight</num> lines for the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> insertion, and <measure n="25cents" type="currency">25 cents</measure> for each continuance</p> </div1> </front> <body> <milestone unit="column" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head>The Daily Dispatch.</head> 
<div2 type="morning"> 
<head><date value="1863-06-11">Thursday morning...June 11, 1863.</date></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>Confederate currency and credit.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="9"/> The plan of <hi rend="italics">driving</hi> Confederate notes into Confederate bonds, by degrading them after a limited time, is <num value="1">one</num> of questionable justice and questionable wisdom.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="10"/>By it we shall see in a few days a large part of the <rs>Confederate</rs> circulation reduced in value below the balance of that circulation.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="11"/>It is declared not fundable after <dateStruct><month>August</month></dateStruct>, and the <name>Banks</name>, conspiring with the <rs>Government</rs> to degrade its own paper, refuse to take it on deposit.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="12"/>This rejected and denounced currency, too, is that which was issued from the <orgName n="Treasury Department" type="department">Treasury Department</orgName> with the expectation that its own story would commend it everywhere.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="13"/>Its promise of <hi rend="italics"><num value="0.08">eight per cent.</num></hi> was the flattering tale of interest to give it general passport and favor.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="14"/>Yet we find that suddenly, upon a notice of a little over <measure n="2months" type="date">two months</measure>, that interest was reduced to <hi rend="italics"><num value="0.07">seven per cent</num>,</hi> and the notes are refused by the <name>Banks</name>; and in <measure n="3months" type="date">three months</measure> more they are declared not fundable at any rate.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="15"/>The summary degradation of a currency such as this is a sample of the operation of the plan.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="16"/>That it will occasion loss to &#x0022;innocent&#x0022; holders, and throw profit into the hands of speculators, is certain; that it will impair somewhat the credit of the general currency of the <rs>Government</rs>, by disturbing public confidence, may be feared. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="17"/> The system, however, is to be extended to subsequent issues.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="18"/>The notes issued since the <date value="04-06">6th April</date> and hereafter to be issued, are to be allowed to be funded within a year from the date of their emission, at <hi rend="italics"><num value="0.06">six per cent.</num>;</hi> after the end of that year they are only fundable at <hi rend="italics"><num value="0.04">four per cent.</num></hi> Now, if there is a want of disposition to fund these notes, is the funding to be stimulated by a refusal of the banks to take them on deposit, (as in the case of the <num value="8">eight</num> per cents.,) and thus practically to make them uncurrent?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="19"/>The Government having set out with the promise of <hi rend="italics"><num value="0.08">eight per cent.</num>,</hi> and found the <hi rend="italics">driving</hi> system of degrading its issues necessary to stimulate investments in bonds <hi rend="italics">even at that rate,</hi> can hardly look for an increased desire to invest at <hi rend="italics"><num value="6">six</num></hi> and <hi rend="italics"><num value="0.04">four per cent.</num></hi> Should bonding flag, and the banks be induced, in regular succession, to apply the screws, and reject, in turn, another degraded currency, what will likely be the state of affairs?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="20"/>Why, that so large a part of the <rs>Confederate</rs> currency will be uncurrent that the credit of the whole must inevitably be impaired. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="21"/> Governments cannot have immunity from the commercial and moral rules which are held just and lawful in the affairs of men.--These rules are based upon common sense and practice, and have the good and right of all in view.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="22"/>The Government in promising <num value="1">one</num> interest and giving another &mdash; in demanding and enforcing an exchange of <num value="1">one</num> promise to pay for another &mdash; is certainly, as a borrower, not complying with them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="23"/>Had it <hi rend="italics">sold its bonds</hi> and taken in its notes, it would have acted more in accordance with commercial usage.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="24"/>Nor would this course have been financially less beneficial than the <num value="1">one</num> adopted.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="25"/>It would have preserved uniformity of value in notes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="26"/>It would have avoided the depreciation of them by declaring a large part of them neither fundable nor bankable, and, as we fear, some detriment to its own credit.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="27"/>It would have avoided any question of the intentions of the <rs>Government</rs> &mdash; any apprehensions of unfairness.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="28"/>It would have saved the people from the trouble of criticising and culling Confederate notes to find the bankable and the uncurrent.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="29"/>It would have saved them from the losses consequent upon an unconvertable and uncurrent paper issue of a very large amount. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="30"/> As there exists generally the most perfect confidence in the ability and resources of the <orgName n="Confederate Government" type="org">Confederate Government</orgName>, it is to be all the more regretted that it should resort to measures which are calculated to do it no good and to occasion public inconvenience.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="31"/>We anticipate that they will be found so to operate, and be abandoned &mdash; leaving as marks of their impolicy a series of bonds and notes varying widely in their values; a variation wrought upon promises to pay issued to the people, all for the same purpose, all taken with the same confidence and trust, and neither being properly entitled above another to preference or excellence! </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head>Action of the <name>Banks</name>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="32"/> We are glad to see that the <name>Banks</name> of <placeName reg="Lynchburg, Lynchburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013981">Lynchburg</placeName> and <placeName reg="Petersburg, Petersburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7014404">Petersburg</placeName> have determined to receive on deposit and pay out all the notes of the <orgName n="Confederate Government" type="org">Confederate Government</orgName>, whether issued before or since the <date value="1862-12-01">1st of December, 1862.</date> The <rs>Banks</rs> here took the contrary course of cooperating with the <rs>Government</rs> in the very questionable (mild term!) measure of interdicting a part of its own issues.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="33"/>The expedient is about to produce an amount of inconvenience to the public that the <name>Banks</name> in <placeName reg="Lynchburg, Lynchburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013981">Lynchburg</placeName> and <placeName reg="Petersburg, Petersburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7014404">Petersburg</placeName> thought too serious to be allowed, so far as they are concerned; and they did right not to be a party to it. Not only will the effect of the measure be seriously to incommode the public, but very probably to impair the value of the <rs>Confederate</rs> money still further in public estimation.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="34"/>The money put under the ban is in all the country &mdash; in the hands of the people &mdash; in the hands of men who have no money to lay up in bonds, and who have no more respect for <num value="1">one</num> of the <num value="0.08">eight per cent.</num> promissory notes than for <num value="1">one</num> which promises nothing but its own amount.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="35"/>They are faithful to the <rs>Government</rs> and kind to its currency.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="36"/>They seek to purchase something in <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> and their money is refused.--They are not wise like the <orgName n="Treasury Department" type="department">Treasury Department</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="37"/>They cannot see why a note promising <num value="0.08">eight per cent.</num> should be worth less than a note which promises no per cent.! They at once conclude that the distinction is outrageous, (if for no better reason, because they lose by it;) that <num value="1">one</num> is no better than the other, and that all are to be doubted. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="38"/> It is well that some of the <name>Banks</name> decline to assist in the degradation of a part of that currency issued to the people to meet the obligations of the <rs>Government</rs>, and the differences in the value of which the people never knew, see no reason for, and ought not to be made the losers by. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head>The <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> <rs n="Know-Nothing" type="political">Know Nothings</rs>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="39"/> A suggestive item of <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> news has been published in this paper, which states that the <rs n="German" type="group">Germans</rs> of New York have held a meeting and passed resolutions declaring &#x0022;the continued abuse of the <orgName type="corps" n="corps 11">11th Army corps</orgName>, composed of <rs n="German" type="group">Germans</rs>, which stampeded at <placeName key="tgn,7017621" n="1.000 260" reg="chancellorsville, spotsylvania, virginia">Chancellorsville</placeName>, to be chiefly attributed to the feeling of Know Nothingism, which prevails to a great extent in both Northern and Southern States.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="40"/> The <rs n="German" type="group">Germans</rs> of the <rs>North</rs>, like the <rs n="Irish" type="group">Irish</rs>, are beginning to find out that, at the bottom of their hearts, their <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> taskmasters have no love for them, but only desire to use them for their own base purposes, and would have no hesitation in making them and other foreigners the victims of their intolerance and bigotry if the <rs>South</rs> were only out of their way. The ridicule heaped upon the retreating <rs n="German" type="group">Germans</rs> at <placeName key="tgn,7017621" n="1.000 260" reg="chancellorsville, spotsylvania, virginia">Chancellorsville</placeName> is a significant indication of the real estimation which <milestone unit="column" n="2"/> they are held in the <rs>North</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="41"/>Why is nothing said of the retreating <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs>?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="42"/>Were the <rs n="German" type="group">Germans</rs> the only soldiers whom the resistless charge of our gallant troops drove from the field?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="43"/>So far from this is the fact, that in that battle, as well as every other <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> defeat, from <placeName key="tgn,2112877" n="1.000 541" reg="manassas, manassas, virginia">Manassas</placeName> down, the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> have run not only faster than the <rs n="German" type="group">Germans</rs>, but than any other people under the sun. The <rs n="German" type="group">German</rs> and <rs n="Irish" type="group">Irish</rs> troops have been the very best in their service, and if these were once out of the way, the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> would never be able to make another fair and square stand-up fight with the <orgName n="Southern Confederacy" type="newspaper">Southern Confederacy</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="44"/> The <rs n="German" type="group">Germans</rs> of New York are quite right in attributing the attack upon their soldiery to the feeling of Know Nothingism in the <rs>North</rs>; but they do not know what they are talking about when they say that it prevails to a great extent in the <rs>South</rs> as well as the <rs>North</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="45"/>It was the <rs>South</rs> which gave Know Nothingism its quietus, and, which saved the <rs n="German" type="group">Germans</rs> and <rs n="Irish" type="group">Irish</rs> from political and religious subjugation.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="46"/>That they should permit themselves to be made the instruments of subjugating their deliverers was both a crime and a blunder, and we trust their eyes will, ere long, be awakened to the fact.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="47"/>The South, which they are invading, has never proscribed any man on account of his creed or race; it has never rode priests on rails, or sacked churches or convents; nor does it intend to permit itself to be visited with impunity with outrages and wrongs from which it has protected others. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head>The <rs>French</rs> and <rs n="Mexican" type="group">Mexicans</rs>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="48"/> The <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName> authorities would like to discredit the reported fall of <placeName key="tgn,7007118" n="1.000 1" reg="puebla,puebla,mexico,north and central america">Puebla</placeName>, and <num value="1">one</num> of their press dispatches announces that the natural defences of <placeName key="tgn,7007118" n="1.000 1" reg="puebla,puebla,mexico,north and central america">Puebla</placeName> were so strong that <num value="10000">ten thousand</num> men could defend it against <num value="4">four</num> times their number.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="49"/>That depends, we suppose, on who the men are. <num value="10000">Ten thousand</num> <rs n="Mexican" type="group">Mexicans</rs> could not hold <placeName key="tgn,7007118" n="1.000 1" reg="puebla,puebla,mexico,north and central america">Puebla</placeName> against <num value="40000">forty thousand</num> <rs n="Frenchman" type="propernoun">Frenchmen</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="50"/>At least we may conclude so from the fact that it was taken without difficulty by the <rs n="American" type="group">Americans</rs>, and the <orgName>army of <persName n="Scott,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00004" reg="mostcommon:Scott,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Scott</surname></persName></orgName> was not superior in numbers or prowess to the army of <placeName key="tgn,1000070" n="1.000 1012" reg="france">France</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="51"/> The <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> look with great alarm upon the progress of the <rs>French</rs> arms in <placeName reg="Mexico, Mexico, North and Central America" key="tgn,1001893">Mexico</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="52"/>We hope they have some grounds for their apprehensions.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="53"/>They say that the <rs n="Mexican" type="group">Mexicans</rs> are their &#x0022;natural allies.&#x0022; They have a happy faculty of making allies of all inferior races.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="54"/>With mixed or black blood they readily assimilate.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="55"/>All that is base and degraded finds a natural fusion with Yankeedom &mdash; Success to the <rs>French</rs>!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="56"/>We hope between <placeName key="tgn,1000070" n="1.000 1012" reg="france">France</placeName> and the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName> the &#x0022;natural allies&#x0022; will both be brought to their proper level. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head>[for the <orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.]<lb/>the <rs>Numerical Combinations</rs>.</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, <dateStruct value="1863-06-02"><month reg="06">June</month> <day reg="2">2</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="57"/> In your issue of this date you say, <q>&#x0022;we make the following extract from the <rs>Paris</rs> <hi rend="italics"><persName n="Nord,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00005" reg="mostcommon:Nord,nomatch:0"><surname>Nord</surname></persName>:</hi>&#x0022; &#x0022;An ingenious arithmetician has made the following calculations, in virtue of which he proposes to call the year <dateStruct value="1863--"><year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct> the year of <hi rend="italics">nines,</hi>&#x0022;</q> and concludes with the announcement that &#x0022;this year is <hi rend="italics">essentially</hi> <num value="1">one</num> of revolutions.&#x0022; [Italics my own] Why did this &#x0022;ingenious arithmetician&#x0022; wait for the year <dateStruct value="1863--"><year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="58"/>For example, if he had gone back to the year <dateStruct value="972"><year reg="972">972</year></dateStruct>, he would have found that, subjected to similar tests, (which any of your readers can do,) it would give like results.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="59"/>The truth is that any number, such as &#x0022;<dateStruct value="1863--"><year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>,&#x0022; &#x0022;<num value="972">972</num>,&#x0022; &#x0026;c., or <num value="2754">2754</num>, (should it ever come.) the <hi rend="italics">sum</hi> of whose digits, taken <num value="2">two</num> and <num value="2">two</num> from the right, is divisible by <hi rend="italics"><num value="9">nine</num>,</hi> will develop nearly all (if not all) of the peculiarities ascribed so ominously to <dateStruct value="1863--"><year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="60"/> As I have often seen similar articles going the rounds of the press, by giving this an insertion in your paper you will promote the interests of true science. </p> <closer> <signed>A Subscriber.</signed> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head><persName n="Harris,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00006" reg="mostcommon:Harris,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Captain</roleName> <surname>Harris</surname></persName></head> 
<div4 type="letter" n="1"> 
<head></head> <opener> <salute>To the <name>Editors</name> of the <name>Dispatch</name>:</salute> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="61"/> I regret that the identity of names between the uncle and nephew should have led to any misrepresentation of <persName n="Harris,Major,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00007" reg="mostcommon:Harris,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <surname>Harris</surname></persName>; but it is certainly not necessary to the defence of <rs type="role">Maj.</rs> H. that there should be an attempt to uphold <persName n="Harris,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00008" reg="mostcommon:Harris,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Capt.</roleName> <surname>Harris</surname></persName> under the overwhelming testimony on our side (coinciding with the <rs>Northern</rs> statements) against him as a <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> spy and emissary.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="62"/>Besides the affidavit of the mate of the <rs>Mercury</rs>, my brother (still in <placeName reg="Fort Lafayette">Fort Lafayette</placeName>) has furnished the same evidence by his late fellow-prisoner, <persName n="Bremond,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00009" reg="mostcommon:Bremond,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Capt.</roleName> <surname>Bremond</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="63"/> It is to be supposed that <persName n="Harris,Major,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00010" reg="mostcommon:Harris,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <surname>Harris</surname></persName>'s sources of information as to the reward of <rs type="role">Capt.</rs> H. are at least not superior to those of the <orgName n="New York Tribune" type="newspaper">New York <hi rend="italics">Tribune</hi></orgName>. </p> <closer> <salute>Very respectfully,</salute> <signed><persName n="Sanders,,George,N.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00011" reg="default:Sanders,George,N.,,"><foreName>George</foreName> <foreName>N.</foreName>  <surname>Sanders</surname>, <genName n="junior">Jr.</genName></persName></signed> </closer> </div4> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="7"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">The Western prisoners.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="64"/> --A correspondent of the <orgName n="Savannah News" type="newspaper">Savannah <hi rend="italics">News</hi></orgName>, writing from near <placeName reg="Jackson, Hinds, Mississippi" key="tgn,7016129">Jackson</placeName>, says: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="65"/> I saw yesterday and the day before <num value="272">272</num> <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> prisoners, who were captured in and around <placeName reg="Jackson, Hinds, Mississippi" key="tgn,7016129">Jackson</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="66"/>It makes them very mad to call them <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="67"/>They call themselves &#x0022;Western men,&#x0022; and say if the d &mdash; d blue-bellied rascals in <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> would only fight as they have fought, they would have whipped us long before this.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="68"/>They all seem confident of success in this State, and are very impertinent in their boasting.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="69"/>They say they intend to overrun and possess <placeName reg="Mississippi" key="tgn,7007522">Mississippi</placeName>; that they have <num value="300000">300,000</num> troops in that State to do it with; that they never saw or heard of such a place as <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName>, but that they intend to have it before long, as they have plenty of grape and canister shot.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="70"/>They seem to think that fighting on gunboats is nonsense, and are opposed to fighting on them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="71"/>They were astonished to see us so well clothed, and said we look like gentlemen and not soldiers I never saw a set of men dressed so badly as they were.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="72"/>I saw a dozen or more of them who had no shoes on, and I should judge, from their appearance, that their army is in a much worse condition than ours. </p> </q><bibl n="A correspondent of the Savannah News"></bibl></cit> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="8"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Rosecrans Falling back.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="73"/> --It was rumored in <placeName reg="Shelbyville, Bedford, Tennessee" key="tgn,2101476">Shelbyville</placeName>, on the <dateStruct value="--27"><day reg="27">27th ult.</day></dateStruct>, that <persName n="Rosecrans,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00012" reg="mostcommon:Rosecrans,nomatch:0"><surname>Rosecrans</surname></persName> had fallen back behind <placeName reg="Murfreesboro, Rutherford, Tennessee" key="tgn,7014175">Murfreesboro</placeName>', and that a majority of his troops have been sent to <placeName reg="Mississippi" key="tgn,7007522">Mississippi</placeName> to reinforce <persName n="Grant,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00013" reg="mostcommon:Grant,Gen,,,:1"><surname>Grant</surname></persName>.--The correspondent of the <orgName n="Columbus Enquirer" type="newspaper">Columbus <hi rend="italics">Enquirer</hi></orgName> thinks this very probable, and firmly believes that the great battle that the public have so long been anxiously looking for to occur in <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName> will shortly be fought on the soil of <placeName reg="Mississippi" key="tgn,7007522">Mississippi</placeName>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="9"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Arming in <placeName reg="Mississippi" key="tgn,7007522">Mississippi</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="74"/> --We learn from the <hi rend="italics">Southern Motive</hi> that <rs n="Choctaw" type="nativeamerican">Choctaw</rs> county, <placeName reg="Mississippi" key="tgn,7007522">Miss.</placeName>, has organized <num value="8">eight</num> new companies, and several more are in progress.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="75"/><persName n="Drane,the Honorable,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00014" reg="default:Drane,James,,,"><roleName n="the Honorable">Hon.</roleName> <foreName>James</foreName> <surname>Drane</surname></persName>, the <rs>President</rs> (we believe) of the <name>Senate</name>, all of whose sons and sons-in-law are in the army, has organized a company of cavalry and gone with them to the scene of action.--<rs n="Choctaw" type="nativeamerican">Choctaw</rs> county, with a voting population of <num value="2100">2,100</num>, had already sent <num value="20">twenty</num> companies to the field, besides conscripts. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="10"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Yellow fever at news <placeName reg="Orleans, Loiret, Centre" key="tgn,7008337">Orleans</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="76"/> --Some of the lately arrived exiles at <placeName reg="Mobile, Mobile, Alabama" key="tgn,7017444">Mobile</placeName> say that the yellow fever has made its appearance in New Orleans.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="77"/>This is quite probable.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="78"/>It has often appeared sooner in the year than this.--Happily it can have no effect except on the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="11"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">From the <rs>Clerk</rs> of the <name>Weather</name>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="79"/> --<num value="7">Seven</num> and <num value="1">one</num> <num value="10" type="ordinal">tenth</num> inches of rain fell in <placeName reg="Macon, Bibb, Georgia" key="tgn,7013980">Macon, Ga.</placeName>, on <dateStruct><day type="name">Thursday</day></dateStruct> last, according to the hydrometeor at the gas house.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="80"/>This is the heaviest fall of rain in <num value="1">one</num> day known of late years, or indeed since the wet times of <persName n="Noah,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00015" reg="mostcommon:Noah,nomatch:0"><surname>Noah</surname></persName>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="12"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Helena,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00016" reg="mostcommon:Helena,nomatch:0"><surname>Helena</surname></persName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="81"/> --<persName n="Helena,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00017" reg="mostcommon:Helena,nomatch:0"><surname>Helena</surname></persName> is in <placeName reg="Phillips, Arkansas, United States" key="tgn,2000158">Phillips county, Arkansas</placeName>, on the west bank of the <placeName reg="Mississippi River" key="tgn,7022231">Mississippi river</placeName>, and nearly opposite the famous <placeName reg="Yazoo Pass, Mississippi, Mississippi" key="tgn,2784618">Yazoo Pass</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="82"/>It is, perhaps, <placeName><distance reg="75miles">75 miles</distance> below <placeName reg="Memphis, Shelby, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017750">Memphis</placeName></placeName>, about <placeName><distance reg="100miles">100 miles</distance> above <placeName key="tgn,2080924;tgn,2165488;tgn,2007681" n="0.142 000000.9915	placename;tgn,2080924;napoleon, henry, ohio,Henry,Ohio,United States,North and Central America;0.028 000000.1983	placename;tgn,2165488;Beulah Island Landing, Desha, Arkansas,Desha,Arkansas,United States,North and Central America;0.028 000000.1983	placename;tgn,2007681;Napoleon, Independence, Arkansas,Independence,Arkansas,United States,North and Central America" reg="napoleon, henry, ohio,Henry,Ohio,United States,North and Central America;Beulah Island Landing, Desha, Arkansas,Desha,Arkansas,United States,North and Central America;Napoleon, Independence, Arkansas,Independence,Arkansas,United States,North and Central America">Napoleon</placeName></placeName>, and is nearly <placeName><distance reg="300miles">300 miles</distance> above <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName></placeName> &mdash; these distances all by way of the river. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="13"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="83"/> The drought is said to be seriously affecting the crops in <placeName reg="Allegany, Maryland, United States" key="tgn,2000934">Alleghany county, Md.</placeName> The same is the case throughout the <rs>State</rs>. </p> </div3> <milestone unit="column" n="3"/> 
<div3 type="article" n="14"> 
<head>The cavalry fight in <placeName reg="Culpeper, Culpeper, Virginia" key="tgn,2111394">Culpeper</placeName> &mdash; further particulars.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="84"/>The fight which took place in <placeName reg="Culpeper, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002155">Culpeper county</placeName>, on <dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct>, was upon a much more extended scale than the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> reports received seemed to indicate.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="85"/>According to the telegram of <persName n="Lee,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00018" reg="nearbymention:Lee,R.,E.,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Lee</surname></persName> to <persName n="Cooper,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00019" reg="nearbymention:Cooper,S.,,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Cooper</surname></persName>, it commenced at <time value="5oclock">5 o'clock</time> in the morning and lasted till <num value="5">5</num> in the afternoon.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="86"/>The reports brought to the city by passengers on the <rs>Central</rs> train yesterday evening, are more than usually conflicting, and it is exceedingly difficult from them to arrive at anything approaching accuracy, as to the attack of the enemy, the loss sustained on either side, or the locality and duration of the fight.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="87"/>All seemed to concur in the opinion, however, that our forces were surprised, and did not know of the presence of the enemy until reports of his artillery were heard.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="88"/>This would hardly seem probable, but there is a singular concurrence of testimony to that effect. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="89"/> As well as we can judge from these confused reports, the fight occurred on the farm of <placeName reg="James Barbour">James Barbour</placeName>, <rs type="role">Esq.</rs>, near <placeName reg="Brandy Station, Culpeper, Virginia" key="tgn,2110767">Brandy Station</placeName>, and about <placeName><distance reg="6miles">six miles</distance> <offset>North</offset> of  <placeName reg="Culpeper Court House">Culpeper C. H.</placeName></placeName> There can be no doubt that the ball was opened by the enemy, who made the attack a little after daylight in the morning.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="90"/>When they <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> opened their batteries they were in rear of the headquarters of <persName n="Stuart,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00020" reg="mostcommon:Stuart,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Stuart</surname></persName>, which they shelled furiously.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="91"/>As a matter of course the camp was thrown into some confusion; but, under the lead of gallant and efficient officers the men rallied and prepared themselves for the conflict. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="92"/> At the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> charge of the enemy's cavalry a number of our men were made prisoners.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="93"/>Some accounts state that we lost <num value="700">seven hundred</num> in this way, whilst others assert that our loss in prisoners will not exceed <num value="300">three hundred</num>, and that these were principally of the <orgName type="regiment" key="9VACav">9th Virginia cavalry</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="94"/>Our loss in killed and wounded is variously estimated, and those who bring reports from points near the battlefield assume a wide range in stating the number.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="95"/>We have heard our loss in this respect estimated as low as <num value="60">sixty</num> and as high as <num value="600">six hundred</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="96"/>From this fact the reader may form some idea of the difficulty of getting up anything approximating an accurate report of the battle. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="97"/> After our troops rallied, a charge was made by our cavalry upon the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> battery in rear of <placeName><persName n="Stuart,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00021" reg="mostcommon:Stuart,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Stuart</surname></persName>'s headquarters</placeName>, and they succeeded in capturing and bringing off <num value="3">three</num> of the <num value="6">six</num> pieces the enemy had engaged.--For some time the cavalry fighting between the contending forces was very severe, and the loss on both sides heavy.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="98"/>Our loss in officers was, as usual, very considerable.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="99"/>Among those killed we have heard the names of <persName n="Hampton,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00022" reg="nearbymention:Hampton,Wade,,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Hampton</surname></persName>, brother of <persName n="Hampton,General,Wade,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00023" reg="default:Hampton,Wade,,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <foreName>Wade</foreName> <surname>Hampton</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Hampton, Hampton, Virginia" key="tgn,7013687">Hampton</placeName>'s Legion; <persName n="Green,Colonel,John,S.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00024" reg="default:Green,John,S.,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <surname>Green</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Rappahannock, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002184">Rappahannock county</placeName>, and <placeName reg="Colorado" key="tgn,7007158">Col.</placeName> <persName n="Williams,,Solomon,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00025" reg="default:Williams,Solomon,,,"><foreName>Solomon</foreName> <surname>Williams</surname></persName>, of the <orgName type="regiment" key="18NCRegiment">18th North Carolina regiment</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="100"/>The latter was married only <num value="1">one</num> week ago. Among the wounded, we have heard of <persName n="Lee,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00026" reg="nearbymention:Lee,R.,E.,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Lee</surname></persName>, <persName n="Lee,IsFather-General,R.,E.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00027" reg="default:Lee,R.,E.,,"><roleName n="IsFather-General">son of Gen.</roleName> <foreName>R.</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>Lee</surname></persName>, who was shot through the thigh, and <persName n="Butler,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00028" reg="mostcommon:Butler,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Butler</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="South Carolina" key="tgn,7007712">South Carolina</placeName>, who is reported to have lost a leg. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="101"/> We had only cavalry and artillery engaged in the fight, the enemy having retired before our infantry came up. In their charge upon the enemy's battery, our cavalry was subjected to a severe infantry fire from several regiments of the enemy who were supporting the battery.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="102"/>In this charge our loss is represented to have been pretty severe. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="103"/> We were unable to learn what particular forces we had in the fight.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="104"/><num value="1">One</num> gentleman reported that the active fighting was done by <placeName reg="Hampton, Hampton, Virginia" key="tgn,7013687">Hampton</placeName>'s Legion, a <orgName type="mil" key="NCRegiment">North Carolina regiment</orgName> of cavalry, commanded by <persName n="Williams,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00029" reg="nearbymention:Williams,Solomon,,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Williams</surname></persName>, and the <num value="4" type="ordinal">4th</num> and <orgName type="regiment" key="5VACav">5th Virginia cavalry</orgName>, but that the <orgName>brigade of <persName n="Jones,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00030" reg="mostcommon:Jones,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Jones</surname></persName></orgName>, lately from the <rs type="place">Valley</rs>, was also engaged. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="105"/> After our men recovered from their surprise, we gained a favorable position, which was held throughout the day, although repeated at tempts were made by the enemy to dislodge our forces.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="106"/>About the time our infantry arrived the enemy gave way, and pursuit was made by our cavalry, and some <num value="3">three</num> or <measure n="400" type="prisoners">four hundred prisoners</measure> taken.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="107"/>This was late in the afternoon, and when, perhaps, our cavalry was too much exhausted by the incessant fighting of the day fully to follow up the advantage gained. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="108"/> From the meagre accounts we already have we are led to conclude that the fight of Tuesday was <num value="1">one</num> of the heaviest cavalry battles that has occurred during the war, and perhaps the severest ever fought in this country.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="109"/>We fear that our loss may turn out to be much larger than is generally supposed. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="110"/> We append the dispatch of <persName n="Lee,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00031" reg="nearbymention:Lee,R.,E.,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Lee</surname></persName> to <persName n="Cooper,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00032" reg="nearbymention:Cooper,S.,,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Cooper</surname></persName>, which furnishes the best idea as to the length of time the fighting continued: </p> 
<div4 type="letter" n="1"> 
<head></head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Culpeper, Culpeper, Virginia" key="tgn,2111394">Culpeper</placeName>, <dateStruct value="1863-06-09"><month reg="06">June</month> <day reg="9">9</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>. </dateline> <salute>To <persName n="Cooper,General,S.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00033" reg="default:Cooper,S.,,,"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <surname>Cooper</surname></persName>:</salute> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="111"/> The enemy crossed the <rs>Rappahannock</rs> this morning at <time value="5am">5 o'clock A. M.</time>, at the various fords from <placeName reg="Beverly, Randolph, West Virginia" key="tgn,2117441">Beverly</placeName> to <persName n="Kelly,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00034" reg="mostcommon:Kelly,nomatch:0"><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>'s, with a large force of cavalry, accompanied by infantry and artillery.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="112"/>After a severe contest till <time value="5pm">5 P. M.</time>, <persName n="Stuart,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00035" reg="mostcommon:Stuart,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Stuart</surname></persName> drove them across the river. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Lee,,R.,E.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00036" reg="default:Lee,R.,E.,,"><foreName>R.</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName>  <surname>Lee</surname></persName>.</signed> </closer> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="113"/> Another account which we received late last night from an officer who took part in the battle represents that we lost not less than <num value="7">seven</num> <rs type="role2">Colonel</rs> in the engagement.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="114"/>The same authority states that a regiment of our cavalry was dismounted and thrown forward as sharpshooters to operate against the artillery of the enemy, and pick off their gunners.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="115"/>This force was charged by a largely superior force of the enemy, and, being without bayonets with which to meet the charge, they fired and then retreated.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="116"/>In the retreat a large number were cut off, and many of them made prisoners.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="117"/>The regiment consisted of nearly <num value="700">seven hundred</num> men. The horses of the dismounted men were stampeded by the shells of the enemy, and many of them had not been recovered at last accounts.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="118"/>It is stated that our loss in horses will reach from <num value="500">500</num> to <num value="600">600</num>. </p> </div4> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="15"> 
<head><placeName reg="Fredericksburg, Fredericksburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013943">Fredericksburg</placeName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="119"/> There is very little change in the position of affairs at <placeName reg="Fredericksburg, Fredericksburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013943">Fredericksburg</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="120"/>Yesterday the enemy's pickets, which have been occupying posts midway between the river and the road leading to <placeName reg="Fredericksburg, Fredericksburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013943">Hamilton's Crossing</placeName>, advanced a short distance and our pickets fell back.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="121"/>Beyond this there is no change in the position of the troops on either side. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="16"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">New music.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="122"/> --We have received from <persName n="Taylor,Mister,P.,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00037" reg="default:Taylor,P.,H.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>P.</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Taylor</surname></persName>'s music store, &#x0022;Violetta,&#x0022; a song, and the &#x0022;Beauregard Grand <dateStruct><month>March</month></dateStruct>,&#x0022; both very pretty pieces of music. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="17"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Counterfeits from a New Quarter.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="123"/> --The <orgName n="Charleston Mercury" type="newspaper">Charleston <hi rend="italics">Mercury</hi></orgName> states that some new counterfeits of Confederate notes, of the denomination of <num value="5">5</num>, <num value="10">10</num>, <num value="20">20</num> and <measure n="50dollars" type="currency">50 dollars</measure>, recently put in circulation there, have been traced to some of the steamers which have lately reached that port from <placeName key="tgn,2535807;tgn,7006630" n="0.105 000000.2107	placename;tgn,2535807;nassau river, florida, florida,Florida,United States,North and Central America;0.019 000000.0372	placename;tgn,7006630;nassau,new providence,bahamas,north and central america,New Providence,Bahamas,North and Central America" reg="nassau river, florida, florida,Florida,United States,North and Central America;nassau,new providence,bahamas,north and central america,New Providence,Bahamas,North and Central America">Nassau</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="124"/><num value="2">Two</num> individuals, who were found to have a quantity of the spurious bills on their persons, have been arrested.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="125"/>The counterfeits are tolerably well executed, and people will do well to be on their guard. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="18"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="126"/> <persName n="Lawhorne,Mrs.,Louisa,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00038" reg="default:Lawhorne,Louisa,,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <foreName>Louisa</foreName> <surname>Lawhorne</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Nelson, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002175">Nelson county, Va.</placeName>, has been convicted of forgery and sentenced to <measure n="2years" type="date">two years</measure> in the penitentiary. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="127"/> <persName n="Vallandigham,the Honorable,C.,L.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00039" reg="default:Vallandigham,C.,L.,,"><roleName n="the Honorable">Hon.</roleName> <foreName>C.</foreName> <foreName>L.</foreName> <surname>Vallandigham</surname></persName> was in <persName n="Tuesday,,Petersburg,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00040" reg="default:Tuesday,Petersburg,,,"><foreName>Petersburg</foreName> <surname>Tuesday</surname></persName>. </p> </div3> <milestone unit="column" n="4"/> 
<div3 type="article" n="19"> 
<head>Additional Northern news.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="128"/> From Northern papers, of the <num value="7" type="ordinal">7th</num>, we get some additional items of interest.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="129"/>The New York press are becoming exercised over the loss of their &#x0022;liberty.&#x0022; The following dispatch has been received by the editor of the <hi rend="italics">World:</hi> </p> 
<div4 type="letter" n="1"> 
<head></head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Lexington, Fayette, Kentucky" key="tgn,7013887">Lexington, Ky.</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-06-4"><month reg="06">June</month> <day reg="4">4</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> <salute><rs type="role" reg="Editor">Editor</rs> of the <name>World</name>:</salute> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="130"/> Having been directed by the <rs>President</rs> of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> to revoke that part of my order suppressing the <orgName n="Chicago Times" type="newspaper">Chicago <hi rend="italics">Times</hi></orgName>, I have revoked the entire order, and your paper will be allowed its circulation in this department. </p> <closer> <signed>(Signed,) <persName n="Burnside,,A.,E.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00041" reg="default:Burnside,A.,E.,,"><foreName>A.</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>Burnside</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <rs type="role" reg="Major-General">Major General</rs>. </closer> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="131"/> A meeting of the press of that city is called for the <dateStruct value="--9"><day reg="9">9th inst.</day></dateStruct>, to consider the subject of the nature, extent and rightful limitations, if any, of the liberty of public journalists to criticise the acts of those charged with the conduct of the <rs>Government</rs> in time of war and civil convulsion.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="132"/>The call is signed by <persName n="Prime,,W.,C.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00042" reg="default:Prime,W.,C.,,"><foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>C.</foreName> <surname>Prime</surname></persName>, <persName n="Godwin,,Parke,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00043" reg="default:Godwin,Parke,,,"><foreName>Parke</foreName> <surname>Godwin</surname></persName>, <placeName reg="James Brooks">James Brooks</placeName>, <persName n="Herrick,,Anson,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00044" reg="default:Herrick,Anson,,,"><foreName>Anson</foreName> <surname>Herrick</surname></persName>, <persName n="Greeley,,Horace,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00045" reg="default:Greeley,Horace,,,"><foreName>Horace</foreName> <surname>Greeley</surname></persName>, and <persName n="Comstock,,Eton,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00046" reg="default:Comstock,Eton,,,"><foreName>Eton</foreName> <surname>Comstock</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="133"/> The <placeName reg="Milwaukee, Milwaukee, Wisconsin" key="tgn,7014071">Milwaukee</placeName> correspondent of the <orgName n="Chicago Tribune" type="newspaper">Chicago <hi rend="italics">Tribune</hi></orgName> (<rs n="Republican" type="political">Republican</rs>) says: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="134"/> Another disgraceful scene occurred in our city this afternoon, similar to that of a few days since.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="135"/>An enrolling officer, while engaged in his duties in <num value="1">one</num> of the wards, was attacked by a large number of woman, armed with clubs, stones, and other missiles, who very seriously injured him. He succeeded in escaping from the infuriated vixens by taking refuge in a grocery near by, and the mob dispersed without committing further outrages. </p> </q><bibl n="The Milwaukee correspondent of the Chicago Tribune (Republican)"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="136"/> The <orgName n="Albany Argus" type="newspaper">Albany <hi rend="italics">Argus</hi></orgName> has the following: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="137"/> <persName n="Forney,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00047" reg="mostcommon:Forney,nomatch:0"><surname>Forney</surname></persName>'s Washington <hi rend="italics">Chronicle,</hi> in referring to the approaching election in <placeName reg="Maryland" key="tgn,7007516">Maryland</placeName>, says: <q>&#x0022;In truth, the loyalists of <placeName reg="Baltimore, Baltimore Independent City, Maryland" key="tgn,7013352">Baltimore</placeName> will not permit <hi rend="italics">doubtful</hi> men to appear at the polls; and we anticipate that the coming election will show that in that State a number of avowed <rs n="Republican" type="political">Republicans</rs> have been chosen to office&#x0022;</q>--Through the <hi rend="italics">Chronicle</hi> and through the <hi rend="italics">Press</hi> <persName n="Forney,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00048" reg="mostcommon:Forney,nomatch:0"><surname>Forney</surname></persName> is constantly throwing out instigations to violence and threats against the people.--There is reason to think that he speaks for the <name>Administration</name>, or rather for the clique that controls it. Forewarned, forearmed!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="138"/>When the <rs>Constitution</rs> is prostrated, and the laws defied, we believe the <rs n="Democrat" type="political">Democrats</rs> of the country can fall back upon the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> principles and defend themselves successfully against violence.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="139"/>And they will do it. </p> </q><bibl n="The Albany Argus"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="140"/> Some excitement still exists in <placeName reg="Alexandria, Alexandria, Virginia" key="tgn,7013269">Alexandria</placeName> in apprehension of a rebel raid, which is certainly contemplated in some direction, of course none can tell where.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="141"/>The colored folks, contrabands and all, are still at work, digging pits, entrenching, etc., in that and other vicinities.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="142"/>There is no apprehension in <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="143"/>The military authorities are on the alert and preparing for contingencies. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="144"/> According to the <rs>Washington</rs> correspondent of the <orgName n="Chicago Times" type="newspaper">Chicago <hi rend="italics">Times</hi></orgName>, no <num value="1">one</num> who sees <persName n="Lincoln,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00049" reg="mostcommon:Lincoln,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Lincoln</surname></persName> can now fail to be struck with his altered appearance as compared with his looks of <measure n="2years" type="date">two years</measure> ago. He looks <measure n="10years" type="date">ten years</measure> older, and the expression of his face is haggard and careworn in the extreme.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="145"/>His eye is restless, and is constantly wandering; at times with a vacant expression, at others in a manner indicative of positive terror.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="146"/>He has exactly the demeanor of a man whose rest is broken by remorse, and to whose pillow tranquil sleep is a stranger. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="147"/> The <orgName n="Troy Times" type="newspaper">Troy <hi rend="italics">Times</hi></orgName> says that a committee of colored men from that city raised upon <persName n="Seymour,Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00050" reg="mostcommon:Seymour,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Governor">Governor</roleName> <surname>Seymour</surname></persName> last week and asked him whether he would favor the organization of regiments of black men. He replied that he should not, stating that he had too much sympathy for the blacks to do so, as the position they must occupy would be <num value="1">one</num> of extreme danger, and would lead to dreadful and unnecessary sacrifice of life. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="148"/> A Baltimore paper says: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="149"/> The detectives of <persName n="Fish,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00051" reg="mostcommon:Fish,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Fish</surname></persName> have, within a few days past, arrested the following named young men of this city and vicinity, upon the charge of being <unclear></unclear> in the commission of a company to join the <orgName n="Confederate Army" type="org">Confederate army</orgName>.--<persName n="Brooks,,A.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00052" reg="default:Brooks,A.,,,"><foreName>A.</foreName> <surname>Brooks</surname></persName>, <persName n="Brooks,,N.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00053" reg="default:Brooks,N.,,,"><foreName>N.</foreName> <surname>Brooks</surname></persName>, <persName n="Dorsey,,W.,S.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00054" reg="default:Dorsey,W.,S.,,"><foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <surname>Dorsey</surname></persName>, <persName n="Parkhurst,,Nye,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00055" reg="default:Parkhurst,Nye,,,"><foreName>Nye</foreName> <surname>Parkhurst</surname></persName>, <persName n="Raphael,,H.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00056" reg="default:Raphael,H.,,,"><foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Raphael</surname></persName>, <persName n="Norwood,,Frederick,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00057" reg="default:Norwood,Frederick,,,"><foreName>Frederick</foreName> <surname>Norwood</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="150"/>Key <persName n="Buchanan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00058" reg="mostcommon:Buchanan,nomatch:0"><surname>Buchanan</surname></persName>, <persName n="Stewart,,William,J.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00059" reg="default:Stewart,William,J.,,"><foreName n="William">Wm.</foreName> <foreName>J.</foreName> <surname>Stewart</surname></persName>. <persName n="Duvall,,Vinton,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00060" reg="default:Duvall,Vinton,W.,,"><foreName>Vinton</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Duvall</surname></persName>, <persName n="Peterson,,P.,Stanley,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00061" reg="default:Peterson,P.,Stanley,,"><foreName>P.</foreName> <foreName>Stanley</foreName> <surname>Peterson</surname></persName>, and <persName n="Williamson,,Eugene,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00062" reg="default:Williamson,Eugene,,,"><foreName>Eugene</foreName> <surname>Williamson</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="151"/>It is stated that the party was to have started South yesterday.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="152"/>All of them are confined in the <rs type="place">Gilmore House</rs>, and none have yet had an examination. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="153"/> The <orgName n="Democratic State Convention" type="convention">Democratic State Convention</orgName> for the <placeName reg="Illinois" key="tgn,7007251">State of Illinois</placeName> is to assemble at <placeName reg="Springfield, Greene, Missouri" key="tgn,7014532">Springfield</placeName> on the <num value="17" type="ordinal">17th</num> of the present month.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="154"/>Prominent representative men of the <orgName n="Democratic party" type="party">Democratic party</orgName> of other States have been invited to be present to confer and counsel with the <rs>Illinois Democracy</rs> at the proposed convention, among whom are: <persName n="Seymour,Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00063" reg="mostcommon:Seymour,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Governor">Gov.</roleName> <surname>Seymour</surname></persName>, of New York; <persName n="Hunt,the Honorable,Washington,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00064" reg="default:Hunt,Washington,,,"><roleName n="the Honorable">Hon.</roleName> <foreName>Washington</foreName> <surname>Hunt</surname></persName>, of New York; <persName n="Pugh,,Hon,George,E.," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00065" reg="default:Pugh,Hon,George,E.,"><foreName>Hon</foreName> <foreName n="George">Geo.</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>Pugh</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Ohio, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007706">Ohio</placeName>; <rs type="role">Hon.</rs> S <persName n="Cox,,S.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00066" reg="default:Cox,S.,,,"><foreName>S.</foreName> <surname>Cox</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Ohio, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007706">Ohio</placeName>; <persName n="Hendricks,the Honorable,Thomas,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00067" reg="default:Hendricks,Thomas,A.,,"><roleName n="the Honorable">Hon.</roleName> <foreName n="Thomas">Thos.</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName> <surname>Hendricks</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Indiana" key="tgn,7007252">Indiana</placeName>; <persName n="Vorhees,,Daniel,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00068" reg="default:Vorhees,Daniel,W.,,"><foreName>Daniel</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Vorhees</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Indiana" key="tgn,7007252">Indiana</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="155"/> A letter in the <orgName n="Boston Transcript" type="newspaper">Boston <hi rend="italics">Transcript</hi></orgName> states that the <term type="ship">schooner</term> <rs type="ship">Jupiter</rs> was captured near <placeName reg="Mobile, Mobile, Alabama" key="tgn,7017444">Mobile</placeName>, while trying to run the blockade.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="156"/>She was owned and manned by the <rs>British Consul</rs> at <placeName reg="Montour Falls, Schuyler, New York" key="tgn,2070618">Havana</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="157"/>He was also the owner of the cargo of the <term type="ship">steamer</term> <rs type="ship">Autona</rs>, captured some time since. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="158"/> The gunboats of the <rs>Potomac</rs> flotilla, now on the <rs>Rappahannock</rs>, under the command of <persName n="McGraw,Captain,Samuel,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00069" reg="default:McGraw,Samuel,,,"><roleName n="Captain">Capt.</roleName> <foreName>Samuel</foreName> <surname>McGraw</surname></persName>, have lately made several expeditions, some of them with very important results. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="159"/> A few days since several of the gunboats steamed up to the town of <placeName reg="Tappahannock, Essex, Virginia" key="tgn,2114560">Tappahannock</placeName>, where there was a strong rebel cavalry picket, which was shelled out, and some of our men landed, and they destroyed about <num value="20000">20,000</num> bushels of grain which were stored there.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="160"/>A party was sent ashore <num value="1">one</num> night near <placeName reg="Urbanna, Middlesex, Virginia" key="tgn,2114705">Urbana</placeName>, and came off with a quantity of goods intended for the rebels.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="161"/>They brought off also a couple of Secesh flags as trophies. </p> </q><bibl n="A Baltimore paper"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="162"/> A dispatch from <placeName reg="Murfreesboro, Rutherford, Tennessee" key="tgn,7014175">Murfreesboro</placeName>', dated the <num value="3" type="ordinal">3d</num>, says: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="163"/> Scouts who have thoroughly scoured the country on our left and in our rear report having neither seen nor heard of any rebels. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="164"/> A gentleman who is known here, and whose statements are regarded as reliable, has just reached our lines from <placeName key="tgn,2101873" n="1.000 68" reg="tullahoma, coffee, tennessee">Tullahoma</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="165"/>He says there are not more than <num value="2">two</num> regiments at that place, and that the enemy has thrown all his fortifications forward to <placeName reg="Shelbyville, Bedford, Tennessee" key="tgn,2101476">Shelbyville</placeName>, <placeName key="tgn,2557019" n="1.000 4" reg="old fosterville, rutherford, tennessee">Beech Grove</placeName>, and other points on our immediate front. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="166"/> A mounted force of rebels advanced this afternoon and engaged our videttes on the <rs type="place">Manchester pike</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="167"/>The firing was very rapid, and lasted about an hour, when the rebels withdrew.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="168"/>The casualties have not been reported. </p> </q><bibl n="Murfreesboro'"></bibl></cit> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="3"> 
<head>Miscellaneous.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="169"/> The <rs>Washingtonian</rs> are getting very shaky in the knees.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="170"/><persName n="Forney,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00070" reg="mostcommon:Forney,nomatch:0"><surname>Forney</surname></persName>, in contradicting a number of false rumors, says: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="171"/> Another rumor is that our pickets have been driven in at <placeName reg="Falmouth, Stafford, Virginia" key="tgn,2111731">Falmouth</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="172"/>Ridiculous! To drive in our pickets there <persName n="Lee,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00071" reg="nearbymention:Lee,R.,E.,,"><surname>Lee</surname></persName> must recross the <rs>Rappahannock</rs> and give <persName n="Hooker,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00072" reg="mostcommon:Hooker,nomatch:0"><surname>Hooker</surname></persName> a general battle with his whole army.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="173"/>No such thing has occurred. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="174"/> The Conscription bill divides citizens liable to draft into <num value="2">two</num> classes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="175"/><num value="1">One</num> comprises all able-bodied men between the ages of <num value="20">20</num> and <num value="35">35</num>, married or unmarried, and all unmarried men between the ages of <num value="35">35</num> and <num value="45">45</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="176"/>The <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> class includes all married men between the last named ages.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="177"/>It turns out, according to the enrollment in <orgName n="New York City" type="newspaper">New York city</orgName>, that the proportion of the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> class to the <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> is nearly as <num value="4">four</num> to <num value="1">one</num>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="178"/> It is said that <persName n="Dahlgren,Admiral,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00073" reg="mostcommon:Dahlgren,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Admiral">Admiral</roleName> <surname>Dahlgren</surname></persName> will relieve <persName n="Farragut,Admiral,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00074" reg="mostcommon:Farragut,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Admiral">Admiral</roleName> <surname>Farragut</surname></persName>, and that <persName n="Wise,Commander,H.,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00075" reg="default:Wise,H.,A.,,"><roleName n="Commander">Commander</roleName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName> <surname>Wise</surname></persName> will take charge of the <orgName n="Ordnance Bureau" type="bureau">Ordnance Bureau</orgName>, <persName n="Dahlgren,vice-Admiral,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00076" reg="mostcommon:Dahlgren,nomatch:0"><roleName n="vice-Admiral">vice Admiral</roleName> <surname>Dahlgren</surname></persName>. <persName n="Rogers,Commander,C.,R.,P.," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00077" reg="default:Rogers,C.,R.,P.,"><roleName n="Commander">Commander</roleName> <foreName>C.</foreName> <foreName>R.</foreName> <foreName>P.</foreName> <surname>Rogers</surname></persName>, now <persName n="Dupont,Admiral,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00078" reg="mostcommon:Dupont,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Admiral">Admiral</roleName> <surname>Dupont</surname></persName>'s <rs type="role" reg="Fleet-Captain">Fleet Captain</rs>, will relieve <persName n="Blake,Commodore,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00079" reg="mostcommon:Blake,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Commodore">Commodore</roleName> <surname>Blake</surname></persName> as <rs type="role" reg="Superintendent">Superintendent</rs> of the <orgName n="Naval Academy" type="academy">Naval Academy</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="179"/> It is stated that the sum of <measure n="855298dollars" type="currency">$855,298</measure>, the proceeds of prize vessel, is now ready to be distributed to the officers, seamen, and marines, entitled to receive it. They are directed to present their claims to the paymaster on whose books their names are borne for payment. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="180"/> A delegation of the members of Manhattan Engine Company, <num value="8">No. 8</num>, of New York, are about to proceed to <placeName reg="London, Madison, Ohio" key="tgn,2080432">London</placeName>, to compete at the great tournament of <rs n="steam fire engines" type="product">steam fire-engines</rs> which will be held in that city on the <date value="07-01">1st of July.</date> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="181"/> <persName n="Ogden,Mister,J.,Depeyster,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00080" reg="default:Ogden,J.,Depeyster,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>J.</foreName> <foreName>Depeyster</foreName> <surname>Ogden</surname></persName>, a well known merchant of New York, was robbed on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> <time>evening</time> of some <measure n="10000dollars" type="currency">$10,000</measure> in greenbacks, while entering a stage on the corner of <address><street n="Bleecker Street">Bleecker street</street></address> and <address><street n="Broadway">Broadway</street></address>. </p> </q><bibl n="Forney"></bibl></cit> </div4> </div3> <milestone unit="column" n="5"/> 
<div3 type="article" n="20"> 
<head>Examination of <persName n="Forde,,Robert,S.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00081" reg="default:Forde,Robert,S.,,"><foreName>Robert</foreName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <surname>Forde</surname></persName>.<lb/>charged with the <name>Murder</name> of <persName><foreName>Robert</foreName></persName> E <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00082" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName>.</head> <byline>[reported for the <orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.]</byline> <opener> <dateline> <orgName n="Hustings Court" type="court">Hustings Court</orgName>, <dateStruct value="1863-06-10"><month reg="06">June</month> <day reg="10">10</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="182"/> --Present: <persName n="Caskie,Recorder,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00083" reg="mostcommon:Caskie,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Recorder">Recorder</roleName> <surname>Caskie</surname></persName>, <persName n="Sanxay,Alderman,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00084" reg="mostcommon:Sanxay,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Alderman">Aldermen</roleName> <surname>Sanxay</surname></persName>, <persName n="Gwathmey,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00085" reg="mostcommon:Gwathmey,nomatch:0"><surname>Gwathmey</surname></persName>, <persName n="Timberlake,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00086" reg="mostcommon:Timberlake,nomatch:0"><surname>Timberlake</surname></persName>, and <persName n="Jones,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00087" reg="mostcommon:Jones,nomatch:0"><surname>Jones</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="183"/> The examination of the witnesses in the case of <persName n="Forde,,Robert,S.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00088" reg="default:Forde,Robert,S.,,"><foreName>Robert</foreName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <surname>Forde</surname></persName> for the shooting of <persName n="Dixon,,Robert,E.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00089" reg="default:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><foreName>Robert</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>Dixon</surname></persName> was resumed. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="184"/> <persName n="Thomas,,George,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00090" reg="default:Thomas,George,W.,,"><foreName n="George">Geo.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Thomas</surname></persName> deposed: Was coming out of the <orgName n="Treasury Department" type="department">Treasury Department</orgName>, and was attracted by the report of a pistol; ran out upon the pavement; saw Forde fire; <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00091" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> was not in view from where he stood; did not see the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> fire, but heard it, ran up as fast as he could; <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00092" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> was then staggering on the pavement and fell, whilst drawing a Derringer; then went across the street to where Forde was standing; some <num value="1">one</num> came up and told Forde to get away; he said he would not leave, and surrendered to witness, who stand with him until <persName n="Freeman,Constable,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00093" reg="mostcommon:Freeman,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Constable">Constable</roleName> <surname>Freeman</surname></persName> came up and took him off. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="185"/> Cross-examined.--Could not distinguish whether the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> fire was a double shot or reverberation from single shot; after that the shots seemed to alternate from <num value="1">one</num> side of the street to the other.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="186"/>The <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> shots were nearly together; thought he heard <num value="7">seven</num> shots and <num value="1">one</num> soap; could not be positive; if the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> sound was a single shot there must have been <num value="7">seven</num>; if double, there was, be thought, <num value="8">eight</num>; was the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> <num value="1">one</num> to approach Forde after the shooting, except <num value="1">one</num>, a gentleman who advised him to escape; Forde's reply to this gentleman was, &#x0022;I am not going anywhere,&#x0022; and surrendered to witness with the remark that he would go with any <num value="1">one</num>, and was willing to surrender to any <num value="1">one</num>; returned to where <placeName reg="Dixon, Lee, Illinois" key="tgn,2027503">Dixon</placeName>'s body was lying; heard <persName n="Cardozo,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00094" reg="mostcommon:Cardozo,nomatch:0"><surname>Cardozo</surname></persName> remark, &#x0022;he has been after him all the morning, and I tried to keep him in my room, but could not.&#x0022; When he <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> saw Forde he was standing about <measure n="7feet" type="distance">seven feet</measure> from the curb, on <address><street n="Bank street">Bank street</street></address>, in the act of stepping back to the pavement, firing as he went; when <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00095" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> fell, Forde was in the act of putting his pistol up; <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00096" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> started towards Forde with a menacing look, and fell after he had taken the <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> step. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="187"/> <persName n="Vest,,George,G.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00097" reg="default:Vest,George,G.,,"><foreName n="George">Geo.</foreName> <foreName>G.</foreName> <surname>Vest</surname></persName> appeared, and was asked by the <rs type="place">Court</rs> why he was absent yesterday, and after his excuse was given he was informed by the <rs type="place">Court</rs> that a fine of <measure n="20dollars" type="currency">$20</measure> would be imposed upon him. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="188"/> The witness replied that he cared nothing for the <measure n="20dollars" type="currency">$20</measure>, but would test the right of this Court to impose a fine upon him. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="189"/> Witness then deposed: Had <num value="2">two</num> interviews with <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00098" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> previous to the shooting.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="190"/>Deceased told him that he expected to have a difficulty with Forde; that he had been detained here in <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> some <measure n="2weeks" type="date">two weeks</measure> after the adjournment of the last session of Congress righting up errors in the journal caused by Forde's negligence; that he had that morning discharged him; did not mean to take him back; <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00099" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> also made some remark to the effect that he did not believe Forde had ever liked him since he said to him <num value="1">one</num> day, &#x0022;Forde, it is very strange that as handsome a woman as your wife should ever have married you;&#x0022; deceased said Forde's face flushed up, and he afterwards demanded an explanation; had a subsequent interview with <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00100" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName>, who was somewhat excited, and told him he had received a letter from Forde; showed witness a knife and pistol; on parting deceased seemed to be somewhat affected, and witness thought his eyes seemed to be a little moist; <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00101" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> said to witness. &#x0022;<name n="God" type="God">God</name> knows I want no difficulty with Forde, but shall not seek or avoid him;&#x0022; he said <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00102" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> then told him be would reinstate Forde but for the letter; witness told <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00103" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> that while that letter remained he could not well reinstate the accused; had several conversations with <persName n="Reed,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00104" reg="mostcommon:Reed,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Reed</surname></persName> about the difficulty, and a day or <num value="2">two</num> before the shooting went with <rs type="role">Gen.</rs> R to hunt Forde, who could not be found; the last interview with <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00105" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> was at the <rs>Capitol</rs> the night before the shooting. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="191"/> <persName n="Fiquet,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00106" reg="mostcommon:Fiquet,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Fiquet</surname></persName> deposed: Was sitting by window in <num value="3" type="ordinal">third</num> story of <orgName n="Post Office Department" type="department">Post-Office Department</orgName>; heard a report which he at <unclear></unclear> thought <unclear></unclear> or a shot gun; soon after heard the report of a pistol; throw up the window and saw a man standing near the curb on <address><street n="Bank street">Bank street</street></address>; heard a shot from the opposite side of the street; then saw <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00107" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName>; the man on the north side of the street seemed unusually cool under the circumstances; he ran down to where the shooting was going on; <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00108" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> fell before he reached the spot; there was a man in the crowd moving to and fro, apparently much excited, and he thought at the time that he was perhaps the party who had shot <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00109" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="192"/> Cross examination commenced, when witness was about to detail what was said to him by <persName n="Goodrich,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00110" reg="mostcommon:Goodrich,nomatch:0"><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName> on the ground. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="193"/> <persName n="Goodrich,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00111" reg="mostcommon:Goodrich,nomatch:0"><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName> was then called, and in reply to a question, stated that he had no recollection of making any remarks at the time. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="194"/> Fiquet resumed: <persName n="Goodrich,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00112" reg="mostcommon:Goodrich,nomatch:0"><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName> was in the crowd; witness asked <persName n="Goodrich,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00113" reg="mostcommon:Goodrich,nomatch:0"><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName> if he saw the firing; <persName n="Goodrich,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00114" reg="mostcommon:Goodrich,nomatch:0"><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName> said he did; witness asked who fire <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num>, to which <persName n="Goodrich,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00115" reg="mostcommon:Goodrich,nomatch:0"><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName> replied, &#x0022;it is impossible to tell; I saw <placeName reg="Dixon, Lee, Illinois" key="tgn,2027503">Dixon</placeName>'s pistol <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num>, and I judge he fired <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num>.&#x0022; To be sure that he was right, witness again asked <persName n="Goodrich,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00116" reg="mostcommon:Goodrich,nomatch:0"><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName> who fired the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> shot, when he repeated what has already been stated.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="195"/>This could not have been more than <measure n="20minutes" type="date">twenty minutes</measure> after the occurrence, and near the spot where <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00117" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> fell; <num value="1">one</num> or <num value="2">two</num> other gentlemen were in the crowd, among them <persName n="Richardson,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00118" reg="mostcommon:Richardson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Richardson</surname></persName>; was satisfied that <persName n="Goodrich,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00119" reg="mostcommon:Goodrich,nomatch:0"><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName> told him that he <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> saw <placeName reg="Dixon, Lee, Illinois" key="tgn,2027503">Dixon</placeName>'s pistol and his impression was that <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00120" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> fired <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num>; <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> report witness heard was so loud he supposed it was a shot gun; it might have been simultaneous pistol fire; there was a clear distinction between the sounds of the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> and <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> fires; saw smoke twice from the side of the street on which <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00121" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> was standing. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="196"/> Wash <persName n="Goodrich,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00122" reg="mostcommon:Goodrich,nomatch:0"><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName>, excitedly.--I wish to make a statement.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="197"/>I wish to tell this witness if he says I told him I saw <placeName reg="Dixon, Lee, Illinois" key="tgn,2027503">Dixon</placeName>'s pistol <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> he says what is not so; he tells a lie. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="198"/> The <rs type="place">Court</rs> told <persName n="Goodrich,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00123" reg="mostcommon:Goodrich,nomatch:0"><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName> to stand aside. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="199"/> <persName n="Crump,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00124" reg="mostcommon:Crump,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Crump</surname></persName> asked the <rs type="place">Court</rs> if any <num value="1">one</num> was to be allowed to come into this Court and intimidate witnesses?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="200"/>If such an act of indecency, indignity and outrage is to be tolerated, let it be known.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="201"/>He trusted in <name n="God" type="God">God</name> that there was not a Court in the <rs>Commonwealth</rs> that would pass by such an offence in silence. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="202"/> The <rs type="place">Court</rs> mildly reprimanded <persName n="Goodrich,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00125" reg="mostcommon:Goodrich,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Goodrich</surname></persName>, and cautioned him not to do so again. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="203"/> <persName n="Randolph,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00126" reg="mostcommon:Randolph,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Randolph</surname></persName>, in a rather excited manner, said that if witnesses were to be bullied by Baltimore Plug Uglies he hoped they would arm themselves, and if the <rs type="place">Court</rs> failed to give them protection that they would defend themselves with their own right arms. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="204"/> The <rs type="place">Court</rs> required the counsel to take his seat. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="205"/> <persName n="Randolph,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00127" reg="mostcommon:Randolph,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Randolph</surname></persName> preferred to stand up. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="206"/> After some further interruption the business of the <rs type="place">Court</rs> was resumed. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="207"/> --<persName n="Richardson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00128" reg="mostcommon:Richardson,nomatch:0"><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>, deposed: On the morning of the shooting was sitting in <num value="1">one</num> of the rooms of the <orgName n="Treasury Department" type="department">Treasury Department</orgName>; owing to defective hearing did not hear any firing; reached the window in time to see <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00129" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> fall; heard <persName n="Goodrich,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00130" reg="mostcommon:Goodrich,nomatch:0"><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName> tell Fiquet &#x0022;that it was impossible to tell who fired <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num>.&#x0022; Witness then asked <persName n="Goodrich,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00131" reg="mostcommon:Goodrich,nomatch:0"><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName> what was his impression with reference to the firing, when the reply was &#x0022;I saw <placeName reg="Dixon, Lee, Illinois" key="tgn,2027503">Dixon</placeName>'s pistol <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num>, and as a matter of course I think he fired the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> shot, but cannot say positively.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="208"/> I. K <persName n="Chase,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00132" reg="mostcommon:Chase,nomatch:0"><surname>Chase</surname></persName>, deposed: Heard <persName n="Goodrich,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00133" reg="mostcommon:Goodrich,nomatch:0"><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName> say, in a crowd in front of the <rs type="place">Treasury building</rs>, that he could not tell who fired the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> shot; <persName n="Goodrich,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00134" reg="mostcommon:Goodrich,nomatch:0"><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName> repeated it twice; his statement was substantially that detailed by <persName n="Fiquet,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00135" reg="mostcommon:Fiquet,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Fiquet</surname></persName> in his testimony. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="209"/> <persName n="Ficklin,,B.,F.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00136" reg="default:Ficklin,B.,F.,,"><foreName>B.</foreName> <foreName>F.</foreName> <surname>Ficklin</surname></persName>, deposed: Was passing <placeName reg="Treasury building">Treasury building</placeName> after the shooting, and saw a crowd standing on the steps; saw a man in the crowd whom he since recognized as <persName n="Goodrich,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00137" reg="mostcommon:Goodrich,nomatch:0"><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName>; in reply to a question as to who fired <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num>, <persName n="Goodrich,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00138" reg="mostcommon:Goodrich,nomatch:0"><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName> said he could not tell who fired <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num>; that <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00139" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> aimed <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num>, but his pistol snapped; that he thought Forde's pistol was the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> to go off. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="210"/> <persName n="Moss,,J.,G.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00140" reg="default:Moss,J.,G.,,"><foreName>J.</foreName> <foreName>G.</foreName> <surname>Moss</surname></persName>, deposed: Saw Forde at the <orgName n="House of Representatives" type="government">House of Representatives</orgName> on the day <rs>Dixon</rs> was shot; he came to the <rs type="place">House</rs> and asked for <persName n="Reed,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00141" reg="mostcommon:Reed,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Reed</surname></persName>; witness looked for <rs type="role">Gen.</rs> R., but he was not in the hall at the time; Forde went off, and about an hour after he learned that <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00142" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> was shot; the day previous Forde came to the door of the hall and handed him a letter addressed to <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00143" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName>, which witness handed to him; heard Forde found <persName n="Reed,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00144" reg="mostcommon:Reed,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Reed</surname></persName> in the building, but knew nothing of what passed between them; knew nothing of the contents of the letter handed him; could not recollect at what hour the letter was handed him. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="211"/> --<persName n="Warrington,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00145" reg="mostcommon:Warrington,nomatch:0"><surname>Warrington</surname></persName> deposed: Was passing up <address><street n="Bank street">Bank street</street></address> towards the <orgName n="War Department" type="department">War Department</orgName>; had reached the <rs type="place">Treasury building</rs>; heard the firing; could <unclear></unclear> fired the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> shot; <milestone unit="column" n="6"/> the firing was rapid, except the last shot of Forde, which was a deliberate <num value="1">one</num>, and, in the judgment of witness, the <num value="1">one</num> which took of feet upon <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00146" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName>; the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> report was prolonged, and be at <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> thought it was the fire of a musket; saw Forde fire <num value="4">four</num> times and <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00147" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> twice; he went over to Forde and said to him, &#x0022;My <name n="God" type="God">God</name>, <persName n="Forde,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00148" reg="nearbymention:Forde,Robert,S.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Forde</surname></persName>, what does this mean?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="212"/>You have shot that gentleman, and I am afraid you have killed him.&#x0022; Forde replied, &#x0022;I am sorry for it; I had a difficulty with that gentleman, and it is now settled, and added, &#x0022;I am ready to surrender.&#x0022; Witness thought Forde was the coolest man he had ever witnessed under the circumstances, and witness thought him the bravest man he ever saw. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="213"/> Cross-examined.--The <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> report was not at all similar to those subsequent, as before remarked, it sounded more like the report of a musket; could not hear the snapping of a pistol; there was an uncertainty in <placeName reg="Dixon, Lee, Illinois" key="tgn,2027503">Dixon</placeName>'s movements; be moved about on the sidewalk, as if dodging or trying to get out of the way; Forde was standing still. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="214"/> <persName n="Johnson,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00149" reg="mostcommon:Johnson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Johnson</surname></persName> deposed: Was in the room occupied by the <rs>President</rs> in <placeName reg="Treasury building">Treasury building</placeName>; heard the firing, which was rapid; went to the window; could see nothing; had heard <num value="4">four</num> shots; in a short time saw Forde, who had a pistol in his hand, moving it as if following the movement of some <num value="1">one</num>, but from his apparent coolness did not think he was principal in the shooting affray; he did not fire, and put up his pistol; some <num value="1">one</num> came in and said <persName n="Dixon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00150" reg="nearbymention:Dixon,Robert,E.,,"><surname>Dixon</surname></persName> was killed. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="215"/> Cross-examined.--When he <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> heard firing it did not occur to him that there was any difficulty; when be heard <num value="4" type="ordinal">fourth</num> shot he was satisfied that an affray was going on; had known Forde slightly for about <measure n="10years" type="date">ten years</measure>; had served with him in the army; witness was <rs type="role" reg="Major">Major</rs> of the <orgName type="regiment" key="2KYRegiment">2d Kentucky regiment</orgName>, and accused was a Lieutenant of the same regiment; thought he was a quiet, peaceable man; was popular at home, and was regarded as a young man of more than ordinary intelligence; was a member of the <orgName n="Secession Convention" type="convention">Secession Convention of <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName></orgName>, and a member of <persName n="McGoffin,Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00151" reg="mostcommon:McGoffin,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Governor">Gov.</roleName> <surname>McGoffin</surname></persName>'s staff; was a practising lawyer, and at <num value="1">one</num> time edited a newspaper; on <num value="1">one</num> occasion witness was sent on an important military service, and selected Forde on account of his high opinion of him as a brave man and disciplinarian. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="216"/> Maj <persName n="Magruder,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00152" reg="mostcommon:Magruder,nomatch:0"><surname>Magruder</surname></persName> deposed: Knew the accused, who was his kinsman; he was a young man who stood well in the estimation of every <num value="1">one</num>; was regarded as a quiet and peaceable man; rather amiable and gentle in his disposition; knew him in <placeName reg="District of Columbia" key="tgn,7013962">Washington city</placeName>, where he held a clerkship, to which he was appointed by <persName n="Guthrie,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00153" reg="mostcommon:Guthrie,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Guthrie</surname></persName>, who selected accused on account of his personal knowledge of his qualifications as a clerk. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="217"/> <persName n="Marshall,,Alexander,K.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00154" reg="default:Marshall,Alexander,K.,,"><foreName n="Alexander">Alex.</foreName> <foreName>K.</foreName> <surname>Marshall</surname></persName> deposed: Knew Forde in <placeName reg="District of Columbia" key="tgn,7013962">Washington city</placeName>, where witness boarded at the same house with him for <num value="2">two</num> successive winters; his standing was as good as that of any man, and witness regarded him as quite a promising young man; believed him to be a brave, spirited man, but quiet and even gentle in his disposition. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="218"/> <persName n="Abboct,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00155" reg="mostcommon:Abboct,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Abboct</surname></persName> deposed: Knew Forde in <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>, where he sustained a high character as a clerk and a gentleman; always believed him a man of quiet, peaceable habits, and not disposed to seek a quarrel with any <num value="1">one</num>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="219"/> <persName n="Cary,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00156" reg="mostcommon:Cary,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Cary</surname></persName> deposed: Was at <num value="1">one</num> time a member of the <rs>Kentucky Legislature</rs>, and Forde was at the same time <rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Clerk">Assistant Clerk</rs> of the body; he was regarded as a faithful and efficient officer; witness was not very intimate with Forde, but knew that he stood high with his party, and enjoyed its confidence; was an earnest Secessionist, and in the canvass of <dateStruct value="1860--"><year reg="1860">1860</year></dateStruct> took an active part in polities. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="220"/> <persName n="Clarke,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00157" reg="mostcommon:Clarke,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Clarke</surname></persName> bore testimony to the character of Forde, and knew him to be high-minded and honorable.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="221"/>Other witnesses bore similar testimony. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="222"/> <persName n="Beasley,Doctor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00158" reg="mostcommon:Beasley,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <surname>Beasley</surname></persName> deposed: Was acquainted with Forde; had known him since <dateStruct value="1858--"><year reg="1858">1858</year></dateStruct>; witness resided in the same county with <persName n="Churchill,Judge,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00159" reg="mostcommon:Churchill,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Judge">Judge</roleName> <surname>Churchill</surname></persName>, who was married to Forde's mother; accused visited the family of witness; Forde's standing at home was very high, and as a young lawyer had a fine practice; as a politician the accused took an active part, and was on <unclear></unclear> in <dateStruct value="1860--"><year reg="1860">1860</year></dateStruct> knew that Forde had sacrificed as comfortable home as any man in <placeName reg="Kentucky, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName> on account of his Southern-rights views; his mother had all the time been a warm secession lady, and witness had felt some anxiety about her, knowing that her husband was a strong Union man. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="223"/> The counsel for the accused applied to the <rs type="place">Court</rs> for permission to introduce the sworn testimony of <persName n="Reed,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00160" reg="mostcommon:Reed,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Reed</surname></persName> before the <rs>Coroner</rs>'s jury, but the <rs type="place">Court</rs> refused to admit the introduction of the testimony. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="224"/> A motion was then made by counsel for the accused to introduce, as testimony, the depositions taken at the <rs>Coroner</rs>'s inquest; but the motion was overruled by the <rs type="place">Court</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="225"/>Counsel then moved to postpone further proceedings on the ground that <num value="1">one</num> of the sitting magistrates acted as coroner at the inquest.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="226"/>This motion was also overruled by the <rs type="place">Court</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="227"/> The <rs type="place">Court</rs> then, at <num value="3">3</num>&#x00BC; o'clock, took a recess till <time value="4:30">half-past 4</time>. </p> 
<div4 type="entry" n="1"> 
<head>Afternoon session.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="228"/> At <time value="4.5oclock">4&#x00BD; o'clock</time> the <rs type="place">Court</rs> again convened, and the motion of prisoner's counsel to offer in testimony the depositions at the coroner's in quest allowed to be put upon record. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="229"/> Counsel for accused then asked time to review the evidence, which was granted, and the <rs type="place">Court</rs> adjourned till <time value="10oclock">10 o'clock</time> this morning, when the arguments in the case will be commenced. </p> </div4> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="21"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Before the New Orleans <rs type="role" reg="Provost Marshal">Provost Marshal</rs>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="230"/> --A few more clippings from New Orleans papers of doings before the <rs type="place">Provost Court</rs> of the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs>: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="231"/> <persName n="McJones,,William,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00161" reg="default:McJones,William,,,"><foreName n="William">Wm.</foreName> <surname>McJones</surname></persName> was arrested yesterday and taken before <persName n="Kilburue,Provost Marshal,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00162" reg="mostcommon:Kilburue,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Provost Marshal">Provost Marshal</roleName> <surname>Kilburue</surname></persName>, on a charge of having in his possession a pocket handkerchief ornamented with <num value="2">two</num> Confederate flags, delicately wrought in fancy needlework.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="232"/><num value="1">One</num> was the &#x0022;Bonnie Blue Flag,&#x0022; and the other the &#x0022;<rs type="color">Red</rs>, <rs type="color">White</rs>, and <rs type="color">Red</rs>.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="233"/> <persName n="Haughery,,Sarah,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00163" reg="default:Haughery,Sarah,,,"><foreName>Sarah</foreName> <surname>Haughery</surname></persName> and <persName n="Farredy,,Josephine,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00164" reg="default:Farredy,Josephine,,,"><foreName>Josephine</foreName> <surname>Farredy</surname></persName>, who reside on <address><street n="Liberty street">Liberty street</street></address>, took the liberty of singing the &#x0022;Bonnie Blue Flag,&#x0022; talking secesh, and cursing <rs n="Unionist" type="political">Unionists</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="234"/>The accused denied the allegations, and averred that the charge originated in spite and personal malice.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="235"/>Witnesses, however, corroborated the complaint in every particular, and thereupon <persName><foreName>Sarah</foreName></persName> was fined <measure n="15dollars" type="currency">$15</measure> and <persName><foreName>Josephine</foreName></persName> <measure n="25dollars" type="currency">$25</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="236"/> <persName n="Bobet,,J.,B.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00165" reg="default:Bobet,J.,B.,,"><foreName>J.</foreName> <foreName>B.</foreName> <surname>Bobet</surname></persName>, who cursed <persName n="Lincoln,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00166" reg="mostcommon:Lincoln,nomatch:0"><surname>Lincoln</surname></persName> on the fast day, said that he had been, and always would be, secesh.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="237"/>He was given a good character by several witnesses, though on the occasion in question he got a little fight.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="238"/>He was sent to prison for <measure n="30days" type="date">thirty days</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="239"/> <persName n="Hickey,,Thomas,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00167" reg="default:Hickey,Thomas,,,"><foreName>Thomas</foreName> <surname>Hickey</surname></persName> was up for telling a soldier that he was a d &mdash; d rebel, and said he would like to shoot down every <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> in the city.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="240"/>He was terribly tight, and confessed everything.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="241"/>In fact, he said he did not know what he had said.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="242"/>He was sent to prison for <measure n="60days" type="date">sixty days</measure>. </p> </q><bibl n="New Orleans papers"></bibl></cit> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="22"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">How <persName n="Grant,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00168" reg="nearbymention:Grant,Gen,,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Grant</surname></persName> started on his present campaign.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="243"/> --The <orgName n="Chicago Tribune" type="newspaper">Chicago <hi rend="italics">Tribune</hi></orgName> learns from a gentleman who participated in the recent campaign of <persName n="Grant,,Gen,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00169" reg="default:Grant,Gen,,,"><foreName>Gen</foreName> <surname>Grant</surname></persName> up to the time the enemy crossed the Big Black in the retreat towards <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName>, that in starting on the movement the <rs>General</rs> disencumbered himself of everything, setting an example to his officers and men. He took neither a horse nor a servant, overcoat nor blanket, nor tent, nor camp-sheet, not even a clean shirt.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="244"/>His only baggage was a <rs n="tooth brush" type="product">tooth-brush</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="245"/>He shared all the hardships of the private soldier, sleeping in the front and in the open air, and eating hard tack and salt pork.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="246"/>He wore no sword, had on a low crowned citizen's hat, and the only thing about him to mark him as a military man was his <num value="2">two</num> stars on his undress military coat.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="247"/>On the battle field he was omnipresent riding everywhere, generally alone, into the thickest of the fight, inspiring the troops by his imperturbable coolness and bravery. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="23"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> orders for <placeName reg="Mississippi" key="tgn,7007522">Mississippi</placeName> and <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="248"/> --An order from the <orgName n="Federal Department" type="department">Federal Department</orgName> directs that within the <name>States</name> of <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName> and <placeName reg="Mississippi" key="tgn,7007522">Mississippi</placeName>, wherever the <rs>Federal</rs> have the rule, all citizens shall be registered in <num value="3">three</num> classes: <num value="1" type="ordinal">1st</num> avowed enemies; <num value="2" type="ordinal">2d</num>, neutral foreigners; <num value="34">34</num>, loyal citizens.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="249"/>The <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> class are all to leave their lines by or before the <date value="06-16">16th of June</date> and their property confiscated; the <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> are to take an oath of neutrality; the <num value="3" type="ordinal">third</num> are to bear certificates of loyalty.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="250"/>No goods of any kind are allowed to be sold except by special permit, except to those showing evidence of loyalty. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="24"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="251"/> The distinguished Polish officer, Rochebrune, was originally a plasterer, but now wears the <unclear></unclear> betokening the high rank of General. </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="7"/> 
<div2 type="local"> 
<head>Local Matters.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Called meeting of the <name>Council</name>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="252"/> --A meeting of the <orgName n="City Council" type="council">City Council</orgName> was held yesterday afternoon.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="253"/>Present: <persName n="Saunders,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00170" reg="mostcommon:Saunders,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Messrs.</roleName> <surname>Saunders</surname></persName>, <persName n="Walber,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00171" reg="mostcommon:Walber,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Walber</surname></persName>, <persName n="Hill,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00172" reg="mostcommon:Hill,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Hill</surname></persName>, <persName n="Richardson,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00173" reg="mostcommon:Richardson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>, <persName n="Denoon,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00174" reg="mostcommon:Denoon,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Denoon</surname></persName>, <persName n="Clopton,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00175" reg="mostcommon:Clopton,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Clopton</surname></persName>, <persName n="Epps,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00176" reg="mostcommon:Epps,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Epps</surname></persName>, and <persName n="Burr,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00177" reg="mostcommon:Burr,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Burr</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="254"/> <placeName reg="The President">The President</placeName> announced the death of <persName n="Stratton,,M.,L.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00178" reg="expanded:Stratton,Moses,L.,,"><foreName>M.</foreName> <foreName>L.</foreName> <surname>Stratton</surname></persName>, long an officer of the city, and late <num value="1" type="ordinal">First</num> Auditor. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="255"/> <persName n="Saunders,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00179" reg="mostcommon:Saunders,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Saunders</surname></persName> offered the following preamble and resolutions: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="256"/> Whereas, it has pleased <name n="God" type="God">God</name>, in His all wise providence, to remove from us by death our late estimable and efficient Auditor, <persName n="Stratton,,Moses,L.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00180" reg="default:Stratton,Moses,L.,,"><foreName>Moses</foreName> <foreName>L.</foreName> <surname>Stratton</surname></persName>, whose long services in the employment of the city, <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> as Register of the <orgName n="City Water Works" type="works">City Water Works</orgName>, elected to that office for a number of years by the almost unanimous voice of the citizens, and for the past <measure n="5years" type="date">five years</measure> as Auditor, elected by the unanimous vote of the <name>Council</name>, whose fidelity in the discharge of the duties of his office, and unassuming manners and accommodating spirit in which those duties have been discharged, have endeared him to every member of the <name>Council</name>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="257"/>Therefore, </p> 
<list type="ordered"> 
<head></head> 
<item n="1"> <num value="1" type="ordinal">1st</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="258"/>Resolved, That in the death of our late <rs type="role" reg="Auditor">Auditor</rs>, <persName n="Stratton,,Moses,L.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00181" reg="default:Stratton,Moses,L.,,"><foreName>Moses</foreName> <foreName>L.</foreName> <surname>Stratton</surname></persName>, the city has been deprived of the services of an efficient and faithful officer, and the community of a worthy and estimable citizen.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="259"/></item> 
<item n="2"> <num value="2" type="ordinal">2d</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="260"/>Resolved, That the members of the <name>Council</name> deeply sympathize with the afflicted widow and children of the deceased in their and bereavement.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="261"/></item> 
<item n="3"> <num value="3" type="ordinal">3d</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="262"/>Resolved, That the <name>Council</name> will in a body attend the funeral of the deceased tomorrow at <time value="10oclock">10 o'clock</time>. </item> 
<item n="4"> <num value="4" type="ordinal">4th</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="263"/>Resolved, That the offices of the <rs>Auditor</rs> and <rs>Chamberlain</rs> be closed from <time value="10:5am">10&#x00BD; o'clock A. M.</time> till <time value="1pm">1 o'clock P. M.</time> to-morrow.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="264"/></item> 
<item n="5"> <num value="5" type="ordinal">5th</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="265"/>Resolved, That the clerk of the <name>Council</name> furnish the family of the deceased with a copy of the above preamble and resolutions.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="266"/></item> </list> 
<p> The resolutions were adopted. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="267"/> <persName n="Harrison,Mister,Thomas,B.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00182" reg="default:Harrison,Thomas,B.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName n="Thomas">Thos.</foreName> <foreName>B.</foreName> <surname>Harrison</surname></persName>, <num value="1" type="ordinal">1st</num> clerk of the <rs>Auditor</rs>, was authorized to act in his stead till the election of his successor. </p> </q><bibl n="Mr. Saunders"></bibl></cit> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">The <rs type="place">Prisons</rs>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="268"/> --At the <rs type="place">Libby prison</rs> yesterday <num value="93">93</num> <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs>, captured at <placeName reg="Jackson, Hinds, Mississippi" key="tgn,7016129">Jackson, Miss.</placeName>, on the <dateStruct value="--16"><day reg="16">16th ult.</day></dateStruct>, and <num value="20">20</num> more, captured last week at <placeName reg="Berryville, Clarke, Virginia" key="tgn,2110642">Berryville, Clarke county, Va.</placeName>, were received. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="269"/> <num value="3">Three</num> very respectable looking men were committed to <placeName reg="Castle Thunder">Castle Thunder</placeName> yesterday, charged with being spies.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="270"/>Their names are <persName n="Hannah,,John,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00183" reg="default:Hannah,John,A.,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName> <surname>Hannah</surname></persName>, <persName n="Howard,,Presley,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00184" reg="default:Howard,Presley,A.,,"><foreName>Presley</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName> <surname>Howard</surname></persName>, and <persName n="Mason,,L.,Dudley,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00185" reg="default:Mason,L.,Dudley,,"><foreName>L.</foreName> <foreName>Dudley</foreName> <surname>Mason</surname></persName>, and they hail from <placeName reg="Mount Sterling, Montgomery, Kentucky" key="tgn,2040401">Mount Sterling, Ky.</placeName>, from which they claim to be exites, and bear passes from the <rs type="role" reg="Provost Marshal">Provost Marshal</rs> there sending them beyond the <rs>Federal</rs> lines.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="271"/>They had been stopping at the <rs type="place">Spotswood Hotel</rs>, and visiting the <orgName n="Tredegar Iron Works" type="works">Tredegar Iron Works</orgName>, <placeName reg="Navy-Yard">Navy-Yard</placeName>, &#x0026;c. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="272"/> List evening the prisoners captured--<num value="302">302</num> in number, arrived at the <rs type="place">Libby Prison</rs> last night.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="273"/>There were <num value="11">eleven</num> officers and <num value="2">two</num> Surgeons among the number.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="274"/>Included in the officers were <persName n="Irwin,Lieutenant-Colonel,William,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00186" reg="default:Irwin,William,,,"><roleName n="Lieutenant-Colonel">Lieut. Col.</roleName> <foreName n="William">Wm.</foreName> <surname>Irwin</surname></persName>, <orgName type="regiment" key="10NYCav">10th N. Y. cavalry</orgName>; <persName n="Morris,Major,Robert,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00187" reg="default:Morris,Robert,,,"><roleName n="Major">Maj.</roleName> <foreName n="Robert">Robt.</foreName> <surname>Morris</surname></persName>, <num value="6" type="ordinal">6th</num> <persName n="Penn,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00188" reg="mostcommon:Penn,nomatch:0"><surname>Penn</surname></persName>; <rs type="role">Capts.</rs> E. A Fobes, <persName n="Getman,,D.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00189" reg="default:Getman,D.,,,"><foreName>D.</foreName> <surname>Getman</surname></persName>, <orgName type="regiment" key="10NYCav">10th N. Y. cavalry</orgName>; <persName n="Coileday,Lieutenant,L.,R.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00190" reg="default:Coileday,L.,R.,,"><roleName n="Lieutenant">Lts.</roleName> <foreName>L.</foreName> <foreName>R.</foreName> <surname>Coileday</surname></persName>, <persName n="Lonning,Lieutenant,T.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00191" reg="default:Lonning,T.,,,"><roleName n="Lieutenant"></roleName><foreName>T.</foreName> <surname>Lonning</surname></persName>, <num value="6" type="ordinal">6th</num> <persName n="Penn,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00192" reg="mostcommon:Penn,nomatch:0"><surname>Penn</surname></persName>; <persName n="Garei,,John,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00193" reg="default:Garei,John,A.,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName> <surname>Garei</surname></persName>, <persName n="Goods,,Thos,G.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00194" reg="default:Goods,Thos,G.,,"><foreName>Thos</foreName> <foreName>G.</foreName> <surname>Goods</surname></persName>, <num value="1" type="ordinal">1st</num> Md; <persName n="Kerrin,,Jos,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00195" reg="default:Kerrin,Jos,,,"><foreName>Jos</foreName> <surname>Kerrin</surname></persName>, <orgName type="regiment" key="6USCav">6th U. S. cavalry</orgName>, and <persName n="Cracker,,H.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00196" reg="default:Cracker,H.,,,"><foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Cracker</surname></persName>, <orgName type="regiment" key="NJ1">1st N. J.</orgName> Accompanying the party was <persName n="Bulkley,,S.,T.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00197" reg="default:Bulkley,S.,T.,,"><foreName>S.</foreName> <foreName>T.</foreName> <surname>Bulkley</surname></persName>, a correspondent of the <orgName n="New York Herald" type="newspaper">New York <hi rend="italics">Herald</hi></orgName>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Night owls.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="275"/> --The garroters about <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> are now called &#x0022;night owls,&#x0022; from the fact that they keep their nests most of the day, only leaving them long enough to take their stands at the street corners to mark their victim for darker hours.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="276"/>These creatures have their regular spies and scouts about the hotels and public places, and know the movements of the police with wonderful accuracy.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="277"/>To get rid of them they must be harnessed as persons of had character; and if they can show no visible means of support, they ought to be dealt with in the most summary manner.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="278"/>If the law officers cannot get rid of such characters, then the <rs>Vigilance Committees</rs> will take them in hand and soon dispose of them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="279"/><placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> cannot afford to loss her good name by foreign thieves and robbers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="280"/>Let her citizens see to it in time, or they may be compelled to enact the scenes of <placeName reg="San Francisco, San Francisco, California" key="tgn,7014456">San Francisco</placeName>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Heavy Robbery.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="281"/> --<persName n="Tadlock,,Carter,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00198" reg="default:Tadlock,Carter,,,"><foreName>Carter</foreName> <surname>Tadlock</surname></persName> and <persName n="Edett,,Willie,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00199" reg="default:Edett,Willie,,,"><foreName>Willie</foreName> <surname>Edett</surname></persName> were yesterday arrested by <persName n="Seat,Officer,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00200" reg="mostcommon:Seat,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Officer">officers</roleName> <surname>Seat</surname></persName> and <persName n="Perrin,Officer,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00201" reg="mostcommon:Perrin,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Officer"></roleName><surname>Perrin</surname></persName>, charged with robbing <persName n="Stephens,,Mary,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00202" reg="default:Stephens,Mary,,,"><foreName>Mary</foreName> <surname>Stephens</surname></persName> of <measure n="1000dollars" type="currency">$1,000</measure> in bank notes, <measure n="365dollars" type="currency">$365</measure> in Confederate notes, <measure n="260dollars" type="currency">$260</measure> in gold, <num value="2">two</num> gold watches, worth <measure n="200dollars" type="currency">$200</measure> each, and a <rs n="silver watch" type="product">silver watch</rs>, worth <measure n="50dollars" type="currency">$50</measure>. They were lodged in the lower station-house and will be examined before the <rs>Mayor</rs> this morning.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="282"/>They were very well dressed, and their passage down the street in custody excited some interest in the case. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Burglary.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="283"/> --On <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time> last the store of <persName n="Alvey,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00203" reg="mostcommon:Alvey,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Messrs.</roleName> <surname>Alvey</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="Lipscomb,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00204" reg="mostcommon:Lipscomb,nomatch:0"><surname>Lipscomb</surname></persName>, on <num value="13" type="ordinal">13th</num>, between <address><street n="Main street">Main</street></address> and <address><street n="Cary street">Cary streets</street></address>, was entered by burglars, who forced open a side door fronting on an alley, and carried off <measure n="500l." type="pounds"><num value="500">500</num> pounds</measure> of sugar, <num value="10">10</num> gallons of <rs n="apple brandy" type="product">apple brandy</rs>, and <num value="5">5</num> gallons of molasses.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="284"/>It is thought that the burglars must have used a cart to carry off their weighty plunder. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics"><placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> <orgName n="Circuit Court" type="court">Circuit Court</orgName>, yesterday.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="285"/> --<persName n="Parker,,Irz,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00205" reg="default:Parker,Irz,,,"><foreName>Irz</foreName> <surname>Parker</surname></persName>, <persName n="Wilson,,Thomas,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00206" reg="default:Wilson,Thomas,,,"><foreName n="Thomas">Thos.</foreName> <surname>Wilson</surname></persName>, <persName n="Westerfield,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00207" reg="default:Westerfield,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Westerfield</surname></persName>, alias <persName n="Farrer,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00208" reg="default:Farrer,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Farrer</surname></persName>, <persName n="Wood,,James,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00209" reg="default:Wood,James,W.,,"><foreName n="James">Jas.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Wood</surname></persName>, <persName n="Tracy,,William,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00210" reg="default:Tracy,William,,,"><foreName>William</foreName> <surname>Tracy</surname></persName>, alias <persName n="Smith,,William,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00211" reg="default:Smith,William,,,"><foreName n="William">Wm.</foreName> <surname>Smith</surname></persName>, and <persName n="Lawrence,,Joseph,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00212" reg="default:Lawrence,Joseph,,,"><foreName>Joseph</foreName> <surname>Lawrence</surname></persName>, indicted by the <rs>Grand Jury</rs> for a conspiracy to escape from the penitentiary, on the <date value="05-09">9th of May,</date> were set to the bar, <persName n="Tazewell,,L.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00213" reg="default:Tazewell,L.,W.,,"><foreName>L.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Tazewell</surname></persName>, <rs type="role" reg="Esquire">Esq.</rs>, Commonwealth's Attorney, <persName n="Young,,Jonathan,B.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00214" reg="default:Young,Jonathan,B.,,"><foreName n="Jonathan">Jno.</foreName> <foreName>B.</foreName> <surname>Young</surname></persName>, <rs type="role">Esq</rs>, for the defence.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="286"/>In consequence of the witnesses being the same in all the cases, and all implicating each alike, they were all tried together.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="287"/>After hearing the arguments of counsel, the jury retired, found a verdict of guilty against <persName n="Parker,,Ira,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00215" reg="default:Parker,Ira,,,"><foreName>Ira</foreName> <surname>Parker</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="288"/><persName n="Wilson,,Thomas,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00216" reg="default:Wilson,Thomas,,,"><foreName n="Thomas">Thos.</foreName> <surname>Wilson</surname></persName>, <persName n="Westerfield,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00217" reg="default:Westerfield,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Westerfield</surname></persName>, <persName n="Tracy,,William,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00218" reg="default:Tracy,William,,,"><foreName n="William">Wm.</foreName> <surname>Tracy</surname></persName>, and <persName n="Lawrence,,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00219" reg="default:Lawrence,James,,,"><foreName n="James">Jas.</foreName> <surname>Lawrence</surname></persName>, fixing their term of additional confinement at <num value="1">one</num> year, and solitary confinement <num value="1">one</num>-<num value="12" type="ordinal">twelfth</num> of the whole time.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="289"/><persName n="Wood,,James,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00220" reg="default:Wood,James,W.,,"><foreName n="James">Jas.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Wood</surname></persName> was found not guilty.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="290"/>A motion was made by defence for an arrest of judgment, which will be argued this morning. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="7"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">C. S. <orgName n="Circuit Court" type="court">Circuit Court</orgName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="291"/> --<persName n="Halyburton,Judge,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00221" reg="mostcommon:Halyburton,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Judge">Judge</roleName> <surname>Halyburton</surname></persName> held Court yesterday for the transaction of such business as came before him. An order was entered directing the <rs>Marshal</rs> to summons the <rs>Grand Jury</rs> for <dateStruct><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct> next.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="292"/>Several entries were made looking to the sequestrations of property of sundry alien enemies.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="293"/>The <rs type="place">Court</rs> then adjourned. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="294"/> <hi rend="italics">The Health of the <rs type="place">City</rs></hi> is an object of too much importance just now to be overlooked, and yet the condition of some of the gutters on <placeName reg="Shockoe Hill">Shockoe Hill</placeName> indicate a disregard of cleanliness that seems truly astonishing.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="295"/>Bad grades cause the water to stagnate, and of course will produce fevers if proper disinfectants are not used.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="296"/>Let the authorities look to this matter at once. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="9"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Chicken Catchers.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="297"/> --<num value="2">Two</num> youngsters &mdash; <persName n="August,,Joseph,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00222" reg="default:August,Joseph,,,"><foreName>Joseph</foreName> <surname>August</surname></persName> and <persName n="McCannon,,Carter,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00223" reg="default:McCannon,Carter,,,"><foreName>Carter</foreName> <surname>McCannon</surname></persName> &mdash; were before the <rs>Mayor</rs> yesterday, charged with stealing a chicken from <persName n="Gamble,,Thomas,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00224" reg="default:Gamble,Thomas,,,"><foreName>Thomas</foreName> <surname>Gamble</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="298"/>The boys, it seems, tolled the little biped into a trap by a few grains of corn, and then bagging him were making off when caught.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="299"/>They were sent to the <orgName n="Hustings Court" type="court">Hustings Court</orgName> to answer the offence. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="10"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Falling back.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="300"/> --The residents in the suburbs of the city are now very much amazed by the scores of ruffians who are evacuating the city at the advance of the <rs>Vigilance Committees</rs>, now organized and ready to act. <orgName n="Our Country" type="newspaper">Our country</orgName> readers must get up similar organizations, and securing the aid of the gallant soldiery in their neighborhoods thus ensure their protection. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="301"/> <hi rend="italics">Mounted Patrol</hi> can effect great good in the vicinity of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, and may thus put an end to the flood of speculators swarming in every by path between here and the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> lines.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="302"/>The vast amount of trash now running the blockade is of no sort of value to our people, and only tends to create extravagance and depreciate the currency. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="303"/> <hi rend="italics">The <rs type="role2">Mayor</rs></hi> had no business of importance before him yesterday.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="304"/>A few disreputable women, <num value="1">one</num> or <num value="2">two</num> fellows for being tipsy, and sundry &#x0022;dram sellers&#x0022; for keeping open after hours and for violating the <name>Sunday</name> law, made up the morning's docket. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="13"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Death of an old citizen.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="305"/> --<persName n="Stratton,Mister,M.,L.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00225" reg="expanded:Stratton,Moses,L.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <foreName>L.</foreName> <surname>Stratton</surname></persName>, the <rs type="place">City</rs> Auditor, and for many years Register of the <orgName n="City Water Works" type="works">City Water Works</orgName>, died at his residence on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time> last, after a long and painful illness. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="14"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="306"/> <hi rend="italics">A <rs n="silver watch" type="product">Silver Watch</rs>,</hi> double case, <num value="6536">No. 6,536</num>, <persName n="Robinson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00226" reg="mostcommon:Robinson,nomatch:0"><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>, <placeName reg="Liverpool, Yazoo, Mississippi" key="tgn,2463110">Liverpool</placeName>, maker, has been taken from a prisoner by a police officer, and is now held subject to the order of the rightful owner. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="15"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Jackson Monument.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="307"/> --<persName n="Maltery,,Lee,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00227" reg="default:Maltery,Lee,,,"><foreName>Lee</foreName> <surname>Maltery</surname></persName>, at <placeName reg="Metropolitan Hall">Metropolitan Hall</placeName>, is giving a series of <unclear>ments</unclear> in aid of the <unclear></unclear>. </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> <milestone unit="page" n="2"/> 
<div1 type="page-image"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="308"/><figure entity="NW_RichTimesD_024_139_002"> <figDesc>Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume <num value="24">24</num>, <num value="139">Number 139</num>, <ref n="page 2">page 2</ref>. </figDesc> </figure></p> </div1> <milestone unit="column" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.</head> 
<div2 type="morning"> 
<head><date value="1863-06-11">Thursday morning...June 11, 1863.</date></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="309"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="telegraphic"> 
<head>Telegraphic news.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>From <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName>.</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Jackson, Hinds, Mississippi" key="tgn,7016129">Jackson, Miss.</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-06-9"><month reg="06">June</month> <day reg="9">9</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="310"/> --Our scouts report the enemy's pickets <measure n="10miles" type="distance">ten miles</measure> deep, every means of approach closely guarded, and that the greatest courage and care are required to reach <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="311"/><persName n="Grant,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00228" reg="nearbymention:Grant,Gen,,,"><surname>Grant</surname></persName> communicates with the fleet by signal lights, which were seen last night, constantly signalling, betokening a movement or renewal of the assault, it is thought.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="312"/>The roar of the enemy's mortars was heard at intervals of <measure n="2seconds" type="date">two seconds</measure> all night, and is continuous this morning.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="313"/>Nothing from <placeName reg="Port Hudson, East Baton Rouge, Louisiana" key="tgn,7017544">Port Hudson</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="314"/>An officer captured by <persName n="Grant,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00229" reg="nearbymention:Grant,Gen,,,"><surname>Grant</surname></persName>'s pickets subsequently escaped, and arrived here this morning.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="315"/>He reports the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> army much depressed by the knowledge of <persName n="Johnston,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00230" reg="mostcommon:Johnston,nomatch:0"><surname>Johnston</surname></persName> massing a heavy force in their rear, and certain death in front.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="316"/>Their officers say certain defeat or annihilation awaits them. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head>From <placeName reg="Tennessee, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName> &mdash; late Northern news.</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Shelbyville, Bedford, Tennessee" key="tgn,2101476">Shelbyville, Tenn.</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-06-9"><month reg="06">June</month> <day reg="9">9</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="317"/> --All quiet in front.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="318"/>The <orgName n="Cincinnati Commercial" type="newspaper">Cincinnati <hi rend="italics">Commercial</hi></orgName>, of the <num value="4" type="ordinal">4th</num>, has been received.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="319"/>At the <orgName n="Peace Convention" type="convention">Peace Convention</orgName> in New York, on the <dateStruct value="--3"><day reg="2">3d</day></dateStruct>, <persName n="Wood,,Fernando,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00231" reg="default:Wood,Fernando,,,"><foreName>Fernando</foreName> <surname>Wood</surname></persName> was a prominent speaker, and presented strong resolutions, which passed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="320"/>The resolutions declare fealty to the <rs>Constitution</rs>, and to the <rs>State</rs> under the <rs>Constitution</rs>; that there is no power to coerce a State by military force; that the war is contrary to the <rs>Constitution</rs>, and should cease; that the claim of dictatorial and unlimited military power for the trial of citizens by court martial is monstrous and execrable.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="321"/>They also protest against the cowardly, despotic, inhuman, accursed act, the banishment of <persName n="Vallandigham,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00232" reg="nearbymention:Vallandigham,C.,L.,,"><surname>Vallandigham</surname></persName>, and recommend a suspension of hostilities and a <orgName n="General Convention" type="misc">general convention</orgName> to settle the manner of reconciliation. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="322"/> <hi rend="italics"><placeName reg="Springfield, Sangamon, Illinois" key="tgn,7014529">Springfield, Ill.</placeName>,</hi> <date value="06-03">June 3.</date>--The <rs type="place">House</rs> has unanimously passed a resolution condemnatory of <persName n="Burnside,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00233" reg="nearbymention:Burnside,A.,E.,,"><surname>Burnside</surname></persName>'s order suppressing newspapers, and calling the attention of the <rs>Government</rs> to the infringement of popular rights and the invasion of State sovereignty. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head>Interesting foreign Chit-Chat.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="323"/> A correspondent of the <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston (S. C.)</placeName> <hi rend="italics">Courier,</hi> writing from <placeName key="tgn,2535807;tgn,7006630" n="0.143 000000.2851	placename;tgn,2535807;nassau river, florida, florida,Florida,United States,North and Central America;0.012 000000.0248	placename;tgn,7006630;nassau,new providence,bahamas,north and central america,New Providence,Bahamas,North and Central America" reg="nassau river, florida, florida,Florida,United States,North and Central America;nassau,new providence,bahamas,north and central america,New Providence,Bahamas,North and Central America">Nassau</placeName>, gives that paper a chatty <hi rend="italics">resume</hi> of the news in the latest foreign papers received there.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="324"/>The letter is very entertaining, and we give some extracts from it: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="325"/> Just now the rage in the fashionable <hi rend="italics">monde</hi> of <persName n="Paris,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00234" reg="mostcommon:Paris,nomatch:0"><surname>Paris</surname></persName> appears to be the <hi rend="italics">Bal Masque.</hi> The masked balls at the <name>Tuileries</name>, both for their number, variety, and splendor, are still the talk of both capitals, <persName n="Paris,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00235" reg="mostcommon:Paris,nomatch:0"><surname>Paris</surname></persName> and <placeName reg="London, Madison, Ohio" key="tgn,2080432">London</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="326"/>The new aristocracy of the <rs>Empire</rs> indulge in a constant round of gaiety and splendor, which throws the tinselled glories of the stage quite into the shade.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="327"/>The ladies try hard to outdo each other inventing the most extravagant costumes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="328"/>The old allegorical devices are left in the dusty lumber-rooms of theatrical costumes, and <num value="1">one</num> lady goes as a pack of cards, another as <num value="0.5">a half</num> nude Bacchante, <num value="0.33">a <num value="3" type="ordinal">third</num></num> as a volcano, and another as an earthquake.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="329"/>The <persName n="Gastiglione,,Countess,,,de" id="n-0001.0000.00000.00236" reg="expanded:Gastiglione,Countess,,,"><foreName>Countess</foreName> <nameLink>de</nameLink> <surname>Gastiglione</surname></persName> has appeared as a Queen of <placeName key="tgn,7024113" n="1.000 10" reg="Etruria,Italian Peninsula,Europe">Etruria</placeName>, with arms, shoulders, and feet bare, and <persName n="Metternich,Princess,,,,Von" id="n-0001.0000.00000.00237" reg="mostcommon:Metternich,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Princess">the Princess</roleName> <nameLink>Von</nameLink> <surname>Metternich</surname></persName> as a black devil.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="330"/>The <rs>Countess Kosakoff</rs> has appeared as a mirror, and <persName n="Rothschild,Madame,,,,de" id="n-0001.0000.00000.00238" reg="mostcommon:Rothschild,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Madame">Madame</roleName> <nameLink>de</nameLink> <surname>Rothschild</surname></persName> has figured as a bird of Paradise.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="331"/>The gentlemen have been equally fantastic in their dresses, and even the saturnine <rs>Emperor</rs> has been compelled to change his dress <num value="3">three</num> times in the course of an evening to join in the gambols. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="332"/> <persName n="Dickens,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00239" reg="mostcommon:Dickens,nomatch:0"><surname>Dickens</surname></persName> is busily engaged on his new novel, the title of which has not yet transpired.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="333"/>He is living in <placeName reg="Department de Ville de Paris, Ile-de-France, France" key="tgn,7002980">Paris</placeName>, but occasionally visits <placeName reg="London, Madison, Ohio" key="tgn,2080432">London</placeName> to give public readings from his works. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="334"/> Spirit Rapping is being outdone by the clever mechanical contrivance of <persName n="Direks,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00240" reg="mostcommon:Direks,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">a Mr.</roleName> <surname>Direks</surname></persName>, who is giving an entertainment called the &#x0022;Spectre Drama.&#x0022; at the <orgName n="Polytechnic Institute" type="institute">Polytechnic Institute</orgName> in <placeName reg="London, Madison, Ohio" key="tgn,2080432">London</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="335"/><num value="2">Two</num> performances a day scarcely seem to satisfy the crowds who flock to witness it; for natural magic, although it has shown the world many wonders, has never before, it is said, produced anything as striking.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="336"/>By <persName n="Dircks,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00241" reg="mostcommon:Dircks,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Dircks</surname></persName>'s apparatus a solid representation of a human being is thrown into the centre of a stage, and is made to appear and disappear at will without the aid of any visible agency.--While essentially solid and real, the image is surrounded by a faint halo of light, just sufficient to give it a supernatural character.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="337"/>It can be cut through with a sword or a hatchet, or walked through by a spectator without being demolished, or it can be changed in an instant for another image.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="338"/>The counterfeit presentment of any person can be thrown on the stage by this contrivance.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="339"/>Some of the papers suggest the invention to the playwrights as an improvement on the supernatural drama.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="340"/>Banquo's spectre or the ghost in Hamlet might be represented with terrible effect this way. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="341"/> Mentioning the theatre, reminds me to notice the close of that trashy play &#x0022;The <rs n="American" type="group">American</rs> <rs type="role2">Cousin</rs>&#x0022; at the <name>Haymarket</name>, <placeName reg="London, Madison, Ohio" key="tgn,2080432">London</placeName>, after a run of <num value="400">four hundred</num> nights.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="342"/>The character of &#x0022;<persName><roleName n="Lord">Lord</roleName> <foreName>Dundreary</foreName></persName>,&#x0022; by <persName n="Sothern,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00242" reg="mostcommon:Sothern,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Sothern</surname></persName>, (the same who personated it originally at Laura Keen's, New York,) gave the play this extraordinary popularity.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="343"/>Those who have seen the piece (it was performed in <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName> about a year before the war) will remember that <num value="1">one</num> peculiarity of the part of &#x0022;<persName><roleName n="Lord">Lord</roleName> <foreName>Dundreary</foreName></persName>&#x0022; is a strong occasional stutter.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="344"/>So long and continuously has <persName n="Sothern,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00243" reg="mostcommon:Sothern,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Sothern</surname></persName> played the character that his friends fear he will contract the same defect in his own speech.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="345"/>Accordingly, by the advice of physicians, he reads aloud for an hour or <num value="2">two</num> every day in his natural voice to preserve that organ from a misfortune so easily acquired.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="346"/>It is said that <sic><persName n="Sothern,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00244" reg="mostcommon:Sothern,nomatch:0"><surname>Sothern</surname></persName></sic> has made <measure n="100000dollars" type="currency">$100,000</measure> by performing &#x0022;<persName><roleName n="Lord">Lord</roleName> <foreName>Dundreary</foreName></persName>.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="347"/> The success of the underground street railroads in <placeName reg="London, Madison, Ohio" key="tgn,2080432">London</placeName> has proved the development of a new company, which proposes to blow letters and parcels from <num value="1">one</num> end of the metropolis to the other through tubes by atmospheric pressure.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="348"/>Your package is put in at <num value="1">one</num> end, the air exhausted from the other end, and through it goes like lightning.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="349"/>The company has been chartered under the name of the &#x0022;Pneumatic Dispatch Company,&#x0022; and has commenced business by laying down pipes between <num value="1">one</num> of the district post offices and the <rs>Northwestern Railway</rs>, through which mail bags are sent with great rapidity.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="350"/>A miles of space is traveled by this method in <measure n="6seconds" type="date">six seconds</measure>. It would not be extraordinary now if invention and enterprise went a step further, and shoved full-grown passengers through the country upon the same principle.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="351"/>A man thus could easily beat the telegraph, particularly as it is conducted at home nowadays. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="352"/> While on the subject of science and mechanics I may mention the resignation of <persName n="Armstrong,Sir,William,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00245" reg="default:Armstrong,William,,,"><roleName n="Sir">Sir</roleName> <foreName n="William">Wm.</foreName> <surname>Armstrong</surname></persName> as Ordnance Engineer to the <rs>British Government</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="353"/><persName><roleName n="Sir">Sir</roleName> <foreName>William</foreName></persName> and the breach-loading party are now rather out of favor, and <persName n="Whitworth,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00246" reg="mostcommon:Whitworth,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Whitworth</surname></persName>'s star is now in the ascendant. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="354"/> <persName n="Hugo,,Victor,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00247" reg="default:Hugo,Victor,,,"><foreName>Victor</foreName> <surname>Hugo</surname></persName>, whose &#x0022;<foreign lang="fre"><persName n="Miserables,,Les,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00248" reg="default:Miserables,Les,,,"><foreName>Les</foreName> <surname>Miserables</surname></persName></foreign>&#x0022; has electrified the world, has left his retreat at <placeName reg="Jersey City, Hudson, New Jersey" key="tgn,7013813">Jersey</placeName> to enter again into active life.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="355"/>Shut out of <placeName key="tgn,1000070" n="1.000 1012" reg="france">France</placeName> as a socialist and a disorganize, he has gone to <placeName key="tgn,7007868" n="1.000 1" reg="bruxelles,bruxelles,belgie,europe">Brussels</placeName> to start a political paper. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="356"/> The <placeName reg="Department de Ville de Paris, Ile-de-France, France" key="tgn,7002980">Paris</placeName> correspondent of the <orgName n="London Telegraph" type="newspaper">London <hi rend="italics">Telegraph</hi></orgName> complains of the increasing freedom in dress prevalent among the higher class of <persName n="Paris,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00249" reg="mostcommon:Paris,nomatch:0"><surname>Paris</surname></persName> females.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="357"/>He was at the <rs n="Italian" type="group">Italian</rs> opera a few nights previous to writing, and was astonished at the magnificence and scantiness of the costumes, which rivalled in those respects the style of the <num value="1" type="ordinal">First</num> Empire, when, to use the expression of <persName n="Talleyrand,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00250" reg="mostcommon:Talleyrand,nomatch:0"><surname>Talleyrand</surname></persName>, the dresses &#x0022;commenced too late and ended too soon.&#x0022;--The <rs type="role2">Count</rs> d'orsay was once congratulated on having the smallest cab-boy in <placeName reg="London, Madison, Ohio" key="tgn,2080432">London</placeName>; he replied that he was leaving off his servants by degrees, and now should soon get rid of them altogether.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="358"/>The correspondent is reminded of <rs type="role2">Count</rs> d'orsay's speech when he sees the gradually receding robes of the ladies of <placeName reg="Department de Ville de Paris, Ile-de-France, France" key="tgn,7002980">Paris</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="359"/> The <placeName reg="London, Madison, Ohio" key="tgn,2080432">London</placeName> <hi rend="italics">Herald</hi> notices a late bit of New York sumptuousness, which might aptly be termed &#x0022;revels on the edge of a bursting volcano.&#x0022; <num value="2">Two</num> successive dinner parties were given in <address><street n="5 Avenue">Fifth Avenue</street></address> to <num value="2">two</num> betrothed ladies by a wealthy bachelor of their acquaintance, each party numbering about <num value="20">twenty</num> persons, and the latter <num value="1">one</num> including General and <persName n="McClellan,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00251" reg="mostcommon:McClellan,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>McClellan</surname></persName> among its guests.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="360"/><num value="1">One</num> very expensive and exquisite difference from ordinary parties consisted in the novel furnishing of the table.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="361"/>It was oval shaped, but with the white cloth only encircling its outer rim. The whole interior was scooped out and fashioned into an exquisitely arranged parterre, filled with baskets of the most costly and sumptuous flowers, act in wet saw dust and moss, and the mir being thus laden with fragrance, white the dinner was handed round in a dainty succession of choice dishes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="362"/><unclear></unclear> of the dinner.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="363"/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/> each lady guest took, as a present from the host, <num value="1">one</num> of the costly and superb baskets of flowers which had ornamented the centre of the table. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="364"/> A Convention of certain prominent chess players in <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName> met about a year ago and drew up a complete set of new rules for the government of the game.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="365"/>Other chess players in <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName> rebelled.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="366"/>The devotees of the game in <placeName reg="France" key="tgn,1000070">France</placeName>, <placeName reg="Germany" key="tgn,7000084">Germany</placeName>, and <placeName reg="Switzerland" key="tgn,7011731">Switzerland</placeName> scouted at the self-elected reformers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="367"/>A Chess Convention has just been held in <placeName reg="Philadelphia, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7014406">Philadelphia</placeName>, and <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> land has also recorded its protest against innovation.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="368"/>The Confederates may thus set their minds at rest, that they will not, when the war is over, be startled with the intelligence of a complete revolution in the regulation of their favorite intellectual pastime. </p> </q><bibl n="Nassau"></bibl></cit> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Late Northern papers.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="369"/> --A new arrival of Northern papers this (<dateStruct><day type="name">Thursday</day></dateStruct>) morning, of the very <hi rend="italics">latest</hi> dates, containing all the news of operations about <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName>, at the <rs>Confederate Reading Room</rs>; <num value="2">two</num> late London Papers; <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> Pictorials.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="370"/>Also, all the city and Southern papers. </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="announcements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="death" n="1"> 
<head>Died.</head> 
<div4 type="obit" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="371"/> On <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time>, <dateStruct value="--9"><day reg="9">9th inst.</day></dateStruct>, after a short Illness, <persName n="Lee,,Charles,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00252" reg="default:Lee,Charles,,,"><foreName>Charles</foreName> <surname>Lee</surname></persName>, infant <persName n="Alex,IsFather,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00253" reg="mostcommon:Alex,nomatch:0"><roleName n="IsFather">son of</roleName> <surname>Alex</surname></persName>'r A and <persName><foreName>Mollie</foreName></persName> E <persName n="White,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00254" reg="mostcommon:White,nomatch:0"><surname>White</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="372"/> The relatives and friends of the parents and of the grandfather, <persName n="Booth,Mister,Wm,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00255" reg="default:Booth,Wm,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>Wm</foreName> <surname>Booth</surname></persName>, are invited to attend the funeral this forenoon at <time value="10oclock">10 o'clock</time>, from their residence, on <address><street n="7 Street">7th street</street></address>, adjoining the <rs type="place">City Spring</rs> enclosure. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="373"/> At his residence, in <placeName reg="Manchester, Manchester, England" key="tgn,7010477">Manchester</placeName>, on <dateStruct value="1863-06-10"><day type="name">Wednesday</day>, <month reg="06">June</month> <day reg="10">10th</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="374"/>at <time value="7:5am">7&#x00BD; o'clock A. M.</time>, <persName><foreName>Samuel</foreName></persName> B <persName n="Wells,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00256" reg="mostcommon:Wells,nomatch:0"><surname>Wells</surname></persName>, in the <num value="49" type="ordinal">49th</num> year of his age. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="375"/> His funeral will take place this evening at <time value="4oclock">4 o'clock</time>, from the M E Church.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="376"/>The friends and acquaintances of the family are respectfully invited to attend without further notice. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="377"/> <placeName reg="Petersburg, Petersburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7014404">Petersburg</placeName> papers please copy. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="378"/> In this city, on the <dateStruct value="--9"><day reg="9">9th inst.</day></dateStruct>, M L <persName n="Stratton,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00257" reg="nearbymention:Stratton,M.,L.,,"><surname>Stratton</surname></persName>, late <rs type="role" reg="Auditor">Auditor</rs> of the city of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, in the <num value="61" type="ordinal">61st</num> year of his age. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="379"/> The friends and acquaintances of the family are respectfully invited to attend his funeral to day, (<dateStruct><day type="name">Thursday</day></dateStruct>,) at <time value="11am">11 o'clock A. M.</time>, from the <orgName n="Baptist Church 2" type="church">2d Baptist Church</orgName>, without farther notice. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="380"/> At the residence of her son-in-law, Jacob Holder <persName n="Fynn,Mrs.,Elizabeth,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00258" reg="default:Fynn,Elizabeth,,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <foreName>Elizabeth</foreName> <surname>Fynn</surname></persName>, aged <measure n="70years" type="date">70 years</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="381"/> Her funeral will take place on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> <time>morning</time>, at <time value="10oclock">10 o'clock</time>, to which her friends and the acquaintances of the family are invited to attend. * </p> </div4> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="special"> 
<head>Special notices.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="382"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="musical"> 
<head><rs n="musical instruments" type="product">Musical instruments</rs>.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="salt"> 
<head>Salt Distribution.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="383"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="substitute"> 
<head>Substitute notices.</head> 
<div3 type="orders" n="1"> 
<head type="nobreak">Substitute Wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="384"/> --For a men over <measure n="45years" type="date">45 years</measure> of age--<num value="1">one</num> who can come well recommended &mdash; I will pay a good price.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="385"/>Call at <persName><foreName>Robert</foreName></persName> A E <persName n="Dabney,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00259" reg="mostcommon:Dabney,nomatch:0"><surname>Dabney</surname></persName>'s store, corner of Broad and <num value="7" type="ordinal">7th</num> sts, from <num value="8">8</num> to <time value="12oclock">12 o'clock</time>. Inquire for &#x0022;A. B.&#x0022; I wish, also, to buy a good, gentle Buggy Horse. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="386"/> <term type="printrun">je 11--4t*</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="2"> 
<head type="nobreak">Substitute Wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="387"/> --To serve in <orgName n="company"><persName n="Jones,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00260" reg="mostcommon:Jones,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Capt.</roleName> <surname>Jones</surname></persName>'s company</orgName>, <num value="12" type="ordinal">12th</num> Regt Va Vols, during the war. For <num value="1">one</num> over <measure n="45years" type="date">45 years</measure> of age a good price will be paid.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="388"/>Apply on <address><street n="10 Street">10th st</street></address>, between <address><street n="Main street">Main</street></address> and <address><street n="Cary street">Cary</street></address>, to <hi rend="smallcaps"><rs type="role">Dr.</rs></hi> E <persName n="Powel,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00261" reg="mostcommon:Powel,nomatch:0"><surname>Powel</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="389"/> <term type="printrun">je 11--1t*</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="3"> 
<head type="nobreak">Substitute Wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="390"/> --For a man over <measure n="45years" type="date">45 years</measure> of age, with good recommendations, a very liberal price will be paid.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="391"/>Apply immediately at. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="James,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00262" reg="mostcommon:James,nomatch:0"><surname>James</surname></persName> T <persName n="Butler,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00263" reg="mostcommon:Butler,nomatch:0"><surname>Butler</surname></persName></signed> &#x0026; Co's, <lb/> <address><street n="Cary street">Cary street</street></address>, below <address><street n="Pearl street">Pearl</street></address>. <term type="printrun">je 11--5t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="4"> 
<head type="nobreak">Substitute Wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="392"/> --For an acceptable man a liberal price will be paid.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="393"/>Call at room <num value="5">No. 5</num> <placeName reg="Linwood House">Linwood House</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="394"/> <term type="printrun">je 11--1t*</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="5"> 
<head type="nobreak">Substitute Wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="395"/> --<measure n="2500dollars" type="currency">$2,500</measure> will be paid for a Substitute to go in a Louisiana regiment, now near <placeName reg="Fredericksburg, Fredericksburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013943">Hamilton's Crossing</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="396"/>Address &#x0022;T L M,&#x0022; <orgName n="Post Office" type="office">Post Office</orgName> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Va.</placeName> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="397"/> <term type="printrun">je 10--5t*</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="6"> 
<head type="nobreak">Substitute Wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="398"/> --For a man over <measure n="45years" type="date">45 years</measure> old, who brings recommendations of good character, I will give <measure n="2000dollars" type="currency">$2,000</measure> to take my place in a stationed battery at <placeName reg="Chaffin's Bluff">Chaffin's Bluff</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="399"/>Apply to </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Jennings,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00264" reg="mostcommon:Jennings,nomatch:0"><surname>Jennings</surname></persName> M Love,</signed> <lb/> <orgName n="Battery"><persName n="Allen,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00265" reg="mostcommon:Allen,nomatch:0"><surname>Allen</surname></persName>'s Battery</orgName>, <placeName reg="Chaffin's Bluff">Chaffin's Bluff</placeName>. <term type="printrun">je 5--5t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="7"> 
<head type="nobreak">Substitute Wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="400"/> --For an acceptable man a liberal price will be paid.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="401"/>Apply to </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Kent,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00266" reg="mostcommon:Kent,nomatch:0"><surname>Kent</surname></persName>, <persName n="Paine,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00267" reg="mostcommon:Paine,nomatch:0"><surname>Paine</surname></persName></signed> &#x0026; Co. <term type="printrun">je 2--ts.</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="402"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="3"/> 
<div2 type="amusements"> 
<head>Amusements.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="403"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="personal"> 
<head>Personal.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="404"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="13"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="14"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="15"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="16"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="17"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="4"/> 
<div2 type="wants"> 
<head>Wants.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="405"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="13"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="announcements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head type="nobreak">Wanted</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="406"/> --<num value="5">Five</num> or <num value="6">six</num> Hands, (<rs type="color">white</rs> or <rs type="color">colored</rs>) to work at <placeName reg="Hollywood Cemetery">Hollywood Cemetery</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="407"/>Apply immediately to </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="O'Keefer,,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00268" reg="default:O'Keefer,James,,,"><foreName>James</foreName>  <surname>O'Keefer</surname></persName>,</signed> <rs type="role">Sup't.</rs> <term type="printrun">je 8--3t*</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="lost"> 
<head>Lost, Strayed, &#x0026;c.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="408"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="13"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="14"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="15"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="16"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="17"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="18"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="19"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="20"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="21"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="22"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="23"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="5"/> 
<div2 type="auction"> 
<head><rs n="auction sales" type="product">Auction Sales</rs>--Future days.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="409"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="announcements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head type="nobreak"><rs type="role2">Commissioner</rs>'s Sale of Negroes.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="410"/> --<unclear></unclear> to a <unclear></unclear> entered by the <orgName n="Circuit Court" type="court">Circuit Court</orgName> of the city of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> on the <dateStruct value="1863-05-21"><day reg="21">21st</day> of <month reg="05">May</month>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct> in the suit of <persName n="Moore,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00269" reg="mostcommon:Moore,James,,,:1"><surname>Moore</surname></persName> and wife vs. <persName n="Newman,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00270" reg="mostcommon:Newman,nomatch:0"><surname>Newman</surname></persName>'s administrator and <unclear></unclear>, I shall on <date>Friday</date>, the <dateStruct value="1863-06-12"><day reg="12">12th</day> day of <month reg="06">June</month>, <year>1863</year>,</dateStruct> at <time value="10oclock">10 o'clock</time>, at the auction room of <orgName><persName n="Dickinson,,Hill,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00271" reg="default:Dickinson,Hill,,,"><foreName>Hill</foreName> <surname>Dickinson</surname></persName> &#x0026; Co.</orgName> In the city of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, said at public auction, to the highest bidder, for cash the slaves <rs>Armistead</rs> and <rs>John</rs>, the <num value="2">two</num> negro men in the proceedings mentioned. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Moore,,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00272" reg="default:Moore,James,,,"><foreName>James</foreName>  <surname>Moore</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <rs type="role" reg="Special-Commissioner">Special Commissioner</rs>. <term type="printrun">je 10--3t*</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="rent"> 
<head>For Rent and Sale.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="411"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="horses"> 
<head>Horses, &#x0026;c., for Sale.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="412"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="boarding"> 
<head>Boarding.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="413"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="6"/> 
<div2 type="auction"> 
<head><rs n="auction sales" type="product">Auction Sales</rs>--Future days.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="414"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="7"/> 
<div2 type="auction"> 
<head><rs n="auction sales" type="product">Auction Sales</rs>--this day.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="415"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="military"> 
<head>Military notices.</head> 
<div3 type="orders" n="1"> 
<head type="nobreak">Attention Marylanders.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="416"/> --Every consideration of pride and interest urges you to unite for the redemption of your native State.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="417"/>An opportunity now offers to enter a favorite branch of the service, with many substantial advantages, and under your own banner.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="418"/>A <hi rend="smallcaps">cavalry</hi> Company is being formed to join the <orgName type="regiment" key="1MDCav">1st Maryland Cavalry</orgName>, under command of <persName n="Brown,Major,Ridgley,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00273" reg="default:Brown,Ridgley,,,"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <foreName>Ridgley</foreName> <surname>Brown</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="419"/>Horses and equipments furnished immediately, and active service entered without delay.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="420"/>Those serving in regiments from other States can be transferred, and to those wishing to enter the service a better opportunity can hardly occur.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="421"/>For further particulars apply at <rs n="Room 5">Room No. 5</rs>, <placeName reg="St Charles Hotel">St Charles Hotel</placeName>, corner of <address><street n="Main Street">Main</street></address> and <address><street n="15 Street">15th streets</street></address>. </p> <closer> <signed>A F <persName n="Schwartz,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00274" reg="mostcommon:Schwartz,nomatch:0"><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <signed>S G <persName n="Bonn,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00275" reg="mostcommon:Bonn,nomatch:0"><surname>Bonn</surname></persName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed><unclear>Cirving</unclear> <persName n="Ditty,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00276" reg="mostcommon:Ditty,nomatch:0"><surname>Ditty</surname></persName>.</signed> <lb/> <signed>F C <persName n="Slingluff,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00277" reg="mostcommon:Slingluff,nomatch:0"><surname>Slingluff</surname></persName>.</signed> <term type="printrun">ts 9--d20t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="2"> 
<head type="nobreak">Address to Marylanders.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="422"/> --<persName n="Trimble,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00278" reg="mostcommon:Trimble,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Trimble</surname></persName> has issued the following orders: </p> 
<div4 type="entry" n="1"> 
<head><hi rend="smallcaps">Headq'rs <orgName n="Valley district" type="district">Valley District</orgName>,</hi><lb/><dateStruct value="1863-06-03"><month reg="06">June</month> <day reg="3">3</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="423"/> <rs type="role" reg="Major-General">Major-General</rs> J E <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Trimble,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00279" reg="mostcommon:Trimble,nomatch:0"><surname>Trimble</surname></persName></hi> having been assigned to the command of the <orgName n="Valley district" type="district">Valley District</orgName> of the <orgName n="Department of Northern Virginia" type="department">department of Northern Virginia</orgName> invites all citizens of <placeName reg="Maryland" key="tgn,7007516">Maryland</placeName>, in or out of the army, to join the <rs>Maryland</rs> troops now serving in this district, with a view to increase the organization from that State to a body formidable by its numbers and gallantry. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="424"/> Under this command every <persName n="Marylander,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00280" reg="mostcommon:Marylander,nomatch:0"><surname>Marylander</surname></persName> will have a field for the display of that devotion and bravery in the cause of the <rs>South</rs> which it is well known they possess, but which have heretofore been such obscured by their separation into almost every brigade of the army. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="425"/> Marylanders should bear in mind that upon themselves must rest the honor and renown of bringing their State into the <orgName n="Southern Confederacy" type="newspaper">Southern Confederacy</orgName>, and of avenging the wrongs inflicted upon her sons and daughters by the <name>Goths</name> and Vandals of the <rs>North</rs>, who, true to the instincts of their race, have done more outrage to the feelings of humanity, to <name>Christian</name> civilization, and to <name>Christian</name> freedom, than any nation of this enlightened age. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="426"/> Let us hope the day is near when, as Marylanders, we may do our part to avenge these wrongs. </p> <closer> By order. <lb/> <persName n="Trimble,Major-General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00281" reg="mostcommon:Trimble,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major-General">Major-General</roleName> <surname>Trimble</surname></persName>. <lb/> <signed>W <placeName reg="Carvel Hall">Carvel Hall</placeName>,</signed> A A <rs type="role">Gen.</rs> <term type="printrun">je 8--6t*</term> </closer> </div4> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="runaways"> 
<head>Runaways.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head type="nobreak"><measure n="200dollars" type="currency">Two hundred dollars</measure> reward.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="427"/> --The above reward will be paid for the arrest and delivery to me (or delivery in any jail, so that I may get them,) of my <num value="2">two</num> negro boys, <persName><foreName>George</foreName></persName> and <persName><foreName>Stephen</foreName></persName> who left my place in <placeName reg="Halifax, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002166">Halifax county, Va.</placeName> on <dateStruct value="--2"><day type="name">Tuesday</day>, <day reg="2">2d inst.</day></dateStruct> <persName><foreName>George</foreName></persName> is about <measure n="20years" type="date">twenty years</measure> of age, <measure n="5feet" type="distance">5 feet</measure> <num value="7">7</num> or <measure n="8inches" type="distance">8 inches</measure> high, black, well formed, large nose, and pleasant countenances.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="428"/><persName><foreName>Stephen</foreName></persName> is about <measure n="5feet" type="distance">5 feet</measure> <measure n="2inches" type="distance">2 inches</measure> high, dark copper color, very short legs, and long bodied for his height; moves well, and is about <num value="19">nineteen</num> or <measure n="20years" type="date">twenty years</measure> of age. They were purchased from <placeName reg="Sussex, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,1002935">Sussex</placeName> and <placeName key="tgn,1002911" n="1.000 7" reg="southampton, virginia, united states">Southampton counties</placeName> and may try to make their way to those places.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="429"/><measure n="100dollars" type="currency">One hundred dollars</measure> each will be paid for their apprehension and delivery as above stated. </p> <closer> <signed>T H <persName n="Hambleton,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00282" reg="mostcommon:Hambleton,nomatch:0"><surname>Hambleton</surname>, <genName n="junior">Jr.</genName></persName>,</signed> <lb/> Box <num value="979">979</num> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> P. O. <lb/> Or, <placeName reg="Wolf Trap Depot">Wolf Trap Depot</placeName>, <placeName reg="Halifax, Halifax, Virginia" key="tgn,2112076">Halifax</placeName> co. <term type="printrun">je 11--6t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head type="nobreak">Runaway.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="430"/> --From the subscriber, in <persName n="Fluvanna,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00283" reg="mostcommon:Fluvanna,nomatch:0"><surname>Fluvanna</surname></persName> co, Va. on the <dateStruct value="-05-29"><day reg="29">29th</day> of <month reg="05">May</month></dateStruct> last, my man Morns.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="431"/>He is near <measure n="5feet" type="distance">5 feet</measure> high, black, rather slender, but large bone; <num value="1">one</num> eye out, the right I believe; knock kneed and turned somewhat to <num value="1">one</num> side, scar on arm between elbow and shoulder, cut by a knife; coarse voice; had on jeans <rs n="sack coat" type="product">sack coat</rs> and mixed uniform pants.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="432"/>He may endeavor to pass as free and gone off with soldiers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="433"/>I will give <unclear><num value="00">00</num></unclear> if taken out of the <rs>State</rs>, or <measure n="50dollars" type="currency">$50</measure> in the <rs>State</rs>; or <unclear><measure n="5dollars" type="currency">$5</measure></unclear> if taken in <persName n="Fluvanna,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00284" reg="mostcommon:Fluvanna,nomatch:0"><surname>Fluvanna</surname></persName>, or any adjoining country to it. In either case to be delivered to me, or placed in jail so that I get him. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Geo,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00285" reg="mostcommon:Geo,nomatch:0"><surname>Geo</surname></persName> W <persName n="Pettit,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00286" reg="mostcommon:Pettit,nomatch:0"><surname>Pettit</surname></persName>,</signed> <placeName reg="Dists Post-Office">Dists P. O.,</placeName> <lb/> Fluvanna Va. <term type="printrun">je 11--6t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head type="nobreak">Ran away--<measure n="25dollars" type="currency">$25</measure> reward.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="434"/> --Ran away from my house, on the <dateStruct value="--9"><day reg="9">9th inst.</day></dateStruct>, a negro boy named <persName><foreName>James</foreName></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="435"/>Said negro was hired to me from <persName n="Wm,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00287" reg="mostcommon:Wm,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Wm</surname></persName> W <persName n="Sledd,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00288" reg="mostcommon:Sledd,nomatch:0"><surname>Sledd</surname></persName>, and I have no doubt but that he is making his way to his farm in <placeName reg="Hanover, Hanover, Virginia" key="tgn,2112147">Hanover</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="436"/>Said negro is about <measure n="5feet" type="distance">5 feet</measure> <measure n="11inches" type="distance">11 inches</measure> high, bright mulatto, downcast look, and speaks very quick when spoken to I will pay the above reward and all expenses for his delivery to me at the <rs type="place">New Market</rs>, <rs n="Stall 20">Stall No. 20</rs>, shed part. </p> <closer> <signed>Wm K <persName n="Sledd,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00289" reg="mostcommon:Sledd,nomatch:0"><surname>Sledd</surname></persName>.</signed> <term type="printrun">je 11--3t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head type="nobreak"><measure n="100dollars" type="currency">One hundred dollars</measure> reward.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="437"/> --Ranaway, on the <dateStruct value="-02-15"><day reg="15">15th</day> of <month reg="02">February</month></dateStruct>, a negro man named miles.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="438"/>He is about <measure n="20years" type="date">20 years</measure> old, <measure n="5feet" type="distance">5 feet</measure> <measure n="9inches" type="distance">9 inches</measure> high rather stout and square shouldered, has had the small-pox, but is not much scarred.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="439"/>He was seen in <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> a short time since, and is supposed to be in the city still.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="440"/>I will give the above reward for his apprehension and delivery to <orgName><persName n="Hill,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00290" reg="mostcommon:Hill,nomatch:0"><surname>Hill</surname></persName>, <persName n="Dickinson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00291" reg="nearbymention:Dickinson,Hill,,,"><surname>Dickinson</surname></persName> &#x0026; Co</orgName>, <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Alvis,,Ro,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00292" reg="default:Alvis,Ro,,,"><foreName>Ro</foreName>  <surname>Alvis</surname></persName>.</signed> <term type="printrun">je 11--ts</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head type="nobreak"><measure n="300dollars" type="currency">Three hundred dollars</measure> reward.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="441"/> --Left my house on the night of the <num value="6" type="ordinal">6th</num> of the present month <num value="3">three</num> Negroes: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="442"/> <persName><foreName>Jim</foreName></persName>, about <measure n="18years" type="date">18 years</measure> old, black, slow of speech, and not very well grown. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="443"/> <persName n="Ned,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00293" reg="mostcommon:Ned,nomatch:0"><surname>Ned</surname></persName>, <measure n="17years" type="date">17 years</measure> of age, of ginger-bread color, thick lips, quite intelligent, and quick spoken and polite. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="444"/> <persName n="Milton,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00294" reg="mostcommon:Milton,nomatch:0"><surname>Milton</surname></persName>, <measure n="16years" type="date">16 years</measure> old, small for his age, large eyes, sharp features and rather indifferent looking. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="445"/> I think they have gone to <persName><roleName n="King">King</roleName> <foreName>William</foreName></persName> in order to get with the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="446"/>I will pay <measure n="100dollars" type="currency">$100</measure> for each of them. </p> <closer> <signed>W L <persName n="Harrison,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00295" reg="nearbymention:Harrison,Thomas,B.,,"><surname>Harrison</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, <dateStruct value="1863-06-09"><month reg="06">June</month> <day reg="9">9</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>. <term type="printrun">je 10--4t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head type="nobreak"><measure n="100dollars" type="currency">One hundred dollars</measure> reward.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="447"/> --The above reward will be paid for the arrest of my boy <persName><foreName>George</foreName></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="448"/>Said slave is about <measure n="5feet" type="distance">5 feet</measure> <measure n="6inches" type="distance">6 inches</measure> high, mulatto, large mouth, forehead receding, gray eyes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="449"/>He lived formerly at the <unclear>Far</unclear> Hotel, in <placeName key="tgn,7013585" n="1.000 66" reg="charlottesville, charlottesville, virginia">Charlottesville</placeName>, and is supposed to be making his way to that place, where he has relatives, and was formerly owned by <persName n="Glover,Major,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00296" reg="mostcommon:Glover,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <surname>Glover</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="450"/>Any <num value="1">one</num> arresting him will please put him in the nearest jail and inform me by mail. </p> <closer> <signed>A Bodeker,</signed> <lb/> <num value="10">No. 10</num>, <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>. <term type="printrun">je 10--4t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="7"> 
<head type="nobreak"><measure n="50dollars" type="currency">Fifty dollars</measure> reward.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="451"/> --The above reward will be paid for the arrest of <persName n="Taylor,,Nelson,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00297" reg="default:Taylor,Nelson,,,"><foreName>Nelson</foreName> <surname>Taylor</surname></persName>, a free man of color.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="452"/>Said <persName n="Nelson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00298" reg="mostcommon:Nelson,nomatch:0"><surname>Nelson</surname></persName> is about <measure n="5feet" type="distance">5 feet</measure> <num value="8">8</num> or <measure n="10inches" type="distance">10 inches</measure> high, very black, and tolerably thick lips, and is between <num value="30">30</num> and <measure n="35years" type="date">35 years</measure> of age. He was living at <placeName reg="Port Mayo">Port Mayo</placeName>, below <placeName key="tgn,2625188" n="1.000 10" reg="Rocketts, Henrico, Virginia">Rocketts</placeName>, in a brick shanty belonging to <persName n="Quarles,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00299" reg="mostcommon:Quarles,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Quarles</surname></persName>--It is thought he is trying to get to <placeName reg="Charles City, Charles City, Virginia" key="tgn,2111055">Charles City</placeName> of New Kent, where his relations are living.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="453"/>Any <num value="1">one</num> arresting him will please try and bring him to <placeName key="tgn,1002467" n="1.000 27" reg="henrico, virginia">Henrico county</placeName> jail or address <persName n="Pleasants,,William,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00300" reg="default:Pleasants,William,,,"><foreName n="William">Wm.</foreName> <surname>Pleasants</surname></persName>, <persName n="Henrico,Sheriff,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00301" reg="mostcommon:Henrico,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Sheriff">Sheriff</roleName> <surname>Henrico</surname></persName> county, <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Va.</placeName> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="454"/> <term type="printrun">je 10--5t*</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="8"> 
<head type="nobreak"><measure n="30dollars" type="currency">Thirty dollars</measure> reward.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="455"/> --Will be paid for the apprehension of my woman <persName n="Maria,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00302" reg="mostcommon:Maria,nomatch:0"><surname>Maria</surname></persName>, who left my house on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Thursday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time> last.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="456"/>She is between <num value="23">23</num> and <measure n="30years" type="date">30 years</measure> old, of dark brown or ginger-bread color, of medium height, good countenance, with good front teeth, but has lost <num value="1">one</num> or <num value="2">two</num> eye teeth.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="457"/>She was seen passing up <address><street n="Cary street">Cary street</street></address>, in <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, early on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> <time>morning</time>. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Tatum,,Tero,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00303" reg="expanded:Tatum,"><foreName>Tero</foreName>  <surname>Tatum</surname></persName>.</signed> <term type="printrun">je 10--3t*</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="458"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> </body> </text> </TEI.2>
 
