<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> <!DOCTYPE TEI.2 PUBLIC "-//TEI P4//DTD Main DTD Driver File//EN" "http://www.tei-c.org/Guidelines/DTD/tei2.dtd" [ <!ENTITY % TEI.XML "INCLUDE"> <!ENTITY % PersProse PUBLIC "-//Perseus P4//DTD Perseus Prose//EN" "http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/DTD/1.0/PersProse.dtd" > %PersProse; <!NOTATION jpg SYSTEM "JPEG"> <!ENTITY NW_RichTimesD_029_082_001 SYSTEM "NW_RichTimesD_029_082_001.jpg" NDATA jpg> <!ENTITY NW_RichTimesD_029_082_002 SYSTEM "NW_RichTimesD_029_082_002.jpg" NDATA jpg> <!ENTITY NW_RichTimesD_029_082_003 SYSTEM "NW_RichTimesD_029_082_003.jpg" NDATA jpg> <!ENTITY NW_RichTimesD_029_082_004 SYSTEM "NW_RichTimesD_029_082_004.jpg" NDATA jpg> ]> <TEI.2 id="NW_RichTimesD_029_082"> <teiHeader type="aacr2"> <fileDesc> <titleStmt> <title type="245">The Daily Dispatch: December 13, 1865. </title> <title type="gmd">[Electronic resource] </title> <funder> Institute of Museum and Library Services National Leadership Grant </funder> <respStmt> <resp>creation of machine-readable version: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> <resp>creation of digital images: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> <resp>Conversion to Tei.2-conformant markup: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> </respStmt> </titleStmt> <extent>ca. <num value="30">XXX</num> kilobytes </extent> <publicationStmt> <publisher>University of <orgName n="Richmond Library" type="library">Richmond Library</orgName> </publisher> <pubPlace>Richmond, Virginia </pubPlace> <idno type="Url">Nw_richtimesd_029_082</idno> <availability> 
<p>&#x00A9; 2004 by the University of Richmond. </p> 
<p>Url: http://oncampus.Richmond.edu/academics/Library/digital/ </p> </availability> <date> </date> </publicationStmt> <seriesStmt> 
<p>Institute of Museum and Library Services Civil War Newspaper Project </p> </seriesStmt> <notesStmt> <note>page images have been included from the microfilm version. </note> <note>images were scanned with a Sunrise 2000 scanner from microfilm, at 14x reduction ratio at 400 dpi Optical resolution. Creation Software: Pixel Translations. Pixtiff version 1.135. </note> <note>Ddd note: shipped: 2005_06_10_ddd_url. </note> </notesStmt> <sourceDesc> <biblFull> <titleStmt> <title type="245">The Daily Dispatch: December 13, 1865. </title> <title type="246"><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName> </title> <respStmt> <resp> </resp> <name> </name> </respStmt> </titleStmt> <editionStmt> 
<p> </p> </editionStmt> <extent>4 pages. </extent> <publicationStmt> <publisher>by Cowardin &#x0026; Hammersley. </publisher> <pubPlace>Richmond </pubPlace> <date value="1865-12-13">December 13, 1865</date><idno type="vol">29.82</idno> </publicationStmt> <seriesStmt> <title> </title> </seriesStmt> <notesStmt> <note>microfilm. Ann Arbor, Mi : Proquest. 1 microfilm reel ; 35 mm. </note> </notesStmt> </biblFull> </sourceDesc> </fileDesc> <encodingDesc> <projectDesc> 
<p>Imls Civil War Newspaper Project. </p> </projectDesc> <editorialDecl> 
<p>the images exist as archival Tiff images, with Jpeg versions for internet access. </p> </editorialDecl> <refsDecl> <state unit="article" /> </refsDecl> <classDecl> <taxonomy id="lcsh"> <bibl> <title>Library of Congress subject Headings, </title> <edition>21st edition, 1998</edition> </bibl> </taxonomy> </classDecl> </encodingDesc> <profileDesc> <creation> <date value="1865">1865 </date> </creation> <langUsage> <language id="eng">English </language> </langUsage> 
<textClass> <keywords scheme="lcsh"> 
<list type="simple"> 
<item>Newspapers -- Virginia -- Richmond</item> </list> </keywords> </textClass> </profileDesc> <revisionDesc> <change> <date>October, 2005 </date> <respStmt> <resp>Checker </resp> <name>Grant Dickie, of the University of <orgName n="Richmond Library" type="library">Richmond Library</orgName> </name> </respStmt> 
<item>File checked, not corrected: DO NOT return to vendor. </item> </change> </revisionDesc> </teiHeader> 
<text id="NW_RichTimesD_029_082T"> <front> <milestone unit="page" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="page-image"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="1"/><figure entity="NW_RichTimesD_029_082_001"> <figDesc>Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume <num value="29">29</num>, <num value="82">Number 82</num>, <ref n="page 1">page 1</ref>. </figDesc> </figure></p> </div1> <titlePage> <docTitle><titlePart type="main"> Daily Dispatch </titlePart> </docTitle> <docImprint> Vol. Xxix &mdash; no.<num value="82">82</num> <pubPlace> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Va.</placeName> </pubPlace> <date value="1865-12-13">Wednesday, December 13, 1865</date> <persName n="Price,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00001" reg="mostcommon:Price,nomatch:0"><surname>Price</surname></persName> <num value="1">one</num> Cent </docImprint> </titlePage> 
<div1 type="subscription"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName><lb/> by <persName n="Cowardin,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00002" reg="mostcommon:Cowardin,nomatch:0"><surname>Cowardin</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="Hammersley,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00003" reg="mostcommon:Hammersley,nomatch:0"><surname>Hammersley</surname></persName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="2"/>the <rs>Daily Dispatch</rs> is served to subscribers at <num value="6.25">Six and A Quarter</num> Cents per week, payable to the <name>Carrier</name> weekly.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="3"/><persName n="Price,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00004" reg="mostcommon:Price,nomatch:0"><surname>Price</surname></persName> for mailing, <measure n="4dollars" type="currency">$4</measure> a year, or <measure n="2.50dollars" type="currency">$2.50</measure> for <measure n="6months" type="date">six months</measure>, in advance.</p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="4"/>the <rs>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</rs> is issued every <dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> and <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> at <measure n="2.00dollars" type="currency">$2.00</measure>, in advance.</p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="5"/>the <rs>Weekly Dispatch</rs> is issued every <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct>, and mailed to subscribers at <measure n="1dollars" type="currency">$1</measure> per annum.</p> </div1> 
<div1 type="advertising"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="6"/> 
<table rows="4" cols="4"> 
<head rend="italics">Terms of advertising.</head> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <num value="1">1</num> day,</cell><cell><measure n="0.50dollars" type="currency">$0.50</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="5days" type="date">5 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="1.50dollars" type="currency">$1.50</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="2days" type="date">2 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="0.75dollars" type="currency">$0.75</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="5days" type="date">5 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="1.75dollars" type="currency">$1.75</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square <measure n="3days" type="date">3 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="1.00dollars" type="currency">$1.00</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="12days" type="date">12 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="3.00dollars" type="currency">$3.00</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square <measure n="4days" type="date">4 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="1.25dollars" type="currency">$1.25</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <dateStruct value="-1-"><month reg="1">1 month</month></dateStruct>,</cell><cell><measure n="5.00dollars" type="currency">$5.00</measure></cell></row> </table></p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="7"/><hi rend="italics">Larger advertisements in exact properties.</hi></p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="8"/>Advertisements published until forbid, will be charged <measure n="50cents" type="currency">50 cents</measure> per square of <num value="8">eight</num> lines for the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> insertion, and <measure n="25cents" type="currency">25 cents</measure> for each continuance</p> </div1> </front> <body> <milestone unit="column" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.</head> 
<div2 type="wednesday"> 
<head><date value="1865-12-13">Wednesday...december 13, 1865.</date></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>The great drought.<lb/><hi rend="italics">a Thrilling story.</hi><lb/>[concluded.]<lb/>chapter <num value="5">V</num>:</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="9"/> Time passed on, and there was no change in the state of things.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="10"/>Still an unclouded sun; still the deep, intense blue sky; winds on the earth, but no moisture; and the whole frame of nature seemed crumbling into chaos.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="11"/>Paulert felt the strife with fate to be unequal indeed, and could scarcely comprehend that he and his family were truly survivors amid such destruction; but he resolved not to give in while the means remained to him, but to fight the fight out until overpowered by the material universe.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="12"/>He told <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> that they must move to more diamonds, and <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> agreed, wishing with Paulette, that the strife were over and the last agony suffered, and that they were among the free and disembodied spirits.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="13"/><placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName> was their object; for there they might hope to find most of the materials of what was now the most precious of all things &mdash; water; and, providing as well as they could for their necessities by the way, they quitted the cavern and set off on their journey. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="14"/> <num value="1" type="ordinal">First</num> came the father, carrying the little <rs>Alice</rs> in his arms; the boy held his mother by the hand, and they followed Paulette in his path.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="15"/>There was the delicate woman, the <rs type="role" reg="IsChild">mother of</rs> all that remained alive of the human race, setting out on the desert, which she remembered but a few years before the scene of luxury and abundance.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="16"/>On her shoulder she carried a burthen, containing corn for their sustenance, and the brave boy took his share by bearing the jar of water which had been provided for their support on the journey; and thus the last family of mankind set out on their pilgrimage over the desolated earth.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="17"/>The unmitigated sun had made great rents in the sides of the hills, and, together with the wind, had broken up the roads, between which and the parched fields there was scarcely now any difference.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="18"/>Where there had been enclosures and hedges, the withered sticks had, in most places, yielded to the winds, and were scattered about the spot where they had stood.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="19"/>Here and there were the marks of fire, which had run along the country till some interval of the previous desolation had stopped it; and where this had been the case, the black, unsightly remains lay strewn over the surface, <num value="1">one</num> further step advanced in dissolution than the dead world around.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="20"/>There was no want of habitations for their nightly shelter.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="21"/>Palaces and cottages, all alike, were open; all alike were silent and tenantless habitations.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="22"/>They might choose where they would.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="23"/>And the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> day they did not go far, for <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> and her children, with stout hearts, had not bodily strength for great fatigue, and were unused to the strong exertion they were now compelled to make.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="24"/>Towards evening, therefore, when they reached a house, with which Paulette and <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> had once been familiar, they determined to rest there for the night.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="25"/>They pushed open the gates, which still swing on their hinges, and which admitted them to what had been a park, filled once with trees, and bathed with waters.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="26"/>A large wood covered the hill which rose on <num value="1">one</num> side, and which now, under a summer sun, stood perfectly bare, and all of <num value="1">one</num> uniform grey color as far as the view extended.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="27"/>On the other side, the eye looked over a tract of country varied with hill and dale, but desolate of every color that used to shine forth in light and shade.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="28"/>The setting sun shone among the leafless branches, casting long brilliant rays of light.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="29"/>The unclouded sky met the sparkling earth, and both glittered with unnatural brilliancy.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="30"/>To Paulette and <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> everything spoke of desolation and death; and an exclamation escaped <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>, in a low tone, that it was a piteous and horrible spectacle.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="31"/>But <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName>, standing still at their side as they looked on the scene, cried, it was beautiful &mdash; the colors of the sun were so splendid on the fine while trees, and <num value="1">one</num> could see so far, and everything was so white and shining on the earth.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="32"/>The parents felt that ideas were ceasing to be in common between the last and the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> members of the old and the new generation; and, far from contradicting their boy, they tried to partake his pleasure and enter into his impressions.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="33"/>They moved on up to the old familiar door, and entered the open, silent hall, where they remembered the ceremonies and the courtesies of life.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="34"/>They chose among the rooms, which had been those of friends, and recognized familiar objects of their every-day existence.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="35"/>It was a conceit of Paulette's, for which he smiled at himself, to wind up the clock in the hall, and set it to toll out the time again for another week.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="36"/>There were <rs n="musical instruments" type="product">musical instruments</rs> in a room adjoining, and over <num value="1">one</num> of these <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> timidly passed her fingers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="37"/>It was out of tune, and the sounds, though sweet in themselves, all jarred with <num value="1">one</num> another. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="38"/> &#x0022;That's the last music of the world, perhaps,&#x0022; said <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>, &#x0022;and all discord, too&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="39"/>They found some small store of corn in <num value="1">one</num> of the rooms; they prepared and ate it, and lay down to sleep, forgetting in fatigue all their dismal feelings, and in their dreams seeing the old state of things and dead persons &mdash; nay, a dead world &mdash; without wondering that they were to come to life again.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="40"/>All the days of their journey wore an uniform character, and they kept on and on through waste and ruin, glad to leave the country behind them, and expecting as some relief the aspect of streets and a town.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="41"/>They halted, at length, within a few miles of <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName>, and lay down to rest, thankful to be so near their home; for they had suffered as much fatigue as they could well bear, and their stock of diamonds was waxing very low, and needed replenishment.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="42"/>Paulette continued busy preparing water from those that remained, after his wife and children were asleep.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="43"/>His own frame scarcely felt the exertion of the journey, and he was full of the thoughts with which the approaching sight of what had been once the great metropolis filled him. The vast untenanted dwelling place, the solitude of the habitation of crowds, the absence of mind and talent from the scene they had so filled &mdash; all these things excited his feelings, and gaining ground in the solitude of the night, he felt at last that he could not willingly delay his <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> meeting with the bereaved city, and that he should be pleased to have an opportunity of indulging alone the highly-wrought emotion with which he expected the sight of it. Accordingly, when the light began to break, he wrote word to <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> that she should wait for him a few hours, and that he would be back in that time to lead her and the children to their journey's end; and then softly leaving the house, set forward eagerly on his way. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="44"/> It was evening before he returned.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="45"/>He came in pale and excited; he took his children in his arms as usual, and seemed like <num value="1">one</num> upon whom a thing he has seen has made a deep impression.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="46"/>but who either doubts the power of words to convey the same impression, or thinks that he himself is over-excited by it. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="47"/> &#x0022;<persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>,&#x0022; he said at last, &#x0022;<placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName> is burned to the ground.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="48"/>The sudden flush on her face, and her clasped hands while she spoke not, showed that the event touched her, too, as deeply as him; and then he went on freely: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="49"/> &#x0022;Oh.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="50"/><persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> ! if you had seen it ! It stands there all in ruins &mdash; the whole city in ruins ! It has been the work of some great storm, which fired it when all were gone or dead; for there has been no pulling down, no pillage, no aid, no attempt to stop the fire ! All the palaces, all the museums, all the stores of learning and art, the streets, the crowded houses; they are gone, <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> &mdash; they are all gone!&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="51"/> His wife had never before, in all their misery, seen him so deeply moved &mdash; so nearly overpowered by anything that had occurred.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="52"/>His excitement communicated itself to her, and she caught the full bearing of his narration.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="53"/>She felt for the long ages of story, and the monuments of human skill, buried in the great city.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="54"/>Irretrievable ruin!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="55"/>The work which men and years and growing knowledge had slowly raised up, all dead, all annihilated so suddenly.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="56"/>They sat talking of it very long before <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> said-- </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="57"/> &#x0022;And what must <hi rend="italics">we</hi> do now, Paulette?&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="58"/> &#x0022;We must go on, <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>; we must travel further.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="59"/>The rest we hoped for is destroyed with the city, and we must press forward if we are to save our lives.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="60"/> &#x0022;That seems less and less possible,&#x0022; said <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>; and in all this destruction, why should we be preserved?&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="61"/> Perhaps because we have, as yet, avoided the stroke by using all our human skill; perhaps because a new race is to spring from us, who <milestone unit="column" n="2"/> shall reign in another mighty <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="62"/>Alas, <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName>!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="63"/>alas, the great city!&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="64"/> Several times during the night <rs>Ellen</rs> heard Paulette murmur to himself words of lament over the fallen city; and when he slept, his rest was agitated, and his frame seemed trembling under the emotions of the day. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="65"/> It was resolved that <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> should rest a little while in their present habitation before undertaking the toils of further travel.--They intended to make for the coast, sure of a dry channel to the opposite shore, and hoping to reach some of the great continental towns before their store of diamonds should be utterly exhausted.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="66"/>In the meantime <rs>Panlett</rs> was bent upon taking his boy through the ruins of <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName> and impressing upon him the memory of the place and its great events.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="67"/>So, the next day, leaving <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> and the little <rs>Alice</rs> together, he and <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName> began their pilgrimage through the mighty ruins.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="68"/>The event must have occurred very many months ago, for the ruins were perfectly cold and the winds had toppled down the walls of all the more fragile buildings, so that the streets lay in confusion over <num value="1">one</num> another, and it was impossible, except by other marks, to recognize the localities.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="69"/>Paulette and <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName> clambered over the fallen walls, and would have been bewildered among the heaps of masonry and houses shaken from their base and blackened by fire, only that over the desolate prospect they saw, and Paulette marked the bearings of <placeName key="tgn,7013947" n="1.000 10" reg="saint paul, ramsey, minnesota">St. Paul</placeName>'s, the chief part of whose dome rose high in the air, though a huge rent let the daylight through it, and threatened a speedy fall.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="70"/>There was here and there a spire rising perfect over the ruins; there were remains of <placeName reg="Whitehall, London, Greater London" key="tgn,7011807">Whitehall</placeName>, strong though blackened, seen over a long view of prostrate streets; and in the distance beyond, fragments of <persName n="Abbey,,Westminster,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00005" reg="default:Abbey,Westminster,,,"><foreName>Westminster</foreName> <surname>Abbey</surname></persName> showed themselves in the sunlight, though defaced and crumbled as if the frame had been too ancient to resist the fire.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="71"/>Guided by these landmarks, Paulette traced out the plan of the city, and by degrees recognized where the great streets had run, where the palaces had stood, where the river had flowed-- and all was silent, all an absolute stillness, where there had been such ceaseless voices and sounds of life.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="72"/>The libraries were burned, the statues calcined, the museums in ashes; the mind of man, which triumphs over the body, had here been subdued by matter, and left no trace of itself. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="73"/> &#x0022;Oh ! <placeName reg="Greater London" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName>, <placeName reg="Greater London" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName> ! So much talent, so much glory and beauty; such mighty hearts, such mighty works; such ages of story,--all buried in <num value="1">one</num> black mass!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="74"/>Piteous spectacle! &#x0022; cried Paulette, striking his breast and stretching forth his arms over the skeleton of what was once a sovereign in the world. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="75"/> He took his son by the hand and led him over the confused masses, telling him as they went along what were the ruins by which they passed. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="76"/> &#x0022;This great heap of buildings which has fallen into the square must be the palace of our kings.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="77"/>It is that <placeName key="tgn,2060347" n="1.000 2" reg="saint james, phelps, missouri">St. James</placeName>'s where they dwelt till nobler buildings rose with the improving times.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="78"/>See here, <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName>, there is less ruin here.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="79"/>This open space was park and garden; and time has been that I have heard the buzz of men filling all this place when the sovereigns came to hold their courts in that building.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="80"/>I think that this dreadful fire must have taken place before life was quite extinct; for, see, there are heaps of bones here, as though men had fled together to avoid it; and it either overtook them with long tongues of fire, such as a burning city would send forth, or smothered them, before they could escape, with its smoke.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="81"/>Ha ! I see almost a palace there &mdash; a wonder of modern art. It is the house I once saw, and only once, for it was built during the years of the great drought.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="82"/> &#x0022;Who could build in those days, father?&#x0022; said <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName>. &#x0022;I thought no <num value="1">one</num> had any heart for doing more than we do, and that is but just keeping ourselves alive.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="83"/> &#x0022;Nay, it was very long before the persuasion came that those were the last days.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="84"/>We all believed that rain would come again and restore the earth to its old order, and whoever possessed the means, builded and projected still.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="85"/>You may see this magnificent place suffered violence before the fire, for its ornaments are torn from the walls, and its statues mutilated by other means than the bare fall.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="86"/>It was the property of a man called Jephcot, who, when the water began to fail, contrived means to bring it into <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName> from great distances, and thus to secure a supply when the ordinary means were useless.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="87"/>He kept his contrivance secret, and supplied the city when other men's resources were exhausted, and he grew exceedingly rich by this exercise of his ingenuity, and built himself the palace which you see there.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="88"/>But when the failure of water amounted to absolute famine, the rich people naturally were the last who wanted; they gave his price, and he supplied them before he would supply others who had no money to bring.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="89"/>This was endured with murmurs, which might have gone on a little longer had not Jephcot, in the midst of their distress, given a banquet to the great people of <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="90"/> It was in the <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> year of the drought, when, little thinking what the end was to be, we all continued to live, as far as possible, as we had done before.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="91"/>I was in <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName>, where the <name>Parliament</name> was then sitting, and, among others, I was invited to this house; and still remember the scene of luxury and profusion of these bare rooms.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="92"/>In the midst of the noise of a crowded assembly, some of us heard sounds outside, which were such as you will never hear even if you live &mdash; sounds of the feet and voices of <num value="1000">thousands</num> of human beings.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="93"/>Among this tumult we began to distinguish individual voices, chiefly those of women, crying out &#x0022;Water! &#x0022; We paid little attention, and those who did, said the police and soldiers were called out and would prevent violence; but before long it was whispered that these forces, pressed by extreme want and seeing their families perishing, had joined the mob and were exciting violence.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="94"/>There fell a silence over all the assembly; every <num value="1">one</num> left the tables and gathered together to hear and to consult; and while we did so, there came an assault on the front of the house, and the voices of the populace all broke out at once into shouting.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="95"/>They were irresistible; they forced their way in, and came pouring up the staircase; they uttered cries of vengeance for imaginary wrongs, saying that the water of <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName> had been kept for the rich, and that there was an abundance for both rich and poor, and threatened the lives of Jephcot and his family even more eagerly than they demanded for water.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="96"/>He tried to address them, but they caught him down from the head of the staircase where he stood and flung him at once over the marble banisters.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="97"/>This was the signal for attack on all sides.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="98"/>We rushed forward to rescue his body and revenge him; they to possess themselves of the treasure they so much coveted.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="99"/>Of course we were overpowered, for we were <num value="1">one</num> to <num value="50">fifty</num>; and that night there fell a <num value="100">hundred</num> of the nobles of <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="100"/>The women were respected by the mob, and except <num value="1">one</num> lady who was shot accidentally, and another, who saw her son fall, and stood over him till he ceased to breathe, then fell wounded and dying herself, all escaped.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="101"/>Your mother was not there.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="102"/>When our party was quite vanquished, I found myself in the midst of the mob, bleeding to death &mdash; as I thought; but they flung me on <num value="1">one</num> side, and I recovered.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="103"/>They pulled the house to the ground after they had satiated themselves with drinking.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="104"/>And that was the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> great calamity which overthrew the government of the country.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="105"/> &#x0022;And how did that come about father?&#x0022; said <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName>, eagerly holding him by the hand and sharing his excitement. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="106"/> Paulette led him on, telling him, at <num value="1">one</num> ruined monument after another, what steps had been taken at each in the destruction of the order of things.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="107"/>They came to the dry channel of the <rs>Thames</rs>, a deep and wide trench, whose bottom showed objects that had lain there when the waters flowed above, and which once would have been as precious an now they were unregarded.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="108"/>Here was a bridge from side to side; and a little way above, stood part of the walls of a noble building, partly black with smoke, partly white with the polish and beauty of stones newly built together. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="109"/> &#x0022;These are the <rs>Houses</rs> of Parliament,&#x0022; said Paulette, the work of many years, which were to replace those burned in <dateStruct value="1834--"><year reg="1834">1834</year></dateStruct>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="110"/>See how beautiful they were, what excellent design, what exquisite finish; how strong and stable, to last for a <num value="1000">thousand</num> ages, and to crown the river which then flowed in this dusty channel.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="111"/>When matters were come almost to the worst, and there were convulsions all over the country in consequence of the famine, the queen, for the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> time, came to these houses to open the last Parliament that ever assembled.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="112"/>There were no beasts of burthen then left alive in the country; it had been found impossible to appropriate water enough to those which had been reserved in the royal stables for the <rs>Queen</rs>, surrounded by a certain number of the court, walked along yonder street to the <rs type="place">House</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="113"/>The sight of so young a woman, and so great a sovereign, thus leveled by physical necessity with the meanest, excited some of the old enthusiasm with which she used to be greeted; the <unclear></unclear> themselves, with their squalid <milestone unit="column" n="3"/> faces, and in their extreme misery, greeted her; out the greatest feeling was aroused among the nobles and gentry, who surrounded her, and who seemed to make a point of offering more nonage the less outer circumstances demanded it. There was assembled in the <rs type="place">House</rs> all that remained alive of the nobles of <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName>, and the sovereign; and they proposed to deliberate upon the possibility of any means remaining to provide water.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="114"/>But a demagogue of the people, <persName n="Matheson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00006" reg="mostcommon:Matheson,nomatch:0"><surname>Matheson</surname></persName> by name, roused their fury and their madness, and they burst in, accusing their superiors of their calamities.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="115"/>The <rs>Queen</rs>'s life was in danger; and then occurred a gallant action, which is worthy to live if man lives.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="116"/>A Churchill, a descendant of that <placeName key="tgn,2050078" n="1.000 4" reg="marlborough, middlesex county, massachusetts">Marlborough</placeName> who fought <placeName key="tgn,2179859;tgn,1014594" n="0.026 000000.0511	placename;tgn,2179859;blenheim, albemarle, virginia,Albemarle,Virginia,United States,North and Central America;0.007 000000.0142	placename;tgn,1014594;blenheim,ontario,canada,north and central america,Ontario,Canada,North and Central America" reg="blenheim, albemarle, virginia,Albemarle,Virginia,United States,North and Central America;blenheim,ontario,canada,north and central america,Ontario,Canada,North and Central America">Blenheim</placeName>, came to the <rs type="place">Hall</rs> whither they had broken in, and required, in the <rs>Queen</rs>'s name, to know what they wanted.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="117"/>He meant to gain time, for other nobles had effected an exit at a private door for her, and were hurrying her away to a place of security till she could escape from <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="118"/>They answered <persName n="Churchill,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00007" reg="mostcommon:Churchill,nomatch:0"><surname>Churchill</surname></persName> that water was monopolized; that <persName n="Matheson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00008" reg="mostcommon:Matheson,nomatch:0"><surname>Matheson</surname></persName> must be minister; that they must speak to the <rs>Queen</rs> face to face, and have her hostage for the accomplishment of what they wished.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="119"/><persName n="Churchill,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00009" reg="mostcommon:Churchill,nomatch:0"><surname>Churchill</surname></persName> pretended to deliberate for an instant with some <num value="1">one</num> in the adjoining chamber, and then returning, said: If the <rs>Queen</rs> do not speak with you in <measure n="10minutes" type="date">ten minutes</measure>, you may tear me in pieces.&#x0027; Some of the mobs cried that he was saying this to give her time to escape; others said if it were so he should assuredly suffer the penalty.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="120"/><persName n="Churchill,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00010" reg="mostcommon:Churchill,nomatch:0"><surname>Churchill</surname></persName> answered nothing, only smiled; and then the majority said he could not be so foolhardy, and they would grant him the <measure n="10minutes" type="date">ten minutes</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="121"/> &#x0022;The time passed, and <persName n="Matheson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00011" reg="mostcommon:Matheson,nomatch:0"><surname>Matheson</surname></persName> eagerly cried, &#x0022;The time is gone, yet we don't see the queen.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="122"/> &#x0022;Then tear me in pieces,&#x0022; said <persName n="Churchill,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00012" reg="mostcommon:Churchill,nomatch:0"><surname>Churchill</surname></persName>; and the mob, finding their prey had escaped, did so, indeed; the gallant man falling where he stood, and not another word coming from his lips. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="123"/> &#x0022;The brave man,&#x0022; cried <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName>; &#x0022;the good man ! Were there many such brave, good men in the old world, father?&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="124"/> &#x0022;Ay, that there were,&#x0022; said Paulette, &#x0022;many a glorious <num value="1">one</num>; some known and some unknown, who did things which made <num value="1">one</num> know <num value="1">one</num>'s self &mdash; a glorious and immortal creature.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="125"/>See, there, that ruined <persName n="Abbey,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00013" reg="nearbymention:Abbey,Westminster,,,"><surname>Abbey</surname></persName> &mdash; there lay the ashes of brave and good; these are their crumbled monuments-- &#x0027;that fane where fame is a spectral resident.&#x0027; Alas, there is no fame, no name left!&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="126"/> Paulette and <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName> went down among the ruins of the <name>Abbey</name>, and there, amidst the fallen stones and broken aisles, saw monumental marbles, old known names and funeral inscriptions, contrasting strongly, by their quiet character, with the confusion around. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="127"/> &#x0022;Never forget them, <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName>,&#x0022; said Paulette. &#x0022;These are names which the world has trembled at, and which are now like to be such as those before the flood, barbarous to those who are building up a new order of things, and known merely as a barren catalogue of names.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="128"/>Yet, if you live, remember <persName><foreName>Edward</foreName></persName>, the <rs>King</rs>, here; remember the <rs>Black Prince</rs>; remember the days and heroes of <placeName reg="Elizabeth City, Pasquotank, North Carolina" key="tgn,2074494">Elizabeth</placeName>; remember the poetry and the romance of the old world.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="129"/> &#x0022;Ay, father; and I'll remember the great name of him who taught you to print, and of <persName n="Wickliffe,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00014" reg="mostcommon:Wickliffe,nomatch:0"><surname>Wickliffe</surname></persName>, the reformer, and of the man who gave you the steam engine.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="130"/> Paulette smiled and sighed; he felt that his own ideas of things heroic were as much contrasted with those of <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName> as their notions of the beautiful.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="131"/>But he thought not to stem the stream. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="132"/> &#x0022;See here,&#x0022; he said, pointing to some new monuments which, like the old, were cracked by fire; &#x0022;there were many brave and good actions done, and <num value="1">one</num> of those who did best was laid here.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="133"/>He was a clergyman &mdash; his name, Host; and during the pestilence, which came on in the <num value="4" type="ordinal">fourth</num> year, he was more like an inspired messenger of good than any mortal creature.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="134"/>You must know, <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName>, that the teachers of religion, at this time, were greatly divided among themselves, and they had led a great portion of the lay world into their disputes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="135"/><num value="1">One</num> party, in an age of reasoning, and when nothing in science was taken upon trust, gave up their reason altogether, and followed authority as blindly as they could, still, however, feeling the influence of the age; for they would argue upon the existence or non- existence of authority, and would fit it, unconsciously, each man to his conceit.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="136"/>Indeed, superstition was the disease of the age, and while the healthy part of the community employed and enjoyed the freest use of their reason, this same infirmity appeared among other people in other forms; so that some men took up the notion that the human mind might act independently of sense and see without eyes, and know intuitively what existed at a distance.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="137"/>Other parties, among professors of religion, allowed nothing in religion that they allowed daily in the evidence of other matters.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="138"/>They gave no weight to research, and thought about religious facts, and dreamed that each <num value="1">one</num> among themselves gained a kind of spiritual knowledge by inspiration.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="139"/>It was a time of conceits and quakery; but there was a better spirit abroad, of which this man, Host, was the representative.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="140"/>He began in the pestilence, and went to all houses indifferently, whether they were princes or peasants; and there was a common sense in what he did and said, a universal character in his religion, which struck men in these evil days.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="141"/>They drew nearer to each other under his influence; and I recollect this great building thronged in <num value="1">one</num> of the last months that men continued here with a congregation of all orders and all division of opinion, who met to pray together and listen to Host.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="142"/>He stood yonder, <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName>; as nearly there, I think, as I can tell from the ruins; he was rapt by his own discourse, and his face was as the face of an angel.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="143"/>And, truly, <measure n="3days" type="date">three days</measure> after, he was dead; and here they buried him &mdash; the last sound of the organ, the last service of this church, being for him. Here is his name still on the tombstone. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="144"/> &#x0022;<hi rend="smallcaps">Host.</hi> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="145"/> <persName><foreName>Pio</foreName></persName> dilecto beato. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="146"/> Populus miserrimus.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="147"/> <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName>'s memory was deeply impressed with this history, and he followed his father, much engrossed and animated by what he had heard.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="148"/>Not so Paulette; for the ruins of <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName> occupied his mind, and filled him with deep pity and regret for the fair world destroyed; and so they returned to their temporary habitation &mdash; the father sorrowful, the son exulting; <num value="1">one</num> full of the old world, <num value="1">one</num> dreaming great actions for the new. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="149"/> After another day's rest the sole surviving family of mankind set forth again on their pilgrimage.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="150"/>Paulette again carried his <persName><foreName>Alice</foreName></persName>, and <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> and <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName> walked hand in hand with such a basket of necessaries as they could support.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="151"/>Paulette secured about his person a large packet of diamonds, collected in palaces and noble dwellings near <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName>, and the apparatus he required for transmuting them into water; and searching for and finding the remains of the railroad to the coast at Hover, they kept on in that track, which, from its evenness, offered facility to their journey.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="152"/>But in several places it had been purposely broken up during the commotions which proceeded the final triumph of the drought, and the tunnel near <placeName key="tgn,7011556" n="1.000 2" reg="folkestone,kent,england,united kingdom,europe">Folkestone</placeName> had fallen in the middle from want of the necessary attention to the masonry.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="153"/>These difficulties seemed harder to bear than those which they had met with in the beginning of their pilgrimage, when their hopes of reaching a certain bourne were more secure.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="154"/>The destruction of <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName> had thrown a deep gloom over all their expectations; and besides, that help was removed to a much greater distance, they could not but feel it very probable that a similar fate might have befallen the other places they looked to. Nevertheless, none of them murmured.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="155"/>They went steadfastly though sadly on; and the <num value="2">two</num> children, with less knowledge of what was to be feared, were encouraged by their parents whenever they broke into a merrier strain.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="156"/><persName><foreName>Alice</foreName></persName> was the happiest of the party, for she knew least.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="157"/>She was the <num value="1">one</num> who suffered least, also; for every <num value="1">one</num> spared her suffering and contrived that what remained on earth of luxury should be hers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="158"/>She had the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> draught of water; she was carried on her father's shoulders; she ran to find pebbles and whatever shone and glittered on their path; and when the others were silent, they heard with joy her infant voice singing without words, like a bird, in a covered <unclear> </unclear> they got wearily over mile by mile <unclear></unclear> way. <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> suffered most, though Paulette tried, by all means that remained, to lightener fatigue and cheer her spirit.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="159"/>She bore up steadfastly, but her frame was slight and her feelings were oppressed by the fearful aspect of things around her. They made a deeper impression, and she was fain to look steadfastly on the faces of the few living to recover from the effects of such universal death. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="160"/> Panlett himself was shaken more than he knew, though he was as energetic as ever; but <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName> was vigorous, and advanced beyond his years, and took more than his share in aiding and in comforting.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="161"/>They came at last to what had been sea coast, and to that <milestone unit="column" n="4"/> part of the road which ran along the face of the cliff overlooking the sea; and here they paused and gazed upon the strange and wild view before them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="162"/>Where the sea had stretched all glorious in motion, expanse and color, there was now a deep valley, the bottom of which was rough with rocks, black for the most part, but in places glittering with the white salt from which the water had evaporated and which the winds had rolled together.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="163"/>Further out from the coast, where the sea had been deepest, there seemed tracks of sand; and far away over this newly exposed desert rose other hills, clearly seen through the unclouded atmosphere, and which they knew to be the rocks of <placeName key="tgn,1000070" n="1.000 1012" reg="france">France</placeName>, and if they should arrive there, what was the hope they offered?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="164"/>Scarce any &mdash; nothing but more pilgrimage.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="165"/>Further wandering, Paulette and <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> sat apart while the children lay sleeping, side by side, for an hour or <num value="2">two</num>, at this point of their journey, and talked over the desolation before them. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="166"/> &#x0022;Yet, &#x0022; said Paulette, &#x0022;the more terrible is the appearance which material things put on, the greater I feel the triumph of the spirit to be. The worse it looks, the more immortal I feel; and when a perishing world shows itself most perishable, I exult most that you and I, <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>, have borne it so far.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="167"/> &#x0022;Yes, I am glad too,&#x0022; said <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>; &#x0022;your strength strengthens me. In the midst of this desolation the mind rises, for an hour an least, higher, perhaps, than it would have ever done if we had been prosperous.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="168"/> &#x0022;Yet we might have used our prosperity to the same good end,&#x0022; said Paulette. &#x0022;It is not necessary to be miserable in order to be noble.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="169"/><num value="1000000">Millions</num> have died before us &mdash; some in agony, some before the struggle began; some hardly, some at ease; they had all their chances; all had their occasions of virtue, if they used them, and some used them, some failed; ours is not over yet; we have to struggle on still; and let us do it, dear <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>, and be ready for the good day when we, too, may be allowed to die.&#x0022; And thus talking for a while, they rested themselves in sight of the desert they had to traverse; then, with renewed strength and steadfast resolution, when the children woke, descended the cliffs, and prepared to trace out a path through what had been the bottom of the sea. The <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> part of the journey was infinitely difficult; the rocks over which the foot of man had never passed; the abrupt precipices over which had flowed the even surface of the ocean, and then the height to climb again, again to find themselves on ledges and shelves of rock; all these seemed at times hardly passable impediments.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="170"/>And when they got to a distance from what had been the shore, the unnatural place where they found them-selves pressed upon the imagination.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="171"/>There was a plain of sand, about which, at irregular distances, rose rocks, which, <name>north</name> and <name>south</name>, stretched out beyond the reach of the eye; and this sand, which had been at such a depth that it never felt the influence of the waves, was covered in places with shells, the inhabitants of which had perished when the waters gradually died away.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="172"/>There lay mixed with these some skeletons of fishes; here a huge heap and there small bones, which looked less terrible; and masses of sea weed, dried and colorless, under which, as it seemed, the creeping things of the ocean had sheltered for a while, and some had crawled to the surface when about to perish.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="173"/>But it was not only the brute creation which had died here; there was in the middle a pile of rocks, on <num value="1">one</num> side of which they came suddenly to a pit, so deep and dark that they perceived no bottom; and here probably there had been sea-water longer than elsewhere, for there were human bones about it, and skulls of men, and human garbs, which the sun had faded, but which were not disturbed by waves.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="174"/>There was a cord and a metal jar attached to it, for lowering into the pit; but Paulette, as he looked at the attitudes of the remaining skeletons, and observed how they seemed distorted in death, fancied that they must have brought up either poisoned water, or waters so intensely salt as to drive them mad with the additional thirst; and that some had died on the instant, some had lingered, some had sought to succor others, and yielded, sooner or later, to the same influence.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="175"/><persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> and he would not dwell on the sight after the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> contemplation of it; they passed on, shuddering, and made toward the great wall of rock which they saw rising to the south, and which must be their way to the land of <placeName key="tgn,1000070" n="1.000 1012" reg="france">France</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="176"/>But before they reached it, the sun began to decline; and without light it was in vain to attempt to seek a path.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="177"/>There was a wind, keener than they had felt of late, which came from the west, and the little <rs>Alice</rs> pressed on her father's bosom to shield her from it. He wrapped her closer in a cloak, and they resolved to put themselves under the shelter of the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> rock they reached, and pass the night in the channel of the sea. They pressed on, and found, at last, the place they sought &mdash; a cliff, which must once have raised its head above the waves, and which now stood like some vast palace wall, bare and huge, upon the ocean sand.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="178"/>Screened from the wind, they collected an abundance of the dried vegetation of the sea, partly for warmth and to roast their corn, partly for Paulette to dissolve some of the diamonds into water; and here they rested, here they slept, many fathoms below that level over which navies used to sail.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="179"/>At times during the night <rs>Paulette</rs> fancied, when the wind abated, that he heard a sound like thunder, or like what used to be the rushing of a distant torrent; and occasionally he thought he felt a vibration in the earth, as if it were shaken by some moving body.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="180"/>The region he was in was so strange that he knew not what might be here or what about to happen; the sounds so imperfect that he tormented himself to be sure of them, or to be sure they were not; and when the time for action came he was beginning to disbelieve them altogether; but <persName><foreName>Alice</foreName></persName> brought all back again by saying: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="181"/> &#x0022;My rock&#x0022; (for her cradle was a rock) &#x0022;shook my head, father.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="182"/>The child could explain herself no further; but the vibration he had fancied seemed to be what she had felt.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="183"/>And now they climbed again and again descended, weary, rock after rock; it was a strange chaos, which the tides had swept and moulded, and which had, in places, risen to the surface and caused the wreck of many a vessel.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="184"/>Fragments of these lay under the rock they had split upon, but the wandering family had no thoughts for them; wonder and pity had been exhausted among exciting and terrific scenes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="185"/>They thought only of forcing their way over the rocks; and feared to think how much of this they had to traverse before they should come to what had been the shore and to towns. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="186"/> Suddenly, as they toiled forward, Paulette said in a low voice to <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>, &#x0022;Don't you hear it?&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="187"/> &#x0022;I have heard it a long time,&#x0022; said <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>, in the same tone; and <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName>, as well as, said, &#x0022;Father, what is that?&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="188"/> &#x0022;I can't tell, my boy,&#x0022; said Paulette, listening. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="189"/> &#x0022;Water?&#x0022; asked <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="190"/> Paulette shook his head, yet they all pressed forward, and there grew a thundering, sullen sound.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="191"/>There was a valley and a ridge of rock before them, and they had to clamber <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> down the rugged precipice they were upon, then to cross the valley, and then to struggle up the opposite side &mdash; a trembling motion growing perceptible as they advanced &mdash; before they stood on a sort of a broad ledge, which they perceived at the angles that jutted out went down straight into a depth, and opposite which was another broad table-land of rock, between which and that they were upon was a rent, wider and narrower in the various parts, and running along, as far as they could see, to right and left.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="192"/>Paulette rushed on to the brink, and stood looking.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="193"/>He put his hand out to keep <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> back, when he heard her close behind; but she also sprang to the edge, and when she had seen, turned to catch <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName> in her arms.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="194"/>Rushing past was a torrent, but not water.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="195"/>It was dark, thick, pitchy; it sent up hot streams to the edge; it was <num value="1">one</num> of the secrets of nature, laid bare when the ocean was taken away.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="196"/>Fire seemed to be at work below, for occasionally it would boil with more violence, and rushed on with an increased, increasing noise, then sullenly fall back to the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> gloomy sound.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="197"/>It bewildered the sense; and though it could threaten no more than death, yet it was death with so many horrors around it that the body and mind both shrank from it. How was it possible, too, to cross it?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="198"/>Yet their way lay over it, for behind was certain destruction, and before it was not yet proved impossible that they might find the element of water.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="199"/>Paulette felt that it would not do to linger on the brink; he drew his family away from the sight, and he himself went up and down to find some narrower place, and some means by which to make a bridge over the abyss; and it was not till their assistance could avail him that he returned for them and brought them to the place where he hoped to get over.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="200"/>It was a fearful point, for in order to reach a space narrow enough to have a chance of throwing a plank over, it was necessary to go down the broken side of the precipice <milestone unit="column" n="5"/> some <measure n="20feet" type="distance">twenty feet</measure>, and there, high above the seething lava, to cross on such a piece of wood as could be got to span the abyss, and then clamber up the rugged opposite side.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="201"/>Paulette had been down to the point he selected, and had got timber, which a wrecked vessel had supplied, to the edge, so that <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> and <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName> might push a plank down to him, and he might try, at least, to cast it to the opposite bank.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="202"/>His head was steady, his hand strong.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="203"/>No <num value="1">one</num> of them spoke a word while he stood below, steadying himself to receive the plank.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="204"/><persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>'s weak arm grew powerful, her wit was ready with expedients to aid him in this necessity; her frame and spirit were strung to the very uttermost, and she was brave and silent, doing all that could be done.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="205"/>No word was spoken till Paulette said: &#x0022;I have done it,&#x0022; and <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> and <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName> had seen him place the plank and secure it on his own side of the abyss with stones.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="206"/>Then they held their breath, beholding him cross it; but his firm foot carried him safely, and he heaped stones on the other side also.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="207"/>He came over again, sprang up the side, and now smiled and spoke. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="208"/> &#x0022;After all, it is but a mountain torrent, <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>,&#x0022; he said, &#x0022;and the water would have destroyed us like yonder seething flood; yet, we have crossed many a <num value="1">one</num> and feared nothing.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="209"/>Now, <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName>, shall go over; then <persName><foreName>Alice</foreName></persName>, and he shall take care of her; and then my <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="210"/>The ground beyond is better; we shall get on well after this.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="211"/> <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> took the girl in her arms, and stood, not trembling, not weeping, seeing and feeling every motion; all was safe that time, again.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="212"/><persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName> was on the opposite bank, and his father waved his hand to <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="213"/>He came back for <persName><foreName>Alice</foreName></persName>, whom her mother tied on his shoulders, for hands as well as feet were wanted to scramble down and up the banks.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="214"/>And now <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> followed to the brink, and forgot, in watching her husband and child pass over, that the black torrent was seething beneath her eyes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="215"/>When they were quite safe, she felt again that it was there, and that here eyes were growing dizzy, and her hands involuntarily grasping about for support.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="216"/>She did not take time to feel more, but sprang upon the plank, and over it, and found Paulette's hand seizing hers, and drawing her up the opposite bank. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="217"/> And once there, with all <num value="3">three</num> round her, she burst into tears &mdash; tears which had not over come her through many miseries &mdash; and embracing them alternately, blessed them, that they were all so far safe.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="218"/>Paulette suffered this emotion to spend itself before he said that he must cross the plank again.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="219"/>To be more at liberty to assist them, he had left the diamonds on the other side till they should be over.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="220"/><persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> offered no remonstrance.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="221"/>The times had so schooled them all that selfish or unreasonable thoughts either did not come at all, or were suppressed at once; and she did not oppose, even with a word, this necessary step.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="222"/>But the renewal of fear after the excited energy had subsided did her more harm than all that had gone before; and she stood on the brink exhausted, yet palpitating again while Paulette made the passage.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="223"/>He himself was wearied; but he had reached the plank, and was upon it on his way back in safety, when <num value="1">one</num> of those ebullitions which stirred the dark fluid began roaring down the cleft rock, and with stunning noise sent up dark and clouding vapor.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="224"/>Paulette seemed suffocating &mdash; he could not be heard &mdash; he could just be seen &mdash; he reeled!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="225"/>Has he fallen?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="226"/>Oh! he has fallen?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="227"/>No, no!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="228"/>he has got his footing again; he forces himself up the bank; he is safe &mdash; but the diamonds are in the bottom of the pit. </p> 
<div4 type="entry" n="1"> 
<head>Chapter <num value="6">VI</num>:</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="229"/> The exhausted family toiled with difficulty over the remaining passage to what had been the main land, and reached a village on the former coast, under a roof of which they entered, and lay down on the floor of the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> room they came to. Their supply of water was almost out; the materials for producing more were gone; and there seemed little chance of finding any in the neighborhood. &#x0022;Death was here;&#x0022; and yet the exhaustion of their frames led them to sleep before they died, and to seek and enjoy a taste of that oblivion which was soon to fall upon them with an impenetrable shroud.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="230"/>All but <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> were soon asleep; but she, the most wearied of all, could not close her eyes and admit rest to her over-wrought frame.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="231"/>There was a burning thirst in her throat, which the small portion of water she and the rest had shared &mdash; being all that remained for them &mdash; had failed to slake.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="232"/>She had not complained of it; but she rejoiced when she heard them sleep, that she could rise and move restlessly about.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="233"/>The night was hot, and yet the west wind continued to blow strongly; the moon shone, but scarcely with so bright a light as usual &mdash; there was a film upon it, or, perhaps, <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> thought it was the dimness of her own weary eyes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="234"/>She came softly up to Paulette, and watched his frame, half-naked in the unconsciousness of sleep, and upon which none of the ravages of want and exertion were now concealed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="235"/>The flesh was wasted; the strong chest showed the bones of the skeleton; the arms which had so strained their powers were thin, and lay in an attitude of extreme exhaustion.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="236"/>His sleep was deep; his lips open; his eyelids blue; he would wake in want; and soon he would be able to sleep no more till the last sleep of all came in torment and anguish.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="237"/>Poor <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName> lay by him, his head on his father's body for a pillow, his limbs drawn somewhat together, his clusters of brown hair parted off his pale, thin cheek; and <persName><foreName>Alice</foreName></persName>, the darling <rs>Alice</rs>, with more color in her face than any of them, slept in deep repose, destined perhaps to live last, and to call in vain on those whose cares hitherto had kept her healthier and happier than themselves.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="238"/>The mother groaned with anguish; she measured what these were about to suffer by all she began to suffer herself, and the sight of them seemed to sear the burning eyes which could no longer weep.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="239"/>She sat down on the floor by <persName><foreName>Alice</foreName></persName>; her head fell against the wall; she caught at a little rosary which hung near her and pressed it in her month, the comparative coolness of the beads giving her a little ease.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="240"/>Her face fell on her bosom. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="241"/> When Paulette woke out of his deep sleep, and as soon as he stirred, the little <rs>Alice</rs> came on tip-toe across the floor to him, and said, &#x0022;Hush, father, my mother is asleep at last. &#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="242"/> &#x0022;At last, my <persName><foreName>Alice</foreName></persName>!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="243"/>What! Could she not sleep?&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="244"/> &#x0022;I think she could not sleep.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="245"/>I woke up, and there was my mother; and <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName> woke presently, and she said, &#x0027;<persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName>, go out and try to bring back some cold stones in a cup,&#x0027; and then presently she sat down again, and went to sleep.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="246"/> He rose softly, and taking the little girl by the hand, came up to <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>'s side, and looked upon her. She was lying at full length on the floor, her head was toward him, but her face was turned upon the ground, and her hair further hid it; her right arm was fallen forward, and the back of that hand lay in the palm of the other.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="247"/>He did not hear nor see her breathe. &#x0022;Is it so, my <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>?&#x0022; he said. &#x0022;Art thou at rest?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="248"/>Is there no farewell for me? &#x0022; He kneeled, and stooped lower and lower.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="249"/>His lip did not venture to feel hers; he longed that she might be free, yet shrank from knowing that she was gone.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="250"/>But no; she had not ceased to suffer; a low sigh came at last, and her parched mouth opened. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="251"/> &#x0022;Water!&#x0022; she said; then lifted her eyes and saw Paulette, and remembered all by degrees. &#x0022;Is not there a little?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="252"/>Oh, no &mdash; none!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="253"/>Nay, I shall not want it soon! &#x0022; She turned her face on Paulette's breast, and soon after tried to rise and push herself from him. &#x0022;Leave me, dear husband; kiss me once and leave me; try to same <hi rend="italics">them!</hi>&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="254"/> But Paulette folded his arms round her. &#x0022;Not so, my <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>; the chances of life are so little that it is lawful for me to give them up unless we can all seek them together.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="255"/>Alas! all I can do is but to see thee die!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="256"/>Oh! If I could give thee <num value="1">one</num> minute's ease!&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="257"/> &#x0022;Alas!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="258"/>you must all die like this&#x0022; said <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>, who was perishing like <num value="1">one</num> of the flowers that had died in the drought for want of rain.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="259"/>Water could have saved that life, spared those sufferings.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="260"/>That burning hand, those gasping lips, those anxious eyes, revealed what the spirit, passing away in that torment, would fain have concealed. &#x0022;<persName><foreName>Alice</foreName></persName>, come near me, hold my hand <persName><foreName>Alice</foreName></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="261"/>Are you thirsty, poor child?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="262"/>Oh, do not grieve your father!

<milestone unit="sentence" n="263"/>It will be but a short time, my little girl; be patient.&#x0022; <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName> tried to kiss her; her husband kneeled and raised her head on his shoulder, bending his face on her forehead, and murmuring the last farewell &mdash; the last thanks &mdash; the agony of his pity for her suffering.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="264"/>The poor child threw herself on her mother, gazing upward, in want and grief and bewilderment, in her face. &#x0022;My <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName>,&#x0022; said the mother, feeling about with the other hand, but she did not find his head to bless it. &#x0022;My <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName>,&#x0022; she repeated in a fainter tone, and her eyelids drooped over the hot eyes. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="265"/> Paulette saw nothing but his suffering wife, heard nothing but her painful breath. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="266"/> At that moment the door opened, and <persName><foreName>Charles</foreName></persName> stood there, paler than ever, with glittering eyes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="267"/>He held the cup towards his <milestone unit="column" n="6"/> father. &#x0022;Father,&#x0022; he said, &#x0022;there is water coming down from Heaven!&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="268"/> Paulette looked up and cried, &#x0022;O. <name n="God" type="God">God</name>, it rains!&#x0022; Va. </p> </div4> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="railroads"> 
<head>Railroads.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="269"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="express"> 
<head>Express Companies.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="270"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> <milestone unit="page" n="2"/> 
<div1 type="page-image"> 
<head></head> 
<p><figure entity="NW_RichTimesD_029_082_002"> <figDesc>Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume <num value="29">29</num>, <num value="82">Number 82</num>, <ref n="page 2">page 2</ref>. </figDesc> </figure></p> </div1> <milestone unit="column" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.</head> 
<div2 type="wednesday"> 
<head><date value="1865-12-13">Wednesday...december 13, 1865.</date></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="271"/> Of all the improvements made or contemplated upon this continent, we hold the water line connecting the <placeName key="tgn,7013964;tgn,1125114" n="0.025 000000.0496	placename;tgn,7013964;Richmond, Richmond, Virginia,Richmond,Virginia,United States,North and Central America;0.025 000000.0496	placename;tgn,1125114;James River, Virginia, Virginia,Virginia,United States,North and Central America" reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia,Richmond,Virginia,United States,North and Central America;James River, Virginia, Virginia,Virginia,United States,North and Central America">James river</placeName> and <placeName key="tgn,1125392" n="1.000 13" reg="kanawha, west virginia, united states">Kanawha</placeName> to be that which will produce the greatest and most direct impression upon the commercial relations of the several parts of the <rs>Union</rs> to each other, and of these, in combination, to the whole world.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="272"/>Rising within <measure n="5miles" type="distance">five miles</measure> of each other, these <num value="2">two</num> great rivers run, the <num value="1">one</num> directly west to the <rs>Ohio</rs>, the other directly east to <placeName key="tgn,2374406" n="1.000 34" reg="hampton roads, hampton, virginia">Hampton Roads</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="273"/>Having once touched the <rs>Ohio</rs>, the water line places us in communication with all the great improvements of <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName>, <placeName reg="Ohio" key="tgn,7007706">Ohio</placeName>. <placeName reg="Indiana" key="tgn,7007252">Indiana</placeName>, <placeName reg="Illinois" key="tgn,7007251">Illinois</placeName>, <placeName reg="Michigan" key="tgn,7007520">Michigan</placeName>, and by their means with <placeName reg="Missouri" key="tgn,7007523">Missouri</placeName> and <placeName reg="Arkansas" key="tgn,7016172">Arkansas</placeName>, on the west of the <rs>Mississippi</rs>, together with <placeName reg="Kansas" key="tgn,7007254">Kansas</placeName> and the boundless regions of the far <rs>West</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="274"/>The <placeName reg="California, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007157">California</placeName> railroad, which will have its eastern terminus at <placeName reg="Saint Louis, Saint Louis City, Missouri" key="tgn,7014444">St. Louis</placeName>, will give us a fair chance for the trade of <placeName reg="California" key="tgn,7007157">California</placeName> itself and of <placeName key="tgn,1000111" n="1.000 120" reg="zhonghua">China</placeName> and the <placeName reg="East Indies" key="tgn,6001831">East Indies</placeName> through <placeName reg="San Francisco, San Francisco, California" key="tgn,7014456">San Francisco</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="275"/>The communication of the <rs>Ohio</rs> with the <rs>Mississippi</rs> will give the canal a fair sweep at the whole cotton region of the <rs>Mississippi</rs>, the <placeName key="tgn,7014191;tgn,7013268;tgn,2611953;tgn,2611945;tgn,2042317;tgn,2000894" n="0.050 000000.4960	placename;tgn,7014191;name,Natchitoches,Louisiana,United States,North and Central America;0.050 000000.4960	placename;tgn,7013268;name,Rapides,Louisiana,United States,North and Central America;0.050 000000.4960	placename;tgn,2611953;name,Brown,Texas,United States,North and Central America;0.050 000000.4960	placename;tgn,2611945;name,Avoyelles,Louisiana,United States,North and Central America;0.050 000000.4960	placename;tgn,2042317;name,Bossier,Louisiana,United States,North and Central America;0.050 000000.4960	placename;tgn,2000894;name,Louisiana,United States,North and Central America" reg="name,Natchitoches,Louisiana,United States,North and Central America;name,Rapides,Louisiana,United States,North and Central America;name,Brown,Texas,United States,North and Central America;name,Avoyelles,Louisiana,United States,North and Central America;name,Bossier,Louisiana,United States,North and Central America;name,Louisiana,United States,North and Central America">Red river</placeName> and <placeName reg="Texas" key="tgn,7007826">Texas</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="276"/>We will thus be placed in a condition to contest the palm of commerce with the other States which have already worked their way to the <rs>Father</rs> of Waters, and we shall be enabled to do so under the most favorable circumstances. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="277"/> On the fact, We have the cities of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="278"/><placeName reg="Petersburg, Petersburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7014404">Petersburg</placeName> and <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName>, and a number of small towns on our great rivers, with depth of water sufficient to qualify them to take rank as important ports.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="279"/>Such are <placeName reg="Urbanna, Middlesex, Virginia" key="tgn,2114705">Urbana</placeName>, on the <rs>Rappahannock</rs>, and <persName n="York,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00015" reg="mostcommon:York,nomatch:0"><surname>York</surname></persName>, on the river of the same name.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="280"/>The importance of <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName>, however, is so transcended as to throw all others in the shade.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="281"/>It is, we have always heard, with the exception of <placeName reg="Montour Falls, Schuyler, New York" key="tgn,2070618">Havana</placeName> and <placeName reg="San Francisco, San Francisco, California" key="tgn,7014456">San Francisco</placeName>, the finest and most capacious harbor on the <name>Continent</name> of <placeName reg="North America" key="tgn,1000001">North America</placeName>, or in any of its islands.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="282"/>We are by no means satisfied that the improvements of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> ought not to have all converged to that point, and had in view the establishment of that <num value="1">one</num> great commercial emporium.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="283"/>It would have been by no means detrimental to the prosperity of any other town or city.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="284"/>A great trade, like that which will pass through <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> if the water line be completed, <hi rend="italics">must </hi> discharge itself into some port which the largest vessels can enter &mdash; must go at once to the wharf and be shipped without, as far as possible, incurring transshipment by the way. The port must be so near the sea as to offer no objection to sea captains and consignors &mdash; all of whom prefer making a voyage across the <rs>Atlantic</rs> to ascending a long river, even with the assistance of steam.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="285"/><placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName> answers this description in every respect; and no matter where the tonnage may halt on its passage, <num value="2">two</num>-<num value=".333">thirds</num> of it must find its way there.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="286"/>Ships are always to be found in abundance wherever there is always plenty of tonnage, because they are always on the look-out for a cargo; and that is the reason why everybody who wishes to ship a cargo from any other point sends to New York.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="287"/>The ships are always there, because the cargo is always there; and if they are wanted elsewhere, they must be paid for going.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="288"/>The ship-yards of <placeName reg="Baltimore, Baltimore Independent City, Maryland" key="tgn,7013352">Baltimore</placeName> turn out the finest clippers in the world.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="289"/>The <rs>Baltimorean</rs> are, naturally, proud of them, and complain that they make <num value="1">one</num> voyage from that port and never return.--They go to New York, where they can always find employment.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="290"/>Let the water line be completed, and <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName> will receive a tonnage from it of <num value="10">ten</num> or <num value="12000000">twelve millions</num>--the largest by far in the world.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="291"/>Capital will hasten there, and ships out of number will follow.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="292"/>It is impossible to prevent this consummation, in the event supposed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="293"/>Commerce will force its way to <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName>, let its people even do their worst to oppose it. It will go where the fine harbor invites the greatest number of ships.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="294"/>Steam has removed the disadvantages it labored under from being situated so far astern of the <rs>Northern</rs> cities in the trade of the <rs type="place">Gulf</rs> stream.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="295"/>Steam will take its ships straight across the mill-pond. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="296"/> <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Peirpoint,Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00016" reg="mostcommon:Peirpoint,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Governor">Governor</roleName> <surname>Peirpoint</surname></persName>,</hi> after advising the sale of the <rs>State</rs>'s interest in the <orgName n="Public Works" type="works">Public Works</orgName>, tells us curtly that the scheme &mdash; that is, the completion of the water line &mdash; is impracticable.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="297"/>As his <rs type="role2">Excellency</rs> never surveyed the route, there is a possibility that he may be mistaken.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="298"/>It is certain, at any rate, that very distinguished engineers, who <hi rend="italics">have</hi> surveyed it, think differently.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="299"/>The <orgName n="French Company" type="company">French company</orgName> think differently, and they are prepared to back their judgment.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="300"/>Let them, by all means, have a fair trial, for the decision of the question is of vital interest to <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> and to the world. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="301"/> Before the session of Congress, the <rs>Northern</rs> press devoted all the space it could spare from the negro question to discussing the currency.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="302"/>It seemed to be taken for granted that the circulation was redundant, and that curtailment was demanded.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="303"/>That, in fact, was supposed to be the grand panacea which was to purge to its pristine health the diseased and suffering currency.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="304"/>Now, the <name>Comptroller</name> of the <name>Currency</name> reports that the circulation is only <num value="460000000">four hundred and sixty millions</num> instead of <num value="1000">one thousand</num> <num value="1000000">millions</num>, as had been assumed when all these pretty articles were written.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="305"/>As the currency stands at <num value="1">one</num> <num value="47">forty-seven</num> for <num value="100">one hundred</num>, this figure of <num value="462000000">four hundred and sixty-two millions</num> represents, in fact, only about <num value="300000000">three hundred millions</num>.--Surely this amount is not too large for a population of <num value="30000000">thirty</num> to <num value="35000000">thirty-five millions</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="306"/>It is impossible that the currency can be very redundant when the money market is so tight as it is everywhere just at this time.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="307"/>Redundant circulation implies plenty of money. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="308"/> In our opinion, it is always the worst policy to meddle with the currency.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="309"/>We had ample experience of this under the <rs>Confederacy</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="310"/>Let it alone and it will right itself.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="311"/><placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName> offers an example of this.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="312"/>In <dateStruct value="1797--"><year reg="1797">1797</year></dateStruct> the <orgName n="Bank of England" type="bank">Bank of England</orgName> suspended specie payment, and did not resume it for <measure n="20years" type="date">twenty years</measure>. The currency had degenerated so greatly by <dateStruct value="1811--"><year reg="1811">1811</year></dateStruct> that an attempt was made in Parliament to force a resumption of specie payments.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="313"/>It failed, and the currency continued to depreciate until <dateStruct value="1815--"><year reg="1815">1815</year></dateStruct>, the end of the war. The return of peace brought an immense increase of business, the redundant circulation was absorbed in the channels of trade and manufactures, the currency appreciated steadily until it reached the metallic standard, and then specie payments were resumed without danger.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="314"/>The same thing will happen here if no rude hands be laid upon the currency. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="315"/> There was a time when nearly all the intelligence of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> was opposed to slavery.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="316"/><hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Jefferson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00017" reg="nearbymention:Jefferson,Thomas,,,"><surname>Jefferson</surname></persName></hi> has left his opinion upon record; <hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName></hi> provided in his will for the emancipation of his slaves, and <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Tucker,,St. George,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00018" reg="default:Tucker,St. George,,,"><foreName>St. George</foreName> <surname>Tucker</surname></persName></hi> (the elder) devoted to the subject <num value="60">sixty</num> pages of his notes upon <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Blackstone,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00019" reg="mostcommon:Blackstone,nomatch:0"><surname>Blackstone</surname></persName>,</hi> in which he decidedly condemned it. Indeed, so general was the feeling that it may be said all <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>, during the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> <measure n="30years" type="date">thirty years</measure> after the <name>Revolution</name>, was anti-slavery.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="317"/>The only stumbling block in the way of emancipation seems to have been the difficulty of disposing of the emancipated negroes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="318"/><hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Jefferson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00020" reg="nearbymention:Jefferson,Thomas,,,"><surname>Jefferson</surname></persName></hi> himself thought the <num value="2">two</num> races ought not to live together.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="319"/>That great, but eccentric genius, <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Randolph,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00021" reg="default:Randolph,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Randolph</surname></persName></hi> of <placeName reg="Roanoke, Roanoke, Virginia" key="tgn,7014343">Roanoke</placeName>, though <num value="1">one</num> among the largest slaveholders in the <rs>State</rs>, and though wont to resent any interference <unclear></unclear> <milestone unit="column" n="2"/> In <dateStruct value="1803--"><year reg="1803">1803</year></dateStruct> he was chairman of a committee upon a memorial from <placeName reg="Indiana" key="tgn,7007252">Indiana</placeName> to dispense, temporarily, with the ordinance of <dateStruct value="1787--"><year reg="1787">1787</year></dateStruct> so far as it was applicable to that State, and made a report, of which the following is an extract: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="320"/> &#x0022;That the rapid population of the <placeName reg="Ohio" key="tgn,7007706">State of Ohio</placeName> sufficiently evinces, in the opinion of your committee, that the labor of the slave is not necessary to promote the growth and settlement of colonies in that region.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="321"/>That this labor, demonstrably the dearest of any, can only be employed to advantage in the cultivation of products more valuable than any known to that quarter of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName>; and your committee deem it highly dangerous and inexpedient to impair a provision wisely calculated to promote the happiness and prosperity of the <rs>Northwestern</rs> country, and to give strength and security to that extensive frontier.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="322"/>In the salutary operations of this sagacious and benevolent restraint, it is believed that the inhabitants of <placeName reg="Indiana" key="tgn,7007252">Indiana</placeName> will, at no very distant day, find ample remuneration for a temporary privation of labor and emigration.&#x0022; </p> </q><bibl n="John Randolph"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="323"/> These are the views of a great Statesman and (we are almost tempted to say) prophet.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="324"/>When this report was written, <placeName reg="Indiana" key="tgn,7007252">Indiana</placeName> was comparatively a wilderness.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="325"/>In <measure n="62years" type="date">sixty-two years</measure> it has become <num value="1">one</num> of the most popular States in the <rs>Union</rs>, far excelling <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>, a part of whose territory she originally was, and by <num value="1">one</num> of whose sons it was won from the <name>Crown</name> of <placeName reg="United Kingdom" key="tgn,7002445">Great Britain</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="326"/>At his death, <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Randolph,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00022" reg="nearbymention:Randolph,John,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Randolph</surname></persName></hi> emancipated all his negroes by will, and provided for their future support.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="327"/>The apparent inconsistency of holding slaves and being opposed to slavery was, in his case, as it was in that of many other <rs n="Virginian" type="group">Virginians</rs>, apparent only.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="328"/><hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Randolph,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00023" reg="nearbymention:Randolph,John,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Randolph</surname></persName></hi> knew not what to do with his slaves if he should emancipate them, and all his contemporaries were a similar quandary. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="329"/> It cannot be denied that a great change took place in the mind of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> during the last years of slavery.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="330"/>This arose, in a great measure, from the resentment engendered by party strife and sectional recrimination.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="331"/>Yet, that <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>, as a community, was much less wedded to the institution than either the majority of <rs n="Virginian" type="group">Virginians</rs> or the people of the <rs>North</rs> supposed, is apparent from the alacrity with which her people submitted to the imposed necessity and the small desire they have to see it restored. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="332"/> We observe that the editors of <placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName> and <placeName key="tgn,7013585" n="1.000 66" reg="charlottesville, charlottesville, virginia">Charlottesville</placeName> are engaged in a severe skirmish about the comparative magnitude and importance of those <num value="2">two</num> enterprising towns.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="333"/>They are both charming places, and each has its attractions.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="334"/><placeName key="tgn,7013585" n="1.000 66" reg="charlottesville, charlottesville, virginia">Charlottesville</placeName>, we may mention for the edification of strangers, lies on the east side of the <rs type="place">Blue Ridge</rs>, and <placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName> lies on the west.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="335"/><placeName key="tgn,7013585" n="1.000 66" reg="charlottesville, charlottesville, virginia">Charlottesville</placeName> has the advantage of being nearer to <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, from <sic>whiich</sic> it is distant only <measure n="85miles" type="distance">eighty-five miles</measure>, whilst <persName n="Staunton,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00024" reg="mostcommon:Staunton,nomatch:0"><surname>Staunton</surname></persName> is <measure n="116miles" type="distance">one hundred and sixteen miles</measure> from this great centre of art and civilization. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="336"/> It must be admitted that this is an advantage difficult to be overcome.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="337"/>When the <name>Charlottesville</name> travels abroad, he can say with pride that his town is only <measure n="4hours" type="date">four hours</measure> ride from the <name>Sebastopol</name> of <placeName reg="United States, North and Central America, " key="tgn,7012149">America</placeName>, the classic ground of the <orgName n="New world" type="newspaper">New World's</orgName> history, for the possession of which the mightiest armies of the world contended for <num value="4">four</num> long years.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="338"/>On the other hand, the <name>Stauntonian</name> can declare that he is next door to <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Jackson,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00025" reg="mostcommon:Jackson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Jackson</surname></persName>'s</hi> county, and that the most famous brigade that made <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> classic came from behind the stone-walls of his wild and romantic county. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="339"/> <placeName key="tgn,7013585" n="1.000 66" reg="charlottesville, charlottesville, virginia">Charlottesville</placeName>, on her side, can boast the greatest <orgName n="South University" type="university">University of the South</orgName>, a famous seat of learning, which has educated many of the great statesmen and scholars of the <rs>Southern States</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="340"/><placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName> can set this off by a lunatic asylum, the inmates of which have more sense than most people outside.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="341"/>It has already a much larger number of occupants than the <rs type="place">University</rs>, and, in the present crazy times, ought to be the most popular and populous institution in the country.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="342"/>If its dimensions are increased in proportion to the public wants, it will soon swell to the dimensions of a considerable city.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="343"/><placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName> has also asylums for the deaf and dumb and for the blind.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="344"/>Whether this is an advantage, under all the circumstances, we cannot pretend to decide.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="345"/>It is somewhat important in towns not yet fully developed that there should be, on the part of all the inhabitants, a capacity of minute inspection, and tongues of sufficient vigor and flexibility to describe all and more than the eyes have seen.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="346"/><placeName key="tgn,7013585" n="1.000 66" reg="charlottesville, charlottesville, virginia">Charlottesville</placeName>, again, has in its neighborhood, only <measure n="3miles" type="distance">three miles distant</measure>, <placeName reg="Monticello, Albemarle, Virginia" key="tgn,7014098">Monticello</placeName>, the seat of <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Jefferson,,Thomas,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00026" reg="default:Jefferson,Thomas,,,"><foreName>Thomas</foreName> <surname>Jefferson</surname></persName>,</hi> and his tomb, which the pilgrims of liberty will visit for ages with the devotion of Mahometans to <placeName key="possibilities=11" n="1.000 10" reg=",">Mecca</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="347"/>On the other hand, <placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName>, if she choose, can recall the fact, not generally known, that <hi rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName></hi> looked to that region as the citadel of the <rs>Independence</rs> about which <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Jefferson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00027" reg="nearbymention:Jefferson,Thomas,,,"><surname>Jefferson</surname></persName></hi> only wrote, and that he declared, &#x0022;Give me but a standard, and let we plant it on the mountains of <placeName key="tgn,2114970" n="1.000 1" reg="west augusta, augusta, virginia">West Augusta</placeName>, and I will yet rescue the cause of my country from its enemies.&#x0022; We are not certain that we give the exact words, for they are so rarely quoted that we cannot vouch for their accuracy.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="348"/><placeName key="tgn,7013585" n="1.000 66" reg="charlottesville, charlottesville, virginia">Charlottesville</placeName>, too, is a place of Revolutionary renown.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="349"/>In <date value="1781-05">May, 1781,</date> when <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName><foreName>Cornwallis</foreName></persName></hi> invaded <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>, the <name>Legislature</name> adjourned from <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> to <placeName key="tgn,7013585" n="1.000 66" reg="charlottesville, charlottesville, virginia">Charlottesville</placeName>, as a place of greater safety.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="350"/>In the succeeding month, the famous partisan officer, <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Tarleton,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00028" reg="mostcommon:Tarleton,nomatch:0"><surname>Tarleton</surname></persName>,</hi> was detached to <placeName key="tgn,7013585" n="1.000 66" reg="charlottesville, charlottesville, virginia">Charlottesville</placeName>, with <num value="180">one hundred and eighty</num> cavalry of his legion and <num value="70">seventy</num> mounted infantry, with directions to surprise the <orgName n="General Assembly" type="misc">General Assembly</orgName> and seize the person of <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Jefferson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00029" reg="nearbymention:Jefferson,Thomas,,,"><surname>Jefferson</surname></persName>,</hi> then the <rs>Governor</rs> of the <rs>Commonwealth</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="351"/><placeName key="tgn,7013585" n="1.000 66" reg="charlottesville, charlottesville, virginia">Charlottesville</placeName> may exult that she did not permit the <name>Legislature</name> to be surprised, but that the <rs>Governor</rs> and all the members, except <num value="7">seven</num> escaped.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="352"/>On the other hand, they might have been running to this day but for <persName n="Staunton,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00030" reg="mostcommon:Staunton,nomatch:0"><surname>Staunton</surname></persName>, whither they repaired with commendable alacrity, and ended their session in peace and safety.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="353"/><placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName> did not permit <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Tarleton,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00031" reg="mostcommon:Tarleton,nomatch:0"><surname>Tarleton</surname></persName></hi> to cross the <rs type="place">Blue Ridge</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="354"/>He might take <placeName key="tgn,7013585" n="1.000 66" reg="charlottesville, charlottesville, virginia">Charlottesville</placeName>, but not <placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="355"/>What does <placeName key="tgn,7013585" n="1.000 66" reg="charlottesville, charlottesville, virginia">Charlottesville</placeName> say to that?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="356"/><placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName> has several newspapers, <placeName key="tgn,7013585" n="1.000 66" reg="charlottesville, charlottesville, virginia">Charlottesville</placeName> only <num value="1">one</num>, but that, though little, is loud.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="357"/>It reminds us of <num value="1">one</num> of those small gunboats used in the late war, carrying a <num value="200">two-hundred</num>-pounder.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="358"/><placeName key="tgn,7013585" n="1.000 66" reg="charlottesville, charlottesville, virginia">Charlottesville</placeName>, having a University, has more beaux than belles.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="359"/>They are, in general, magnificent fellows (or were when we were young), who can write, fight, make war or make love with equal audacity and success.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="360"/>The belles, too, are glorious creatures, but there are not enough of them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="361"/>In <placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName>, on the contrary, there is an excess of lovely woman.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="362"/>There is no male educational institution of sufficient capacity to supply the resident female population with beaux, to say nothing of the large seminaries for young ladies, which are never gladdened by the sight of a man. We would recommend enterprising young gentlemen, about to emigrate to the country,--we beg pardon, --to the inland towns,--to settle in <placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName>, and young ladies to make a raid on <placeName key="tgn,7013585" n="1.000 66" reg="charlottesville, charlottesville, virginia">Charlottesville</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="363"/>We believe that each town can boast of having had the small-pox and other epidemics common to great marts of trade.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="364"/>A vigorous effort was made at <num value="1">one</num> time to prove that there had been several cases of cholera in <placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName> during the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> visitation of that epidemic to this country, but the effort was reluctantly abandoned, and ended in nothing but wind.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="365"/>Both towns may be considered, in a measure, seaport places, <placeName key="tgn,7013585" n="1.000 66" reg="charlottesville, charlottesville, virginia">Charlottesville</placeName> being situated on the right bank of the <placeName key="tgn,1129131" n="1.000 3" reg="rivanna, virginia, united states">Rivanna river</placeName>, so called, and <placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName> being situated on both banks of <persName n="Lewis,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00032" reg="nearbymention:Lewis,Zachariah,,,"><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>'s <rs n="Creek" type="nativeamerican">creek</rs>, the modest title of a meritorious stream, which, however, when excited, has sometimes threatened to carry away the town.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="366"/>During the late war, both <placeName key="tgn,7013585" n="1.000 66" reg="charlottesville, charlottesville, virginia">Charlottesville</placeName> and <placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName> had a good many more Northern visitors than they are ever likely to have again.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="367"/><placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName>, we believe, has the advantage in this respect, having entertained a succession of cavalry and infantry <unclear></unclear> <milestone unit="column" n="3"/> can only boast of a solitary cavalry parade.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="368"/><num value="1">One</num> of the chief glories of <placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName> has disappeared since the introduction of railroads.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="369"/>The innumerable stage coaches, which would have delighted the heart of the elder <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Weller,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00033" reg="mostcommon:Weller,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Weller</surname></persName>,</hi> and made it a perfect horse heaven, have departed to the regions of the setting sun. What the commercial prospects of the <num value="2">two</num> towns are in the future, we do not care to inquire.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="370"/>We dare say that neither of them will become a Tyre or <placeName reg="Babylon, Suffolk, New York" key="tgn,2067899">Babylon</placeName>, but they may be content if they always remain as they are, the homes of a population which few of the great hives of commerce can equal in all the qualities which ennoble human nature. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="371"/> The editor of the <orgName n="New York Express" type="newspaper">New York <hi rend="italics">Express</hi></orgName> is, we believe, the oldest editor whose name has steadily appeared in the imprint of any newspaper in that city.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="372"/>The <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> day of its publication was <date value="1817-02-17">17th February, 1817.</date> At that time, <hi rend="smallcaps">John Long</hi> and <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Turner,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00034" reg="default:Turner,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Turner</surname></persName>,</hi> of the <rs>New</rs> <orgName n="York Gazette" type="newspaper">York <hi rend="italics">Gazette</hi></orgName>, were the oldest editors; the next in order was <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Lewis,,Zachariah,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00035" reg="default:Lewis,Zachariah,,,"><foreName>Zachariah</foreName> <surname>Lewis</surname></persName>,</hi> editor of the <hi rend="italics"><orgName n="Commercial Advertiser" type="newspaper">Commercial Advertiser</orgName>;</hi> <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Butler,,Amos,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00036" reg="default:Butler,Amos,,,"><foreName>Amos</foreName> <surname>Butler</surname></persName>,</hi> of the <hi rend="italics">Mercantile Advertiser;</hi> <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Coleman,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00037" reg="mostcommon:Coleman,nomatch:0"><surname>Coleman</surname></persName></hi> and <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Burnham,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00038" reg="mostcommon:Burnham,nomatch:0"><surname>Burnham</surname></persName>,</hi> of the <hi rend="italics"><orgName n="Evening Post" type="newspaper">Evening Post</orgName>;</hi> <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Spooner,,Aldon,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00039" reg="default:Spooner,Aldon,,,"><foreName>Aldon</foreName> <surname>Spooner</surname></persName>,</hi> of the <hi rend="italics"><orgName type="college" n="Columbian college">Columbian</orgName>,</hi> and <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Wheaton,,Henry,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00040" reg="default:Wheaton,Henry,,,"><foreName>Henry</foreName> <surname>Wheaton</surname></persName>,</hi> of the <hi rend="italics">National Advocate.</hi> These were the only daily papers then printed in New York.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="373"/>Most of these editors are dead and their papers discontinued.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="374"/>The <hi rend="italics">Express</hi> is a continuation of the <hi rend="italics"><orgName n="Daily Advertiser" type="newspaper">Daily Advertiser</orgName>;</hi> The <hi rend="italics">Post,</hi> which was established by <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Hamilton,,Alexander,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00041" reg="default:Hamilton,Alexander,,,"><foreName>Alexander</foreName> <surname>Hamilton</surname></persName>, <persName n="King,,Rufus,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00042" reg="default:King,Rufus,,,"><foreName>Rufus</foreName> <surname>King</surname></persName>, <persName n="Wolcott,,Oliver,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00043" reg="default:Wolcott,Oliver,,,"><foreName>Oliver</foreName> <surname>Wolcott</surname></persName></hi> and others, as a high-toned Federal journal, is now ably conducted as a Democratic paper by <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Bryant,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00044" reg="mostcommon:Bryant,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Bryant</surname></persName>.</hi> In nothing is the amazing growth of New York more evident than in the typographical improvement and increased circulation of its press.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="375"/>We do not know that there has been much progress in editorial ability and dignity, for half a century ago the newspapers of New York were conducted by men fully as able to enlighten the public as any who have succeeded them, and who had a high standard of decorum and good taste. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="376"/> What vast changes have since taken place in New York.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="377"/>The city, which now numbers about <num value="800000">eight hundred thousand</num>, had then a population of less than a <num value="160000">hundred and sixty thousand</num>, and <placeName reg="Brooklyn, New York, Kings" key="tgn,7015822">Brooklyn</placeName>, now numbering <num value="200000">two hundred thousand</num> and more inhabitants, was then a village.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="378"/>The great canal which has made New York the <rs>Empire State</rs> was then only talked of, and often derisively talked of as the big ditch.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="379"/>Not a railroad of any importance threaded the land.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="380"/>And yet the real greatness of the city was in those <hi rend="italics">men,</hi> now dead and almost forgotten, whose far-sighted wisdom and inexhaustible energy, while New York was a <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num>-rate town, discovered her capabilities of a grander fortune and adopted the means for its accomplishment.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="381"/>The vast river of life that rolls unheeding by their graves is only sounding with its murmuring tide the requiem of the mighty spirits who excavated the channels for its triumphal progress, and whose magic genius converted a barren island into the golden high way of the world's commerce. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="382"/> The writers from <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName> represent that Capital as crowded to overflowing with applicants for office.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="383"/>They are, in general, willing to take anything they can get, from a foreign mission down to a pair of old breeches. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="384"/> It has always been so at the commencement of every new Congress, and we suppose will always be so to the end of time.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="385"/>Office-seekers always abound in a Republic, and in this Republic, we suspect, above all others that ever existed. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="386"/> There must be something supremely enchanting in the touch of public money.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="387"/>Men tell us that gold is <rs type="color">gold</rs>, and <rs type="color">silver</rs> is silver, no matter by whom paid, or for what service or purpose.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="388"/>It cannot be true; public money must be better than any other money, else why do we see so many men, well off in the world, leaving their farms, where they could live in ease and independence, to run in debt, and toil like galley slaves in the offices at <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>? </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="389"/> Of all situations in life, we should think that of a department clerk, with a family to rear and educate, the least desirable.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="390"/>And yet we see hundreds every year, with this encumbrance upon them, crowding to <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName> to beg, cringe, bow, sue, do anything, for <num value="1">one</num> of these clerkships.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="391"/>Among them are many men of talent, who either previously occupied, or could, by proper exertion, easily occupy, elevated positions among their friends and neighbors.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="392"/>It is incomprehensible.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="393"/>Public money must assuredly possess attractions that no other money can make any pretensions to. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="394"/> That good, old <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> newspaper, the <orgName n="Abingdon Virginian" type="newspaper">Abingdon <hi rend="italics">Virginian</hi></orgName>, after an enforced sleep of exactly <measure n="12months" type="date">twelve months</measure>, roused itself, like a strong man refreshed by slumber, on the <num value="8" type="ordinal">8th</num> day of the present month.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="395"/><hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Stoneman,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00045" reg="mostcommon:Stoneman,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Stoneman</surname></persName>,</hi> it seems, took the duties of the editors off their hands, and, turning editor himself, wrote a valedictory for them on the <date value="1864-12-15">15th day of December, 1864.</date> Whether they were pleased with the substitution we are left to conjecture.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="396"/>We should rather suppose the contrary, since they have again taken the field of journalism on their own hook. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="397"/> We wish our old acquaintance, the <hi rend="italics"><rs n="Virginian" type="group">Virginian</rs>,</hi> all the success its editors can desire; and are confident, from past experience, that they will deserve all they may meet, let it be as ample as it may. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="8"> 
<head rend="smallcaps">Police for <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Manchester</placeName> and <placeName reg="Chesterfield, Chesterfield, Virginia" key="tgn,2111165">Chesterfield</placeName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="398"/> The <rs type="place">County Court</rs> of <placeName reg="Chesterfield, Chesterfield, Virginia" key="tgn,2111165">Chesterfield</placeName> decided on <dateStruct><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct> last, to organize a police corps for the county, and appointed a committee of <num value="2">two</num> from each <orgName n="Magisterial District" type="district">magisterial district</orgName> to make recommendations to the <rs type="place">Court</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="399"/>It was ordered that <num value="40">forty</num> be the number appointed for the <orgName n="Magisterial District" type="district">magisterial district</orgName> embracing <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Manchester</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="400"/>In most of the other districts, the number was fixed at <num value="24">twenty-four</num>, <num value="20">twenty</num> being the smallest number for any district.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="401"/>The members of this corps are to be selected with reference to their military experience, it being the object of the <rs type="place">Court</rs> to secure a bold and efficient organization for the protection of the county.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="402"/>So we learn from the <orgName n="Petersburg Express" type="newspaper">Petersburg <hi rend="italics">Express</hi></orgName>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="9"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><orgName n="King George Court" type="court">King George Court</orgName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="403"/> --<dateStruct><day type="name">Thursday</day></dateStruct> last was court day at <persName><roleName n="King">King</roleName> <foreName>George</foreName></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="404"/>The attendance was large for the season, but there was nothing of interest outside of court. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="405"/> In court, <persName n="Weaver,,Benjamin,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00046" reg="default:Weaver,Benjamin,,,"><foreName>Benjamin</foreName> <surname>Weaver</surname></persName> was arraigned on a charge of shooting &mdash; Rawlet some <measure n="15months" type="date">fifteen months</measure> ago. After a patient investigation of the case and argument by counsel, the evidence of guilt being inconclusive, the prisoner was discharged. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="10"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Religious meetings in <placeName reg="Fredericksburg, Fredericksburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013943">Fredericksburg</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="406"/> --The new <rs n="Methodist" type="religion">Methodist</rs> <persName n="Clarke,Minister,Joseph,S.,R.," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00047" reg="default:Clarke,Joseph,S.,R.,"><roleName n="Minister">minister</roleName>, <foreName>Joseph</foreName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <foreName>R.</foreName> <surname>Clarke</surname></persName>, has arrived, and preached on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Sunday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="407"/> <persName n="Williams,Reverend-Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00048" reg="mostcommon:Williams,Sophia,,,:1"><roleName n="Reverend-Mister">Rev. Mr.</roleName> <surname>Williams</surname></persName>, at the <orgName n="Baptist Church" type="church">Baptist Church</orgName>, is conducting a series of religious meetings.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="408"/><persName n="Burrows,Reverend-Doctor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00049" reg="mostcommon:Burrows,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Reverend-Doctor">Rev. Dr.</roleName> <surname>Burrows</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, preached last night.--<hi rend="italics">Ledger.</hi> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="11"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Insurrection.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="409"/> --We hear that the <rs type="place">County Court</rs> of <placeName reg="Spotsylvania, Spotsylvania, Virginia" key="tgn,2114316">Spotsylvania</placeName> has expressed to <persName n="Harris,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00050" reg="mostcommon:Harris,Tom,,,:1"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Harris</surname></persName> its fears of a negro insurrection during <placeName reg="Christmas, Lincoln, New Mexico" key="tgn,2238892">Christmas</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="410"/><persName n="Harris,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00051" reg="mostcommon:Harris,Tom,,,:1"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Harris</surname></persName> will, we learn, take prompt measures to repress any disturbance, should <num value="1">one</num> occur, but does not share the apprehensions felt by the <rs type="place">Court</rs>.--<hi rend="italics"><orgName n="Fredericksburg Ledger" type="newspaper">Fredericksburg Ledger</orgName>.</hi> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="411"/> The Young Men's <orgName n="Literary Society" type="society">Literary Society of <placeName reg="Fredericksburg, Fredericksburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013943">Fredericksburg</placeName></orgName> organized on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time> by the election of <persName n="Jones,Doctor,C.,A.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00052" reg="default:Jones,C.,A.,,"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <foreName>C.</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName> <surname>Jones</surname></persName> as president, <persName n="Chewning,,William,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00053" reg="default:Chewning,William,M.,,"><foreName>William</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Chewning</surname></persName> and <persName n="Goolrick,,John,T.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00054" reg="default:Goolrick,John,T.,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>T.</foreName> <surname>Goolrick</surname></persName> as vice-presidents, <persName n="Knox,,Samuel,S.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00055" reg="default:Knox,Samuel,S.,,"><foreName>Samuel</foreName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <surname>Knox</surname></persName> secretary, <persName n="Foster,,M.,L.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00056" reg="default:Foster,M.,L.,,"><foreName>M.</foreName> <foreName>L.</foreName> <surname>Foster</surname></persName> treasurer, <persName n="Mill,,L.,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00057" reg="default:Mill,L.,M.,,"><foreName>L.</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Mill</surname></persName> librarian, and <persName n="Crump,,Robert,C.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00058" reg="default:Crump,Robert,C.,,"><foreName>Robert</foreName> <foreName>C.</foreName> <surname>Crump</surname></persName> sergeant-at-arms. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="13"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="412"/> No <num value="1">one</num> but Little, of the <rs>Fredericksburg</rs> <hi rend="italics"><orgName n="New Era" type="newspaper">New Era</orgName>,</hi> could have &#x0022;got up&#x0022; the following: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="413"/> &#x0022;The meeting on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time> to organize a fire company did not meet, because of the non-attendance of the public.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="414"/>The public ought to be ashamed.&#x0022; </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="14"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="415"/> <persName n="Rothrock,,George,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00059" reg="default:Rothrock,George,W.,,"><foreName>George</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Rothrock</surname></persName>, an old citizen of <placeName reg="Fredericksburg, Fredericksburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013943">Fredericksburg</placeName>, died suddenly on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time>, </p> </div3> <milestone unit="column" n="4"/> 
<div3 type="article" n="15"> 
<head><orgName n="General Assembly" type="misc">General Assembly of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName></orgName>.</head> 
<div4 type="entry" n="1"> 
<head>Senate.</head> <opener> <dateline> <dateStruct value="1865-12-12"><day type="name">Tuesday</day>, <month reg="12">December</month> <day reg="12">12</day>, <year reg="1865">1865</year></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="416"/> The Senate met at the usual hour, <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Cowper,Lieutenant-Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00060" reg="mostcommon:Cowper,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lieutenant-Governor">Lieutenant-Governor</roleName> <surname>Cowper</surname></persName></hi> in the chair.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="417"/>Prayer by <persName n="Barten,Reverend,O.,S.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00061" reg="default:Barten,O.,S.,,"><roleName n="Reverend">Rev.</roleName> <foreName>O.</foreName> <foreName>S.</foreName> <surname>Barten</surname></persName>, of <orgName n="Christ Church" type="church">Christ Church</orgName>, <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="418"/> A bill was received from the <orgName n="House of Delegates" type="government">House of Delegates</orgName> to authorize the <rs type="place">County Court</rs> of <placeName key="tgn,1002368" n="1.000 18" reg="fauquier, virginia, united states">Fauquier</placeName> to borrow money for county purposes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="419"/>Referred to Committee on <persName n="Laws,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00062" reg="mostcommon:Laws,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Laws</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="420"/> By <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Kello,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00063" reg="mostcommon:Kello,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Kello</surname></persName>,</hi> of <placeName reg="Southampton, Hampshire, England" key="tgn,7011385">Southampton</placeName>: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="421"/> &#x0022;<hi rend="italics">resolved,</hi> That the <rs>Governor</rs> be requested to inform the <name>Senate</name> what steps are necessary to procure arms for militia purposes.&#x0022; Passed. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="422"/> By <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Trout,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00064" reg="mostcommon:Trout,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Trout</surname></persName>,</hi> of <placeName reg="Augusta, Richmond, Georgia" key="tgn,7017498">Augusta</placeName>: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="423"/> &#x0022;<hi rend="italics">Resolved,</hi> That the <rs>Committee</rs> on Public Institutions inquire into the expediency of making a special appropriation to discharge the outstanding liabilities of the <rs>Western Lunatic Asylum</rs>.&#x0022; Passed. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="424"/> Also, a resolution that the same committee inquire into the expediency of authorizing the <name>Directors</name> of the <rs>Western Lunatic Asylum</rs> to dispense with the <orgName>office of Treasurer</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="425"/>Passed. </p> 
<p> By <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Cabell,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00065" reg="mostcommon:Cabell,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Cabell</surname></persName>,</hi> of <persName n="Nelson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00066" reg="mostcommon:Nelson,nomatch:0"><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="426"/> &#x0022;<hi rend="italics">Resolved,</hi> That the <rs>Committee</rs> on <persName n="Laws,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00067" reg="mostcommon:Laws,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Laws</surname></persName> be instructed to inquire into the necessary legislation to secure to <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> the lands donated by the <orgName n="U. S. Congress" type="Congress">United States Congress</orgName> on the <date value="1862-07-02">2d July, 1862,</date> to the <name>States</name> for educational purposes.&#x0022; Passed. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="427"/> By <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Meade,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00068" reg="mostcommon:Meade,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Meade</surname></persName>,</hi> of <placeName reg="Frederick, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002161">Frederick</placeName>: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="428"/> &#x0022;<hi rend="italics">Resolved,</hi> That the <rs>Committee</rs> on Courts of Justice be instructed to inquire into the expediency of amending the <orgName type="regiment" key="6Section">sixth section</orgName> of the act passed <date value="1865-01">January, 1865,</date> entitled &#x0027;an act staying the collection of certain debts.&#x0027;&#x0022; Passed. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="429"/> By <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Strother,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00069" reg="mostcommon:Strother,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Strother</surname></persName>,</hi> of <placeName reg="Culpeper, Culpeper, Virginia" key="tgn,2111394">Culpeper</placeName>: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="430"/> &#x0022;<hi rend="italics">Resolved,</hi> That so much of the <rs>Governor</rs>'s message as relates to railroads be referred to the <rs>Committee</rs> on Roads and Internal Navigation, and that they inquire into the expediency of selling the interest of the <rs>State</rs> in said railroads.&#x0022; Passed. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="431"/> The bill <sic>adthorizing</sic> the <orgName n="Richmond and Petersburg Railroad" type="railroad">Richmond and Petersburg Railroad</orgName> Company to borrow money was taken up and read <num value="0.33">a <num value="3" type="ordinal">third</num></num> time.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="432"/>The ayes and noes were ordered, and a lengthy debate ensued, in which <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Russell,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00070" reg="mostcommon:Russell,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Messrs.</roleName> <surname>Russell</surname></persName>, <persName n="Gilmer,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00071" reg="mostcommon:Gilmer,nomatch:0"><surname>Gilmer</surname></persName></hi> and <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Bolling,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00072" reg="mostcommon:Bolling,nomatch:0"><surname>Bolling</surname></persName></hi> took active part. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="433"/> The bill was passed almost unanimously, <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Carter,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00073" reg="mostcommon:Carter,Dick,,,:1"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Carter</surname></persName></hi> only voting against it. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="434"/> On motion of <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Coleman,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00074" reg="mostcommon:Coleman,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Coleman</surname></persName>,</hi> of <placeName reg="Louisa, Louisa, Virginia" key="tgn,2112748">Louisa</placeName>, a bill to authorize the <orgName n="Central Railroad" type="railroad">Central Railroad</orgName> Company to borrow <measure n="300000dollars" type="currency">three hundred thousand dollars</measure> was taken up, read twice and ordered to be engrossed. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="435"/> On motion of <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Gilmer,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00075" reg="mostcommon:Gilmer,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Gilmer</surname></persName>,</hi> of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, an act to increase the capital stock of the <orgName n="Richmond, Fredericksburg, and Potomac Railroad" type="railroad">Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad</orgName> Company was taken up and passed. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="436"/> A bill to incorporate the <rs>Virginia</rs> <orgName n="Insurance Company" type="company">Insurance Company</orgName> was read twice and ordered to be engrossed. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="437"/> <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Bolling,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00076" reg="mostcommon:Bolling,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Bolling</surname></persName>,</hi> from Select Committee to wait on the <rs>Governor</rs> in reference to dispensing with the offices of <num value="2" type="ordinal">Second</num> Auditor and Register of the <orgName n="Land Office" type="office">Land Office</orgName>, reported in writing as follows.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="438"/>The Governor says: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="439"/> &#x0022;I am of opinion that there is no necessity for the office of <num value="2" type="ordinal">Second</num> Auditor.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="440"/>The whole business of that office belongs properly to that of the <rs>Auditor</rs>, <hi rend="italics">in my opinion.</hi> </p> </q><bibl n="The Governor"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="441"/> &#x0022;I think that the <orgName>office of <rs type="role" reg="Secretary">Secretary</rs></orgName> of the <orgName n="Land Office" type="office">Land Office</orgName> might be put under the <rs>Secretary</rs> of the <rs>Commonwealth</rs>, with authority to employ a chief clerk.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="442"/> Referred to a joint committee. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="443"/> Joint resolution (communicated from the <rs type="place">House</rs>) that when the <name>Legislature</name> adjourns on the <dateStruct value="--21"><day reg="21">21st instant</day></dateStruct> that it adjourn to meet on the <date value="1866-01-03">3d January, 1866.</date> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="444"/>Senate adjourned. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="2"> 
<head><orgName n="House of Delegates" type="government">House of Delegates</orgName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="445"/> The <rs type="place">House</rs> met at <time value="12oclock">twelve o'clock</time>. Prayer by <persName n="Jeter,Reverend,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00077" reg="mostcommon:Jeter,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Reverend">the Rev. Mr.</roleName> <surname>Jeter</surname></persName>, of the <orgName n="Baptist Church" type="church">Baptist Church</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="446"/> <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Wood,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00078" reg="mostcommon:Wood,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Wood</surname></persName>,</hi> from the <rs>Committee</rs> on the <name>Penitentiary</name>, reported a bill amending and re-enacting chapter <num value="213">two hundred and thirteen</num> of the <name>Code</name> of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>, reorganizing the penitentiary, which was ordered to be printed. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="447"/> <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Garnett,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00079" reg="mostcommon:Garnett,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Garnett</surname></persName>,</hi> from the <orgName n="Propositions and Grievances Committee" type="committee">Committee on Propositions and Grievances</orgName>, to whom had been referred the resolution relative to the removal of freedmen from the <rs type="place">York Peninsula</rs>, reported the same back with the request that it be referred to the joint committee to confer with the <rs>Superintendent</rs> of the <rs type="place">Freedmen's Bureau</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="448"/>The resolution was so disposed of. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="449"/> The following bills were considered and passed: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="450"/> A bill to incorporate the <rs>Virginia</rs> <orgName n="Insurance Company" type="company">Insurance Company</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="451"/> A bill to incorporate the <rs>Virginia State</rs> <orgName n="Insurance Company" type="company">Insurance Company</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="452"/> A bill to incorporate the <rs>Belvidere Manufacturing Company</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="453"/> The bill incorporating the <rs>Lynchburg Mining</rs> and Manufacturing Company in the counties of <placeName key="tgn,2002150" n="1.000 6" reg="campbell, virginia, united states">Campbell</placeName>, <placeName key="tgn,2002140" n="1.000 15" reg="amherst, virginia, united states">Amherst</placeName> and <placeName reg="Bedford, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002144">Bedford</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="454"/> <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Watkins,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00080" reg="mostcommon:Watkins,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Watkins</surname></persName>,</hi> from the <rs>Committee</rs> on Schools and Colleges, made a report, asking that <num value="500">five hundred</num> copies of the act of Congress entitled &#x0022;an act donating public lands to the several States and Territories which may provide colleges for the benefit of agricultural and mechanic arts,&#x0022; approved <date value="1862-07-02">July 2, 1862, </date> be printed for the use of the <rs type="place">House</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="455"/>The report was adopted. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="456"/> By <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Gibbony,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00081" reg="mostcommon:Gibbony,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Gibbony</surname></persName>.</hi>--A resolution that the <rs type="place">House</rs>, with the concurrence of the <name>Senate</name>, will, on Thursday the <dateStruct value="--14"><day reg="14">14th instant</day></dateStruct>, at <time value="1pm">one P. M.</time>, proceed to elect a Public Printer, <rs type="role" reg="Superintendent">Superintendent</rs> of the <name>Penitentiary</name>, and Penitentiary Storekeeper, which, being objected to, was laid over. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="457"/> The resolution of <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Langhorne,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00082" reg="mostcommon:Langhorne,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Langhorne</surname></persName></hi> relative to the hour of meeting and the reduction of the pay of members was considered and again laid on the table. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="458"/> By <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Garnett,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00083" reg="mostcommon:Garnett,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Garnett</surname></persName>.</hi>--A resolution that when this <persName n="House,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00084" reg="mostcommon:House,nomatch:0"><surname>House</surname></persName> adjourn on <date>Thursday</date>, the <dateStruct value="--21"><day reg="21">21st instant</day></dateStruct>, it will, with the consent of the <name>Senate</name>, adjourn until <time value="12oclock">twelve o'clock</time> on <dateStruct><day type="name">Wednesday</day></dateStruct>, the <date value="1866-01-03">3d day of January, 1866.</date> The resolution was agreed to. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="459"/> By <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Pate,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00085" reg="mostcommon:Pate,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Pate</surname></persName>.</hi>--A resolution that the <rs>Committee</rs> on Agriculture be instructed to inquire into the expediency of reporting a bill to prohibit the distillation of grain within this Commonwealth.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="460"/>Agreed to. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="461"/> By <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Townes,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00086" reg="mostcommon:Townes,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Townes</surname></persName>,</hi> of <placeName key="tgn,7014021" n="1.000 1" reg="mecklenburg, north carolina, united states">Mecklenburg</placeName>.--A resolution that the <rs>Committee</rs> on Courts of Justice inquire into the expediency of creating some tribunal for the purpose of deciding, in a summary way, on all contracts made during the war, so as to reach the justice and right of each case; or, if it is deemed better, to confer on courts of the <rs>State</rs> already in existence full power and authority to do the same, and report by bill or otherwise. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="462"/> By <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Dunnington,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00087" reg="mostcommon:Dunnington,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Dunnington</surname></persName>.</hi>--A resolution of inquiry into the expediency of directing the <rs>Librarian</rs> to procure and file, and have bound for reference, copies of all the newspapers of this and other cities of the <rs>Commonwealth</rs>, and <num value="1">one</num>, at least; of such semi-weekly or weekly newspapers as may be published in counties where there are no daily papers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="463"/>Agreed to. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="464"/> By <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Woodson,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00088" reg="mostcommon:Woodson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Woodson</surname></persName>.</hi>--A resolution that the <rs>Committee</rs> on Finance inquire into the expediency of reporting the bill releasing the taxes anterior to the year <dateStruct value="1865--"><year reg="1865">1865</year></dateStruct> which now remain unpaid, and providing some mode for the settlement of the accounts of sheriffs and clerks in regard to their official transactions in the year <dateStruct value="1861--"><year reg="1861">1861</year></dateStruct> and subsequent thereto. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="465"/> By <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Gibboney,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00089" reg="mostcommon:Gibboney,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Gibboney</surname></persName>.</hi>--A resolution that the <rs>Committee</rs> for Courts of Justice be instructed to inquire into the expediency of abolishing imprisonment in the penitentiary for a less term than <measure n="5years" type="date">five years</measure>, and to provide some other punishment in lieu thereof. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="466"/> By <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Seawell,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00090" reg="mostcommon:Seawell,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Seawell</surname></persName>.</hi>--A resolution that the <rs>Committee</rs> on Courts of Justice inquire into the expediency of providing by law for the regulation of contracts for manual labor, and the proper enforcement thereof, when such contracts are for a period of &mdash; days.--Agreed to. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="467"/> By <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Jones,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00091" reg="nearbymention:Jones,C.,A.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Jones</surname></persName>.</hi>--A resolution, which was agreed to, that the <rs>Committee</rs> on Courts of Justice be instructed to inquire into the propriety of giving to persons with whom contracts for the performance of agricultural labor are made, a remedy for their enforcement similar to the specific performance of contracts in equity; annexing penalties; also, for their violation, and of giving jurisdiction in all such cases to single justices of the peace by a summary proceeding, and to report by bill or otherwise. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="468"/> On motion of <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Gibboney,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00092" reg="mostcommon:Gibboney,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Gibboney</surname></persName>,</hi> of <persName n="Wythe,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00093" reg="mostcommon:Wythe,nomatch:0"><surname>Wythe</surname></persName>, the <rs type="place">House</rs>, at <time value="1pm">1 o'clock P. M.</time>, adjourned. </p> </div4> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="16"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">The custom-house Frauds.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="469"/> --The case of the people against <persName n="Barney,,William,Chase,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00094" reg="default:Barney,William,Chase,,"><foreName>William</foreName> <foreName>Chase</foreName> <surname>Barney</surname></persName>, Benthian Fabian, late of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Va.</placeName>, and <persName n="Chauncey,Captain,Reginald,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00095" reg="default:Chauncey,Reginald,,,"><roleName n="Captain">Captain</roleName> <foreName>Reginald</foreName> <surname>Chauncey</surname></persName>, on the complaint of <unclear></unclear> <persName n="Wheeler,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00096" reg="mostcommon:Wheeler,nomatch:0"><surname>Wheeler</surname></persName>, for an alleged attempt to <unclear></unclear> internal revenue by fraudulently attempting to clear <measure n="300barrels" type="mass">three hundred barrels</measure> of alcohol from the custom-house, by which the <rs>Government</rs> would have lost the dues thereon, amounting to <measure n="40000dollars" type="currency">$40,000</measure>, was brought before Justice <unclear></unclear> of <orgName n="New York City" type="newspaper">New York city</orgName>, <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> <time>morning</time> last, who said: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="470"/> &#x0022;Upon the motion to dismiss the prisoners for want of jurisdiction, I have come to the conclusion that I have jurisdiction to arrest and examine the prisoners for the offence charged; but, as they constitute violations of <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> laws, it is best that the proceedings be concluded before the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> officials.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="471"/>I shall therefore simply hold the prisoners for the purpose of permitting the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> Court to proceed in the matter. &#x0022; </p> </q><bibl n="Justice"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="472"/> The case, therefore, next comes up in a <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> Court. </p> </div3> <milestone unit="column" n="5"/> 
<div3 type="article" n="17"> 
<head>Complexion of the standing committees &mdash; great Dissatisfaction.</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>, <dateStruct value="1865-12-11"><month reg="12">December</month> <day reg="11">11</day>, <year reg="1865">1865</year></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="473"/> --The New York delegation feel that they have been ignored, the chairmanship of only <num value="2">two</num> unimportant committees having been given them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="474"/><placeName reg="Massachusetts" key="tgn,7007517">Massachusetts</placeName>, on the contrary, is given the heads of <num value="4">four</num> important committees, viz: Foreign affairs, post-offices, elections and naval affairs.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="475"/>The Western States have the chairmanship of <num value="18">eighteen</num> committees, with <num value="3">three</num> Western members on the <orgName n="Ways and Means Committee" type="committee">committee of ways and means</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="476"/>The pressure from the <rs>West</rs> on the <rs>Speaker</rs> was very great.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="477"/>The changes in the old committee of military affairs elicited the greatest surprise--<persName n="Garfield,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00097" reg="mostcommon:Garfield,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Generals</roleName> <surname>Garfield</surname></persName> and <persName n="Farnsworth,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00098" reg="mostcommon:Farnsworth,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General"></roleName><surname>Farnsworth</surname></persName> being left off, and their places supplied with new members. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="478"/> The partial effect of the bill introduced into the <rs type="place">House</rs> by <persName n="Patterson,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00099" reg="mostcommon:Patterson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Patterson</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="New Hampshire" key="tgn,7007564">New Hampshire</placeName>, is to repeal the charter of the city of <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="479"/>In view of the almost certainly of negro suffrage, and for other substantial reasons, a movement is on foot among some of the citizens to surrender the charter of the city to Congress. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="480"/> The bill introduced by <persName n="Garfield,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00100" reg="mostcommon:Garfield,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Garfield</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Ohio, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007706">Ohio</placeName>, to facilitate commercial intercourse between the several States is in accordance with a paragraph in the annual message on that subject.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="481"/>It prohibits a per capita tax by a State on passengers traveling by rail or boat, and looks to a so-called air-line railway between New York and <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="482"/> The Tennessee Representatives are still in <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="18"> 
<head>Arrival of the <rs>Asia</rs>'s Mails.--Dates to the <dateStruct value="--25"><day reg="25">25th Ultimo</day></dateStruct>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="483"/> The <placeName reg="Halifax, Halifax, Virginia" key="tgn,2112076">Halifax</placeName> telegrams, a day or <num value="2">two</num> ago, favor us with the <hi rend="italics">skimmings</hi> of the news, but the following details are of interest: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="484"/> The <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName> <hi rend="italics">Star</hi> refers to the claim of the <rs n="Dutch" type="group">Dutch</rs> envoy in <placeName reg="United States, North and Central America, " key="tgn,7012149">America</placeName> for an increase of salary on account of the war prices which prevail in New York.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="485"/>The increase was opposed by the <rs type="place">Lower House</rs> of the <rs n="Dutch" type="group">Dutch</rs> Legislature, and the poor, unfortunate envoy, says the <hi rend="italics">Star,</hi> is &#x0022;left living over a barber's shop in <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="486"/> Parliament will meet on the <dateStruct value="-01-25"><day reg="25">twenty-fifth</day> of <month reg="01">January</month></dateStruct>, in order to get through the preliminary business.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="487"/>The <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> thing to be done is to elect a Speaker, the next is to administer the oaths to the new members.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="488"/>This business usually occupies a week, and until it is completed there is no Parliament, in the legal sense of the work, nor can any legislation be proceeded with.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="489"/>It is believed that the formal opening of Parliament by the reading of the <rs>Queen</rs>'s speech will take place on <dateStruct value="-02-1"><month reg="02">February</month> <day reg="1">first</day></dateStruct>, which is <num value="2">two</num> or <measure n="3days" type="date">three days</measure> earlier than the average date. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="490"/> The news is confirmed that the cattle plague throughout Britain has broken out afresh, and is now more fatal than ever.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="491"/>The number of cases for the week ending <date value="11-18">November 18th</date> was <num value="2669">2,669</num>, as compared with <num value="2580">2,580</num> and <num value="1765">1,765</num> of the <measure n="2weeks" type="date">two weeks</measure> ending <date value="11-11">November 11th</date> and <num value="4" type="ordinal">4th</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="492"/>The total number of cases has been <num value="27432">27,432</num>, of which <num value="8998">8,998</num> have proved fatal, and in <num value="1777">1,777</num> have recovered, and of the remaining <num value="3977">3,977</num> the fate is still uncertain.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="493"/>Thus about <num value="22000">22,000</num> cattle have died directly or indirectly from the plague. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="494"/> The famous <term type="ship">steamship</term> <rs type="ship">Trent</rs>, associated with the seizure of <persName n="Mason,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00101" reg="mostcommon:Mason,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Messrs.</roleName> <surname>Mason</surname></persName> and <persName n="Slidell,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00102" reg="mostcommon:Slidell,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Slidell</surname></persName> by a <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> frigate, has closed her career, and is now being broken up near the <rs type="place">Isle of Dogs</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="495"/> The <term n="CS cruiser">rebel cruiser</term> <rs type="ship">Shenandoah</rs> left the <rs>Mersey</rs> for New York on the <dateStruct value="--21"><day reg="2">21st</day></dateStruct>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="496"/> The disposition, however, seems to be, to laugh at it, rather than to treat it with gravity.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="497"/>The <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName> <hi rend="italics">Mercantile Gazette</hi> <sic>thinsk</sic>-- </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="498"/> &#x0022;The whole thing appears to be dying out. The laugh at it grows daily louder, and the proofs of the want of real power and influence amongst its leaders daily more conspicuous. &#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="499"/> The <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName> <orgName n="Daily News" type="newspaper">Daily <hi rend="italics">News</hi></orgName> is of opinion that &#x0022;it is quite probable a raid may be attempted on <placeName reg="Canada, North and Central America, " key="tgn,7005685">Canada</placeName> in the course of the winter, but it will not be a military affair at all &mdash; only a matter of police, which will be put down without difficulty. &#x0022; He thinks, also, that if there is any fighting to be done at all it will have to be done in <placeName key="tgn,7001181" n="1.000 212" reg="eire">Ireland</placeName>, which is very consolatory, considering that the only occasion on which the boasted arms of the <name>Fenians</name> have been used, was that on which the <num value="2">two</num> policemen were shot in the back from a garret window. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="500"/> On the whole, the editor thinks it will do to conclude that: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="501"/> &#x0022;There is little danger that men who are earning good wages, and who are well fed and well clothed, will leave the place in which they obtain all these advantages, even for the sake of gratifying a sentimental devotion to the country in which they starved, or a groundless hatred to <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName>.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="502"/> The <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName> <hi rend="italics"><orgName n="Morning Herald" type="newspaper">Morning Herald</orgName></hi> pitches into <persName><roleName n="Uncle">Uncle</roleName> <foreName>Sam</foreName></persName> for not snuffing the <name>Fenians</name>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="503"/>It says: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="504"/> &#x0022;The Federal Government has hardly acted a wise or dignified part in regard to the <name>Fenian</name> agitation.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="505"/>It is unworthy of a Power which pretends to respect public law, and which desires to maintain peace, to allow a conspiracy to be carried on within its jurisdiction for the invasion of the dominions of a neighbor. </p> </q><bibl n="The London Morning"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="506"/> We never interfere with the plots of <persName n="Mazzini,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00103" reg="mostcommon:Mazzini,nomatch:0"><surname>Mazzini</surname></persName> or <placeName key="tgn,2056764" n="1.000 3" reg="kossuth, alcorn, mississippi">Kossuth</placeName> so long as their execution is to take place solely on <rs n="Italian" type="group">Italian</rs> or Hungarian soil, but if either were to collect a force of aliens in this country for the invasion of <placeName key="tgn,7018159" n="1.000 10" reg="Venezia,Venezia,Veneto,Italia,Europe">Venetian</placeName> or of <placeName key="tgn,7006278" n="1.000 27" reg="magyarorszag">Hungary</placeName>, we should speedily knock the scheme on the head.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="507"/>So we do not ask the <rs n="American" type="group">Americans</rs> to prevent <persName n="Mahoney,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00104" reg="mostcommon:Mahoney,nomatch:0"><surname>Mahoney</surname></persName> talking of an <orgName n="Irish Republic" type="newspaper">Irish Republic</orgName>, or sending money and instructions to his dupes in <placeName reg="Dublin, Pulaski, Virginia" key="tgn,2111523">Dublin</placeName>; but we must remind them that a raid into <placeName reg="Canada, North and Central America, " key="tgn,7005685">Canada</placeName> could hardly fail to have very serious consequences. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="19"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Singular murder in <orgName n="New York City" type="newspaper">New York city</orgName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="508"/> --<persName n="Cunningham,,Alexander,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00105" reg="default:Cunningham,Alexander,,,"><foreName>Alexander</foreName> <surname>Cunningham</surname></persName> was killed in <placeName reg="New City, Rockland, New York" key="tgn,2070742">New city</placeName> last Sunday by an unknown person (though seen, he escaped,) who took his umbrella, which he had in his hand, and shoved it into the eye of <persName n="Cunningham,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00106" reg="nearbymention:Cunningham,Alexander,,,"><surname>Cunningham</surname></persName>, the instrument of death entering the left eye and making a deep wound in the brain.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="509"/>The unfortunate man fell on the floor insensible, and soon afterwards died. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="20"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Trial of <persName n="Davis,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00107" reg="nearbymention:Davis,Jefferson,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Davis</surname></persName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="510"/> --<persName n="Wilson,Representative,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00108" reg="mostcommon:Wilson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Representative">Representative</roleName> <surname>Wilson</surname></persName>, of <rs n="Iowa" type="nativeamerican">Iowa</rs>, introduced a bill <name>Monday</name>, which was referred to the <rs>Committee</rs> on Judiciary, reorganizing the judicial system in the <rs>Southern States</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="511"/>The object of this bill is to perfect arrangements for the trial of <persName n="Davis,,Jefferson,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00109" reg="default:Davis,Jefferson,,,"><foreName>Jefferson</foreName> <surname>Davis</surname></persName> before the <orgName n="U. S. Circuit Court" type="org">United States Circuit Court</orgName> at <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>.--<hi rend="italics"><persName n="San,,Baltimore,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00110" reg="default:San,Baltimore,,,"><foreName>Baltimore</foreName> <surname>San</surname></persName>.</hi> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="21"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Contested election.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="512"/> --<persName n="Kennedy,,John,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00111" reg="default:Kennedy,John,W.,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Kennedy</surname></persName> has notified <persName n="Hall,,E.,B.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00112" reg="default:Hall,E.,B.,,"><foreName>E.</foreName> <foreName>B.</foreName> <surname>Hall</surname></persName> of his intention to contest his right to be commissioned and hold the <orgName>office of <rs type="role" reg="Judge">Judge</rs></orgName> of the <num value="10" type="ordinal">Tenth</num> Judicial Circuit, <placeName key="tgn,7013961" n="1.000 1042" reg="west virginia">West Virginia</placeName>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="22"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">A good Sign.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="513"/> --A house and lot at <placeName reg="Culpeper Courthouse, Virginia">Culpeper Courthouse, Va.</placeName>, was recently sold at auction for <measure n="10060dollars" type="currency">ten thousand and sixty dollars</measure>--a property which the <hi rend="italics">Observer</hi> says would not, before the war, have sold for half that sum. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="23"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Adjournment of <orgName n="Carolina Legislature" type="legislature"><persName n="North,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00113" reg="mostcommon:North,nomatch:0"><surname>North</surname></persName> Carolina Legislature</orgName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="514"/> --The two Houses of the <orgName n="General Assembly" type="misc">General Assembly</orgName> have, by joint resolution, agreed to adjourn <date>Monday</date>, the <dateStruct value="--18"><day reg="18">18th instant</day></dateStruct>, to meet again in <date value="1866-02">February, 1866.</date> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="24"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">The &#x0022;<placeName reg="Utah" key="tgn,7007827">State of Utah</placeName>.&#x0022;</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="515"/> --It is said that the <rs>Honorable</rs> <persName n="Hooper,,William,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00114" reg="default:Hooper,William,H.,,"><foreName>William</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Hooper</surname></persName>, delegate to Congress from <placeName reg="Utah, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007827">Utah</placeName>, will soon introduce a bill to admit that territory into the <rs>Union</rs> as a State. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="25"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Receipts of cotton and tobacco.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="516"/> --The <term type="ship">steamers</term> <rs type="ship">Petersburg</rs> and <rs type="ship">Ellie Knight</rs>, both from <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, came into port on yesterday, each bringing large and valuable cargoes of cotton and tobacco.-- <hi rend="italics"><orgName n="Baltimore Sun" type="newspaper">Baltimore Sun</orgName> of <dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct>.</hi> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="26"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> manufactures.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="517"/> --The <term type="ship">schooner</term> <rs type="ship">Litchfield</rs>, from <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, arrived this morning in a disabled condition, having on board <num value="3">three</num> new locomotives for the <orgName n="Mobile and Ohio Railroad" type="railroad">Mobile and Ohio railroad</orgName>.-- <hi rend="italics"><orgName n="Mobile Tribune" type="newspaper">Mobile Tribune</orgName>.</hi> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="27"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="518"/> <persName n="Shoup,Brigadier-General,Francis,B.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00115" reg="default:Shoup,Francis,B.,,"><roleName n="Brigadier-General">Brigadier-General</roleName> <foreName>Francis</foreName> <foreName>B.</foreName> <surname>Shoup</surname></persName>, of the late <orgName n="Confederate Army" type="org">Confederate army</orgName>, has been elected to the <name>Chair</name> of Physics, Astronomy and Civil Engineering of the <orgName n="Mississippi University" type="university">University of Mississippi</orgName>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="28"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="519"/> The <orgName n="Raleigh Progress" type="newspaper">Raleigh <hi rend="italics">Progress</hi></orgName> says that a party of capitalists from the <rs>North</rs> have gone to <placeName reg="Wilmington, New Hanover, North Carolina" key="tgn,7014631">Wilmington</placeName> with the view of inspecting timber lands.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="520"/>It is understood that the company has a large capital with which to purchase lands, provided proper inducements are offered them. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="521"/> The Confederate <persName n="Ewell,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00116" reg="mostcommon:Ewell,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Ewell</surname></persName> and lady, and <persName n="Brown,General,John,C.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00117" reg="default:Brown,John,C.,,"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>C.</foreName> <surname>Brown</surname></persName>, also of the late <orgName n="Confederate Army" type="org">Confederate army</orgName>, were in <placeName reg="East Nashville, Davidson, Tennessee" key="tgn,2308580">Nashville</placeName> last week. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="522"/> <num value="2">Two</num> youths, under writs of <hi rend="italics">habeas corpus,</hi> <unclear></unclear> discharged from the military service of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> by the <rs>Baltimore Circuit</rs> in court on <dateStruct><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct> last. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="523"/> The receipts from internal revenue on <dateStruct><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct> last amounted to <measure n="834529.80dollars" type="currency">eight hundred and thirty-four thousand five hundred and twenty-nine dollars and eighty cents</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="524"/> <hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Sanders,,George,N.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00118" reg="default:Sanders,George,N.,,"><foreName>George</foreName> <foreName>N.</foreName> <surname>Sanders</surname></persName> in <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName>.</hi>--A letter received in <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>; from <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName>, speaks of the arrival there of <persName n="Sanders,,George,N.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00119" reg="default:Sanders,George,N.,,"><foreName>George</foreName> <foreName>N.</foreName> <surname>Sanders</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="525"/> <persName n="Young,,Brigham,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00120" reg="default:Young,Brigham,,,"><foreName>Brigham</foreName> <surname>Young</surname></persName> is indeed a pillar of <placeName reg="Salt Lake, Millard, Utah" key="tgn,2639101">Salt Lake</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="526"/>His idea of a wife is &mdash; Lots. </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> <milestone unit="column" n="6"/> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="special"> 
<head>Special Notices.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="527"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="13"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> <milestone unit="page" n="3"/> 
<div1 type="page-image"> 
<head></head> 
<p><figure entity="NW_RichTimesD_029_082_003"> <figDesc>Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume <num value="29">29</num>, <num value="82">Number 82</num>, <ref n="page 3">page 3</ref>. </figDesc> </figure></p> </div1> <milestone unit="column" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="528"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.</head> 
<div2 type="wednesday"> 
<head><date value="1865-12-13">Wednesday...december 13, 1865.</date></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head><num value="2">Two</num> carriers wanted.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="529"/><num value="2">Two</num> active and energetic young men wanted to establish new routes for the <hi rend="smallcaps">Dispatch.</hi> Apply before <time value="2oclock">2 o'clock</time> to-day. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head>Only <num value="2">two</num> Cents.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="530"/> We are determined that not <num value="1">one</num> of the <num value="30">thirty</num>-odd <num value="1000">thousand</num> subscribers formerly on the books of the <hi rend="smallcaps">Daily Dispatch</hi> shall be deprived of it by reason of the hard times, and have placed the paper at the low price of <num value="2">two</num> Cents, less than <num value="0.5">one-half</num> charged by the other dailies. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head>Advertisements.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="531"/> Our advertising columns show that our old friends have not forgotten through what channel they can most certainly reach the largest number of readers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="532"/>They shall not be disappointed in their estimate of the ubiquitous power of the <hi rend="smallcaps">Dispatch.</hi> Wherever the mail, the <orgName n="Express Company" type="company">express company</orgName>, our special messengers, the city carriers, and our agents in all the towns and villages of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>, <placeName reg="North Carolina" key="tgn,7007709">North Carolina</placeName> and <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName> can reach a family, there we are resolved that the <hi rend="smallcaps">Dispatch</hi> shall be found, cost what it may of capital, energy and labor. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head>Our city subscribers.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="533"/> It will require a few days more to arrange for the regular delivery of the <hi rend="smallcaps">Dispatch</hi> to our city subscribers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="534"/>Our old carriers are rapidly making up their former lists, and will be aided by special canvassers, who will call on our citizens during the week.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="535"/>Orders left with any of the carriers or canvassers, or at our counting-room, on <address><street n="Governor street">Governor street</street></address>, <num value="1">one</num> door from Main, will insure the delivery of the paper early every morning.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="536"/>Any subscriber failing to receive the paper will please notify us. </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="local"> 
<head>Local matters.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">The <persName n="Kirby,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00121" reg="nearbymention:Kirby,Anne,E.,,"><surname>Kirby</surname></persName> murder case.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="537"/> --<hi rend="smallcaps">Argument upon the <rs>Prisoner</rs>'s Insanity &mdash; Motion for Postponement</hi>--<persName n="Kirby,Mrs.,Anne,E.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00122" reg="default:Kirby,Anne,E.,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <foreName>Anne</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>Kirby</surname></persName>, charged with the murder of her husband, <persName n="Kirby,,Robert,F.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00123" reg="default:Kirby,Robert,F.,,"><foreName>Robert</foreName> <foreName>F.</foreName> <surname>Kirby</surname></persName>, by shooting him with a pistol, at the <rs>Second Market</rs>, on the <date value="11-21">21st of November</date> last, was again arraigned before the <orgName n="Hustings Court" type="court">Hustings Court</orgName> yesterday morning.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="538"/>The <rs type="place">Court</rs> was composed of the following Magistrates: <persName n="Regnault,Alderman,John,F.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00124" reg="default:Regnault,John,F.,,"><roleName n="Alderman">Aldermen</roleName> <foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>F.</foreName> <surname>Regnault</surname></persName>. <persName n="Higgins,,John,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00125" reg="default:Higgins,John,M.,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Higgins</surname></persName>, <persName n="Timberlake,,W.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00126" reg="default:Timberlake,W.,W.,,"><foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Timberlake</surname></persName>, <persName n="Jones,,Thomas,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00127" reg="default:Jones,Thomas,M.,,"><foreName>Thomas</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Jones</surname></persName> and <persName n="McCarthy,,James,T.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00128" reg="default:McCarthy,James,T.,,"><foreName>James</foreName> <foreName>T.</foreName> <surname>McCarthy</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="539"/> <persName n="Chandler,Recorder,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00129" reg="mostcommon:Chandler,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Recorder">Recorder</roleName> <surname>Chandler</surname></persName> left the bench in consequence of having presided at the preliminary examination, and his place was occupied by <persName n="Regnault,Senior-Alderman,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00130" reg="nearbymention:Regnault,John,F.,,"><roleName n="Senior-Alderman">Senior Alderman</roleName> <surname>Regnault</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="540"/> All the witnesses for the <rs>Commonwealth</rs> responded except <persName n="Carlton,,Ambrose,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00131" reg="default:Carlton,Ambrose,,,"><foreName>Ambrose</foreName> <surname>Carlton</surname></persName>, who was detained at home by sickness. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="541"/> Some time was consumed in sending for the witnesses on the part of the defence, the counsel for the prisoner having insisted upon their presence before the commencement of proceedings.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="542"/>The witnesses afterwards made their appearance, and the case proceeded. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="543"/> The prisoner was attended by <num value="2">two</num> female companions.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="544"/>She constantly interrupted the proceedings by incoherent and senseless exclamations. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="545"/> <persName n="Cannon,Mister,Edward,Y.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00132" reg="default:Cannon,Edward,Y.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>Edward</foreName> <foreName>Y.</foreName> <surname>Cannon</surname></persName>. <num value="1">one</num> of the counsel for the defence, <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> addressed the <rs type="place">Court</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="546"/>He adverted to the mental condition of the prisoner, which was such as to render it incompetent for the <rs type="place">Court</rs> to proceed with the trial.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="547"/>He would not discuss the question as to whether she was insane or not at the time of the commission of the alleged crime, but whether she was at present in a condition of mental incapacity. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="548"/> <persName n="Daniel,Mister,R.,T.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00133" reg="default:Daniel,R.,T.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>R.</foreName> <foreName>T.</foreName> <surname>Daniel</surname></persName>, Attorney for the <rs>Commonwealth</rs>, said that it was putting the cart before the horse to argue at length and in advance a motion which no <num value="1">one</num> doubted their right to make. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="549"/> <persName n="Johnson,Mister,Marmatluke,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00134" reg="default:Johnson,Marmatluke,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>Marmatluke</foreName> <surname>Johnson</surname></persName> said it was not proposed to argue the right to make a motion, but whether the <rs type="place">Court</rs> would hear the testimony as to the insanity of the accused. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="550"/> <persName n="Daniel,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00135" reg="nearbymention:Daniel,R.,T.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Daniel</surname></persName> conceded this point, and told the defence to go on with their testimony. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="551"/> <persName n="Cannon,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00136" reg="nearbymention:Cannon,Edward,Y.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Cannon</surname></persName> said the argument was merely to sustain the right of the defence to introduce testimony as to the mental condition of the accused, which he did not call putting the cart before the horse. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="552"/> The prisoner.--Well, you can't have my horse &mdash; he's in the stable. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="553"/> The witnesses for the defence were then called. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="554"/> <persName n="Dove,Doctor,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00137" reg="default:Dove,John,,,"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Dove</surname></persName> testified that he had frequently seen the prisoner since her confinement in the city jail, and considered her <hi rend="italics">non compos mentis.</hi> His impressions on his <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> interview were confirmed by subsequent examinations.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="555"/>He had seen her <num value="3">three</num> times since the day of his <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> visit, but had not treated her. He had not been sent for professionally.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="556"/>He was not prepared to say what effect <unclear></unclear> remedies would produce, but his impression was that if she were sent to a lunatic asylum her condition would improve.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="557"/>The detection of insanity was quite difficult, as was also the simulation of insanity.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="558"/>He did not think she could have kept up a simulation for such a length of time, and he believed her case to be that of real insanity.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="559"/>The city jail was no place for the treatment of such a case as hers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="560"/>His opinion was that she was now in a worse condition mentally, than at any previous time.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="561"/>Her protracted confinement, he thought, would produce permanent insanity.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="562"/>Her ravings are more incoherent than before, and she firmly believes me to be a brother of <persName n="Hix,Miss,Polly,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00138" reg="default:Hix,Polly,,,"><roleName n="Miss">Miss</roleName> <foreName>Polly</foreName> <surname>Hix</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="563"/> <persName n="Trent,Doctor,Peterfield,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00139" reg="default:Trent,Peterfield,,,"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <foreName>Peterfield</foreName> <surname>Trent</surname></persName> testified that he had been <persName n="Kirby,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00140" reg="nearbymention:Kirby,Robert,F.,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Kirby</surname></persName>'s family physician for several years.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="564"/>He saw her at the jail this morning, and made a protracted examination of her case.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="565"/>He thought she was a deranged woman, and perfectly unconscious of what was here going on. I have no doubt of this.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="566"/>I concur with <persName n="Dove,Doctor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00141" reg="nearbymention:Dove,John,,,"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <surname>Dove</surname></persName> that the jail is a very unsuitable place for her to be. She is getting worse and worse.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="567"/>She was always of a very excitable disposition, though I cannot say that I thought she was going deranged, or heretofore predisposed that way. On the occasion of a professional visit to her house, I <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> learned that there was any jealousy of her husband, and she was much excited.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="568"/>Should think she was predisposed to jealous frenzy, and believe she was in that condition when the act was done.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="569"/>Her symptoms at present are those of unmistakable insanity. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="570"/> <persName n="Croft,Major,J.,N.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00142" reg="default:Croft,J.,N.,,"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <foreName>J.</foreName> <foreName>N.</foreName> <surname>Croft</surname></persName>, <rs type="role" reg="Chief of Police">Chief of Police</rs>, testified that <persName n="Kirby,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00143" reg="nearbymention:Kirby,Robert,F.,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Kirby</surname></persName> was placed in his custody on the morning of <date value="11-21">November 21st,</date> and remained there over <measure n="24hours" type="date">twenty-four hours</measure>. Had seen her frequently since.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="571"/>When he <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> saw her he made up his mind that she was insane; and his impressions had been confirmed since.--She had become much worse within a week. --He visited her yesterday, and she insisted that he was <persName n="Richardson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00144" reg="mostcommon:Richardson,nomatch:0"><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>, who brought bad oysters from <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="572"/>Her ravings were senseless and incoherent.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="573"/>His observations of persons in her condition had been such that he was not very apt to be deceived.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="574"/>He had been in the police <measure n="13years" type="date">thirteen years</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="575"/> Cross-examined by <persName n="Daniel,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00145" reg="nearbymention:Daniel,R.,T.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Daniel</surname></persName>.--She was <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> carried to the upper station-house on the morning of the murder, and afterwards brought to my office.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="576"/>I saw her <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> about <time value="9oclock">9 o'clock</time>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="577"/> <persName n="Collins,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00146" reg="nearbymention:Collins,Mary,,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Collins</surname></persName> testified that she had seen <persName n="Kirby,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00147" reg="nearbymention:Kirby,Robert,F.,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Kirby</surname></persName> every day for the past <measure n="2weeks" type="date">two weeks</measure>--was there <num value="1">one</num> night.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="578"/>She believed her to be a crazy woman.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="579"/>She does not sleep at all at night &mdash; was constantly awake and talking &#x0022;so queer.&#x0022; Had seen her exhibit symptoms of insanity before the murder. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="580"/> <persName n="Collins,Miss,Mary,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00148" reg="default:Collins,Mary,,,"><roleName n="Miss">Miss.</roleName> <foreName>Mary</foreName> <surname>Collins</surname></persName> testified that she stayed with <persName n="Kirby,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00149" reg="nearbymention:Kirby,Robert,F.,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Kirby</surname></persName> night and day. She talked wildly all the time, and was a crazy woman.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="581"/><persName n="Kirby,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00150" reg="nearbymention:Kirby,Robert,F.,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Kirby</surname></persName> believes her husband to be still living and in <placeName reg="Wilmington, New Hanover, North Carolina" key="tgn,7014631">Wilmington</placeName>; she expects him back next week.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="582"/>She has <num value="3">three</num> children--<num value="1">one</num> aged about <measure n="4months" type="date">four months</measure> and <measure n="20days" type="date">twenty days</measure>, an other about <num value="2">two</num> and another about <measure n="4years" type="date">four years</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="583"/> <persName n="Johnson,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00151" reg="nearbymention:Johnson,Marmatluke,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Johnson</surname></persName>.--I presume the <rs type="place">Court</rs> is well satisfied as to her mental condition.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="584"/>Our only other witness is <persName n="O'Brian,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00152" reg="mostcommon:O'Brian,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Captain</roleName> <surname>O'Brian</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="585"/> The <rs type="place">Court</rs>.--This testimony, it is presumed, is merely corroborative. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="586"/> <persName n="Johnson,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00153" reg="nearbymention:Johnson,Marmatluke,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Johnson</surname></persName>.--Very strongly so. We had supposed that the <rs type="place">Court</rs> would be so well satisfied as to <persName n="Kirby,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00154" reg="nearbymention:Kirby,Robert,F.,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Kirby</surname></persName>'s mental condition that they would refuse to go on with the trial. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="587"/> <persName n="Cannon,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00155" reg="nearbymention:Cannon,Edward,Y.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Cannon</surname></persName>.--<persName n="O'Brian,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00156" reg="mostcommon:O'Brian,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Captain</roleName> <surname>O'Brian</surname></persName> has said that she was getting so much worse that she could not be treated at the jail; that he was unable to take care of her any longer, and intended to ask for her removal. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="588"/> <persName n="Johnson,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00157" reg="nearbymention:Johnson,Marmatluke,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Johnson</surname></persName>.--I was at the jail yesterday, and <persName n="O'Brian,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00158" reg="mostcommon:O'Brian,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Captain</roleName> <surname>O'Brian</surname></persName> made this statement to me. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="589"/> <persName n="Daniel,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00159" reg="nearbymention:Daniel,R.,T.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Daniel</surname></persName>.--As <persName n="Johnson,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00160" reg="nearbymention:Johnson,Marmatluke,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Johnson</surname></persName> states that of his own knowledge, I am willing to admit it for what it is worth. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="590"/> <persName n="Cannon,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00161" reg="nearbymention:Cannon,Edward,Y.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Cannon</surname></persName> said, that in the state of facts which had been proved, the sole question was <milestone unit="column" n="2"/> whether the <rs type="place">Court</rs> would now proceed with the trial of this unfortunate woman, who was charged with felonious homicide.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="591"/>He appealed to the humanity of the <rs type="place">Court</rs> for delay, and said that it was mockery to contend that this was not, to all intents and purposes, a trial.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="592"/>He contended that there was no statute, either of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> or of any other State, which authorized even a justice to proceed with the examination of a person arraigned before him who was proved to be <hi rend="italics">non compos mentis;</hi> and asked if this Court would be willing to go upon the record as having tried a lunatic.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="593"/><persName n="Cannon,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00162" reg="nearbymention:Cannon,Edward,Y.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Cannon</surname></persName> also said that the <rs type="place">Court</rs> was bound to stop this prosecution at the present stage, and that was the whole extent of his motion.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="594"/>It was their duty to send her to a lunatic asylum; and if she recovered she would be as much amenable to this offence as ever. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="595"/> <persName n="Daniel,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00163" reg="nearbymention:Daniel,R.,T.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Daniel</surname></persName> said that as he saw the counsel for the defence were well armed with legal authorities, he would like to have the benefit of them before proceeding with his argument. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="596"/> <persName n="Crump,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00164" reg="nearbymention:Crump,Robert,C.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Crump</surname></persName> here mentioned several authorities from which he proposed to quote. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="597"/> <persName n="Daniel,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00165" reg="nearbymention:Daniel,R.,T.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Daniel</surname></persName> then proceeded to address the <rs type="place">Court</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="598"/>The question which the <rs type="place">Court</rs> had to try now was whether they were competent to inquire into this case, and say whether this woman should or should not be sent on. He would not strip the accused of the benefits of any testimony which she claimed; but it was not contended that she was insane at the time she committed the crime, while in half an hour afterwards she was found at <persName n="Croft,Major,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00166" reg="nearbymention:Croft,J.,N.,,"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <surname>Croft</surname></persName>'s in a state of insanity; <persName n="Daniel,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00167" reg="nearbymention:Daniel,R.,T.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName><surname>Daniel</surname></persName> here reviewed the testimony which had been adduced, and then proceeded to examine the statutory laws upon the subject.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="599"/>If it were proved that the woman had become insane since the crime had been committed, the <orgName n="Circuit Court" type="court">Circuit Court</orgName> <rs type="role2">Judge</rs> would swear a jury, and it was their duty to ascertain whether she was or was not insane; if sane, the trial would go on; if not, the <rs type="place">Court</rs> might remand the person to jail or send him to a lunatic asylum until such time as he should recover, and then the trial would proceed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="600"/>If the counsel for the accused had succeeded in convincing this Court that they had now no right to examine this case, it must be examined here in case of the woman's recovery.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="601"/>If sent on, she will have the benefit of a jury; and if found sane, the trial must go on; if not, she must be sent to a lunatic asylum to await recovery.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="602"/>He contended, however, that she must be examined before this Court. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="603"/> <persName n="Crump,Mister,W.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00168" reg="default:Crump,W.,W.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Crump</surname></persName> next addressed the <rs type="place">Court</rs> for the defence.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="604"/>He contended that this was a <hi rend="italics">bona fide.</hi> trial; that if the insanity of the prisoner was proven, the <rs type="place">Court</rs> was forbidden to go on with the case, but must send the accused to a lunatic asylum, where she might have every advantage for recovery.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="605"/>He spoke at considerable length, and quoted liberally from authorities to sustain his position. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="606"/> After the conclusion of <persName n="Crump,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00169" reg="nearbymention:Crump,W.,W.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Crump</surname></persName>'s remarks, <persName n="Daniel,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00170" reg="nearbymention:Daniel,R.,T.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Daniel</surname></persName> briefly replied, calling the attention of the <rs type="place">Court</rs> to authorities which he said the counsel for the defence had neglected to notice, defining the meaning of the word &#x0022;trial&#x0022; in a legal sense. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="607"/> <persName n="Johnson,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00171" reg="nearbymention:Johnson,Marmatluke,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Johnson</surname></persName> insisted upon his right to close the argument, but hoped the <rs type="place">Court</rs> would adjourn over until to-morrow. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="608"/> The <rs type="place">Court</rs> stated that <persName n="Johnson,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00172" reg="nearbymention:Johnson,Marmatluke,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Johnson</surname></persName> had signified his intention not to argue the case, but that he might go on if he would confine himself to the arguments of <persName n="Daniel,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00173" reg="nearbymention:Daniel,R.,T.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Daniel</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="609"/> This <persName n="Johnson,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00174" reg="nearbymention:Johnson,Marmatluke,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Johnson</surname></persName> could not promise, and then the <rs type="place">Court</rs> adjourned until to-day at <time value="11oclock">eleven o'clock</time>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Convicted of stealing tobacco.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="610"/> --Yesterday morning, <persName n="Robinson,,William,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00175" reg="default:Robinson,William,,,"><foreName>William</foreName> <surname>Robinson</surname></persName> and <persName n="Wickers,,William,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00176" reg="default:Wickers,William,,,"><foreName>William</foreName> <surname>Wickers</surname></persName>, both negro boys, were tried by <persName n="McEntee,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00177" reg="mostcommon:McEntee,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Colonel</roleName> <surname>McEntee</surname></persName>, Provost <rs type="role2">Judge</rs>, on the charge of burglariously entering Castle Godwin and stealing therefrom a large quantity of tobacco, the property of <persName n="McMillan,,Charles,G.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00178" reg="default:McMillan,Charles,G.,,"><foreName>Charles</foreName> <foreName>G.</foreName> <surname>McMillan</surname></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="611"/> From the evidence of <persName n="McMillan,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00179" reg="nearbymention:McMillan,Charles,G.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>McMillan</surname></persName>, it was shown that, on the morning of the <dateStruct value="--11"><day reg="11">11th instant</day></dateStruct>, he visited the <rs type="place">Castle</rs>, situated in <placeName reg="Lumpkin, Dawson, Georgia" key="tgn,2476218">Lumpkin</placeName>'s alley, where he had stored away a large quantity of tobacco.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="612"/>On trying the door, he found it unlocked, whereupon his suspicions were excited, and he immediately instituted a search of the premises.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="613"/>In a short while he ascertained that <measure n="68boxes" type="mass">sixty- eight boxes</measure> of tobacco, averaging over <measure n="20l." type="pounds"><num value="20">twenty</num> pounds</measure> each, had been stolen.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="614"/>Going from the main building to the kitchen, he there discovered the accused in the act of opening <num value="2">two</num> of the boxes which had been stolen on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Sunday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time> from his store-house, while a short distance from them were <num value="6">six</num> other boxes, which also belonged to the lot he had lost.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="615"/>Upon ascertaining these facts, <persName n="McMillan,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00180" reg="nearbymention:McMillan,Charles,G.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>McMillan</surname></persName> arrested the parties. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="616"/> Wickers, <num value="1">one</num> of the accused, a boy of about <measure n="12years" type="date">twelve years</measure> of age, attempted to exonerate himself from the charge by stating that, early on the morning of <dateStruct><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct>, while passing Castle Godwin, he was called into the kitchen by <persName n="Robinson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00181" reg="nearbymention:Robinson,William,,,"><surname>Robinson</surname></persName> and <num value="2">two</num> white boys, who proposed to sell him some tobacco.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="617"/>He declined purchasing because he had no funds; whereupon they prevailed upon him to assist them in opening the boxes and assorting their contents.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="618"/>He knew nothing of the robbery; otherwise he would not have gone into the kitchen. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="619"/> At the conclusion of the evidence, <persName n="McEntee,Judge,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00182" reg="mostcommon:McEntee,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Judge">Judge</roleName> <surname>McEntee</surname></persName> decided to send <persName n="Robinson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00183" reg="nearbymention:Robinson,William,,,"><surname>Robinson</surname></persName> to the penitentiary for <measure n="2years" type="date">two years</measure>. Wickers, in consideration of his extreme youth and apparently honest statement, was released. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="620"/> <num value="2">Two</num> white boys, who were arrested on the same charge, will be examined before <persName n="Saunders,Mayor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00184" reg="mostcommon:Saunders,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mayor">Mayor</roleName> <surname>Saunders</surname></persName>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Horse thieves on the <name>Rampage</name>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="621"/> --On <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time>, between <time value="11">eleven</time> and <time value="12oclock">twelve o'clock</time>, the attention of <persName n="Clarke,Mister,William,John,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00185" reg="default:Clarke,William,John,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>William</foreName> <foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Clarke</surname></persName>, residing at the corner of <address><street n="18 Street">Eighteenth</street></address> and <address><street n="Broad Street">Broad streets</street></address>, was attracted by the loud barking of his dog. He went out, but saw nothing, but observed that the <rs n="Gas Light" type="newspaper">gas light</rs> near the corner had been extinguished.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="622"/>In the morning it was ascertained that <persName n="Clarke,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00186" reg="nearbymention:Clarke,William,John,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Clarke</surname></persName>'s stable had been broken open and a horse, belonging to a negro man named <persName n="Johnson,,Henderson,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00187" reg="default:Johnson,Henderson,,,"><foreName>Henderson</foreName> <surname>Johnson</surname></persName>, stolen therefrom.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="623"/>The thieves also broke open the stable of <persName n="Smith,Mister,Abram,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00188" reg="default:Smith,Abram,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>Abram</foreName> <surname>Smith</surname></persName>, close by, and stole a valuable bay horse; and, to perfect their work, took a quantity of corn for his feed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="624"/>It has since been learned that <num value="2">two</num> horses were sent off yesterday morning by the <rs>Norfolk</rs> boat, and it is quite probable that they were the ones stolen as above stated. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond city</placeName> Railway.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="625"/> --The <orgName n="City Council" type="council">City Council</orgName>, at its last meeting, passed the ordinance relative to the <rs type="place">Richmond City</rs> Railway, with some, amendments.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="626"/>It stipulates among its provisions that the <orgName type="regiment" key="1Section">first section</orgName> of the road, leading from <placeName key="tgn,2625188" n="1.000 10" reg="Rocketts, Henrico, Virginia">Rocketts</placeName> up to <address><street n="9 Street">Ninth street</street></address>, shall be completed within <num value="1">one</num> year from the date of its passage.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="627"/>The company suffered much, pecuniarily, from the disasters of war, and they propose to renew their enterprise by means of a loan, effected in the usual manner.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="628"/>That the road will eventually be constructed from <placeName key="tgn,2625188" n="1.000 10" reg="Rocketts, Henrico, Virginia">Rocketts</placeName> up Main to <address><street n="9 Street">Ninth street</street></address>, thence out to the corporation line, up <num value="9" type="ordinal">Ninth</num> to Broad, and out Broad to <address><street n="Brook avenue">Brook avenue</street></address>, with various diverging routes to the railroad depots, we entertain no sort of doubt. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">A negro Assassinated by soldiers.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="629"/> --A negro was found dead near the <rs type="place">Old Fair Grounds</rs> yesterday morning, having been shot through the head, as has been ascertained, by <num value="2">two</num> soldiers, on the previous night.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="630"/>Circumstances also went to show that his person had been robbed of <num value="2">two</num> watches and <measure n="5dollars" type="currency">five dollars</measure> in money.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="631"/>An inquest was held by <persName n="Tyler,Justice,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00189" reg="mostcommon:Tyler,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Justice">Justice</roleName> <surname>Tyler</surname></persName>, when the foregoing facts were disclosed, and a verdict was rendered accordingly.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="632"/>The parties who committed the deed are supposed to have taken refuge in their camp, and their arrest has not been effected. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Suicide at sea.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="633"/> --The captain of the <term type="ship">brig</term> <rs type="ship">Troubadour</rs>, which arrived at <placeName reg="City Point, Virginia, Virginia" key="tgn,2240477">City Point</placeName> a day or <num value="2">two</num> since from <placeName key="tgn,7013172" n="1.000 13" reg="saint john,new brunswick,canada,north and central america">St. John</placeName>'s, N. B., rushed upon the deck of his vessel at an early hour <num value="1">one</num> morning while coming into the <name>Capes</name> of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>, and jumped overboard.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="634"/>The crew made an effort to save him by throwing out a plank, but he took no notice of it, and diving down into the water, was drowned.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="635"/>The captain is supposed to have been laboring under a fit of the &#x0022;horrors&#x0022; at the time, and was probably not aware of what he was doing. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="7"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Licenses.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="636"/> --The <orgName n="Hustings Court" type="court">Hustings Court</orgName> yesterday granted a large number of persons licenses to keep &#x0022;ordinaries,&#x0022; which means, in fact, the privilege of selling liquor by the glass.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="637"/>There are many in the city who have not yet made application, among them most of the prominent hotel-keepers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="638"/>They would do well to apply before the close of the present term, as otherwise they will be liable to indictment by the <rs>Grand Jury</rs>, which meets on the <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> Monday in <dateStruct value="-01-"><month reg="01">January</month></dateStruct> next. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="8"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Qualified.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="639"/> --<persName n="Ellett,Mister,Temple,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00190" reg="default:Ellett,Temple,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>Temple</foreName> <surname>Ellett</surname></persName> yesterday qualified before the <orgName n="Hustings Court" type="court">Hustings Court</orgName> as deputy for <persName n="Wright,Mister,John,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00191" reg="default:Wright,John,W.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Wright</surname></persName>, sheriff of the city.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="640"/><persName n="Ellett,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00192" reg="nearbymention:Ellett,Temple,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Ellett</surname></persName> has for some time past, very acceptably filled the position of clerk of the <rs type="place">Freedmen's Court</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="641"/>His new occupation <unclear></unclear> doubtless be more to his taste.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="642"/>Several <unclear></unclear> and practicing attorneys also qualified yesterday. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="9"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Case of somnambulism.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="643"/> --On <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time> last, <persName n="Lambert,Mister,D.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00193" reg="default:Lambert,D.,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>D.</foreName> <surname>Lambert</surname></persName>, while in a somnambulism state, walked out of his chamber, at his mother's residence, on <address><street n="6 Street">Sixth street</street></address>, between <address><street n="Clay street">Clay</street></address> and <address><street n="Leigh street">Leigh</street></address>, and fell down a flight of steps, producing a contusion on his head, but not seriously injuring him. The fall most effectually waked him up. </p> </div3> <milestone unit="column" n="3"/> 
<div3 type="article" n="10"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Masonic Grand officers.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="644"/> --The <placeName reg="Grand Lodge">Grand Lodge</placeName> of <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> last night elected the following officers to serve for <measure n="12months" type="date">twelve months</measure>: </p> 
<list> 
<head></head> 
<item>M. <persName n="Lane,,W.,E.,H.," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00194" reg="default:Lane,W.,E.,H.,"><foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Lane</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Louisa Courthouse">Louisa Courthouse</placeName>, G. M.; </item> 
<item><persName n="William,,R.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00195" reg="default:William,R.,W.,,"><foreName>R.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>William</surname></persName> <persName n="Terry,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00196" reg="mostcommon:Terry,nomatch:0"><surname>Terry</surname></persName>, of <placeName key="tgn,2115154" n="1.000 60" reg="wytheville, wythe, virginia">Wytheville</placeName>, D. G. M. </item> 
<item>R. <persName n="Owens,,W.,T.,F.," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00197" reg="default:Owens,W.,T.,F.,"><foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>T.</foreName> <foreName>F.</foreName> <surname>Owens</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName>, G. S. W.; </item> 
<item><persName n="William,,R.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00198" reg="default:William,R.,W.,,"><foreName>R.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>William</surname></persName> <persName n="Maule,,L.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00199" reg="default:Maule,L.,,,"><foreName>L.</foreName> <surname>Maule</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, G. J. W.; </item> 
<item>R. <persName n="Dudley,,W.,T.,U.," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00200" reg="default:Dudley,W.,T.,U.,"><foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>T.</foreName> <foreName>U.</foreName> <surname>Dudley</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, G. T.; </item> 
<item><persName n="John,,R.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00201" reg="default:John,R.,W.,,"><foreName>R.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>John</surname></persName> <persName n="Dove,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00202" reg="nearbymention:Dove,John,,,"><surname>Dove</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, G. S.; </item> 
<item><persName n="Robert,,R.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00203" reg="default:Robert,R.,W.,,"><foreName>R.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Robert</surname></persName> E., <persName n="Withers,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00204" reg="mostcommon:Withers,nomatch:0"><surname>Withers</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Danville, Danville, Virginia" key="tgn,7014729">Danville</placeName>, G. S. D.; </item> 
<item><persName n="William,,R.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00205" reg="default:William,R.,W.,,"><foreName>R.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>William</surname></persName> <persName n="Lambert,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00206" reg="nearbymention:Lambert,D.,,,"><surname>Lambert</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Alexandria, Alexandria, Virginia" key="tgn,7013269">Alexandria</placeName>, G. J. D. </item> </list> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="11"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="Mayor's Court">Mayor's Court</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="645"/> --<num value="2">Two</num> white boys, named <persName n="Carter,,Dick,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00207" reg="default:Carter,Dick,,,"><foreName>Dick</foreName> <surname>Carter</surname></persName> and John Camp, were before the <rs>Mayor</rs> yesterday, charged with stealing a quantity of tobacco from the warehouse of <persName n="McMurray,Mister,C.,G.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00208" reg="default:McMurray,C.,G.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>C.</foreName> <foreName>G.</foreName> <surname>McMurray</surname></persName>, in <placeName reg="Lumpkin, Dawson, Georgia" key="tgn,2476218">Lumpkin</placeName>'s alley.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="646"/>The evidence was sufficient to justify the <rs>Mayor</rs> in remanding them for further examination before the <orgName n="Hustings Court" type="court">Hustings Court</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="647"/> The remainder of the session was occupied in disposing of cases involving drunkenness and disorderly conduct, a detail of which would not interest our readers. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="12"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Court of Conciliation.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="648"/> --The following cases were heard by this Court yesterday: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="649"/> <persName n="Clopton,,E.,A.,J.," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00209" reg="default:Clopton,E.,A.,J.,"><foreName>E.</foreName> <foreName>A.</foreName> <foreName>J.</foreName> <surname>Clopton</surname></persName> <hi rend="italics">vs.</hi> E; <persName n="Apperson,,B.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00210" reg="default:Apperson,B.,W.,,"><foreName>B.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Apperson</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="650"/>Case dismissed by plaintiff. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="651"/> <persName n="Bliss,,Z.,R.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00211" reg="default:Bliss,Z.,R.,,"><foreName>Z.</foreName> <foreName>R.</foreName> <surname>Bliss</surname></persName> <hi rend="italics">vs.</hi> <persName n="Ferguson,,Eli,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00212" reg="default:Ferguson,Eli,,,"><foreName>Eli</foreName> <surname>Ferguson</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="652"/>Judgment for the plaintiff for the sum of <measure n="15dollars" type="currency">fifteen dollars</measure>, in full satisfaction of his claim. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="653"/> West &#x0026; <hi rend="italics"><rs type="role2">Brother</rs> vs.</hi> <persName n="King,,E.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00213" reg="default:King,E.,,,"><foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>King</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="654"/>Case dismissed by plaintiffs. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="655"/> <persName n="Ballard,,John,P.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00214" reg="default:Ballard,John,P.,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>P.</foreName> <surname>Ballard</surname></persName> <hi rend="italics">vs.</hi> <persName n="King,,Fernando,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00215" reg="default:King,Fernando,,,"><foreName>Fernando</foreName> <surname>King</surname></persName> and <persName n="Weinholtz,,Louis,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00216" reg="default:Weinholtz,Louis,,,"><foreName>Louis</foreName> <surname>Weinholtz</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="656"/>Case dismissed by plaintiff. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="657"/> <persName n="McDowell,,F.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00217" reg="default:McDowell,F.,,,"><foreName>F.</foreName> <surname>McDowell</surname></persName> <hi rend="italics">vs.</hi> <persName n="Baker,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00218" reg="mostcommon:Baker,William,V.,B.,:1"><surname>Baker</surname></persName> &#x0026; Perr.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="658"/>The case was dismissed without costs. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="659"/> Several petitions were filed, the evidence partly heard, and the cases continued until to-day. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="13"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><placeName reg="Provost Court">Provost Court</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="660"/> --<hi rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Presiding,Brevet-Colonel,McEntee,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00219" reg="default:Presiding,McEntee,,,"><roleName n="Brevet-Colonel">Brevet-Colonel</roleName> <foreName>McEntee</foreName> <surname>Presiding</surname></persName>.</hi>--<persName n="Knight,,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00220" reg="default:Knight,James,,,"><foreName>James</foreName> <surname>Knight</surname></persName> and <persName n="Watson,,Lavinia,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00221" reg="default:Watson,Lavinia,,,"><foreName>Lavinia</foreName> <surname>Watson</surname></persName>, colored, were arraigned yesterday on a charge of fighting, and sent to prison for <measure n="3months" type="date">three months</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="661"/> <persName n="Harris,,Tom,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00222" reg="default:Harris,Tom,,,"><foreName>Tom</foreName> <surname>Harris</surname></persName>, a little darkey, charged with throwing rocks at <persName n="Scott,,Harrison,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00223" reg="default:Scott,Harrison,,,"><foreName>Harrison</foreName> <surname>Scott</surname></persName>, negro, was released. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="662"/> <persName n="Williams,,Sophia,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00224" reg="default:Williams,Sophia,,,"><foreName>Sophia</foreName> <surname>Williams</surname></persName>, negro, charged with stealing a shawl, was released. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="663"/> <persName n="Sullivan,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00225" reg="default:Sullivan,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Sullivan</surname></persName>, <orgName type="regiment" key="12USInfantry">Twelfth United States infantry</orgName>, charged with drunkenness and disorderly conduct, was sent to prison for <measure n="10days" type="date">ten days</measure>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="14"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">The Sidewalks on <address><street n="Governor street">Governor street</street></address>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="664"/> --Workmen are now employed in re-laying the sidewalk on <address><street n="Governor street">Governor street</street></address>, from <address><street n="Main street">Main street</street></address> to the <hi rend="italics">Dispatch</hi> office, which will enable the friends of the paper to reach our place of business without difficulty.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="665"/>We learn that, immediately after this work is completed, <persName n="Gill,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00226" reg="mostcommon:Gill,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Gill</surname></persName> will cause the removal of the obstructions from the remainder of the walk, extending to <address><street n="Franklin street">Franklin street</street></address>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="15"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Arrests.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="666"/> --The following arrests were made by the military police yesterday; <persName n="Donald,,Reuben,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00227" reg="default:Donald,Reuben,,,"><foreName>Reuben</foreName> <surname>Donald</surname></persName>, for stealing clothing from <persName n="Harrison,,Milton,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00228" reg="default:Harrison,Milton,,,"><foreName>Milton</foreName> <surname>Harrison</surname></persName>, negro; <persName n="Toomey,,William,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00229" reg="default:Toomey,William,,,"><foreName>William</foreName> <surname>Toomey</surname></persName>, a little <num value="10">ten</num> year old white boy, for stealing tobacco from <persName n="McMurray,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00230" reg="nearbymention:McMurray,C.,G.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>McMurray</surname></persName>; <persName n="Johnson,,Annanias,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00231" reg="default:Johnson,Annanias,,,"><foreName>Annanias</foreName> <surname>Johnson</surname></persName>, negro, for stealing a gold ring from <persName n="McQuimby,,E.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00232" reg="default:McQuimby,E.,,,"><foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>McQuimby</surname></persName>; and Elick Bunday, a Baltimore negro, for attempting to steal a pair of boots. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="16"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">A Lunatic.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="667"/> --<persName n="Baker,,William,V.,B.," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00233" reg="default:Baker,William,V.,B.,"><foreName n="William">Wm.</foreName> <foreName>V.</foreName> <foreName>B.</foreName> <surname>Baker</surname></persName> was yesterday examined before <persName n="Wade,Justice,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00234" reg="mostcommon:Wade,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Justice">Justices</roleName> <surname>Wade</surname></persName>, <persName n="Nettles,Justice,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00235" reg="mostcommon:Nettles,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Justice"></roleName><surname>Nettles</surname></persName> and <persName n="Lee,Justice,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00236" reg="mostcommon:Lee,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Justice"></roleName><surname>Lee</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Henrico, Virginia" key="tgn,1002467">Henrico county</placeName>, on the charge of attempting to kill his father, <persName n="Baker,,George,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00237" reg="default:Baker,George,,,"><foreName>George</foreName> <surname>Baker</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="668"/>The magistrates arrived at the conclusion that there was no doubt about his insanity, and determined to send him to the <rs>Eastern Lunatic Asylum</rs>, at <placeName reg="Williamsburg, Williamsburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7014629">Williamsburg</placeName>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="17"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Direct Importation.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="669"/> --During the past week <num value="6">six</num> cargoes of salt, averaging from <num value="4000">four thousand</num> to <num value="10000">ten thousand</num> bushels each, destined for the <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> market, have arrived at <placeName reg="City Point, Virginia, Virginia" key="tgn,2240477">City Point</placeName>, direct from <placeName reg="Liverpool, Liverpool, England" key="tgn,7010597">Liverpool</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="670"/>And yet we hear, that some of our retail merchants are sending North for their supplies of this indispensable article. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="18"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Organization of the city Police.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="671"/> --Yesterday was the day appointed by <persName n="Saunders,Mayor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00238" reg="mostcommon:Saunders,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mayor">Mayor</roleName> <surname>Saunders</surname></persName> for administering the oath of office to the new <rs type="role" reg="Chief of Police">Chief of Police</rs>, <persName n="Claiborne,Major,John,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00239" reg="default:Claiborne,John,H.,,"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Claiborne</surname></persName>, and his subordinates.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="672"/>No time will now be lost in perfecting the organization of the department, which goes into operation on the <dateStruct value="--20"><day reg="20">20th instant</day></dateStruct>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="19"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">The <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> market</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="673"/> was liberally supplied yesterday morning with meats, fish, poultry and vegetables.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="674"/>Oysters were selling at <measure n="1dollars" type="currency">one dollar</measure> per gallon.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="675"/>There is no difficulty now in getting a good dinner, provided a man has the greenbacks. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="20"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Sudden death.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="676"/> --On <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct> <time>afternoon</time>, <persName n="Cottrell,Mister,Joseph,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00240" reg="default:Cottrell,Joseph,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>Joseph</foreName> <surname>Cottrell</surname></persName>, a citizen of <placeName reg="Henrico, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,1002467">Henrico</placeName>, fell suddenly dead on the <placeName reg="Corn Brook, Bartholomew, Indiana" key="tgn,2031483">Brook</placeName> road, near this city.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="677"/>An inquest was held by <persName n="Wade,Justice,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00241" reg="mostcommon:Wade,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Justice">Justice</roleName> <surname>Wade</surname></persName>, and a verdict rendered, that death was occasioned by disease of the heart. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="21"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">We are</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="678"/> indebted to the <orgName n="Adams Express Company" type="company">Adams Express Company</orgName> for New York papers some <measure n="16hours" type="date">sixteen hours</measure> in advance of the mail. </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="marine"> 
<head>Marine intelligence.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="679"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> <milestone unit="column" n="4"/> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="telegraphic"> 
<head>Telegraphic news.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>Associated Press dispatches.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="680"/><lb/>Congressional proceedings.</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-12-12"><month reg="12">December</month> <day reg="12">12</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="681"/> --<hi rend="smallcaps">Senate.</hi>--<persName n="Davis,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00242" reg="nearbymention:Davis,Jefferson,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Davis</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName>, offered a resolution, which was referred to the <orgName n="Judiciary Committee" type="committee">Judiciary Committee</orgName>, declaring that whereas there is no longer rebellion in the limits of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName>, therefore the privilege of the writ of <hi rend="italics">habeas corpus</hi> is restored in every State. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="682"/> The Senate resumed the consideration of the <rs type="place">House</rs> resolution providing for the appointment of a joint committee of <num value="15">fifteen</num> to inquire into the condition of the <name>States</name> which formed the so- called Confederacy, and report whether they, or any of them, are entitled to be represented in either House of Congress.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="683"/>The resolution was amended and passed &mdash; ayes, <num value="33">33</num>; nays, <num value="11">11</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="684"/>The Senate then adjourned. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="685"/> <hi rend="smallcaps"><orgName n="House of Representatives" type="government">House of Representatives</orgName>.</hi>The Speaker submitted a communication from the <rs>Governor Virginia</rs>, enclosing an act of the <orgName n="General Assembly" type="misc">General Assembly</orgName> in favor of the repeal of the act giving the consent of the <orgName n="Virginia Legislature" type="legislature">Legislature of Virginia</orgName> for forming the new <placeName reg="West Virginia" key="tgn,7013961">State of West Virginia</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="686"/>Referred to the <orgName n="Judiciary Committee" type="committee">Judiciary Committee</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="687"/> <persName n="Raymond,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00243" reg="mostcommon:Raymond,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Raymond</surname></persName> presented the credentials of the members elect from <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="688"/> <persName n="Stevens,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00244" reg="mostcommon:Stevens,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Stevens</surname></persName> objected, saying that the <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825">State of Tennessee</placeName> was not known to the <rs type="place">House</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="689"/> The Speaker overruled the objection. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="690"/> <persName n="Raymond,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00245" reg="mostcommon:Raymond,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Raymond</surname></persName> said there were many facts connected with <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName>, past and present, which commended its case to the early consideration of the <rs type="place">House</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="691"/> Several gentlemen wanted the <rs>Tennessee</rs> members at once admitted, lauding them for their patriotism during the war. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="692"/> The <rs type="place">House</rs> referred their credentials to the joint committee of <num value="15">fifteen</num> on the condition of the late <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName>--yeas, <num value="125">125</num>; nays, <num value="42">42</num>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="693"/> A resolution was passed inviting the members elect from <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825">Tennessee</placeName> to occupy seats in the <rs type="place">Hall</rs> of Representatives.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="694"/>Pending the decision of their case, the <rs type="place">House</rs> then adjourned. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head>From <placeName key="tgn,7007248" n="1.000 6199" reg="georgia">Georgia</placeName>.</head> <opener> <dateline> New York, <dateStruct value="-12-12"><month reg="12">December</month> <day reg="12">12</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="695"/> --The <term type="ship">steamer</term> <rs type="ship">Herman Livingston</rs>, from <placeName reg="Savannah, Chatham, Georgia" key="tgn,7014487">Savannah</placeName> <dateStruct value="--9"><day reg="9">9th instant</day></dateStruct>, has arrived. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="696"/> <persName n="Stephens,the Honorable,Alexander,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00246" reg="default:Stephens,Alexander,H.,,"><roleName n="the Honorable">Hon.</roleName> <foreName>Alexander</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Stephens</surname></persName> peremptorily declines the candidacy for the <orgName n="U. S. Senate" type="org">United States Senate</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="697"/> <persName n="Jenkins,the Honorable,C.,J.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00247" reg="default:Jenkins,C.,J.,,"><roleName n="the Honorable">Hon.</roleName> <foreName>C.</foreName> <foreName>J.</foreName> <surname>Jenkins</surname></persName>, recently elected Governor of <placeName reg="Georgia" key="tgn,7007248">Georgia</placeName>, sent a communication to the <name>Legislature</name> on the <dateStruct value="--8"><day reg="8">8th instant</day></dateStruct> declining the inauguration at present. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="698"/> Nothing is said in the proclamation about the election of Governor. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="699"/> The <placeName reg="Savannah, Chatham, Georgia" key="tgn,7014487">Savannah</placeName> <hi rend="italics">Herald</hi> contains <persName n="Johnson,Provisional-Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00248" reg="nearbymention:Johnson,Annanias,,,"><roleName n="Provisional-Governor">Provisional Governor</roleName> <surname>Johnson</surname></persName>'s message to the <name>Legislature</name>, in which he entreats them to bring forward their prejudices and animosities and offer them as a sacrifice on the altar of our common country, that we may once more present the happy spectacle of brothers. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="700"/> The <orgName n="House of Representatives" type="government">House of Representatives</orgName> has instructed the <orgName n="Judiciary Committee" type="committee">Judiciary Committee</orgName> to report a bill securing to persons of color the right of property, the right to sue and be sued, and to testify in the courts. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head>Death of <persName n="Morris,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00249" reg="mostcommon:Morris,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Morris</surname></persName>.</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Baltimore, Baltimore Independent City, Maryland" key="tgn,7013352">Baltimore</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-12-12"><month reg="12">December</month> <day reg="12">12</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="701"/> --<persName n="Morris,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00250" reg="mostcommon:Morris,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Morris</surname></persName>, commanding at <placeName key="tgn,7018023" n="1.000 10" reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi">Fort McHenry</placeName>, died to-day. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head>Failure of a Banking firm.</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Saint Louis, Saint Louis City, Missouri" key="tgn,7014444">St. Louis</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-12-12"><month reg="12">December</month> <day reg="12">12</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="702"/> --Laude, <orgName><persName n="Jersey,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00251" reg="mostcommon:Jersey,nomatch:0"><surname>Jersey</surname></persName> &#x0026; Co.</orgName>, bankers, suspended payment and closed their doors to-day. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head>New York markets.</head> <opener> <dateline> New York, <dateStruct value="-12-12"><month reg="12">December</month> <day reg="12">12</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="703"/> --Flour has declined <num value="10">10</num>&#x0040;<measure n="20cents" type="currency">20</measure> per barrel.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="704"/><persName n="Wheat,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00252" reg="mostcommon:Wheat,nomatch:0"><surname>Wheat</surname></persName> dull.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="705"/>Corn firm; sales <num value="80000">80,000</num> bushels yellow Southern at <num value="90">90</num>&#x0040;<measure n="93cents" type="currency">93</measure> Beef and pork firm.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="706"/>Whisky steady.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="707"/>Cotton dull; sales of <measure n="1400barrels" type="mass">1,400 bales</measure> at <num value="47">47</num>&#x0040;<measure n="48cents" type="currency">48</measure> Naval stores quiet.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="708"/>Freights dull.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="709"/>Gold, <num value="144">144</num>&#x215E; </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head><placeName reg="Baltimore, Baltimore Independent City, Maryland" key="tgn,7013352">Baltimore</placeName> markets.</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Baltimore, Baltimore Independent City, Maryland" key="tgn,7013352">Baltimore</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-12-12"><month reg="12">December</month> <day reg="12">12</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="710"/> --Flour very heavy for common; high grades unchanged.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="711"/><persName n="Wheat,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00253" reg="mostcommon:Wheat,nomatch:0"><surname>Wheat</surname></persName> drooping.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="712"/>Corn dull &mdash; white, <measure n="80cents" type="currency">80</measure>; yellow, <num value="77">77</num>&#x0040;<measure n="78cents" type="currency">78</measure> Cloverseed lower &mdash; sales at <measure n="8.12dollars" type="currency">$8.12</measure>. Provisions dull.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="713"/>Sugars have a downward tendency.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="714"/>Whisky dull, at <measure n="2.31dollars" type="currency">$2.31</measure>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="7"> 
<head><placeName reg="Memphis market">Memphis market</placeName>.</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Memphis, Shelby, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017750">Memphis</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-12-12"><month reg="12">December</month> <day reg="12">12</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="715"/> --The cotton market is depressed: sales at <num value="40">40</num>&#x0040;<measure n="43cents" type="currency">43</measure> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="8"> 
<head>Fenian meeting at <placeName reg="Philadelphia, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7014406">Philadelphia</placeName>.</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Philadelphia, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7014406">Philadelphia</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-12-11"><month reg="12">December</month> <day reg="11">11</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="716"/> --A large and enthusiastic meeting of the <rs>Fenian Circles</rs> in this city was held to-night.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="717"/>Resolutions were unanimously adopted endorsing <persName n="O'Mahony,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00254" reg="mostcommon:O'Mahony,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Colonel</roleName> <surname>O'Mahony</surname></persName> as president. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="9"> 
<head>New York bank statement.</head> <opener> <dateline> New York, <dateStruct value="-12-11"><month reg="12">December</month> <day reg="11">11</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="718"/> --The weekly statement of the city banks shows the following total; Decrease, loans, <measure n="1350000dollars" type="currency">$1,350,000</measure>; increase, specie, <measure n="2190000dollars" type="currency">$2,190,000</measure>; circulation, <measure n="77000dollars" type="currency">$77,000</measure>; deposits, <measure n="950000dollars" type="currency">$950,000</measure>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="10"> 
<head><placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> oyster trade.</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName key="tgn,7013920" n="1.000 64" reg="fortress monroe, hampton, virginia">Fort Monroe</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-12-10"><month reg="12">December</month> <day reg="10">10</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="719"/> --A large delegation of oystermen held a meeting in <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName> yesterday, and passed resolutions appointing a committee, of which <persName n="Fitzgerald,Captain,Henry,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00255" reg="default:Fitzgerald,Henry,,,"><roleName n="Captain">Captain</roleName> <foreName>Henry</foreName> <surname>Fitzgerald</surname></persName> is chairman, to go to <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> for the purpose of obtaining a revision of the laws regulating the oyster trade in <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="11"> 
<head>Boston Mayoralty election.</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Boston, Suffolk, Massachusetts" key="tgn,7013445">Boston</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-12-11"><month reg="12">December</month> <day reg="11">11</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="720"/> --<persName n="Lincoln,,F.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00256" reg="default:Lincoln,F.,W.,,"><foreName>F.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Lincoln</surname></persName> was re-elected mayor of this city to-day by a majority of about <num value="2000">two thousand</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="721"/>The <orgName n="City Council" type="council">City Council</orgName> is largely <rs n="Republican" type="political">Republican</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="722"/>The vote is light &mdash; a little over <num value="8000">eight thousand</num>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="12"> 
<head>From <placeName reg="California, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007157">California</placeName>.</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="San Francisco, San Francisco, California" key="tgn,7014456">San Francisco</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-12-9"><month reg="12">December</month> <day reg="9">9</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="723"/> --The <rs>Colorado</rs> sailed to-day, taking <measure n="1010000dollars" type="currency">$1,010,000</measure> in treasure, of which <measure n="859000dollars" type="currency">$859,000</measure> goes to New York. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="13"> 
<head>From <placeName reg="Kentucky, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName>.</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Louisville, Jefferson, Kentucky" key="tgn,7013915">Louisville</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-12-12"><month reg="12">December</month> <day reg="12">12</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="724"/> --In the <name>Senate</name>, the joint resolution to proceed to the ratification of the <rs>Constitutional Amendment</rs> was laid over under the rules. </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="725"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> <milestone unit="column" n="5"/> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="telegraphic"> 
<head>Telegraphic news</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>By <persName n="Johnson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00257" reg="nearbymention:Johnson,Annanias,,,"><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>'s Independent agency.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="726"/><lb/>from <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>.</head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-12-12"><month reg="12">December</month> <day reg="12">12</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="727"/> --This reconstruction resolution agreed to in the <rs>Union</rs> caucus last night will probably pass the <name>Senate</name> without long debate.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="728"/><orgName n="House Committee" type="committee">House Committee</orgName> on the <orgName n="Columbia District" type="district">District of Columbia</orgName> was purposely made up with a majority of men known to favor equal suffrage here.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="729"/>The proposition introduced into the <rs type="place">House</rs> to charge upon the <rs>National Treasury</rs> all war expenses of the <name>States</name> meets with opposition in the <orgName n="Treasury Department" type="department">Treasury Department</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="730"/>Hundreds of <num value="1000000">millions</num> are involved in the settlement of these claims.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="731"/>The Conservatives claim the result of the caucus of <rs n="Republican" type="political">Republican</rs> <rs type="role2">Senators</rs> yesterday as a triumph, which will be followed by the admission of the <rs>Tennessee</rs> delegation. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="732"/> The <orgName n="War Department" type="department">War Department</orgName> has taken steps to repair damages to levees on the <placeName reg="Mississippi River" key="tgn,7022231"><rs type="direction">lower</rs> Mississippi river</placeName>, on the ground that <placeName reg="Louisiana, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007256">Louisiana</placeName> and <placeName reg="Mississippi, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007522">Mississippi</placeName> are under martial law. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="733"/> <persName n="Mitchell,General,Robert,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00258" reg="default:Mitchell,Robert,,,"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <foreName>Robert</foreName> <surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="West Virginia" key="tgn,7013961">West Virginia</placeName>, has been appointed Governor of <placeName reg="New Mexico" key="tgn,7007565">New Mexico</placeName>. </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="734"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="13"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="6"/> 
<div2 type="for rent"> 
<head>For rent.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="735"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="lost"> 
<head>Lost, Strayed and found.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="736"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="wants"> 
<head>Wants.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="737"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="shipping"> 
<head>Shipping.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="738"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="drugs"> 
<head>Drugs, Medicines, &#x0026;c.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="739"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> <milestone unit="page" n="4"/> 
<div1 type="page-image"> 
<head></head> 
<p><figure entity="NW_RichTimesD_029_082_004"> <figDesc>Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume <num value="29">29</num>, <num value="82">Number 82</num>, <ref n="page 4">page 4</ref>. </figDesc> </figure></p> </div1> <milestone unit="column" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.</head> 
<div2 type="wednesday"> 
<head><date value="1865-12-13">Wednesday...december 13, 1865.</date></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Illustrative of the <rs>War</rs>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="740"/> --A relic of the past is seen in a man bearing upon his face and body the impress of many years.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="741"/>This man walks the streets daily, bearing the marks of misfortune, amid the friends he had known in better years, but with an appearance so changed <num value="1">one</num> can hardly recognize in him the <name>Mercutio</name> of the <rs type="place">Crescent City</rs>; the gay, witty and elegant gentleman who was at <num value="1">one</num> time the very leader of fashion.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="742"/>Seedy habiliments, a bent body and wrinkled face, have nearly obliterated all in him that was familiar in the past.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="743"/>Inheriting a great fortune, he increased it largely by marriage, and from his profession at the bar had an income of <num value="40">forty</num> or <num value="50000">fifty thousand</num> a year, and received a single free of <measure n="60000dollars" type="currency">sixty thousand dollars</measure> upon a claim on <rs n="real estate" type="product">real estate</rs> in the lower part of the city. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="744"/> This wealth he scattered with princely generosity and royal profusion.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="745"/>He was a Lucullus at home, and his hospitalities aspired to all the magnificence of the ancient <rs n="Roman" type="ethnic">Roman</rs> noblemen.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="746"/>In <dateStruct value="1837--"><year reg="1837">1837</year></dateStruct> he gave a single soiree that cost <measure n="25000dollars" type="currency">$25,000</measure>, and which exceeded in splendor anything ever before known here.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="747"/>The very floors over which the dancers moved were covered with scenic paintings, the work of the most accomplished artist then in New Orleans; and in the saloon where gaming tables were arranged stood <num value="2">two</num> baskets--<num value="1">one</num> filled with bank notes and the other with gold, for the use of those guests who were unfortunate with the fickle goddess. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="748"/> The dispenser of this gorgeous hospitality is now dependent upon his relatives.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="749"/>He takes his loss with <name>Christian</name> resignation, and does not fly from the world or fall against it, like <persName n="Timon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00259" reg="mostcommon:Timon,nomatch:0"><surname>Timon</surname></persName> of <placeName reg="Athens, Clarke, Georgia" key="tgn,7013329">Athens</placeName>, but moves through the world with a pleasant and urbane manner, as if he had still the princely fortune at command.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="750"/>Such cases as this are common since the war.-- <hi rend="italics"><orgName n="New Orleans Crescent" type="newspaper">New Orleans Crescent</orgName>.</hi> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Discovery of a New process for the <name>Preservation</name> of animal food.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="751"/> --Some <measure n="12months" type="date">twelve months</measure> ago, an association was formed in <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName> to ascertain the best means of supplying the markets with fresh animal food from those counties where it is produced in immense quantities and at little cost.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="752"/>The result of the efforts of this association is stated to be the discovery of a process by which venison, poultry, mutton, beef, and other similar articles, may be preserved in a fresh raw state for an indefinite period, and under all circumstances of climate and temperature.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="753"/>If the <rs>English</rs> statements upon the subject are correct, the application of this new discovery &mdash; which is understood to be patented &mdash; to animal food in <placeName reg="Texas" key="tgn,7007826">Texas</placeName> and the far <rs>West</rs>, and brought, thus preserved, into the great cities and most populous parts of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName>, would be of incalculable benefit to the inhabitants.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="754"/>The capital of the association is very large, and the owner of <num value="1">one</num> of the most extensive estates in <placeName key="tgn,7000490;tgn,2140674" n="0.010 000000.3296	placename;tgn,7000490;australia,Oceania;0.009 000000.2851	placename;tgn,2140674;australia island, madison, louisiana,Madison,Louisiana,United States,North and Central America" reg="australia,Oceania;australia island, madison, louisiana,Madison,Louisiana,United States,North and Central America">Australia</placeName> has offered to supply them with meat of the finest quality at a penny a pound. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="755"/> Not a few people in <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> would like to have the benefits of this discovery, and to eat meat &#x0022;at a penny a pound.&#x0022; </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="756"/> The following is told of <persName n="Magruder,General,J.,B.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00260" reg="default:Magruder,J.,B.,,"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <foreName>J.</foreName> <foreName>B.</foreName> <surname>Magruder</surname></persName>: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="757"/> While retreating from the <rs type="place">Peninsula</rs>, in <dateStruct value="1862--"><year reg="1862">1862</year></dateStruct>, the <rs>General</rs> and his staff stopped at the house of a widow lady, on the road, and engaged dinner.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="758"/>In a few moments <persName n="Phelps,,Jim,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00261" reg="default:Phelps,Jim,,,"><foreName>Jim</foreName> <surname>Phelps</surname></persName>, a Louisiana soldier, accosted the lady with, &#x0022;<rs type="role2">Madam</rs>, can I get dinner?&#x0022; &#x0022;Yes, sir, &#x0022; was the reply, &#x0022;but I am preparing dinner for <persName n="Magruder,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00262" reg="nearbymention:Magruder,J.,B.,,"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Magruder</surname></persName> and staff, and have not room at my table for more; you will have to wait for a <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> table.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="759"/> &#x0022;Very well, madam, thank you,&#x0022; said <persName n="Phelps,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00263" reg="nearbymention:Phelps,Jim,,,"><surname>Phelps</surname></persName>, taking his seat in a position to command a view of the dining room. </p> </q><bibl n="General J. B. Magruder"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="760"/> Watching the movements of the servants, <persName n="Phelps,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00264" reg="nearbymention:Phelps,Jim,,,"><surname>Phelps</surname></persName> waited until the feast was on the table; and while the hostess proceeded to the parlor to announce dinner to the <rs>General</rs> and staff, <persName n="Phelps,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00265" reg="nearbymention:Phelps,Jim,,,"><surname>Phelps</surname></persName> entered the dining-room, and, seating himself at the table, awaited further developments. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="761"/> Upon the entrance of the party of officers, there was found to be seats for all but <num value="1">one</num>, and <num value="1">one</num> politely retired to the parlor to wait.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="762"/>The General took a seat next to <persName n="Phelps,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00266" reg="nearbymention:Phelps,Jim,,,"><surname>Phelps</surname></persName>, and, after the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> course was finished, turning to <persName n="Phelps,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00267" reg="nearbymention:Phelps,Jim,,,"><surname>Phelps</surname></persName>, he inquired: &#x0022;Sir, have you any idea with whom you are dining?&#x0022; &#x0022;No, sir,&#x0022; coolly replied <persName n="Phelps,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00268" reg="nearbymention:Phelps,Jim,,,"><surname>Phelps</surname></persName>. &#x0022;I used to be particular, but since I turned soldier, I don't care a d &mdash; n who I eat with, so that the victuals are clean.&#x0022; </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="763"/> Not content with the usual means of telegraphing, the <orgName n="Richmond Papers" type="newspaper">Richmond papers</orgName> have originated another &#x0022;line,&#x0022; which furnishes them such Northern news as would not be likely to find its way over the wires through the agency of the <rs>Associated Press</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="764"/>On <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> <time>morning</time> they contained, as evidence of the wideawake character of their new agent, a portion of the &#x0022;<rs type="role2">Reverend</rs>&#x0022; <placeName reg="John Chambers">John Chambers</placeName>'s &#x0022;Thanksgiving Sermon,&#x0022; in <placeName reg="Philadelphia, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7014406">Philadelphia</placeName>, on last <dateStruct><day type="name">Thursday</day></dateStruct>.--<hi rend="italics">Washington Chronicle.</hi> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="765"/> The <hi rend="italics">Chronicle</hi> does great injustice to the &#x0022;<placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> papers&#x0022; in the above paragraph.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="766"/>They have &#x0022;originated&#x0022; no telegraphic line for any purpose, much less for the <num value="1">one</num> assumed &mdash; of procuring forbidden news &mdash; but merely publish such dispatches as are forwarded to them, whether from the <num value="1">one</num> line or the other.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="767"/>If we were disposed to be querulous, we might complain of the &#x0022;telegraph lines&#x0022; for furnishing us with articles which we are not at all anxious to pay for; and we are certainly not inclined to be considered as endorsing our telegraphic dispatches, which are received at the office late at night, after everything else in the paper has been put into type. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">A row among soldiers and negroes.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="768"/> --On <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> <time>afternoon</time>, <address><street n="2 Street">Second street</street></address> was the scene of a row, in which Federal soldiers and negroes were the combatants.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="769"/>Our informant tells us that <num value="1">one</num> soldiers &#x0022;coming down&#x0022; the street met another &#x0022;going up&#x0022; the street, when the former rather roughly threw himself against the latter, for which he excused himself by saying, &#x0022;I thought you were a <hi rend="italics">nigger,</hi>&#x0022; whereupon the <num value="2">two</num> fell to fighting.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="770"/>The affray soon attracted a party of negroes, who joined in. Not long, however, says our informant, did the fighting progress before a party of Federal teamsters, with their whips, &#x0022;waded in,&#x0022; cutting and slashing right and left.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="771"/>During the affair the combatants once separated, when the negroes formed a &#x0022;line of battle,&#x0022; which the soldiers immediately charged.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="772"/>The result of the row was certainly <num value="1">one</num> badly bruised head, which, we were told, belonged to the man whose insulting conduct occasioned the disturbance.-- <hi rend="italics"><orgName n="Petersburg Express" type="newspaper">Petersburg Express</orgName>.</hi> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Singular case of murder.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="773"/> --<persName n="Mallory,,Patrick,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00269" reg="default:Mallory,Patrick,,,"><foreName>Patrick</foreName> <surname>Mallory</surname></persName>, a returned soldier, was arrested a few days since on the charge of murdering his wife, <address><street n="Ann street">Ann</street></address>, by shooting her with a musket, at <persName n="Martin,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00270" reg="mostcommon:Martin,nomatch:0"><surname>Martin</surname></persName>'s Corners.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="774"/>It appears that no person saw the act, and <persName n="Mallory,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00271" reg="nearbymention:Mallory,Patrick,,,"><surname>Mallory</surname></persName> relates the circumstances as follows: He was shooting at a mark near the house with a musket, and at <num value="1">one</num> time, as he was about to fire, he observed a dog chasing his cat, and turned to fire at him. Just as he fired, his wife came out of the door, near where the animals were, and the ball struck her in the groin.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="775"/>He picked his wife up and carried her into the house, where she lingered until <time value="5oclock">five o'clock</time> next morning, when she died. --<hi rend="italics"><orgName n="Buffalo Commercial Advertiser" type="newspaper">Buffalo Commercial Advertiser</orgName>.</hi> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="776"/> A very singular case of wife killing occurred in the suburbs of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> recently. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="7"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">News from <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> <placeName reg="Via London">Via London</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="777"/> --A Richmond correspondent of the <orgName n="London Times" type="newspaper">London <hi rend="italics">Times</hi></orgName> says: <q> &#x0022;<rs type="role">Mr.</rs> [i. e., Governor] <persName n="Peirpoint,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00272" reg="mostcommon:Peirpoint,nomatch:0"><surname>Peirpoint</surname></persName> told me a curious circumstance: When the condition of the freedmen was investigated this summer it was found that they had parted with every dollar of Confederate currency almost as soon as it had come into their hands.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="778"/><num value="1">One</num> man in the city had over <measure n="20000dollars" type="currency">twenty thousand dollars</measure>, <measure n="15000dollars" type="currency">fifteen thousand dollars</measure> of which he had hoarded in gold, and <measure n="5000dollars" type="currency">five thousand dollars</measure> in greenbacks.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="779"/>Others had spent their Confederate notes in the purchase of land about the town.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="780"/>These well-to-do negroes had kept stores or amassed money in domestic service, and it is to be wished that their masters had taken as good care of themselves as their servants managed to do.&#x0022;</q> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="8"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Sales of timber Land.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="781"/> --The <placeName reg="Pleasant Valley, Rockingham, Virginia" key="tgn,2113687">Rockingham</placeName> and <placeName reg="Augusta, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002142">Augusta, Virginia</placeName>, land market is very lively.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="782"/>Within the last few days there have been sold to a party of capitalists, from <placeName reg="Carlisle, Cumberland, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7013550">Carlisle, Pennsylvania</placeName>, a tract of <measure n="8000acres" type="area">eight thousand acres</measure> of timber land, belonging to <persName n="Cupp,,D.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00273" reg="default:Cupp,D.,,,"><foreName>D.</foreName> <surname>Cupp</surname></persName>; another, of <measure n="4000acres" type="area">four thousand acres</measure>, belonging to Click and others; another, of <measure n="1400acres" type="area">fourteen hundred acres</measure>, belonging to <orgName><persName n="Almond,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00274" reg="mostcommon:Almond,nomatch:0"><surname>Almond</surname></persName> &#x0026; Co.</orgName> The prices have not yet transpired. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="9"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Smocking Accident.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="783"/> --A man was dreadfully cut a day or <num value="2">two</num> ago by a circular saw, in a mill at <placeName reg="Franklin Depot, Delaware, New York" key="tgn,2338961">Franklin Depot</placeName>, on the line of the <orgName n="Seaboard and Roanoke Railroad" type="railroad">Seaboard and Roanoke railroad</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="784"/>Doubts were entertained of his recovery. </p> </div3> <milestone unit="column" n="2"/> 
<div3 type="article" n="10"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">How the negroes vote.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="785"/> --We clip the following amusing item from a Washington exchange: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="786"/> It is said that <num value="1">one</num> of <persName><roleName n="Uncle">Uncle</roleName> <foreName>Sam</foreName></persName>'s contraband agents in <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> the other day tried about a <num value="1000">thousand</num> of them in the art of voting.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="787"/>He told them they should be allowed to elect a commissioner of their own choice to see to their affairs, and directed them, all of them in favor of a Mr. W. to say &#x0022;aye.&#x0022; <num value="1">One</num> long unearthly yell went up &#x0022;aye, &#x0022; every particular nigger &#x0022;wotting&#x0022; with all his might.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="788"/>Then he told all opposed to <rs type="role">Mr.</rs> W. to vote &#x0022;no,&#x0022; and every darkey &#x0022;woted&#x0022; &#x0022;no&#x0022; <num value="10">ten</num> times harder than ever.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="789"/>Thereupon the agent looked puzzled and grum, and finally swore that the voters ought to be in &mdash; a very warm place. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="11"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps"><persName n="Johns,Bishop,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00275" reg="mostcommon:Johns,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Bishop">Bishop</roleName> <surname>Johns</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Virginia" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>, Officiating in <placeName reg="Maryland" key="tgn,7007516">Maryland</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="790"/> --At the request of <persName n="Whittingham,Bishop,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00276" reg="mostcommon:Whittingham,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Bishop">Bishop</roleName> <surname>Whittingham</surname></persName>, <persName n="Johns,Bishop,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00277" reg="mostcommon:Johns,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Bishop">Bishop</roleName> <surname>Johns</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Virginia" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>, visited this city on thanksgiving day, and in the evening preached in <orgName n="Protestant Episcopal Church" type="church"><persName n="Emanuel,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00278" reg="mostcommon:Emanuel,nomatch:0"><surname>Emanuel</surname></persName> Protestant Episcopal Church</orgName>, and administered the apostolic rite of confirmation to <num value="17">seventeen</num> persons.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="791"/>In the morning, <persName n="Johns,Bishop,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00279" reg="mostcommon:Johns,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Bishop">Bishop</roleName> <surname>Johns</surname></persName> assisted in the communion sacrament.--<hi rend="italics"><placeName reg="Cumberland, Allegany, Maryland" key="tgn,2046811">Cumberland</placeName> (<orgName n="Maryland Union" type="newspaper">Maryland) Union</orgName>.</hi> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="12"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">An old resignation.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="792"/> --<persName n="Scott,Colonel,H.,L.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00280" reg="default:Scott,H.,L.,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Colonel</roleName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <foreName>L.</foreName> <surname>Scott</surname></persName>, whose resignation has recently been accepted by the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>, is the nephew of <persName n="Scott,Lieutenant-General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00281" reg="nearbymention:Scott,H.,L.,,"><roleName n="Lieutenant-General">Lieutenant-General</roleName> <surname>Scott</surname></persName>, and formerly an aide-de-camp on his staff.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="793"/>He received, in <dateStruct value="1861--"><year reg="1861">1861</year></dateStruct>, a leave of absence, with permission to visit <placeName key="tgn,1000003" n="1.000 139" reg="europe,">Europe</placeName>, where he remained during the rebellion.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="794"/><persName n="Scott,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00282" reg="nearbymention:Scott,H.,L.,,"><roleName n="Colonel">Colonel</roleName> <surname>Scott</surname></persName> tendered his resignation, to date back to <date value="1862-10-31">October 31, 1862.</date> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="13"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Broke jail.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="795"/> --On <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> <time>evening</time>, <measure n="5" type="prisoners">five prisoners</measure> escaped from the <rs>Petersburg</rs> jail, and have not been yet recaptured.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="796"/>They were confined in the <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> story, and let themselves down into the court below by means of a rope.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="797"/>Having gained the yard, they found the inner gate open, passed through it, and made their final exit through the wall <hi rend="italics">via</hi> a shell hole. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="14"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="798"/> <persName n="Bedinger,Reverend-Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00283" reg="mostcommon:Bedinger,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Reverend-Mister">Rev. Mr.</roleName> <surname>Bedinger</surname></persName>, formerly of <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName>, has accepted a call as assistant pastor of the <orgName n="Presbyterian Church" type="church">Presbyterian Church</orgName> at <placeName reg="Charles Town, Jefferson, West Virginia" key="tgn,2117756">Charlestown</placeName>, <placeName reg="Jefferson county, West Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002269">Jefferson county, Virginia</placeName>, in place of <persName n="Hopkins,Reverend,A.,C.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00284" reg="default:Hopkins,A.,C.,,"><roleName n="Reverend">the Rev.</roleName> <foreName>A.</foreName> <foreName>C.</foreName> <surname>Hopkins</surname></persName>, who has been called to <placeName reg="Cumberland Courthouse">Cumberland Courthouse</placeName>, <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="799"/><persName n="Dutton,Reverend-Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00285" reg="mostcommon:Dutton,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Reverend-Mister">Rev. Mr.</roleName> <surname>Dutton</surname></persName>, the regular pastor of the church, is in too feeble health for active duty. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="15"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="800"/> <measure n="4126hogsheads" type="mass">Four thousand one hundred and twenty-six hogsheads</measure> of tobacco have been inspected in <placeName reg="Petersburg, Petersburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7014404">Petersburg</placeName> since the <date value="06-01">1st of June</date> last. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="801"/> Regular steamboat communication has been opened between <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName> and <placeName reg="Isle of Wight, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,1002506">Isle of Wight county</placeName>. </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> </body> <back> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="insurance"> 
<head>Insurance Companies.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="802"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="commission"> 
<head>Commission merchants.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="803"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="13"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="14"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="3"/> 
<div2 type="dry goods"> 
<head><rs n="dry goods" type="product">Dry Goods</rs>, Shoes, &#x0026;c.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="804"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="furnishing"> 
<head><rs n="furnishing goods" type="product">Furnishing Goods</rs>.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="business"> 
<head>Business Cards.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="805"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="4"/> 
<div2 type="auction"> 
<head><rs n="auction sales" type="product">Auction sales</rs>--this day.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="806"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="real estate for sale"> 
<head><rs n="real estate" type="product">Real estate</rs> for sale.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="807"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="books"> 
<head>Books, Stationery, &#x0026;c.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="808"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="5"/> 
<div2 type="auction"> 
<head><rs n="auction sales" type="product">Auction sales</rs>--future day.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="809"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="steamers"> 
<head>Steamers.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="810"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="coal"> 
<head>Coal and wood.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="811"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="6"/> 
<div2 type="auction"> 
<head><rs n="auction sales" type="product">Auction sales</rs>--future day.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="812"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="professional"> 
<head><rs n="professional card" type="product">Professional Cards</rs>.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="banks"> 
<head><persName n="Banks,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00286" reg="mostcommon:Banks,nomatch:0"><surname>Banks</surname></persName> and bankers.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="813"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> </back> </text> </TEI.2>
 
