<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> <!DOCTYPE TEI.2 PUBLIC "-//TEI P4//DTD Main DTD Driver File//EN" "http://www.tei-c.org/Guidelines/DTD/tei2.dtd" [ <!ENTITY % TEI.XML "INCLUDE"> <!ENTITY % PersProse PUBLIC "-//Perseus P4//DTD Perseus Prose//EN" "http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/DTD/1.0/PersProse.dtd" > %PersProse; <!NOTATION jpg SYSTEM "JPEG"> <!ENTITY NW_RichTimesD_025_032_001 SYSTEM "NW_RichTimesD_025_032_001.jpg" NDATA jpg> <!ENTITY NW_RichTimesD_025_032_002 SYSTEM "NW_RichTimesD_025_032_002.jpg" NDATA jpg> ]> <TEI.2 id="NW_RichTimesD_025_032"> <teiHeader type="aacr2"> <fileDesc> <titleStmt> <title type="245">The Daily Dispatch: August 6, 1863. </title> <title type="gmd">[Electronic resource] </title> <funder> Institute of Museum and Library Services National Leadership Grant </funder> <respStmt> <resp>Creation of machine-readable version: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> <resp>Creation of digital images: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> <resp>Conversion to Tei.2-conformant markup: </resp> <name>digital Divide Data </name> </respStmt> </titleStmt> <extent>ca. <num value="30">XXX</num> kilobytes </extent> <publicationStmt> <publisher>University of <orgName n="Richmond Library" type="library">Richmond Library</orgName> </publisher> <pubPlace>Richmond, Virginia </pubPlace> <idno type="Url">Nw_richtimesd_025_032</idno> <availability> 
<p>&#x00A9; 2004 by the University of Richmond. </p> 
<p>Url: http://oncampus.Richmond.edu/academics/Library/digital/ </p> </availability> <date> </date> </publicationStmt> <seriesStmt> 
<p>Institute of Museum and Library Services Civil War Newspaper Project </p> </seriesStmt> <notesStmt> <note>page images have been included from the microfilm version. </note> <note>images were scanned with a Sunrise 2000 scanner from microfilm, at 14x reduction ratio at 400 dpi Optical Resolution. Creation Software: Pixel Translations. Pixtiff version 1.135. </note> <note>Ddd note: shipped: 2005_03_25_ddd_url. </note> </notesStmt> <sourceDesc> <biblFull> <titleStmt> <title type="245">The Daily Dispatch: August 6, 1863. </title> <title type="246"><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName> </title> <respStmt> <resp> </resp> <name> </name> </respStmt> </titleStmt> <editionStmt> 
<p> </p> </editionStmt> <extent>2 pages. </extent> <publicationStmt> <publisher>by Cowardin &#x0026; Hammersley. </publisher> <pubPlace>Richmond </pubPlace> <date value="1863-08-06">August 6, 1863</date><idno type="vol">25.32</idno> </publicationStmt> <seriesStmt> <title> </title> </seriesStmt> <notesStmt> <note>microfilm. Ann Arbor, Mi : Proquest. 1 microfilm reel ; 35 mm. </note> </notesStmt> </biblFull> </sourceDesc> </fileDesc> <encodingDesc> <projectDesc> 
<p>Imls Civil War Newspaper Project. </p> </projectDesc> <editorialDecl> 
<p>the images exist as archival Tiff images, with Jpeg versions for internet access. </p> </editorialDecl> <refsDecl> <state unit="article" /> </refsDecl> <classDecl> <taxonomy id="lcsh"> <bibl> <title>Library of Congress subject Headings, </title> <edition>21st edition, 1998</edition> </bibl> </taxonomy> </classDecl> </encodingDesc> <profileDesc> <creation> <date value="1863">1863 </date> </creation> <langUsage> <language id="eng">English </language> </langUsage> 
<textClass> <keywords scheme="lcsh"> 
<list type="simple"> 
<item>Newspapers -- Virginia -- Richmond</item> </list> </keywords> </textClass> </profileDesc> <revisionDesc> <change> <date>September, 2005 </date> <respStmt> <resp>Checker </resp> <name>Grant Dickie, of the University of <orgName n="Richmond Library" type="library">Richmond Library</orgName> </name> </respStmt> 
<item>File checked, not corrected: RETURN TO DDD. Did not key "Runaways" page 2, column 7. 1 article. </item> </change> </revisionDesc> </teiHeader> 
<text id="NW_RichTimesD_025_032T"> <front> <milestone unit="page" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="page-image"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="1"/><figure entity="NW_RichTimesD_025_032_001"> <figDesc>Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume <num value="25">25</num>, <num value="32">Number 32</num>, <ref n="page 1">page 1</ref>. </figDesc> </figure></p> </div1> <titlePage> <docTitle><titlePart type="main"> Daily Dispatch </titlePart> </docTitle> <docImprint> Vol. Xxv &mdash; no.<num value="32">32</num> <pubPlace> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond, Va.</placeName> </pubPlace> <date value="1863-08-06">Thursday, August 6, 1863</date> <persName n="Price,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00001" reg="mostcommon:Price,nomatch:0"><surname>Price</surname></persName> <num value="1">one</num> Cent </docImprint> </titlePage> 
<div1 type="subscription"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName><lb/> by <persName n="Cowardin,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00002" reg="mostcommon:Cowardin,nomatch:0"><surname>Cowardin</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="Hammersley,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00003" reg="mostcommon:Hammersley,nomatch:0"><surname>Hammersley</surname></persName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="2"/>the <rs>Daily Dispatch</rs> is served to subscribers at <num value="6.25">six and A Quarter</num> Cents per week, payable to the <name>Carrier</name> weekly.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="3"/><persName n="Price,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00004" reg="mostcommon:Price,nomatch:0"><surname>Price</surname></persName> for mailing, <measure n="4dollars" type="currency">$4</measure> a year, or <measure n="2.50dollars" type="currency">$2.50</measure> for <measure n="6months" type="date">six months</measure>, in advance.</p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="4"/>the <rs>Semi-Weekly Dispatch</rs> is issued every <dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> and <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> at <measure n="2.00dollars" type="currency">$2.00</measure>, in advance.</p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="5"/>the <rs>Weekly Dispatch</rs> is issued every <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct>, and mailed to subscribers at <measure n="1dollars" type="currency">$1</measure> per annum.</p> </div1> 
<div1 type="advertising"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="6"/> 
<table rows="4" cols="4"> 
<head rend="italics">Terms of Advertising.</head> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <num value="1">1</num> day,</cell><cell><measure n="0.50dollars" type="currency">$0.50</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="5days" type="date">5 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="1.50dollars" type="currency">$1.50</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="2days" type="date">2 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="0.75dollars" type="currency">$0.75</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="5days" type="date">5 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="1.75dollars" type="currency">$1.75</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square <measure n="3days" type="date">3 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="1.00dollars" type="currency">$1.00</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <measure n="12days" type="date">12 days</measure>,</cell><cell><measure n="3.00dollars" type="currency">$3.00</measure></cell></row> 
<row><cell><num value="1">1</num> square <measure n="4days" type="date">4 days</measure></cell><cell><measure n="1.25dollars" type="currency">$1.25</measure></cell><cell><num value="1">1</num> square, <dateStruct value="-1-"><month reg="1">1 month</month></dateStruct>,</cell><cell><measure n="5.00dollars" type="currency">$5.00</measure></cell></row> </table></p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="7"/><hi rend="italics">Larger advertisements in exact properties.</hi></p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="8"/>Advertisements published until forbid, will be charged <measure n="50cents" type="currency">50 cents</measure> per square of <num value="8">eight</num> lines for the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> insertion, and <measure n="25cents" type="currency">25 cents</measure> for each continuance</p> </div1> </front> <body> <milestone unit="column" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head>The Daily Dispatch.</head> 
<div2 type="morning"> 
<head><date value="1863-08-06">Thursday morning...August 6, 1863.</date></head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>Morality and Might the Old World and the <rs>New</rs></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="9"/> The <orgName n="London Times" type="newspaper">London <hi rend="italics">Times</hi></orgName> is pleased to expatiate at much length upon the text of this article &mdash; assuming that <num value="2">two</num> different principles govern the Old World of <placeName key="tgn,1000003" n="1.000 139" reg="europe,">Europe</placeName> and the <rs>New</rs> of the <name>States</name> of the late <name>North</name> <orgName n="American Union" type="newspaper">American Union</orgName>; the former being controlled by <hi rend="smallcaps">Morality,</hi>the latter by <hi rend="smallcaps">Might.</hi> There is little if anything in history, either <rs n="European" type="group">European</rs> or <rs n="American" type="group">American</rs>, to sustain the views of the <hi rend="italics">Times</hi> save that part of the <rs n="American" type="group">American</rs> history which developes the motives and measures which terminated in this war. In <rs n="European" type="group">European</rs> diplomacy <hi rend="smallcaps">Morality </hi> has had the smallest possible share, and we have seldom seen her triumphant save when, by rare good luck, she happened to be on the same side with Might.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="10"/>Power is never just where it has a selfish motive opposed to Justice.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="11"/>The <name>English</name> nation can lay as little claim to credit for Morality as any power on earth.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="12"/>The Old World of which it has been a chief Director of affairs has been the scene of successive national outrages &mdash; a conspicuous <num value="1">one</num> of modern times being the partisan of <placeName key="tgn,7006366" n="1.000 33" reg="polska">Poland</placeName>, to which <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName> was a party.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="13"/>In all the revolutions and vicissitudes of nations of that world, where Might has prevailed, it was as often against Morality as for it. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="14"/> On the other hand, with regard to the <rs>North</rs> <rs n="American" type="group">American</rs> States, the charge of the <hi rend="italics">Times</hi> only holds good with reference to the besotted and brutalized power which now rules in the <rs>Northern States</rs>, and which, by its flagrant outrages upon the <rs>Federal Constitution</rs> and the rights of the <rs>Southern States</rs>, forced a dissolution of the old Union.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="15"/>The States of that Union became independent after a struggle, painful and prolonged, against the injustice of the <hi rend="smallcaps">Might</hi> of <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName>, the mother country.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="16"/>Thus the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> great act of the <orgName n="New world" type="newspaper">New World</orgName> was a triumph in its war for Morality and Right over the injustice and Might of the <rs>Old</rs>. After its triumph the <name>States</name> whose combined efforts achieved the result proceeded to form their own political systems.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="17"/>These, in their very essence, involved the principles of Right and Morality against the doctrine of Might, the power of mere numbers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="18"/>They established separate State Governments, which contained checks and balances for the preservation of Order and protection of Right, and they jointly formed a <orgName n="Confederate Government" type="org">Confederate Government</orgName> with limited powers, in which it was sought, constitutionally, to protect the <name>States</name> and the country against the tyranny of numbers merely.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="19"/>In the election of <rs type="role2">President</rs> the vote was by States.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="20"/>The Legislative Department had its revisory and checkmating body in the <name>Senate</name>, to which each State, irrespective of size, sent <num value="2">two</num> members, and the <rs>President</rs> had the veto power over acts of Congress as a still further protection against the force of numbers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="21"/>The whole system was interwoven with the moral principle &mdash; the safeguards for the protection of the minorities and the localities against the oppression of sectional and numerical power &mdash; Might.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="22"/>It may be said they were not strong or clear enough.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="23"/>We rather think they were, Had they been respected they certainly would have been sufficient, and none, however strong, would have prevailed against that unscrupulous and infatuated sectional majority by which they were trodden into the dust. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="24"/> So that in the political institutions of the <orgName n="New world" type="newspaper">New World</orgName> the moral principle was set up over that of Might.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="25"/>In its history down to the present struggle there is certainly nothing to impeach its integrity in all its foreign relations it acquired no territory by might save that from <placeName reg="Mexico, Mexico, North and Central America" key="tgn,1001893">Mexico</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="26"/>In the war with that nation it had right on its side, and the acquisition of territory was an incident justifiable by the highest examples of the Old World.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="27"/>Its other acquisitions were by purchase; including those from the poor <name>North</name> <rs n="American" type="group">American</rs> <rs n="Indian" type="group">Indians</rs>, in which it deviated from the example of the <hi rend="italics">Times's</hi> own nation, whose Morality it holds up to the admiration of the world ! In the <num value="2" type="ordinal">second</num> war between the <orgName n="New world" type="newspaper">New World</orgName> and Old England, the former was resisting the principle of Might asserted by the latter, against the <name>Moral</name> principle that a man had a right to choose his country and serve under what flag he pleased. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="28"/> The Government of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> in all its relations with the world up to the time of the dissolution of the <rs>Union</rs>, presents the fairest record of all nations.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="29"/>Not an act of injustice stained its pages.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="30"/>Those who shaped its policy and controlled its councils were distinguished Southern statesmen, and to them is chiefly attributable the <name>Morality</name>, the <name>Might</name> and Justice which prevailed. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="31"/> But the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> was doomed to repeat history, and to imitate the Old Word in its many examples that Might makes Right, in order to initiate here a struggle that was to teach them the lesson of Morality.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="32"/>It did this not in its foreign relations, but in its domestic.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="33"/>The besotted power of numbers which became, by peculiarity of pursuits and social condition, centered in the <rs>Northern States</rs>, broke down the barriers of the <rs>Constitution</rs> which had been raised to protect the <name>States</name> and the minorities, and for the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> time involved the <orgName n="New world" type="newspaper">New World</orgName> in that Crime which has so much cursed the <rs>Old</rs>, and which has made <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName> in days gone by conspicuous among the nations &mdash; the crime of substituting the power of Might for that of Right.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="34"/>In this situation of affairs we confess a part of the lecture of the leading journal of <placeName key="tgn,7002445" n="1.000 1835" reg="united kingdom">England</placeName> is applicable to the <orgName n="New world" type="newspaper">New World</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="35"/>It thus truthfully tells the fate which must follow the persistence in the rule of Might by the blind despotism of the <orgName n="Federal Union" type="newspaper">Federal Union</orgName>: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="36"/> &#x0022;If they persist in the rule of might, there is only <num value="1">one</num> result.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="37"/>They will just annihilate <num value="1">one</num> another.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="38"/>A miserable remnant, a ruined country, a relapse into savagery, and other revile unknown and inconceivable will be the only possible result.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="39"/>We see it because we are bystanders and spectators, and because we look on from the vantage ground of our tried communities, our established principles, and our ancient institutions.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="40"/>From this vantage ground, as if from a secure elevation in a wide spread deign, we tell these poor drowning wretches that they have no chance whatever but to forget their dream of infinite numbers, boundless territory, inexhaustible wealth, and Irresistible might, and bow low, like children, to the teaching and arbitration of right.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="41"/>Let them just consider what they ought to do, and what &#x0027;ought&#x0027; means, and they have some chance of getting out of this difficulty without blasting a whole continent.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="42"/>We do not say this is an easy or altogether a pleasant course; but it is the only course which does not lead to utter destruction.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="43"/> But the principle of Morality will prevail in this struggle, and the <rs>South</rs> will vindicate its Right.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="44"/>History is, in our case, merely repeating itself.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="45"/>People that cannot live together must separate.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="46"/>Civilized and manly people will not submit to the despotisms inseparable from large areas of territory controlled by <num value="1">one</num> Government.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="47"/>Morality and Right demand the division of such countries into smaller areas as population increases.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="48"/>All history proves this, and we are repeating history.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="49"/>On this subject we propose to say a word on another day, to assist in some degree to quiet the minds of any who may be uneasy, and of any who look book with regret, considering the present condition as something that was not <unclear></unclear> and that might have been avoided.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="50"/>We are ranging ourselves in the <name>History</name> of the <name>World</name> and Menkied, just where we must <milestone unit="column" n="2"/> be, and are about to report History in the vindication of certain Providential laws which cannot be put aside. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head><persName n="Maffic,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00005" reg="mostcommon:Maffic,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Captain</roleName> <surname>Maffic</surname></persName></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="51"/> This gallant and enterprising officer is a son of the celebrated <rs n="Methodist" type="religion">Methodist</rs> preacher and orator, <persName n="Newlin,Reverend,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00006" reg="default:Newlin,John,,,"><roleName n="Reverend">Rev.</roleName> <foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Newlin</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="52"/><persName n="Moffit,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00007" reg="mostcommon:Moffit,nomatch:0"><surname>Moffit</surname></persName>. He entered the <orgName n="U. S. Navy" type="org">U. S. navy</orgName>, we think, about the year <dateStruct value="1832--"><year reg="1832">1832</year></dateStruct>, and must be now about <measure n="45years" type="date">45 years</measure> old. He was always considered <num value="1">one</num> of the best officers and most high toned gentlemen of the old service.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="53"/>For some years he was connected with the <orgName n="Coast Survey" type="military">Coast Survey</orgName>, and <rs type="role2">Professor</rs> <unclear><persName n="Bache,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00008" reg="mostcommon:Bache,nomatch:0"><surname>Bache</surname></persName></unclear> the head of that Department, declared that if Maffin was taken from him be could not supply his place in the whole navy.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="54"/>He is not only a thorough seaman and game to the back house, but a gentleman of superior intellect, a humorist of rare excellence, and of <num value="1">one</num> of the most delightful of compacious.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="55"/>There is no position in his profession which Maffic is not capable of filling with house and destination. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="56"/> We rejoice to see the hived that the brilliant Confederate captain is playing with <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> commerce.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="57"/>He has made them bleed already nearly to the tune of <num value="10000000">ten millions</num>, which we hope will swell to a <num value="100000000">hundred millions</num> before he has done with them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="58"/>Like his father before him, he has to deal with some hardened sinners; but he generally manages to bring them to the anxious seat and make them how for mercy.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="59"/>Between the <name>Maffits</name>, father and son, the <name>Devil</name> has had a very uneasy time of it, both on land and water.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="60"/><num value="1">One</num> of the orator <rs>Maffit</rs>'s finest pulpit efforts was from the text, &#x0022;Come thou and all thy house into the ark,&#x0022; an invitation which the son extends through the cannon of the <rs>Florida</rs> to all <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> wayfarers upon the ocean.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="61"/>We rejoice at the success which has attended his mission, and hope he will continue to press it with irresistible ardency till the ocean is delivered of the most unclean and nefarious of all its reptiles &mdash; the <name>Sous</name> of the <name>Pilgrims</name>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head>From <orgName n="Army"><persName n="Lee,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00009" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Gen,,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Lee</surname></persName>'s Army</orgName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="62"/> All the information we have from <placeName reg="Virginia" key="tgn,7007919"><rs type="direction">Northern</rs> Virginia</placeName> points to the concentration of the contending forces in the neighborhood of <placeName reg="Fredericksburg, Fredericksburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013943">Fredericksburg</placeName>, the enemy having evidently selected that route for the next &#x0022;On to <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>&#x0022; demonstration. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="63"/> We have a report, which is deemed reliable, that our pickets in the neighborhood of <placeName reg="Staffords Store, Weakley, Tennessee" key="tgn,2101649">Stafford's Store</placeName> were driven in by the enemy on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> <time>afternoon</time>. Another report, not well authenticated, however, states that the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs>, in force, have occupied <placeName reg="Stafford, Stafford, Virginia" key="tgn,2114347">Stafford Heights</placeName>, nearly opposite <placeName reg="Fredericksburg, Fredericksburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013943">Fredericksburg</placeName>.--From present indications it is not improbable that the next trial of strength between the <num value="2">two</num> armies will take place on the old battlefield of <dateStruct value="-12-"><month reg="12">December</month></dateStruct> last. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head>The enemy in <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">James river</placeName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="64"/> We learn that the enemy on <dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> last made his appearance again in <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">James river</placeName>.--On the afternoon of that day <num value="2">two</num> Monitors and <num value="3">three</num> gunboats entered the mouth of the river and proceeded up as far as <placeName key="possibilities=81" n="1.000 10" reg=",">Sandy Point</placeName>, where they anchored for the night.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="65"/>Of their movements yesterday we heard nothing, but it is not believed that the expedition contemplates more than a negro stealing affair. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<argument> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="66"/> Army Correspondence the fight in <placeName reg="Culpeper, Culpeper, Virginia" key="tgn,2111394">Culpeper</placeName> &mdash; another crossing by the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> at <unclear> </unclear> &#x0026;c. </p> </argument> 
<div4 type="entry" n="1"> 
<head>[special Correspondence of the <name>Dispatch</name>]</head> <opener> <dateline> Army <placeName reg="Virginia" key="tgn,7007919">Northern Virginia</placeName>, <dateStruct value="1863-08-03"><month reg="08">August</month> <day reg="3">3d</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="67"/> <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time> last a force of the enemy's cavalry, estimated at <num value="3">three</num> brigades, crossed, or were reported to be crossing, the <rs>Rappahannock</rs> at <placeName reg="Kelly's Ford, Culpeper, Virginia" key="tgn,2112479">Kelly's Ford</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="68"/><placeName reg="Hampton, Hampton, Virginia" key="tgn,7013687">Hampton</placeName>'s <orgName n="Cavalry Brigade" type="brigade">cavalry brigade</orgName> were on picket at the time, their line extending from <persName n="Kelly,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00010" reg="mostcommon:Kelly,nomatch:0"><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>'s to <placeName reg="Beverly's Ford">Beverly's Ford</placeName>.--By morning the entire <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> force engaged were across, and began a bold advance towards <placeName reg="Brandy Station, Culpeper, Virginia" key="tgn,2110767">Brandy Station</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="69"/>Their force greatly outnumbering ours, <placeName reg="Hampton, Hampton, Virginia" key="tgn,7013687">Hampton</placeName>'s brigade commenced falling back slowly, the pickets having been previously driven by the enemy back to the main body.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="70"/>After falling back a mile or more, the brigade halted and checked the enemy's advance for a considerable time.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="71"/>The enemy's movements were covered, in a measure, by woods, of which they availed themselves; but whenever the opportunity and ground favored, were frequently and most gallantly charged by our regiments and driven back. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="72"/> The day thus passed with successive skirmishing, fighting, and charging, until between <time value="4">four</time> and <time value="5pm">five o'clock P. M.</time>, when within about a mile and <num value="0.5">a half</num> of <placeName reg="Culpeper, Culpeper, Virginia" key="tgn,2111394">Culpeper</placeName> <num value="2">two</num> regiments of infantry from <orgName n="division"><persName n="Anderson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00011" reg="mostcommon:Anderson,nomatch:0"><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>'s division</orgName> &mdash; the <orgName type="regiment" key="VA12">12th Va.</orgName>, of <orgName n="brigade"><persName n="Mahone,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00012" reg="mostcommon:Mahone,nomatch:0"><surname>Mahone</surname></persName>'s brigade</orgName>, and the <num value="2" type="ordinal">2d</num> <rs type="role2">Miss</rs>, of <orgName n="brigade"><persName n="Posey,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00013" reg="mostcommon:Posey,nomatch:0"><surname>Posey</surname></persName>'s brigade</orgName> &mdash; were thrown out as skirmishers, and advanced to the support of our cavalry.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="73"/>The <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> perceiving these supports coming up, &#x0022;about-faced&#x0022; and &#x0022;skedaddled&#x0022; across an open field, or other open space of ground, in our front.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="74"/>The pursuit was continued until the enemy escaped out of sight, and, it is believed, recrossed the river that night. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="75"/> We had not more than <num value="1">one</num> battery of artillery engaged, which poured at intervale a number of rounds of grape and cannister into the enemy's ranks with great effect.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="76"/><num value="6">Six</num> or <num value="8">eight</num> of our artillerymen were wounded, <num value="3">three</num> of them mortally.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="77"/>The <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> had at least <num value="2">two</num> batteries engaged; but most of the casualties among our men were caused by their sharpshooters, their artillery on this occasion having been an ineffective auxiliary.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="78"/>It is alleged that our artillery would have done greater execution but for the deficiency of rifle ammunition provided. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="79"/> <persName n="Hampton,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00014" reg="mostcommon:Hampton,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Hampton</surname></persName> being yet disabled from returning to the field by his wound, the brigade, as you have probably learned, was commanded and admirably handled by <persName n="Baker,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00015" reg="mostcommon:Baker,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Baker</surname></persName>, of the <orgName type="regiment" key="1NCRegiment">1st North Carolina regiment</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="80"/>Our loss is, at this writing, unknown, but will probably be covered by <num value="75">75</num> or <measure n="100" type="killed and wounded">100 killed and wounded</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="81"/> The purpose of this movement was a reconnaissance, doubtless, to feel the position of our army. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="82"/> Excepting this spirited affair the period elapsed since the <num value="2">two</num> armies entered the section they now occupy has been unprolific of important news that could be communicated with propriety.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="83"/>In <placeName key="tgn,1002368" n="1.000 18" reg="fauquier, virginia, united states">Fauquier</placeName> and <placeName reg="Culpeper, Culpeper, Virginia" key="tgn,2111394">Culpeper</placeName> the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> have freely indulged their devilish proclivities.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="84"/>Their depredations extended to the destruction of growing and harvested crops of grain, and the shooting of cattle, mules, horses, and everything of the kind &mdash; Such has been their course, it is reported, since they reinvade the <rs>State</rs>, which, it is hoped, will be the last time. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="85"/> They have rebuilt the bridge at <orgName n="Rappahannock Station" type="station">Rappahannock Station</orgName>, where the <orgName n="Orange and Alexandria Railroad" type="railroad">Orange and Alexandria railroad</orgName> crossed the river, and are said to be running trains regularly. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="86"/> Meads seems to be proceeding with great caution in his movements, so much so as not to have yet developed his designs fully.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="87"/>Whenever and wherever he may decide to join the fearful issue of battle, he will find <persName n="Lee,,Gen,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00016" reg="default:Lee,Gen,,,"><foreName>Gen</foreName> <surname>Lee</surname></persName> on the <hi rend="italics">qui vive,</hi> as usual, and prepared to meet him. Our gallant men are now on their own soil, and well may Meads be cautious how he risked the already precarious tenure of his position. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="88"/> All has been quiet since <dateStruct><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct>, and nothing from the enemy except a report that they have occupied <placeName reg="Culpeper Court House">Culpeper C. H.</placeName> in force. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="2"> 
<head></head> <opener> <dateline> <dateStruct value="1863-08-04"><month reg="08">August</month> <day reg="4">4th</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="89"/> A body of the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> cavalry crossed the river at <placeName key="tgn,2113994" n="1.000 4" reg="rixeyville, culpeper, virginia">Rixeyville</placeName> early this morning, and were repaired by the <orgName type="regiment" key="11VARegiment">11th Va. regiment</orgName>, on picket of the time.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="90"/><persName n="Stuart,,Gen,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00017" reg="default:Stuart,Gen,,,"><foreName>Gen</foreName> <surname>Stuart</surname></persName> attacked them in the afternoon and drove them back to the river.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="91"/>They had artillery planted on the other side of the river.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="92"/>No further particulars yet. </p> </div4> </div3> <milestone unit="column" n="3"/> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head>Later from the <rs>North</rs>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="93"/> We are indebted to the courtesy of <persName n="Hatch,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00018" reg="mostcommon:Hatch,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Capt.</roleName> <surname>Hatch</surname></persName>, of the <rs type="place">Bureau of Exchange</rs>, for a copy of the <orgName n="New York World" type="newspaper">New York <hi rend="italics">World</hi></orgName>, of the addust.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="94"/>The usual exchange of files has not been recommended as yet by the <rs type="role" reg="U. S. Commissioner">U. S. Commissioner</rs>, <persName n="Meredith,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00019" reg="mostcommon:Meredith,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Meredith</surname></persName>, who takes the place of <persName n="Ludlow,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00020" reg="mostcommon:Ludlow,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Ludlow</surname></persName>. </p> 
<div4 type="entry" n="1"> 
<head>The <orgName n="Army of the Potomac" type="army">Army of the Potomac</orgName>--a fight and Discovery of Gen Let's position</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="95"/>The <hi rend="italics">World</hi> says that the reconnaissance made on Friday by <orgName n="cavalry"><persName n="Buford,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00021" reg="mostcommon:Buford,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Buford</surname></persName>'s cavalry</orgName> across the <rs>Rappahannock</rs> resulted in a sharp fight, with considerable loss on both sides.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="96"/>The whereabouts of the rebel army were found to be between the <rs>Rapidan</rs> and the <rs>Rappahannock</rs>, with <placeName><persName n="Lee,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00022" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Gen,,,"><surname>Lee</surname></persName>'s headquarters</placeName> at <placeName key="tgn,2114382" n="1.000 36" reg="stevensburg, culpeper, virginia">Stevensburg</placeName>, <placeName><distance reg="4miles">four miles</distance> from <placeName reg="Culpeper, Culpeper, Virginia" key="tgn,2111394">Culpeper</placeName></placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="97"/>The Confederates have a very strong picket line across the <rs>Rappahannock</rs>, but do not seem to be in any considerable force as far up as <placeName reg="Fredericksburg, Fredericksburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013943">Fredericksburg</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="98"/>The following dispatch from <persName n="Washington,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00023" reg="mostcommon:Washington,nomatch:0"><surname>Washington</surname></persName>, <date value="08-02">August 2d,</date> gives an account of the reconnaissance: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="99"/> <orgName n="cavalry"><persName n="Buford,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00024" reg="mostcommon:Buford,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Buford</surname></persName>'s cavalry</orgName>, artillery, and a supporting infantry force, yesterday crossed the <rs>Rappahannock</rs> at the railroad station.--Thence with his cavalry and artillery he proceeded toward <placeName reg="Culpeper, Culpeper, Virginia" key="tgn,2111394">Culpeper</placeName>, driving <orgName n="cavalry"><persName n="Stuart,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00025" reg="nearbymention:Stuart,Gen,,,"><surname>Stuart</surname></persName>'s cavalry</orgName> before him. When near <placeName reg="Culpeper, Culpeper, Virginia" key="tgn,2111394">Culpeper</placeName> <persName n="Raford,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00026" reg="mostcommon:Raford,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen'l</roleName> <surname>Raford</surname></persName> encountered a large rebel force of infantry and artillery, and a fierce light ensued, lasting until dark, when he withdrew to a strong position east of <placeName reg="Beandy Station">Beandy Station</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="100"/>The losses on both sides was considerable.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="101"/>This reconnaissance confirms the concentration of <persName n="Lee,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00027" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Gen,,,"><surname>Lee</surname></persName>'s forces near <placeName reg="Culpeper, Culpeper, Virginia" key="tgn,2111394">Culpeper</placeName>, and indicates that his present headquarters are at <placeName key="tgn,2114382" n="1.000 36" reg="stevensburg, culpeper, virginia">Stevensburg</placeName>, <placeName><distance reg="4miles">four miles</distance> <offset>southeast</offset> of  <placeName reg="Culpeper, Culpeper, Virginia" key="tgn,2111394">Culpeper</placeName></placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="102"/>The <num value="29">twenty nine</num> sutler wagon captured near <placeName reg="Fairfax, Fairfax, Virginia" key="tgn,7014159">Fairfax</placeName> <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Thursday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time> by <persName n="Mosby,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00028" reg="mostcommon:Mosby,nomatch:0"><surname>Mosby</surname></persName> and his band were recaptured, with all their contents, <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct> <time>morning</time>, near Aldle, by the <orgName type="regiment" key="2MACav">2d Massachusetts cavalry</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="103"/>A skirmish ensured between the guerillas and our advance guard, but on the approach of the main body <persName n="Mosby,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00029" reg="mostcommon:Mosby,nomatch:0"><surname>Mosby</surname></persName> fled, closely pursued by the cavalry.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="104"/>Several of the enemy are reported killed and wounded but no report has been received of the result of the pursuit.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="105"/>This morning a detachment of our cavalry <measure n="2" type="killed">killed two</measure> and <measure n="2" type="captured">captured two</measure> others of <persName n="Mosby,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00030" reg="mostcommon:Mosby,nomatch:0"><surname>Mosby</surname></persName>'s band near New Baltimore, and were engaged in ferreting out others.--Yesterday and to-day the weather has been by far the hottest of the season.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="106"/>All quiet to-night. </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="107"/> Another dispatch says: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="108"/>The rebel forces are still between the <rs>Rapidan</rs> and the <rs>Rappahannock</rs>, and have made no movement eastward.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="109"/>It is not true that our forces occupy the city of <placeName reg="Fredericksburg, Fredericksburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013943">Fredericksburg</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="110"/>The weather has been intensely hot where the army is stationed during the past <measure n="2days" type="date">two days</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="111"/> <persName n="Lovell,Lieutenant-Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00031" reg="mostcommon:Lovell,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lieutenant-Colonel">Lieut Col.</roleName> <surname>Lovell</surname></persName>, of the <orgName type="regiment" key="2MARegiment">Second Massachusetts regiment</orgName>, has recaptured all prisoners, wagons, supplies, &#x0026;c., taken by <persName n="Mosby,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00032" reg="mostcommon:Mosby,nomatch:0"><surname>Mosby</surname></persName>'s guerillas at <placeName reg="Fairfax, Fairfax, Virginia" key="tgn,7014159">Fairfax</placeName> on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Thursday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time>. The rebel escape was out off, and for the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> time <persName n="Mosby,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00033" reg="mostcommon:Mosby,nomatch:0"><surname>Mosby</surname></persName> has been thwarted in his bold and desperate raids.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="112"/>The value of the goods, horses, &#x0026;c., recaptured, which mostly belonged to suiters, is estimated at <measure n="150000dollars" type="currency">$150,000</measure>. </p> </q><bibl n="Another dispatch"></bibl></cit> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="2"> 
<head>Protection to negro soldiers &mdash; retaliation.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="113"/> A telegram from <persName n="Washington,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00034" reg="mostcommon:Washington,nomatch:0"><surname>Washington</surname></persName> gives the following official order of <persName n="Lincoln,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00035" reg="nearbymention:Lincoln,Abraham,,,"><surname>Lincoln</surname></persName> on the subject of negro soldiers in the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> army and their treatment: </p> 
<div5 type="letter" n="1"> 
<head><hi rend="smallcaps">War Dep't, <orgName><rs type="role" reg="Adjutant-General">Adj General</rs>'s office</orgName>,</hi> <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>, <date value="07-31">July 31.</date></head> <opener> <salute><rs n="General Order" type="misc">General Order</rs> No. <num value="252">252</num>.</salute> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="114"/> The following order of the <rs>President</rs> is published for the information and government of all concerned: </p> </div5> 
<div5 type="letter" n="2"> 
<head></head> <opener> <dateline> <placeName reg="Executive Mansion">Executive Mansion</placeName>. <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>, <dateStruct value="-07-30"><month reg="07">July</month> <day reg="30">30</day></dateStruct> </dateline> </opener> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="115"/> It is the <unclear></unclear> of every Government to give protection to its citizens, of whatever class, color, or condition, and especially to those who are duly organized as soldiers in the public service.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="116"/>The law of nations, and the usages and custom of war, as carried on by civilized powers, permit no distinction as to color in the treatment of prisoners of war as public enemies.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="117"/>To sell or enslave any captured person on account of his color and for no offence against the laws of war, is a relapse into barbarism, and a crime against the civilization of the age. The Government of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> will give the same protection to all its soldiers, and if the enemy shall sell or enslave any <num value="1">one</num> because of his color, the offence shall be punished by retaliation upon the enemy's prisoners in our possession.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="118"/>It is therefore ordered, that for every soldier of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> killed in violation of the laws of war, a rebel soldier shall be executed; and for every <num value="1">one</num> enslaved by the enemy, or sold into slavery, a rebel soldier shall be placed at hard labor on the <orgName n="Public Works" type="works">public works</orgName>, and continue at such labor until the other shall be released, and receive the treatment our to a prisoner of war. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Lincoln,,Abraham,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00036" reg="default:Lincoln,Abraham,,,"><foreName>Abraham</foreName>  <surname>Lincoln</surname></persName>.</signed> <lb/> By order of the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>. <lb/> <signed>E <persName n="Townsend,,D.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00037" reg="default:Townsend,D.,,,"><foreName>D.</foreName> <surname>Townsend</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> <rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Adjutant-General">Assistant Adjt. General</rs>. </closer> </div5> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="3"> 
<head>The draft in <placeName reg="Illinois" key="tgn,7007251"><rs type="direction">Southern</rs> Illinois</placeName>--a Congress man arrested</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="119"/> A dispatch from <placeName reg="Cairo Junction, Alexander, Illinois" key="tgn,7018995">Cairo</placeName>, Ill, dated the <dateStruct value="--2"><day reg="2">2nd inst.</day></dateStruct>, gives the following about the enrollment for the draft in the <rs>Southern</rs> part of that State: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="120"/> <persName n="Phillips,Provost Marshal,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00038" reg="mostcommon:Phillips,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Provost Marshal">Provost Marshal</roleName> <surname>Phillips</surname></persName> has completed the enrollment in the <orgName type="district" n="district 13">13th district</orgName> of this State, and is prepared to make a draft as soon as directed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="121"/>He enrolled about <num value="18000">18,000</num> names, and arrested a large number of deserters.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="122"/>He was obliged to place the town of <placeName reg="Marion, Smyth, Virginia" key="tgn,2112906">Marion</placeName>, the residence of <persName n="Allen,Congressman,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00039" reg="mostcommon:Allen,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Congressman">Congressman</roleName> <surname>Allen</surname></persName>, under martial law. Pickets were stationed around the town, and orders issued preventing persons leaving the place without passes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="123"/><persName n="Allen,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00040" reg="mostcommon:Allen,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Allen</surname></persName> attempted to pass the guards, and was brought before <persName n="Phillips,Provost Marshal,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00041" reg="mostcommon:Phillips,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Provost Marshal">Provost Marshal</roleName> <surname>Phillips</surname></persName>, where he demanded to know if a Congressman was obliged to obey the orders of a petty <rs type="role" reg="Provost Marshal">Provost-Marshal</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="124"/>He was told all were subject to enrollment, and no <num value="1">one</num> could receive a pass without taking the oath of allegiance to the <orgName n="U. S. Government" type="org">United States Government</orgName>, which he refused to do on the ground that it would compromise him with his constituents and force him to violate certain pledges he had made.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="125"/>He therefore remains an involuntary prisoner within the limits of <placeName reg="Marion, Smyth, Virginia" key="tgn,2112906">Marion</placeName>. </p> </q><bibl n="A dispatch from Cairo, Ill"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="126"/> A dispatch from <persName n="Washington,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00042" reg="mostcommon:Washington,nomatch:0"><surname>Washington</surname></persName>, dated the <dateStruct value="--2"><day reg="2">2d inst.</day></dateStruct>, says: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="127"/> It may be stated on excellent authority that the draft will commence in New York during the earlier part of next week, and be as fully carried out from that time forward as it will be in <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName>, where it will go on at the same time.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="128"/>The authorities are understood to have all the enrollment lists, &#x0026;c., ready to proceed at once.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="129"/>It is believed that there will be no longer any delay anywhere in the country in executing the draft. </p> </q><bibl n="A dispatch from Washington"></bibl></cit> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="4"> 
<head>Temporary Abandonment of the assault on <orgName n="Battery Wagner" type="battery">battery Wagner</orgName>--<placeName key="tgn,7013582" n="1.000 46" reg="charleston, charleston, south carolina">Fort Sumter</placeName> to Reforest reduced.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="130"/> Advices from <placeName reg="Charleston, Charleston, South Carolina" key="tgn,7013582">Charleston</placeName> to the <dateStruct value="--29"><day reg="29">29th ult.</day></dateStruct>, received in New York by the <term type="ship">transport</term> <rs type="ship">Belvidere</rs>, state that <persName n="Gilmore,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00043" reg="mostcommon:Gilmore,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Gilmore</surname></persName> had succeeded in creating a long line of batteries within <placeName><distance reg="250yards">250 yards</distance> of <placeName key="tgn,2525074" n="1.000 107" reg="morris island, charleston, south carolina">Fort Wagner</placeName></placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="131"/>He had also mounted <num value="3">three</num> heavy siege guns within a mile and <num value="0.25">a quarter</num> of <placeName key="tgn,7013582" n="1.000 46" reg="charleston, charleston, south carolina">Fort Sumter</placeName>, which were to open fire on <placeName key="tgn,2096786" n="1.000 14" reg="sumter, sumter, south carolina">Sumter</placeName> on <dateStruct><day type="name">Wednesday</day></dateStruct> last.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="132"/><num value="2">Two</num> monitors and the <rs>Ironsides</rs> were engaging <placeName key="tgn,2525074" n="1.000 107" reg="morris island, charleston, south carolina">Fort Wagner</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="133"/>The <hi rend="italics">World</hi> says: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="134"/> No engagement of any account has taken place since the assault of the <date value="07-19">19th of July</date> upon <placeName key="tgn,2525074" n="1.000 107" reg="morris island, charleston, south carolina">Fort Wagner</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="135"/>Our losses since that time have not averaged more than <num value="4">four</num> per day. <persName n="Gilmore,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00044" reg="mostcommon:Gilmore,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Gilmore</surname></persName> has now <num value="14">fourteen</num> <persName n="Parrott,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00045" reg="mostcommon:Parrott,nomatch:0"><surname>Parrott</surname></persName> guns and mortars in position on <persName n="Morris,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00046" reg="mostcommon:Morris,nomatch:0"><surname>Morris</surname></persName>'s island.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="136"/>For the present, the idea of taking <placeName key="tgn,2525074" n="1.000 107" reg="morris island, charleston, south carolina">Fort Wagner</placeName> has been abandoned &mdash; shells making but alight impression upon the sand of which that work is composed; the breach made by <num value="1">one</num> shall being soon filled up by the explosion of another.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="137"/><persName n="Gilmore,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00047" reg="mostcommon:Gilmore,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Gilmore</surname></persName> is confident that with his heavy siege guns he can breach <placeName key="tgn,7013582" n="1.000 46" reg="charleston, charleston, south carolina">Fort Sumter</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="138"/> The <orgName type="regiment" key="10CTRegiment">10th Connecticut regiment</orgName> occupies the riffe-pite within <placeName><distance reg="250yards">250 yards</distance> of <placeName reg="Fort Wagnes">Fort Wagnes</placeName></placeName>. --<persName n="Otin,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00048" reg="mostcommon:Otin,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Otin</surname></persName>, of this regiment, came here on the <rs>Belvidere</rs> for the purpose of taking drafted men. The <rs>Belvidere</rs> has on board the <orgName type="regiment" key="174PARegiment">174th Pennsylvania regiment</orgName> numbering <num value="417">417</num> noncommissioned <unclear></unclear> and privates, whose term of service has expired. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="139"/> The <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> <term type="ship">steam transport</term> <rs type="ship">Fulton</rs>, <milestone unit="column" n="4"/> <persName n="Eldridge,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00049" reg="mostcommon:Eldridge,nomatch:0"><surname>Eldridge</surname></persName>, from <placeName reg="Port Royal, Beaufort, South Carolina" key="tgn,2096511">Port Royal, S. C.</placeName>, <date value="07-31">July 31st,</date> reached here last evening.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="140"/>The siege of <placeName key="tgn,2525074" n="1.000 107" reg="morris island, charleston, south carolina">Fort Wagner</placeName> still continued.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="141"/><persName n="Gilmore,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00050" reg="mostcommon:Gilmore,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Gilmore</surname></persName> has mounted a number of <num value="200">200</num> pounder siege guns within <placeName><distance reg="1mile">one mile</distance> of <placeName key="tgn,7013582" n="1.000 46" reg="charleston, charleston, south carolina">Fort Sumter</placeName></placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="142"/>He is confident of reducing both <placeName key="tgn,7013582" n="1.000 46" reg="charleston, charleston, south carolina">Sumter</placeName> and <persName n="Wagner,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00051" reg="mostcommon:Wagner,nomatch:0"><surname>Wagner</surname></persName> in a short time. </p> </q><bibl n="World"></bibl></cit> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="5"> 
<head>Outrage on Confederate officers &mdash; Morgat treated as a Convict.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="143"/> The <orgName n="New York World" type="newspaper">New York <hi rend="italics">World</hi></orgName>, of <dateStruct><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct>, has an editorial on the conduct of <persName n="Burnsides,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00052" reg="mostcommon:Burnsides,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Burnsides</surname></persName>, from which we learn that <persName n="Morgan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00053" reg="mostcommon:Morgan,nomatch:0"><surname>Morgan</surname></persName> and his officers, now in the <rs>Ohio</rs> penitentiary, are treated like convicts, and their heads have been shaved.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="144"/>The following is a paragraph: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="145"/> After several months of junketing, his army finally moved out to the <placeName key="tgn,1125516" n="1.000 12" reg="kentucky, kentucky, united states">Kentucky river</placeName>, but never came near an enemy.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="146"/>The only enemy in <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName> was allowed to pass directly through the <rs>State</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="147"/>In the face of <persName n="Burnside,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00054" reg="nearbymention:Burnside,Gen,,,"><surname>Burnside</surname></persName> and of all his troops, <persName n="Morgan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00055" reg="mostcommon:Morgan,nomatch:0"><surname>Morgan</surname></persName> was permitted to ride by him almost unmolested, and to cross into <placeName reg="Indiana" key="tgn,7007252">Indiana</placeName> and <placeName reg="Ohio" key="tgn,7007706">Ohio</placeName>, and not until the citizens of those States hadrailled in sufficient numbers was the bold marauder captured.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="148"/>But if <persName n="Burnside,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00056" reg="nearbymention:Burnside,Gen,,,"><surname>Burnside</surname></persName> had nothing to do with catching the hare, <unclear></unclear> upon his light to cook it when caught. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="149"/> The commander of the <orgName n="Department of the Ohio" type="department">Department of the Ohio</orgName> <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> appears in the field as a barber and jailor.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="150"/>He orders the captured officers <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> to the city prison of <placeName reg="Cincinnati, Hamilton, Ohio" key="tgn,7013604">Cincinnati</placeName> and afterward to the <rs>Ohio</rs> penitentiary, <hi rend="italics">Where they are subjected to the indignity of having their heads shaved.</hi> Such a preceding is as unworthy of a great nation or its representatives as it is unwarrantable by all the laws of war. it is perfectly right of course that these officers should be detained as hostages for <persName n="Streight,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00057" reg="mostcommon:Streight,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Colonel</roleName> <surname>Streight</surname></persName>'s party, captured in <placeName reg="Georgia" key="tgn,7007248">Georgia</placeName>, but <persName n="Straight,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00058" reg="mostcommon:Straight,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Col.</roleName> <surname>Straight</surname></persName> is in the <rs type="place">Libby prison</rs>, treated as all other officers are treated.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="151"/>The cases are so nearly alike that they are naturally suggestive offeets of each other.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="152"/>And if we mistake not greatly, this cruelty towards <persName n="Morgan,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00059" reg="mostcommon:Morgan,nomatch:0"><surname>Morgan</surname></persName> will but though rate a fresh and painful retaliation upon our prisoners in <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>. </p> </q><bibl n="New York World"></bibl></cit> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="6"> 
<head>Burnside Proclaims martial law in <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName> on the <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Ky.</placeName>, of the election no disloyal.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="153"/>Persons to be allowed to vote.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="154"/> The State election in <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName> was in take place on <dateStruct><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct> last.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="155"/>A telegram from <placeName reg="Cincinnati, Hamilton, Ohio" key="tgn,7013604">Cincinnati</placeName>, dated the <num value="31" type="ordinal">31st</num>, gives the following action of <persName n="Burnside,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00060" reg="nearbymention:Burnside,Gen,,,"><surname>Burnside</surname></persName> in the premises: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="156"/> <persName n="Burnside,Major-General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00061" reg="nearbymention:Burnside,Gen,,,"><roleName n="Major-General">major General</roleName> <surname>Burnside</surname></persName> has issued an order declaring the <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">State of Kentucky</placeName> invaded by a rebel force, with the avowed intention of overawing the <rs>Judges</rs> of Elections, intimidating loyal voters and keeping them from the polls, and forcing the election of disloyal candidates at the election on the <num value="31">31</num> proximo.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="157"/>The military of the <rs>Government</rs>, the order declares, is the only force that can defeat this attempt, and the <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">State of Kentucky</placeName> is therefore placed under martial law. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="158"/> All <rs type="role" reg="military-Officer">military officers</rs> are commanded to aid the constituted authorities of the <rs>State</rs> in the support of the laws and the purity of suffrage.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="159"/>The legally appointed Judges of the polls will be held strictly responsible that no disloyal person be allowed to vote, and to this end the military power of the <rs>Government</rs> is ordered to give them its utmost support. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="160"/> The <orgName n="New York World" type="newspaper">New York <hi rend="italics">World</hi></orgName> thus comments on this action: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="161"/> The coincidence of <persName n="Burnside,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00062" reg="nearbymention:Burnside,Gen,,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Burnside</surname></persName>'s demonstration in <placeName reg="Kentucky" key="tgn,7007255">Kentucky</placeName> against the freedom of election, with the extraordinary discrimination made under the draft in this State against the <rs>Democratic</rs> districts, demands attention, and goes alarmingly for toward giving color to the charge that the party in power are determined to <unclear></unclear> the bayonet against the ballot all over the <rs>Union</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="162"/> We await fuller explanations than we yet have of the former proceeding, of its motives and of its bearings, and the latter may be at once explained by the simple process of <unclear></unclear> the military <unclear></unclear> upon the people of <rs n="Delaware" type="nativeamerican">Delaware</rs> at the election in that State we cannot pronounce the suspicious which more recent events have awakened to be utterly unreasonable. </p> </q><bibl n="New York World"></bibl></cit> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="7"> 
<head>Important from <placeName reg="Mexico, Mexico, North and Central America" key="tgn,1001893">Mexico</placeName> &mdash; French Reinforcements, <num value="10000">10,000</num> strong expected at <placeName key="tgn,7007127" n="1.000 1" reg="acapulco de juarez,guerrero,mexico,north and central america">Acapulco</placeName> &mdash; all the <rs n="Mexican" type="group">Mexican</rs> Ports to be Garrisoned <num value="7000">7,000</num> <name>French</name> troops reported to be Marching on <placeName key="tgn,1017836" n="1.000 1" reg="matamoros,tamaulipas,mexico,north and central america">Matamoros</placeName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="163"/> Advices from the <rs type="place">City of Mexico</rs> are to <date value="06-25">June 25th.</date> <persName n="Alvarez,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00063" reg="mostcommon:Alvarez,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Alvarez</surname></persName>, from whom accounts are received to the <dateStruct value="--30"><day reg="30">30th inst.</day></dateStruct>, was expecting the arrival at <placeName key="tgn,7007127" n="1.000 1" reg="acapulco de juarez,guerrero,mexico,north and central america">Acapulco</placeName> of the <orgName n="French fleet" type="fleet">French fleet</orgName>, with <num value="10000">10,000</num> soldiers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="164"/>This force is to come from the <placeName reg="Gulf of Mexico" key="tgn,7021009">Gulf of Mexico</placeName> across Tehuantepec, and from <placeName key="tgn,7007127" n="1.000 1" reg="acapulco de juarez,guerrero,mexico,north and central america">Acapulco</placeName> will be dispatched for garrisons for all the <rs n="Mexican" type="group">Mexican</rs> Pacific port.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="165"/>A letter, dated <placeName reg="New Matamoras, Washington, Ohio" key="tgn,2081017">Matamoras</placeName>, <date value="06-16">June 16th;</date> says: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="166"/> There is a rumor here that <num value="7000">seven thousand</num> <name>French</name> soldiers are on the way here from <placeName reg="Veracruz, Mexico, North and Central America" key="tgn,7005599">Vera Cruz</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="167"/>It needs confirmation.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="168"/>If true, the authorities will endeavor to meet and fight them with such force as they can collect.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="169"/>They will surely dispute with an earnest struggle for the possession of Tamaulipas and of course this most important town would be the principal prize to be fought for. The <rs n="Mexican" type="group">Mexicans</rs> are resolute, and will fight the <rs>French</rs> to the last.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="170"/>They are united here in their opposition to the invaders.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="171"/><persName n="Miramon,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00064" reg="mostcommon:Miramon,nomatch:0"><surname>Miramon</surname></persName> is the lion of <placeName key="tgn,7013459" n="1.000 16" reg="brownsville, cameron, texas">Fort Brown</placeName> of late.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="172"/>He has attempted to tamper with the authorities here, but has utterly failed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="173"/>They say that <placeName reg="Mexico, Mexico, North and Central America" key="tgn,1001893">Mexico</placeName> wants none of the services of men who have already betrayed the nation.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="174"/>The people are essentially loyal and patriotic.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="175"/>The <placeName key="tgn,7007826" n="1.000 4446" reg="texas">Texas</placeName> people are desirous of playing into the bands of the <rs>French</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="176"/>They are up for anything that will embarrass the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">United States</placeName> and prefer <rs n="European" type="group">European</rs> monarchy.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="177"/>They are playing the part of adventurers to the fullest extent. </p> </q><bibl n="A letter, date Matmamoras"></bibl></cit> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="8"> 
<head>Miscellaneous.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="178"/> A surgeon who is engaged at <placeName reg="Gettysburg, Adams, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7014060">Gettysburg</placeName>, ascertains the <rs>Federal</rs> loss to be <measure n="14200" type="wounded">14,200 wounded</measure> and <measure n="5000" type="killed">5,000 killed</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="179"/> <placeName reg="Brashear City, Saint Mary, Louisiana" key="tgn,7014102">Brashear City, La.</placeName>, was re-occupied by the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">yankees</rs> on the <date value="07-23">23d of July.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="180"/></date> </p> 
<p> The <term n="CS steamer">C. S. steamer</term> <rs type="ship">Florida</rs> sailed from <placeName key="tgn,7005064" n="1.000 3" reg="bermuda">Bermuda</placeName> on the <dateStruct value="--25"><day reg="25">25th ult.</day></dateStruct>, after receiving coal and all necessary repairs.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="181"/>The coal she received was brought by the <term type="ship">steamer</term> <rs type="ship">Harriet Pinckney</rs> from <placeName reg="Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada" key="tgn,7013046">Halifax</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="182"/> The expedition which left <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName> a few days ago has arrived at <placeName reg="Port Hudson, East Baton Rouge, Louisiana" key="tgn,7017544">Port Hudson</placeName>. <persName n="Grant,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00065" reg="mostcommon:Grant,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Grant</surname></persName>, it is said, commands in person.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="183"/>Its destination is unknown. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="184"/> The recent cavalry raid from <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName> to <persName n="Jackson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00066" reg="mostcommon:Jackson,nomatch:0"><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="185"/><placeName reg="North Carolina" key="tgn,7007709">N. C.</placeName>, found the <rs>Confederates</rs> entrenched strongly at <placeName reg="Jackson, Hinds, Mississippi" key="tgn,7016129">Jackson</placeName>, which commands the approaches to <placeName reg="Weldon, Halifax, North Carolina" key="tgn,2077124">Weldon</placeName>, and was forced to return. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="186"/> Claims for damages to the total amount of over <measure n="750000dollars" type="currency">seven hundred and fifty thousand dollars</measure>, for losses resulting from the recent riots in New York, have already been presented. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="187"/> It has been decided that it will be safe and expedient to send the <rs>Washington</rs> and New York mails to New Orleans via the <placeName reg="Mississippi River" key="tgn,7022231">Mississippi river</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="188"/>Arrangements have been made for a convoy at least once a week from <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName> to New Orleans, and convoys can be more frequent when required by the necessities of trade or public interest. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="189"/> Gold was quoted in <persName n="Saturday,,New York,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00067" reg="default:Saturday,New York,,,"><foreName>New York</foreName> <surname>Saturday</surname></persName> at <num value="129.75">129&#x00BE;</num>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="190"/> By way of <placeName reg="San Francisco, San Francisco, California" key="tgn,7014456">San Francisco</placeName> we learn that the latest news from <placeName key="tgn,1000120" n="1.000 78" reg="nihon">Japan</placeName> stated that war with <placeName reg="France" key="tgn,1000070">France</placeName> and <placeName reg="United Kingdom" key="tgn,7002445">England</placeName> was certain, and that the <name>Japanese</name> were much better prepared for it than had been supposed. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="191"/> The following is a dispatch from <placeName reg="Cincinnati, Hamilton, Ohio" key="tgn,7013604">Cincinnati</placeName>, dated <date value="08-02">August 2d:</date> </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="192"/> The rebels burned <num value="60">sixty</num> wagon loaded with forage at <placeName reg="Stamford, Fairfield, Connecticut" key="tgn,7014535">Stamford</placeName>, Ky., yesterday. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="193"/> <persName n="Sanders,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00068" reg="mostcommon:Sanders,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Colonel</roleName> <surname>Sanders</surname></persName> reports to <persName n="Burnside,,Gen,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00069" reg="default:Burnside,Gen,,,"><foreName>Gen</foreName> <surname>Burnside</surname></persName> having <measure n="350" type="captured">captured three hundred and fifty</measure> rebels near the <placeName key="tgn,2592540;tgn,2038647" n="0.074 000000.1488	placename;tgn,2592540;Cumberland River, Kentucky, Kentucky,Kentucky,United States,North and Central America;0.074 000000.1488	placename;tgn,2038647;Eddyville, Lyon, Kentucky,Lyon,Kentucky,United States,North and Central America" reg="Cumberland River, Kentucky, Kentucky,Kentucky,United States,North and Central America;Eddyville, Lyon, Kentucky,Lyon,Kentucky,United States,North and Central America">Cumberland river</placeName>, including <persName n="Ashby,Colonel,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00070" reg="mostcommon:Ashby,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Colonel">Colonel</roleName> <surname>Ashby</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="194"/>The balance of the raiders are rapidly retreating, having abandoned their plunder at <placeName key="tgn,2414682" n="1.000 10" reg="Irwin, Spokane, Washington">Irvin</placeName>, Ky. </p> </div4> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="7"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">The reported victory in <placeName reg="Louisiana" key="tgn,7007256">Louisiana</placeName>.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="195"/> --The <orgName n="Mobile Tribune" type="newspaper">Mobile <hi rend="italics">Tribune</hi></orgName>, of the <num value="1" type="ordinal">1st</num> last, has the following paragraph </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="196"/> The latest arrivals, yesterday, from <placeName reg="Louisiana" key="tgn,7007256">Louisiana</placeName> repeat the rumor respecting a great victory gained a few days ago by <persName n="Thylor,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00071" reg="mostcommon:Thylor,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Thylor</surname></persName> ever the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> General <unclear></unclear> The battle, it is stated, was fought at <placeName key="tgn,2042665" n="1.000 57" reg="donaldsonville, ascension, louisiana">Donaldsonville</placeName> &mdash; Over <measure n="5000" type="prisoners">five thousand prisoners</measure> and <num value="9">nine</num> tran sports were taken.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="197"/>The <term type="ship">gunboat</term> <rs type="ship">Essex</rs> and another iron clad were also suck.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="198"/>This is substantially the some story from several different persons.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="199"/>There may be some truth in it. </p> </div3> <milestone unit="column" n="5"/> 
<div3 type="article" n="8"> 
<head>Progress of the <rs>War</rs>.</head> 
<div4 type="entry" n="1"> 
<head>The <dateStruct value="-07-4"><day reg="4">Fourth</day> of <month reg="07">July</month></dateStruct> among the <name>Traitors</name> at <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName> &mdash; companies formed and tendered to the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs>--Subscriptions for the families.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="200"/>The <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName> correspondent of the <orgName n="Baltimore American" type="newspaper">Baltimore <hi rend="italics">American</hi></orgName>, writing on the <num value="4" type="ordinal">4th</num> ult, gives an account of a meeting of the <rs>Union Leagues</rs> of <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName> and <placeName reg="Portsmouth, Portsmouth, Virginia" key="tgn,7014278">Portsmouth</placeName>, held at <time value="8.5oclock">8 &#x00BD; o'clock</time> that morning, in accordance with a notice given them by the <orgName n="Union League" type="league">Union League</orgName> <orgName n="Central Committee" type="committee">Central Committee</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="201"/>We give the proceedings in full, including a <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> writer's eulogiums upon the speakers and participators </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="202"/>The meeting was called to order by <persName n="Chandler,the Honorable,L.,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00072" reg="default:Chandler,L.,H.,,"><roleName n="the Honorable">the Hon.</roleName> <foreName>L.</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Chandler</surname></persName>, who nominated <persName n="Butt,,Robert,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00073" reg="default:Butt,Robert,,,"><foreName>Robert</foreName> <surname>Butt</surname></persName>, <rs type="role">Esq.</rs>, of <placeName reg="Portsmouth, Portsmouth, Virginia" key="tgn,7014278">Portsmouth</placeName>, as temporary <rs type="role2">President</rs>, and <persName n="Melton,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00074" reg="default:Melton,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Melton</surname></persName>, <rs type="role">Esq.</rs>, as <rs type="role2">Secretary</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="203"/>These gentlemen having taken their seats, on motion of <persName n="Fitzgerald,,George,B.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00075" reg="default:Fitzgerald,George,B.,,"><foreName>George</foreName> <foreName>B.</foreName> <surname>Fitzgerald</surname></persName>, <rs type="role">Esq.</rs>, the <name>Chair</name> appointed the following committee to nominate officers for the meeting: <persName n="Fitzgerald,Mister,George,B.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00076" reg="default:Fitzgerald,George,B.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Messrs.</roleName> <foreName>George</foreName> <foreName>B.</foreName> <surname>Fitzgerald</surname></persName>, <persName n="Green,Mister,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00077" reg="default:Green,James,,,"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><foreName>James</foreName> <surname>Green</surname></persName>, <persName n="Whitchead,Mister,Daniel,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00078" reg="default:Whitchead,Daniel,,,"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><foreName>Daniel</foreName> <surname>Whitchead</surname></persName>, <persName n="Melton,Mister,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00079" reg="default:Melton,John,,,"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Melton</surname></persName> and <persName n="Johnson,Mister,Michael,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00080" reg="default:Johnson,Michael,,,"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><foreName>Michael</foreName> <surname>Johnson</surname></persName>; who, after a brief absence, submitted the following ticket, which was unanimously elected; <persName n="Bull,President,Robert,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00081" reg="default:Bull,Robert,,,"><roleName n="President">President</roleName>, <foreName>Robert</foreName> <surname>Bull</surname></persName>, <rs type="role" reg="Esquire">Esq.</rs>, <placeName reg="Portsmouth, Portsmouth, Virginia" key="tgn,7014278">Portsmouth</placeName>; <num value="1" type="ordinal">1st</num> <persName n="Whitehurst,Vice-President,Peter,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00082" reg="default:Whitehurst,Peter,H.,,"><roleName n="Vice-President">Vice President</roleName>, <foreName>Peter</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Whitehurst</surname></persName>, <rs type="role" reg="Esquire">Esq.</rs>, <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName>; <num value="2" type="ordinal">2d</num> <persName n="Brown,Vice-President,Thomas,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00083" reg="default:Brown,Thomas,M.,,"><roleName n="Vice-President">Vice-President</roleName>, <foreName>Thomas</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Brown</surname></persName>, <rs type="role" reg="Esquire">Esq.</rs>, <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName>; Recording <rs type="role2">Secretary</rs>, <persName n="Bottomore,,Judson,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00084" reg="default:Bottomore,Judson,,,"><foreName>Judson</foreName> <surname>Bottomore</surname></persName>, <placeName reg="Portsmouth, Portsmouth, Virginia" key="tgn,7014278">Portsmouth</placeName>; <persName n="Kewen,Treasurer,Robert,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00085" reg="default:Kewen,Robert,,,"><roleName n="Treasurer">Treasurer</roleName>, <foreName>Robert</foreName> <surname>Kewen</surname></persName>, <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="204"/><placeName reg="The President">The President</placeName>, in returning thanks for the honor so unexpectedly and unworthily conferred upon him, spoke in language of burning eloquence concerning the present critical condition of his beloved country, imploring his fellow citizens that, whatever others might do elsewhere, they at least would set an example worthy of all ages to follow.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="205"/>His facetious anecdotal allusion to the &#x0022;junk shop, old rope, and pickled cabbage,&#x0022; was truly humorous and irresistible.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="206"/>I would give it here, but have not space; but suffice it to say it elicited roars of laughter and thunders of applause, our highly esteemed <rs type="role" reg="Attorney-General">Attorney General</rs>, <persName n="Bowden,,Thomas,Russell,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00086" reg="default:Bowden,Thomas,Russell,,"><foreName n="Thomas">Thos.</foreName> <foreName>Russell</foreName> <surname>Bowden</surname></persName>, <rs type="role">Esq.</rs>, being particularly amused. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="207"/> On motion of <persName n="Bowden,,Thomas,R.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00087" reg="expanded:Bowden,Thomas,Russell,,"><foreName>Thomas</foreName> <foreName>R.</foreName> <surname>Bowden</surname></persName>, <rs type="role">Esq.</rs>, the following resolution was unanimously adopted: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="208"/> <hi rend="italics">Resolved,</hi> That in the present critical condition of our beloved country it behooves every true, patriotic, loyal man to contribute his aid and uncompromising support in <num value="1">one</num> way or another towards defending, upholding, and restoring the <rs>Union</rs>; that animated by the spirit which impelled our revolutionary fathers, we at once proceed without further delay to the organizing of volunteer battalion, to be composed of citizens of <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName>, <placeName reg="Portsmouth, Portsmouth, Virginia" key="tgn,7014278">Portsmouth</placeName>, and vicinity, whose services shall be immediately tendered for the common defence of our beloved though imperilled Union. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="209"/> <persName n="Bowden,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00088" reg="nearbymention:Bowden,Thomas,R.,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Bowden</surname></persName>, in eloquently supporting the resolution, was followed by <persName n="Brown,,Thomas,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00089" reg="default:Brown,Thomas,M.,,"><foreName n="Thomas">Thos.</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Brown</surname></persName>, <rs type="role">Esq.</rs>, in an argumentative and eloquent, though brief, speech, his manly and graceful form harmonizing with the patriotism beaming from his noble countenance, inspiring his hearers with the proper sentiments and feelings of true <rs n="American" type="group">Americans</rs>. </p> </q><bibl n="Thomas R. Bowden,"></bibl></cit> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="210"/> On motion of <persName n="Berum,,John,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00090" reg="default:Berum,John,H.,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Berum</surname></persName>, <rs type="role">Esq.</rs>, the <name>Chair</name> was requested to invite persons to come forward and enroll their names for the <num value="4">four</num> companies to constitute the battalion.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="211"/>In the incredible short space of <measure n="38minutes" type="date">thirty eight minutes</measure> <num value="425">four hundred and twenty five</num> names were obtained.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="212"/>At this stage of the proceedings, the utmost enthusiasm prevailing, <persName n="Green,,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00091" reg="default:Green,James,,,"><foreName>James</foreName> <surname>Green</surname></persName>, <rs type="role">Esq.</rs>, with his proverbial munificence, came forward and gave a check on the <orgName n="Virginia Bank" type="bank">Bank of Virginia</orgName> for <measure n="1000dollars" type="currency">$1,000</measure>, to be appropriated to the support of the families of those members least able to leave home for any given length of time.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="213"/>This announcement was received with over whelming applause, the noble example being followed by the subjoined contributions.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="214"/>with many others from <num value="50">fifty</num> to <measure n="5dollars" type="currency">five dollars</measure> greater of <measure n="6750dollars" type="currency">$6,750</measure>, thus showing that if our Union brethren have recently been successful in business, they know how and when to properly appropriate a liberal portion of the profit, and patriotically have they done so in this instance, and posterity will bless them for the good deed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="215"/>I have attended many meetings, but never have I witnessed such unbounded enthusiasm as was indicated at this.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="216"/>The following is the list: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="217"/> <persName n="Green,,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00092" reg="default:Green,James,,,"><foreName>James</foreName> <surname>Green</surname></persName>, <rs type="role">Esq.</rs> <measure n="1000dollars" type="currency">$1,000</measure>; His Honor, <dateStruct><month>May</month></dateStruct> or Wm B <persName n="Brooks,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00093" reg="mostcommon:Brooks,nomatch:0"><surname>Brooks</surname></persName>, <measure n="500dollars" type="currency">$500</measure>; P H <persName n="Whitehurst,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00094" reg="nearbymention:Whitehurst,Peter,H.,,"><surname>Whitehurst</surname></persName>, <measure n="500dollars" type="currency">$500</measure>; <rs type="role">Dr.</rs> D W <persName n="Todd,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00095" reg="mostcommon:Todd,nomatch:0"><surname>Todd</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="218"/><measure n="300dollars" type="currency">$300</measure>, <rs type="role">Dr.</rs> Z <persName n="Sykes,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00096" reg="mostcommon:Sykes,nomatch:0"><surname>Sykes</surname></persName>, <measure n="200dollars" type="currency">$200</measure>, Wm A Mehagen, <measure n="200dollars" type="currency">$200</measure>; <persName n="Belote,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00097" reg="default:Belote,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Belote</surname></persName>, <measure n="150dollars" type="currency">$150</measure>; L W <persName n="Webb,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00098" reg="mostcommon:Webb,nomatch:0"><surname>Webb</surname></persName>, <measure n="225dollars" type="currency">$225</measure>; <persName n="Bunkley,,Joseph,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00099" reg="default:Bunkley,Joseph,,,"><foreName>Joseph</foreName> <surname>Bunkley</surname></persName>, <measure n="170dollars" type="currency">$170</measure>; <persName n="Frost,,Samuel,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00100" reg="default:Frost,Samuel,,,"><foreName>Samuel</foreName> <surname>Frost</surname></persName>, <measure n="200dollars" type="currency">$200</measure>; <persName><foreName>John</foreName></persName> T <persName n="Daniels,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00101" reg="mostcommon:Daniels,nomatch:0"><surname>Daniels</surname></persName>, <measure n="280dollars" type="currency">$280</measure>, <persName n="Zautzinger,,Frank,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00102" reg="default:Zautzinger,Frank,,,"><foreName>Frank</foreName> <surname>Zautzinger</surname></persName>, <measure n="200dollars" type="currency">$200</measure>; <persName n="Charles,,Hon,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00103" reg="default:Charles,Hon,,,"><foreName>Hon</foreName> <surname>Charles</surname></persName> H <persName n="Whitehurst,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00104" reg="nearbymention:Whitehurst,Peter,H.,,"><surname>Whitehurst</surname></persName>, <measure n="100dollars" type="currency">$100</measure>; <persName n="Thos,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00105" reg="mostcommon:Thos,nomatch:0"><surname>Thos</surname></persName> M <persName n="Brown,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00106" reg="nearbymention:Brown,Thomas,M.,,"><surname>Brown</surname></persName>, <measure n="200dollars" type="currency">$200</measure>; <persName><foreName>John</foreName></persName> H <persName n="Borum,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00107" reg="mostcommon:Borum,nomatch:0"><surname>Borum</surname></persName>, <measure n="300dollars" type="currency">$300</measure>; R B <persName n="Lovitt,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00108" reg="mostcommon:Lovitt,nomatch:0"><surname>Lovitt</surname></persName>; <measure n="200dollars" type="currency">$200</measure>; D C <persName n="Crowell,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00109" reg="mostcommon:Crowell,nomatch:0"><surname>Crowell</surname></persName>, <measure n="200dollars" type="currency">$200</measure>; <persName n="Jennings,,Asa,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00110" reg="default:Jennings,Asa,,,"><foreName>Asa</foreName> <surname>Jennings</surname></persName>, <measure n="150dollars" type="currency">$150</measure>; <persName><foreName>George</foreName></persName> R <persName n="Fitzgerald,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00111" reg="nearbymention:Fitzgerald,George,B.,,"><surname>Fitzgerald</surname></persName>, <measure n="200dollars" type="currency">$200</measure>; <persName><foreName>George</foreName></persName> P <persName n="Kneller,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00112" reg="mostcommon:Kneller,nomatch:0"><surname>Kneller</surname></persName>, <measure n="100dollars" type="currency">$100</measure>; L Waterfield, <measure n="150dollars" type="currency">$150</measure>; <persName n="Kewen,,Robert,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00113" reg="default:Kewen,Robert,,,"><foreName>Robert</foreName> <surname>Kewen</surname></persName>, <measure n="200dollars" type="currency">$200</measure>; <persName n="Magee,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00114" reg="mostcommon:Magee,nomatch:0"><surname>Magee</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="Freeman,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00115" reg="mostcommon:Freeman,nomatch:0"><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>, <measure n="200dollars" type="currency">$200</measure>; <persName n="Dilwock,,Peter,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00116" reg="default:Dilwock,Peter,,,"><foreName>Peter</foreName> <surname>Dilwock</surname></persName>, <measure n="2hogsheads" type="mass">two hogsheads</measure> tobacco, proceeds to be applied.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="219"/>What is more, the greater part was paid immediately or checked for. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="220"/>The meeting then proceeded to the election of company officers resulting as follows: </p> 
<list type="ordered"> 
<head></head> 
<item n="1"> <orgName type="company" n="Company A">Company A</orgName>.--<persName n="Peter,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00117" reg="mostcommon:Peter,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Capt</roleName> <surname>Peter</surname></persName> H <persName n="Whitehurst,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00118" reg="nearbymention:Whitehurst,Peter,H.,,"><surname>Whitehurst</surname></persName>, <persName n="Geo,Lieutenant-1,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00119" reg="mostcommon:Geo,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lieutenant-1">1st Lieut</roleName> <surname>Geo</surname></persName> B <persName n="Fitzgerald,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00120" reg="nearbymention:Fitzgerald,George,B.,,"><surname>Fitzgerald</surname></persName>, <persName n="Butt,Lieutenant-2,Robt,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00121" reg="default:Butt,Robt,,,"><roleName n="Lieutenant-2">2d Lieut</roleName> <foreName>Robt</foreName> <surname>Butt</surname></persName>, <num value="1" type="ordinal">1st</num> <persName n="Sergeant,Orderly,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00122" reg="mostcommon:Sergeant,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Orderly">Orderly</roleName> <surname>Sergeant</surname></persName> R B <persName n="Lovitt,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00123" reg="mostcommon:Lovitt,nomatch:0"><surname>Lovitt</surname></persName>, <num value="2" type="ordinal">2d</num> <persName n="Whitchead,Orderly,Sergeant,Daniel,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00124" reg="default:Whitchead,Sergeant,Daniel,,"><roleName n="Orderly">Orderly</roleName> <foreName>Sergeant</foreName> <foreName>Daniel</foreName> <surname>Whitchead</surname></persName>. </item> 
<item n="2"> <orgName type="company" n="Company B">Company B</orgName>.--<rs type="role2">Capt</rs> L W <persName n="Webb,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00125" reg="mostcommon:Webb,nomatch:0"><surname>Webb</surname></persName>, <persName n="Jno,Lieutenant-1,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00126" reg="mostcommon:Jno,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lieutenant-1">1st Lieut</roleName> <surname>Jno</surname></persName> H <persName n="Borum,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00127" reg="mostcommon:Borum,nomatch:0"><surname>Borum</surname></persName>, <rs type="role" reg="Lieutenant-2">2d Lieut</rs> C <persName n="Saunders,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00128" reg="mostcommon:Saunders,nomatch:0"><surname>Saunders</surname></persName>, <num value="1" type="ordinal">1st</num> <persName n="Bunkley,Orderly,Sergeant,Jos,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00129" reg="default:Bunkley,Sergeant,Jos,,"><roleName n="Orderly">Orderly</roleName> <foreName>Sergeant</foreName> <foreName>Jos</foreName> <surname>Bunkley</surname></persName>, <num value="2" type="ordinal">2d</num> <persName n="Zantzinger,Orderly,Sergeant,Frank,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00130" reg="default:Zantzinger,Sergeant,Frank,,"><roleName n="Orderly">Orderly</roleName> <foreName>Sergeant</foreName> <foreName>Frank</foreName> <surname>Zantzinger</surname></persName>. </item> 
<item n="3"> <orgName type="company" n="Company C">Company C</orgName>.--<persName n="Dilworth,Captain,Peter,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00131" reg="default:Dilworth,Peter,,,"><roleName n="Captain">Capt</roleName> <foreName>Peter</foreName> <surname>Dilworth</surname></persName>, <persName n="John,Lieutenant-1,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00132" reg="mostcommon:John,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lieutenant-1">1st Lieut</roleName> <surname>John</surname></persName> T <persName n="Daniels,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00133" reg="mostcommon:Daniels,nomatch:0"><surname>Daniels</surname></persName>, <persName n="Belote,Lieutenant-2,Jas,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00134" reg="default:Belote,Jas,,,"><roleName n="Lieutenant-2">2d Lieut</roleName> <foreName>Jas</foreName> <surname>Belote</surname></persName>, <num value="1" type="ordinal">1st</num> <persName n="Hodges,Orderly,Sergeant,Wm,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00135" reg="default:Hodges,Sergeant,Wm,,"><roleName n="Orderly">Orderly</roleName> <foreName>Sergeant</foreName> <foreName>Wm</foreName> <surname>Hodges</surname></persName>, <num value="2" type="ordinal">2d</num> <persName n="Kewen,Orderly,Sergeant,Robt,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00136" reg="default:Kewen,Sergeant,Robt,,"><roleName n="Orderly">Orderly</roleName> <foreName>Sergeant</foreName> <foreName>Robt</foreName> <surname>Kewen</surname></persName>. </item> 
<item n="4"> <orgName type="company" n="Company D">Company D</orgName>.--<persName n="Frost,Captain,Samuel,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00137" reg="default:Frost,Samuel,,,"><roleName n="Captain">Capt</roleName> <foreName>Samuel</foreName> <surname>Frost</surname></persName>, <persName n="Geo,Lieutenant-1,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00138" reg="mostcommon:Geo,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lieutenant-1">1st Lieut</roleName> <surname>Geo</surname></persName> P Kueller, <persName n="Thos,Lieutenant-2,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00139" reg="mostcommon:Thos,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lieutenant-2">2d Lieut</roleName> <surname>Thos</surname></persName> P <persName n="Crowell,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00140" reg="mostcommon:Crowell,nomatch:0"><surname>Crowell</surname></persName>, <num value="1" type="ordinal">1st</num> <persName n="Sergeant,Orderly,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00141" reg="mostcommon:Sergeant,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Orderly">Orderly</roleName> <surname>Sergeant</surname></persName> D C <persName n="Crowell,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00142" reg="mostcommon:Crowell,nomatch:0"><surname>Crowell</surname></persName>, <num value="2" type="ordinal">2d</num> <persName n="Edward,Orderly,Sergeant,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00143" reg="default:Edward,Sergeant,,,"><roleName n="Orderly">Orderly</roleName> <foreName>Sergeant</foreName> <surname>Edward</surname></persName> C Doming, <persName n="Edward,Quartermaster,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00144" reg="nearbymention:Edward,Sergeant,,,"><roleName n="Quartermaster">Quartermaster</roleName> <surname>Edward</surname></persName> M <persName n="Keer,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00145" reg="mostcommon:Keer,nomatch:0"><surname>Keer</surname></persName>, <persName n="Doctor,Surgeon,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00146" reg="mostcommon:Doctor,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Surgeon">Surgeon</roleName> <surname>Doctor</surname></persName> D W <persName n="Tod,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00147" reg="mostcommon:Tod,nomatch:0"><surname>Tod</surname></persName>. <persName n="Doctor,Assistant-Surgeon,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00148" reg="mostcommon:Doctor,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Assistant-Surgeon">Assistant Surgeon</roleName> <surname>Doctor</surname></persName> Z <persName n="Sykes,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00149" reg="mostcommon:Sykes,nomatch:0"><surname>Sykes</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="221"/></item> </list> 
<p> <persName n="Green,,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00150" reg="default:Green,James,,,"><foreName>James</foreName> <surname>Green</surname></persName>, <rs type="role">Esq.</rs>, was unanimously elected <rs type="role2">Major</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="222"/>This was an excellent choice, as were all the rest.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="223"/><persName n="Green,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00151" reg="nearbymention:Green,James,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Green</surname></persName> is grandson of <persName n="Green,,George,Nathaniel,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00152" reg="default:Green,George,Nathaniel,,"><foreName n="George">Geo.</foreName> <foreName>Nathaniel</foreName> <surname>Green</surname></persName>, of Revolutionary fame.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="224"/><persName n="Tod,Doctor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00153" reg="mostcommon:Tod,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <surname>Tod</surname></persName> is brother of <persName n="Tod,Governor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00154" reg="mostcommon:Tod,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Governor">Governor</roleName> <surname>Tod</surname></persName>, of <placeName reg="Ohio, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007706">Ohio</placeName>; <persName n="Sykee,Doctor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00155" reg="mostcommon:Sykee,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <surname>Sykee</surname></persName> <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> cousin of <persName n="Sykee,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00156" reg="mostcommon:Sykee,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Sykee</surname></persName>, of the <orgName n="U. S. Army" type="org">United States Army</orgName>; so you see patriotism is well represented in this little group.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="225"/>The meeting adjourned over to <dateStruct><day type="name">Monday</day></dateStruct> next, at <time value="4pm">4 P. M.</time>, same place, in order to join in the celebration of this glorious day, the <dateStruct value="-07-4"><day reg="4">Fourth</day> of <month reg="07">July</month></dateStruct>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="226"/>The procession is just passing the <rs type="place">Hall</rs>, preceded by the splendid band from <placeName key="tgn,7013920" n="1.000 1" reg="Fortress Monroe, Hampton, Virginia">Fortress Monroe</placeName>, followed by a large platform on <num value="6">six</num> wheels.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="227"/>beautifully painted <rs type="color">red</rs>, <rs type="color">white</rs> and <rs type="color">blue</rs>, and drawn by <num value="6">six</num> milk-white horses.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="228"/>This vehicle contained <num value="33">thirty-three</num> fair young maidens, members of the <rs type="place">Butte Street</rs> <placeName reg="Virginia Classical Institute">Virginia Classical Institute</placeName>, conducted by <num value="3">three</num> accomplished and refined gentlemen, <persName n="Cohen,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00157" reg="mostcommon:Cohen,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Messrs.</roleName> <surname>Cohen</surname></persName> and <persName n="Tyler,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00158" reg="mostcommon:Tyler,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister"></roleName><surname>Tyler</surname></persName>, A. M. Each maiden, dressed in a robe of pure white, had a brilliant golden star in the centre of her forehead, and bearing in her right hand the glorious <orgName n="Star Spangled Banner" type="newspaper">Star Spangled Banner</orgName>, which was gracefully waved as the procession moved up the main avenue of the city toward the <rs type="place">Fair Grounds</rs>, where <persName><foreName>Edward</foreName></persName> A Mosely, <rs type="role">Esq.</rs>, and <persName n="Mills,,H.,W.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00159" reg="default:Mills,H.,W.,,"><foreName>H.</foreName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <surname>Mills</surname></persName>, <rs type="role">Esq.</rs>, the orators of the day, addressed the large assemblage.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="229"/>The <orgName type="regiment" key="173PARegiment">173d Pennsylvania regiment</orgName> constituted the military escort, and made an imposing appearance.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="230"/>I regret to say that such was the concussion of the guns fired early this morning in honor of the day a great number of window glasses in the lower part of the city were broken.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="231"/>A splendid flag, <num value="16">16</num> by <num value="30">30</num>, is now floating from the <rs n="Methodist" type="religion">Methodist</rs> <orgName n="African Church" type="church">African Church</orgName>, <address><street n="Butte street">Butte street</street></address>, presented by <persName n="Whitehurst,,P.,H.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00160" reg="expanded:Whitehurst,Peter,H.,,"><foreName>P.</foreName> <foreName>H.</foreName> <surname>Whitehurst</surname></persName>, <rs type="role">Esq.</rs>, who gives a ball to-night in his beautiful mansion, formerly owned by <persName n="Barron,Commodore,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00161" reg="default:Barron,James,,,"><roleName n="Commodore">Commodore</roleName> <foreName>James</foreName> <surname>Barron</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="232"/>All the military dignities of the place are invited. </p> <closer> <salute>Very respectfully, yours,</salute> <lb/> <signed><persName n="Bottomore,,J.,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00162" reg="expanded:Bottomore,Judson,,,"><foreName>J.</foreName>  <surname>Bottomore</surname></persName>,</signed> <persName n="Rec,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00163" reg="mostcommon:Rec,nomatch:0"><surname>Rec</surname></persName>. Sec'y </closer> </div4> 
<div4 type="entry" n="2"> 
<head>Lets Army must be caused &mdash; no Headway against the rebellion until that is down</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="233"/> The <orgName n="New York Times" type="newspaper">New York <hi rend="italics">Times</hi></orgName> thinks the &#x0022;<num value="1">one</num> supreme necessity&#x0022; of this war is the destruction of <orgName n="army"><persName n="Lee,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00164" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Gen,,,"><surname>Lee</surname></persName>'s army</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="234"/>Its history has been &#x0022;mainly <unclear> cord </unclear> of success &mdash; invariably so when it acted on the defensive.&#x0022; The <hi rend="italics">Times</hi> continues: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="235"/> It has stood like a wall of fire between us and the rebel capital; and to day we are just as far from that point as when <measure n="2years" type="date">two years</measure> ago last week we fled back from <placeName reg="Bull Run, Prince William, Virginia" key="tgn,7013988">Bull Run</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="236"/>On the <rs>Chickahominy</rs>, at <placeName reg="Fredericksburg, Fredericksburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013943">Fredericksburg</placeName>, at <placeName key="tgn,7017621" n="1.000 260" reg="chancellorsville, spotsylvania, virginia">Chancellorsville</placeName>, and on scores of minor fields, enough of patriotic blood has been need to make a river, and yet in vain.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="237"/>The same tremendous foe to-day confronts us. The most we have done has been to cheek it &mdash; when it, in turn, become the invader.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="238"/>By the most corporate fighting we succeeded in harting it back at <unclear></unclear> and at <placeName reg="Gettysburg, Adams, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7014060">Gettysburg</placeName>, but in neither of these <unclear></unclear> did we do anything <milestone unit="column" n="6"/> more than best it back.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="239"/>We did not disable it; we did not even cripple it. We broke down no part of its organization.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="240"/>We did not even deprive it of any of its artillery, or any important portion of its material of any kind.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="241"/>Its only loss on both occasions was a loss of strength; and as this was repaired after the <rs n="Battle of Antietam" type="battle">battle of Antietam</rs> by new accessions, so the same thing will quickly follow upon the <rs n="Battle of Gettysburg" type="battle">battle of Gettysburg</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="242"/>Other armies will be depilated, if need be, to bring up this old giant champion to his old strength.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="243"/>We may as well accept it at once as a fixed fact that, whatever also has to be sacrificed, the rebel Government will keep up its <orgName n="Army of Virginia" type="army">Army of Virginia</orgName> to the almost possible efficiency; that it will make that army its forlorn hope, as it always has made is its main bulwark; and that on the fate of that army hangs the fate of the rebellion. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="244"/> The gravest mistake in our military management thus far has been that this rebel <orgName n="Army of Virginia" type="army">Army of Virginia</orgName> has been confronted by an army of only about the same magnitude, or, at least, of no such preponderance as was necessary, considering that the proper <hi rend="italics">role</hi> of the latter was attack, and that of the former only defence.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="245"/>An army operating in a hostile country, against an enemy having all the facilities <unclear></unclear> lines necessarily labors under great disadvantage; and this can be counterbalanced only by a proportionate superiority in numerical strength.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="246"/>The <orgName n="Army of the Potomac" type="army">Army of the Potomac</orgName> has never had any such superiority.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="247"/>However true it may be that its generalship has been often very faulty, still the main cause of its failures has been its insufficiency of force for the work in hand.--From the outset, the true policy has been to approach <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> simultaneously from different directions, so as to compel <persName n="Lee,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00165" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Gen,,,"><surname>Lee</surname></persName> to divide his army, and expose each fraction of it to a largely superior force.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="248"/>As it is, he has always been able to pit his army as a unit against us; and, with the consummate skill with which he has handled it, the wonder rather is that on the whole we have held our own so well than that we have not overrun <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>, as was <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> anticipated. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="249"/> The <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> object of <orgName n="army"><persName n="Lee,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00166" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Gen,,,"><surname>Lee</surname></persName>'s army</orgName> is undoubtedly the defence of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="250"/>But it does not necessarily follow that the <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> object of the <orgName n="Army of the Potomac" type="army">Army of the Potomac</orgName> should be the capture of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="251"/>If <orgName n="army"><persName n="Lee,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00167" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Gen,,,"><surname>Lee</surname></persName>'s army</orgName> fails, so does <persName n="Richmond,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00168" reg="mostcommon:Richmond,nomatch:0"><surname>Richmond</surname></persName>; but <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> may fall and leave <orgName n="army"><persName n="Lee,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00169" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Gen,,,"><surname>Lee</surname></persName>'s army</orgName> still as formidable as ever.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="252"/>The Confederacy can give up the <num value="1">one</num> and yet be a great military power; but to loose the other is death inevitable and immediate.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="253"/>Too much importance has been attached to local conquests.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="254"/>These of course have their value, but a secondary value only.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="255"/>Just as far as they can serve as footholds from which the rebel armies can be more effectually assailed, just so far are they to be prized.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="256"/>They are to be estimated solely by a military standard; not at all by territorial measurements.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="257"/>The Confederacy has no geographical entity.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="258"/>It is but the shadow of military power.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="259"/>Strike down that power, and itself at once disappears.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="260"/>But this power lies in, the armies and nowhere else.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="261"/>The <num value="1" type="ordinal">first</num> duty, therefore &mdash; we may say, in fact, the only duty; for that done, all is done &mdash; is to destroy the armies.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="262"/>And as <orgName n="army"><persName n="Lee,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00170" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Gen,,,"><surname>Lee</surname></persName>'s army</orgName> is now almost the only <num value="1">one</num> of any considerable power existing in the <rs>Confederacy</rs>, it is the duty of our Government to make, now and henceforth, the destruction of that army its <num value="1">one</num> great purpose. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="263"/> There is but <num value="1">one</num> way to secure this, and that is the <hi rend="italics">concentration of overwhelming forces into <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>.</hi> Our recent successes in the <rs>South</rs> weet have released from active service an immense number of veteran soldiers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="264"/>Probably it would not be too much to say that from the armies of <persName n="Grant,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00171" reg="mostcommon:Grant,nomatch:0"><surname>Grant</surname></persName>, Banke, and Rosecan, <num value="60000">sixty thousand</num> men could be spared, and yet leave forces amply large enough to meet all the troops that could be mastered against them by the rebels in that quarter of the country.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="265"/>With the aid of the rapidly multiplying negro regiments, whose fighting qualities are now universally acknowledged, it would seem that there could be no question of this ability.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="266"/><unclear></unclear> of the <rs>Western</rs> soldiers &mdash; some <num value="30">thirty</num> or <num value="40">forty</num> regiments there made up of Eastern man &mdash; thus to be thrown, by the <placeName reg="Knoxville, Knox, Tennessee" key="tgn,7013841">Knoxville</placeName> road, through <placeName reg="Tennessee" key="tgn,7007825"><rs type="direction">Eastern</rs> Tennessee</placeName> and <placeName reg="West Virginia" key="tgn,7013961">Western Virginia</placeName>, upon <persName n="Lee,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00172" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Gen,,,"><surname>Lee</surname></persName>'s flank, and were the old <orgName n="Army of the Potomac" type="army">Army of the Potomac</orgName> at an early day to be reinforced up to its proper standard by the new draft, it would be physically impossible for <persName n="Lee,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00173" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Gen,,,"><surname>Lee</surname></persName> to hold out for any long period.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="267"/>Of course he, too, would be to some extent reinforced, as he has been already since the <rs n="Battle of Gettysburg" type="battle">battle of Gettysburg</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="268"/>But the forces and the resources of the <rs>Confederacy</rs> are now too much reduced to admit of any such contribution to its favorite army as thus lies in our power, in respect to the <orgName n="Army of the Potomac" type="army">Army of the Potomac</orgName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="269"/>Undoubtedly. <placeName reg="Jeff Davis, Noxubee, Mississippi" key="tgn,2420078">Jeff Davis</placeName> will strain every energy to the utmost to keep up the efficiency of <orgName n="command"><persName n="Lee,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00174" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Gen,,,"><surname>Lee</surname></persName>'s command</orgName>, for he knows that his fate depends upon it. But our own Government has to put forth only <unclear></unclear> limited measure of the same energy to insure the completes breaking up of that command and with it the instantaneous and absolute collapse of the <rs>Confederacy</rs>. </p> </div4> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="9"> 
<head>The fight at <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> City.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="270"/> The <placeName reg="Atlanta, Fulton, Georgia" key="tgn,7013331">Atlanta</placeName> <hi rend="italics">Appeal's</hi> <placeName reg="Morton, Scott, Mississippi" key="tgn,2057020">Morton (Miss.)</placeName> correspondent, under date of <date value="07-28">July 28,</date> gives the following account of the evacuation of <placeName reg="Yazoo City, Yazoo, Mississippi" key="tgn,2057820">Yazoo City</placeName>, and the immense destruction of steamers which had been run up the <rs>Yazoo</rs> for safety: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="271"/> You have been informed of the gallant fight made by the garrison of <num value="700">700</num> men at <placeName reg="Yazoo City, Yazoo, Mississippi" key="tgn,2057820">Yazoo City</placeName>, reputing the gunboats, and the subsequent blowing up of the works and evacuation of the place.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="272"/>It appears now that <num value="5000">five thousand</num> <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> infantry were moving to the rear of the city.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="273"/>It was a cunning move on the part of the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs>, their object being to interest both the fortifications and <persName n="Brown,Commander,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00175" reg="nearbymention:Brown,Thomas,M.,,"><roleName n="Commander">Com.</roleName> <surname>Brown</surname></persName>'s fleet of beats until the infantry could get above them on the river, thus cutting off retreat and capturing a very rich prize.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="274"/>Our men were too wise to be caught in such a trap.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="275"/>The only boat captured was the little <term type="ship">packet boat</term> <rs type="ship">St. Mary</rs>, the crew escaping in small boats. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="276"/> Though the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> gained nothing our loss is very heavy in boats and material of a character much needed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="277"/>Com <persName n="Brown,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00176" reg="nearbymention:Brown,Thomas,M.,,"><surname>Brown</surname></persName> scuttles and burned the <rs>Magenta</rs>, Mary Keens Magnolia, Pargoud.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="278"/><persName n="Walsh,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00177" reg="default:Walsh,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Walsh</surname></persName>, Luckland, <placeName key="tgn,7002444" n="1.000 148" reg="scotland">Scotland</placeName>, <persName n="Age,,Golden,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00178" reg="default:Age,Golden,,,"><foreName>Golden</foreName> <surname>Age</surname></persName>, <placeName key="tgn,2042173;tgn,2057900" n="0.225 000000.6735	placename;tgn,2042173;arcadia, bienville, louisiana,Bienville,Louisiana,United States,North and Central America;0.174 000000.5206	placename;tgn,2057900;arcadia, iron, missouri,Iron,Missouri,United States,North and Central America" reg="arcadia, bienville, louisiana,Bienville,Louisiana,United States,North and Central America;arcadia, iron, missouri,Iron,Missouri,United States,North and Central America">Arcadia</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="279"/><persName n="Kennett,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00179" reg="mostcommon:Kennett,nomatch:0"><surname>Kennett</surname></persName>, <persName n="Gay,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00180" reg="mostcommon:Gay,nomatch:0"><surname>Gay</surname></persName>, Peytons, <rs type="role" reg="Prince">Prince</rs> of <placeName reg="Wales, United Kingdom, Europe" key="tgn,7002443">Wales</placeName>, <rs n="Natchez" type="nativeamerican">Natchez</rs>, and Parallel, in the <placeName key="tgn,2784619" n="1.000 77" reg="yazoo river, united states, north and central america">Yazoo river</placeName>, the <rs>Dew Drop</rs>, <persName n="Bott,,Emms,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00181" reg="default:Bott,Emms,,,"><foreName>Emms</foreName> <surname>Bott</surname></persName>, Sharke, and <persName n="Mears,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00182" reg="mostcommon:Mears,nomatch:0"><surname>Mears</surname></persName>, in the <rs>Sunflower</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="280"/>We have only left, of all the splendid fleet which caught refuge in the <placeName key="tgn,2784619" n="1.000 77" reg="yazoo river, united states, north and central america">Yazoo river</placeName>, the <rs>Hope</rs>, <placeName reg="Hartford City, Blackford, Indiana" key="tgn,2032125">Hartford City</placeName>, <persName n="McCulloch,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00183" reg="mostcommon:McCulloch,nomatch:0"><surname>McCulloch</surname></persName>, and <placeName key="tgn,2008024" n="1.000 3" reg="cotton plant, woodruff, arkansas">Cotton Plant</placeName>, which are up the <rs>Tallahatchie</rs> and <rs>Yellobuche</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="281"/>The <rs>Kennett</rs> is sunk across the mouth of the <name>Yellobuche</name>, and the <name>Walsh</name> across that of the <rs>Tallahatchie</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="282"/> The gunboats came up the river as far as the month of the <placeName reg="Rio Tula, Mexico, North and Central America" key="tgn,1131086">Tula river</placeName>, and raided in the direction of <placeName reg="Blackwater Creek, Virginia Beach, Virginia" key="tgn,2178820">Blackwater</placeName> and <placeName reg="Lexington, Lexington, Virginia" key="tgn,7013889">Lexington</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="283"/>This closes the history of another strongly defended river. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="284"/> I am indebted to <persName n="Applagale,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00184" reg="mostcommon:Applagale,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Captain</roleName> <surname>Applagale</surname></persName>, captain and owner of the <name>Walsh</name>, for the above interesting facts.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="285"/>He is on his way to <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> to secure a settlement of his affairs with the <rs>Government</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="286"/>Other owners and captains are enroute for the same purpose.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="287"/>I trust the <orgName n="Navy Department" type="department">Navy Department</orgName> will adjust the affairs of these gentlemen as promptly as possible, not only because it is proper and right that they should be paid for their losses and services, but because they are the most proper men to lead in the new system of fighting for the rivers. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="288"/> The destruction of these boats releases a large number of energetic, shrewd men, who understand every habit and eccentricity of the <placeName reg="Mississippi River" key="tgn,7022231">Mississippi river</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="289"/>They are bold, enterprising, and have a commendable contempt for their ancient fellows, who have abandoned their friends and the true cause, for fat places with the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="290"/>Every inducement should be offered to these men to organize, under their respective <rs type="role2">Captains</rs>, or otherwise, as they see fit, for the purpose of capturing, destroying, and annoying <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> boats.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="291"/>This can be best done by sending back to them at once the <name>Captained</name> who have led them for years.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="292"/><persName n="Applegate,Captain,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00185" reg="mostcommon:Applegate,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Captain">Capt.</roleName> <surname>Applegate</surname></persName>, for <num value="1">one</num>, will be off on this mission the day his affairs are adjusted. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="293"/> <persName n="Montgomery,,Charles,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00186" reg="default:Montgomery,Charles,,,"><foreName>Charles</foreName> <surname>Montgomery</surname></persName>, an amiable gentleman of <placeName reg="Canton, Madison, Mississippi" key="tgn,2056100">Canton</placeName>, employed in the <orgName n="Telegraph Office" type="office">telegraph office</orgName>, was severely stabbed by <persName n="Booth,Doctor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00187" reg="mostcommon:Booth,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <surname>Booth</surname></persName>, formerly of <placeName reg="Memphis, Shelby, Tennessee" key="tgn,7017750">Memphis</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="294"/>The difficulty grow act of the delivery of a message, the <rs>Doctor</rs> behaving so badly as to compel <unclear></unclear> to step him in the face, where upon be received the <unclear></unclear> in the back, completely <unclear></unclear> him. The next day <persName n="Booth,Doctor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00188" reg="mostcommon:Booth,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <surname>Booth</surname></persName> was killed by a <unclear></unclear> who shot him ever the head with a gun. This had no <unclear></unclear> with the officer of the day previous. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="295"/> The briders over the Big Black, where the <rs>Mississippi</rs> <unclear></unclear> was not destroyed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="296"/><persName n="Grant,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00189" reg="mostcommon:Grant,nomatch:0"><surname>Grant</surname></persName> seems to be ending that road for <unclear></unclear> use. </p> </div3> <milestone unit="column" n="7"/> 
<div3 type="article" n="10"> 
<head>Later from <placeName key="tgn,1000003" n="1.000 139" reg="europe,">Europe</placeName>.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="297"/> The <term type="ship">steamship</term> <rs type="ship">America</rs> has arrived at New York with <name>English</name> dates of the <dateStruct value="--22"><day reg="22">22d ult.</day></dateStruct>, <measure n="2days" type="date">two days</measure> later.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="298"/>The news in not important.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="299"/>It was expected that the <orgName n="English Parliament" type="parliament">English Parliament</orgName> would be prorogated on the <dateStruct value="--28"><day reg="28">28th ult.</day></dateStruct> In the <orgName n="House of Commons" type="government">House of Commons</orgName>, on the <dateStruct value="--29"><day reg="2">29th</day></dateStruct>, a motive by <persName n="Horseman,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00190" reg="mostcommon:Horseman,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Horseman</surname></persName>, looking to active interference in the <name>Polish</name> question by <persName n="England,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00191" reg="mostcommon:England,nomatch:0"><surname>England</surname></persName>, was withdrawn. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="300"/> It is generally thought that the server of the <rs>Russian Government</rs> to the notes of the <num value="3">three</num> powers upon the <name>Polish</name> question to act considered satisfactory.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="301"/>It is stated in the <rs>French</rs> papers that the reply is being examined by the <num value="3">three</num> powers, and that it in the positive intention of the <num value="3">three</num> powers to agree upon the means of settling in a definite manner as serious a question.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="302"/>The reply while act declining the conference, represents is on superfluous; and while the entering upon the intaintive course suggested by the <num value="3">three</num> powers to declined, the promulgation of a full and complete amounts in favor of the <name>Polan</name> in promised.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="303"/>A dispatch from <unclear></unclear> with the reply, will <unclear></unclear> Western powers for the <unclear></unclear> common purpose.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="304"/><unclear></unclear> taken place between the <unclear></unclear> and the <unclear></unclear> forces, with varying fortunes. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="305"/> The <orgName n="London Times" type="newspaper">London <hi rend="italics">Times</hi></orgName> has an editorial on the result of <placeName reg="Gettysburg, Adams, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7014060">Gettysburg</placeName>, and concludes that while the <rs>North</rs> can never be successful in the <rs>South</rs>, the <rs>South</rs>, on the other hand, can never fight successfully on Northern soil It thinks fighting will never and the war, even &#x0022;if the <num value="300000">300,000</num> troops called for by the <rs>Northern</rs> conscription are enrolled, armed, and slaughtered in another <measure n="2years" type="date">two years</measure> of miserable conflict.&#x0022; It adds: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="306"/> The Cabinet at <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName> are not equal to the task.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="307"/>Every crisis of affairs seems as elicit additional proofs that they are in every respect until to feat with the events passing around them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="308"/>The gleam of success which has fallen on the <rs>Federal</rs> arms in the surrender of <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName> and the incidents of the <orgName type="regiment" key="MD2">second Maryland</orgName> campaign have exhibited the <rs>President</rs> and his chief ministers in a manner almost pitiable.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="309"/>With their country tern asunder, and its soil reeking with blood, they only find a voice to make poor and flippant election speeches.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="310"/>When &#x0022;serenaded,&#x0022; as a popular congratulation on the <rs n="Fall of Vicksburg" type="battle">fall of Vicksburg</rs>, the <rs>President</rs> made an address to the crowd that &#x0022;not even the friendly reports could invest with dignity.&#x0022;--The <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs> &#x0022;claimed the merits of retaining <persName n="Grant,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00192" reg="mostcommon:Grant,nomatch:0"><roleName n="General">General</roleName> <surname>Grant</surname></persName> in command, and consequently of the victory achieved.&#x0022; He turned the event to a crimination of some of his colleagues and a glorifying of himself.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="311"/><persName n="Stanton,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00193" reg="mostcommon:Stanton,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Stanton</surname></persName> made a party triumph over the advocates of peace by a small anear at the &#x0022;Copperheads.&#x0022; And <persName n="Seward,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00194" reg="mostcommon:Seward,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Seward</surname></persName> crowned the wretched display by something that we record, but will not here repeal, for it was simply blasphemes.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="312"/>That men in such positions could so express themselves at such a time is a deplorable illustration of the degeneracy of <rs n="American" type="group">American</rs> rulers. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="313"/> In another article, which appears in the impression of the <num value="21" type="ordinal">21st</num>, it says it can see <unclear></unclear> termination of the war at present in view, and goes on. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="314"/> Let us look to what has just happened.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="315"/>On the <dateStruct value="--4"><day reg="2">4th</day></dateStruct>, so it is said, <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName> surrendered, its desperate condition having probably been known some days before.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="316"/>On the same day <persName n="Lee,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00195" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Gen,,,"><surname>Lee</surname></persName> was found to have commenced his retreat from <placeName reg="Gettysburg, Adams, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7014060">Gettysburg</placeName> back into <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="317"/>On the same day the <rs>Confederate</rs> <rs type="role" reg="Vice-President">Vice President</rs>, with a commissioner, came down the <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">James river</placeName> with a flag of truce, bearing letters from <persName n="Davis,President,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00196" reg="mostcommon:Davis,nomatch:0"><roleName n="President">President</roleName> <surname>Davis</surname></persName> to <persName n="Lincoln,President,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00197" reg="nearbymention:Lincoln,Abraham,,,"><roleName n="President">President</roleName> <surname>Lincoln</surname></persName>, and <unclear>wish</unclear> deliver them in person.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="318"/><unclear></unclear> some hesitation, was <hi rend="italics">refused, </hi> and that in a way which implied that the <rs>Federal Government</rs> would not communicate with the <rs>Confederate</rs>, unless the subject of the communication was known before the envoys were even admitted within the <rs>Federal</rs> lines New, it is not too much to say that at the time the <rs>Federal Government</rs> returned this answer to a request which could only be of a <unclear></unclear> tendency, they had just been relieved of the worst of their fears with regard to the <num value="2">two</num> most critical points of the war, even though they might not know the whole.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="319"/>They were just in that very mood of reinstated confidence and credit which <name>English</name> observers are very <unclear></unclear> to think the most favorable for peace. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="320"/> Such an incident casts an ominous shadow on the prospects of this war. Whether the <rs>Federal</rs> are ever beaten into peace or act, it is evident they will never be softened into kindness by success.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="321"/>The least advantage, however dearly purchased, and be it ever so trifling in the great balance of war, brings them to the balcony, and sends them to &#x0022;the <name n="God" type="God">God</name> of Battles&#x0022; and &#x0022;sternal justice of their cause&#x0022; When this is all that victory, all that religion teaches them, we may reasonably ask when will they ever condescend to be reasonable and wise. * * * * </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="322"/> &#x0022;<hi rend="italics">Aut C&#x0153;sar, out nikil,</hi>&#x0022; is the real secret of the <rs>Federal</rs> obstinacy; and, since it must be so, since <placeName reg="America, Pulaski, Illinois" key="tgn,2026331">America</placeName> will play that gams, and we cannot but feel we are ourselves included in the stake, and are humble counters on the board, we have no alternative but to acquaint in this great and unexpected confusion of <rs n="American" type="group">American</rs> tongued. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="323"/> The Confederate loan in <placeName reg="London, Greater London, England" key="tgn,7011781">London</placeName> was quoted at <num value="3.5">3&#x00BD;</num>a4 per cent discount. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="11"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">The most Brutal murder of the <rs>War</rs></head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="324"/> --The <placeName reg="Montgomery, Montgomery, Alabama" key="tgn,7013928">Montgomery (Ala.)</placeName> <hi rend="italics">Advertiser</hi> learns from a relative of the victim the following pastionlars of the fiendish <rs>Marder</rs> of an old lady near <placeName reg="Canton, Madison, Mississippi" key="tgn,2056100">Canton, Miss.</placeName>, by the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">yankees</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="325"/> <rs type="role">Mrs.</rs> M. R. Fort was a lady <measure n="65years" type="date">sixty-five years</measure> of age, of the highest respectability, and supposed to be worth some <measure n="40000dollars" type="currency">forty thousand dollars</measure>. She was visiting the house of a friend some <placeName><distance reg="6miles">six miles</distance> <offset>south</offset> of  <placeName reg="Canton, Madison, Mississippi" key="tgn,2056100">Canton</placeName></placeName>, some <measure n="2weeks" type="date">two weeks</measure> ago, when some <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> officers hearing of her wealth and believing that she had gone to the country for the purpose of hiding money, went with a gang of negro to the house at <time value="2am">2 o'clock A. M.</time>, took her out of had and whipped her until <time value="6oclock">6 o'clock</time>--<measure n="4hours" type="date">four hours</measure>--to make her <unclear></unclear> where her money could be found.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="326"/>She <unclear></unclear> no money, and of course could not satisfy the <unclear></unclear> The wretched lady died under the torture of the last. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="12"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Going North for <unclear></unclear> in <persName n="Green,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00198" reg="nearbymention:Green,George,Nathaniel,,"><surname>Green</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="327"/>Backs.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="328"/> --In <placeName reg="Mobile, Mobile, Alabama" key="tgn,7017444">Mobile</placeName> last week <unclear></unclear> <placeName reg="Vicksburg, Warren, Mississippi" key="tgn,7018023">Vicksburg</placeName> soldier went into <persName n="Simon,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00199" reg="mostcommon:Simon,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>Simon</surname></persName>'s clothing store, on <address><street n="Dauphin street">Dauphin street</street></address>, to purchase a <unclear></unclear> The clerk &mdash; a man named Mark <unclear></unclear>--attended on him and commenced to exhibit his goods.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="329"/>During the conversation <rs>Woal</rs> asked him if he had some greenbacks, and was answered in the affirmative.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="330"/>The soldier selected a shirt and inquired the price.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="331"/>He was told that he could have it for <measure n="25dollars" type="currency">$25</measure> in Confederate money or <measure n="2.50dollars" type="currency">$2.50</measure> in greenbacks.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="332"/>The soldier paid him with the latters, and immediately afterwards reported the case to <persName n="Denis,Major,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00200" reg="mostcommon:Denis,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Major">Major</roleName> <surname>Denis</surname></persName>, the <rs type="role" reg="Provost Marshal">Provost Marshal</rs>, who <unclear></unclear> his arrest.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="333"/>The <hi rend="italics">Advertiser</hi> says: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="334"/> Wohl was afterwards taken out on a writ <hi rend="italics">of habeas corpus.</hi> <rs type="role">Gen.</rs> <unclear></unclear> of the action, dispatched officer <unclear></unclear> with instructions to rearrest him and to send him to <placeName reg="Atlanta, Fulton, Georgia" key="tgn,7013331">Atlanta</placeName>, and from there, we learn, he will be taken to <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> to be some across the lines.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="335"/>He was put on board the <term type="ship">steamer</term> <rs type="ship">Mary Wileba</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="336"/>which left at <time value="1:30oclock">half- past 1 o'clock</time>--Wohl made this ceremonial by his employee </p> </q><bibl n="Advertiser"></bibl></cit> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="13"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">A daring <placeName reg="Confederate Court">Confederate Court</placeName> <unclear></unclear></head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="337"/> --<persName n="Humphreys,,Pillow,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00201" reg="default:Humphreys,Pillow,,,"><foreName>Pillow</foreName> <surname>Humphreys</surname></persName>, <persName n="Humphreys,IsFather-General,West,E.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00202" reg="default:Humphreys,West,E.,,"><roleName n="IsFather-General">son of Gen.</roleName> <foreName>West</foreName> <foreName>E.</foreName> <surname>Humphreys</surname></persName>, now presiding <unclear></unclear> the <rs type="place">Confederate Court</rs> in session in <placeName reg="Knoxville, Knox, Tennessee" key="tgn,7013841">Knoxville</placeName>, was captured by the <name>Federates</name> in the <unclear></unclear> of <placeName reg="East Nashville, Davidson, Tennessee" key="tgn,2308580">Nashville</placeName> last week.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="338"/>He was <num value="1">one</num> of <persName n="Dors,,,,,Van" id="n-0001.0000.00000.00203" reg="mostcommon:Dors,nomatch:0"><nameLink>Van</nameLink> <surname>Dors</surname></persName>'s most daring scouts, and at <num value="1">one</num> time even <unclear></unclear> <placeName reg="East Nashville, Davidson, Tennessee" key="tgn,2308580">Nashville</placeName> and made purchase of a number of articles he needed. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="14"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="smallcaps">Deserters</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="339"/> --The Lexington (Fa) <hi rend="italics">Gazette</hi> has heard <unclear></unclear> of large companies of <unclear></unclear> from the army, passing through <unclear>bridge</unclear> county, on their way to their <unclear></unclear>--As many on <num value="20">twenty</num> <unclear></unclear> from <unclear></unclear> in <num value="1">one</num> company, carrying their <unclear></unclear> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="15"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="340"/> In <placeName reg="Nelson, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,2002175">Nelson county</placeName>, Va, <unclear></unclear> of <persName n="Jones,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00204" reg="mostcommon:Jones,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">a Mr.</roleName> <surname>Jones</surname></persName> was <unclear></unclear> and <persName n="Jones,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00205" reg="mostcommon:Jones,nomatch:0"><surname>Jones</surname></persName> <unclear></unclear> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> <milestone unit="page" n="2"/> 
<div1 type="page-image"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="341"/><figure entity="NW_RichTimesD_025_032_002"> <figDesc>Page image of Daily Dispatch, Volume <num value="25">25</num>, <num value="32">Number 32</num>, <ref n="page 2">page 2</ref>. </figDesc> </figure></p> </div1> <milestone unit="column" n="1"/> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="342"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="news"> 
<head><orgName n="Richmond Dispatch" type="newspaper">Richmond Dispatch</orgName>.</head> 
<div2 type="local"> 
<head>Local Matters.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics"><persName n="Nevel,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00206" reg="mostcommon:Nevel,nomatch:0"><surname>Nevel</surname></persName> case.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="343"/> --<num value="4">Four</num> negroes &mdash; <placeName reg="Mary Susan Hill">Mary Susan Hill</placeName>, <placeName reg="Harriet Hill">Harriet Hill</placeName>, George Powders, free, and <persName n="Jack,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00207" reg="mostcommon:Jack,nomatch:0"><surname>Jack</surname></persName>, slave to <persName n="Wright,,P.,J.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00208" reg="default:Wright,P.,J.,,"><foreName>P.</foreName> <foreName>J.</foreName> <surname>Wright</surname></persName> &mdash; were before the <name>Mayer</name> yesterday, on the warrant of <persName n="Sanzay,Coroner,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00209" reg="mostcommon:Sanzay,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Coroner">Coroner</roleName> <surname>Sanzay</surname></persName>, charged with the murder of <persName n="Henson,,James,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00210" reg="default:Henson,James,,,"><foreName>James</foreName> <surname>Henson</surname></persName>, a free negro, on the <date value="07-29">29th of July </date> last.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="344"/><num value="2">Two</num> witnesses were examined, but neither of them implicated <placeName reg="Harriet Hill">Harriet Hill</placeName> or the <num value="2">two</num> men in the slightest degree with the murder. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="345"/> Ann Peppercorn deposed, that on the <date value="07-27">27th of July,</date> <persName><foreName>Mary</foreName></persName> <num value="8">8</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="346"/><persName n="Hill,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00211" reg="mostcommon:Hill,nomatch:0"><surname>Hill</surname></persName> came into her yard, adjoining that in which deceased resided, and purchased a lawn sack of her, paying her <measure n="1dollars" type="currency">$1</measure>, and promising to pay the balance of the money when she called for the garment.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="347"/><persName n="Susan,,Mary,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00212" reg="default:Susan,Mary,,,"><foreName>Mary</foreName> <surname>Susan</surname></persName> then left the premise, and on getting into the street, witness heard her say Jim Hod son would not let her come to his house &mdash; that he thought more of her <persName><roleName n="Sister">sister</roleName> <foreName>Harriet</foreName></persName> than he did of her &mdash; and that he should not live till <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Sunday</day></dateStruct> <time>night</time>. Witness did not see the deceased, and could not say that he heard the prisoner's remarks. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="348"/> <persName n="Byrne,,Catherine,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00213" reg="default:Byrne,Catherine,,,"><foreName>Catherine</foreName> <surname>Byrne</surname></persName> occupied a room immediately under the <num value="1">one</num> occupied by <persName n="Hudson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00214" reg="mostcommon:Hudson,nomatch:0"><surname>Hudson</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="349"/>On <dateStruct><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct>, the <date value="07-28">28th July,</date> between the hours of <time value="12">12</time> and <time value="1oclock">1 o'clock</time>, she heard something fall heavily on the floor above her, and heard a groan, but did not ascertain the cause.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="350"/>She heard no other unusual noise, and did not go out to ascertain the cause of the groan. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="351"/> Upon this evidence the <rs>Mayor</rs> adjourned the investigation till <dateStruct><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct>, and committed <persName n="Susan,,Mary,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00215" reg="default:Susan,Mary,,,"><foreName>Mary</foreName> <surname>Susan</surname></persName> to jail; but admitted the other <num value="3">three</num> to bail for their appearance. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Prison record.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="352"/> --At the <rs type="place">Libby prison</rs> yesterday there were some <num value="740">740</num> <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankees</rs> received, the remnant of captures at <placeName reg="Gettysburg, Adams, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7014060">Gettysburg</placeName> and other points.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="353"/>In this lot of prisoners were the following officers, viz: Capts C D <persName n="Bowers,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00216" reg="mostcommon:Bowers,nomatch:0"><surname>Bowers</surname></persName>, <num value="18" type="ordinal">18th</num> <persName n="Conn,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00217" reg="mostcommon:Conn,nomatch:0"><surname>Conn</surname></persName>; R T <persName n="Cornwell,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00218" reg="mostcommon:Cornwell,nomatch:0"><surname>Cornwell</surname></persName>, <num value="67" type="ordinal">67th</num> <persName n="Penn,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00219" reg="mostcommon:Penn,nomatch:0"><surname>Penn</surname></persName>; W H <persName n="Bender,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00220" reg="mostcommon:Bender,nomatch:0"><surname>Bender</surname></persName>, <orgName type="regiment" key="OH123">123d Ohio</orgName>; and J P <persName n="Gleason,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00221" reg="mostcommon:Gleason,nomatch:0"><surname>Gleason</surname></persName>, <num value="5" type="ordinal">5th</num> N Y <persName n="Murwin,Lieutenant-1,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00222" reg="mostcommon:Murwin,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Lieutenant-1">1st Lieut</roleName> <surname>Murwin</surname></persName>, <num value="18" type="ordinal">18th</num> Coun; <num value="2" type="ordinal">2d</num> L's J S <persName n="Paul,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00223" reg="mostcommon:Paul,nomatch:0"><surname>Paul</surname></persName>, <orgName type="regiment" key="OH122">122d Ohio</orgName>, and G D Dakers, <orgName type="regiment" key="OH123">123d Ohio</orgName>; Surgeons D <persName n="Meeker,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00224" reg="mostcommon:Meeker,nomatch:0"><surname>Meeker</surname></persName> and L <persName n="Holbrook,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00225" reg="mostcommon:Holbrook,nomatch:0"><surname>Holbrook</surname></persName>; <rs type="role" reg="Assistant-Surgeon">Assistant Surgeons</rs> A M <persName n="Parker,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00226" reg="mostcommon:Parker,nomatch:0"><surname>Parker</surname></persName>, S L <persName><foreName>Henry</foreName></persName>, and J R Uhler.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="354"/>In addition to the above there were <num value="9">nine</num> citizens of <placeName reg="Gettysburg, Adams, Pennsylvania" key="tgn,7014060">Gettysburg</placeName> received at the above- named prison. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="355"/> At Castle Thunder there were no commitments of any consequence.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="356"/>We understand that under the recent proclamation of the <rs>President</rs> about <measure n="500" type="prisoners">500 prisoners</measure>, now confined in the <rs type="place">Castle</rs>, will be released and sent to their regiments. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Sudden death.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="357"/> --<persName n="Hammond,Doctor,W.,M.,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00227" reg="default:Hammond,W.,M.,,"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <foreName>W.</foreName> <foreName>M.</foreName> <surname>Hammond</surname></persName>, formerly of <placeName reg="Maryland" key="tgn,7007516">Maryland</placeName>, died suddenly in this city on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Tuesday</day></dateStruct> <time>afternoon</time> last. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="4"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Police Items.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="358"/> --The <rs>Mayor</rs> heard and disposed of the following cases yesterday: </p> <cit><q rend="break"> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="359"/> <persName n="Gaines,,Reuben,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00228" reg="default:Gaines,Reuben,,,"><foreName>Reuben</foreName> <surname>Gaines</surname></persName>, drunk and disorderly in the streets.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="360"/>Sent to the <rs type="role" reg="Provost Marshal">Provost Marshal</rs>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="361"/> <persName n="Kendrick,,William,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00229" reg="default:Kendrick,William,,,"><foreName n="William">Wm.</foreName> <surname>Kendrick</surname></persName>, drunk and disorderly.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="362"/>Held to bail. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="363"/> <persName n="Goode,,Charles,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00230" reg="default:Goode,Charles,,,"><foreName n="Charles">Chas.</foreName> <surname>Goode</surname></persName>, beating his stepson, <persName n="Kranas,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00231" reg="default:Kranas,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Kranas</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="364"/>Hold to bail. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="365"/> <placeName reg="Washington, District of Columbia, United States" key="tgn,7013962">Washington</placeName> and <persName n="Jenkins,,Johannah,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00232" reg="default:Jenkins,Johannah,,,"><foreName>Johannah</foreName> <surname>Jenkins</surname></persName>, assaulting <persName n="Purkins,,Virginia,Ann,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00233" reg="default:Purkins,Virginia,Ann,,"><foreName>Virginia</foreName> <foreName>Ann</foreName> <surname>Purkins</surname></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="366"/>Bound over. </p> </q><bibl n="Mayor"></bibl></cit> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="5"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Military defence.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="367"/> --A very strong petition was presented to the <rs type="place">County Court</rs> of <persName n="Tuesday,,Henrico,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00234" reg="default:Tuesday,Henrico,,,"><foreName>Henrico</foreName> <surname>Tuesday</surname></persName> by farmers of that county, praying the <rs type="place">Court</rs> to ask the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs> to so establish military sentinels around the city fortifications as to prevent stragglers, skulkers, deserters, convalescents, depredators with foreign protection papers in their pockets, and thieves disguised in military clothes, from prowling the country day and night, pillaging farms and gardens at pleasure, breaking down fences, and wantonly destroying the growing crops, not only to the injury of the petitioners, but to that of the army and the people generally.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="368"/>The petition states that this sentry duty can be performed by the commands at the stationary batteries in the various forts, under their own officers, and can be made so complete that all deserters, spies, blockaders and skulkers will be readily captured.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="369"/>These sentinels will require passes from all persons going beyond their lines, and can detect all illegal travel, and break up all improper intercourse between the capital of the <rs>Confederacy</rs> and the <rs n="Yankee" type="group">Yankee</rs> Government.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="370"/>The <rs type="place">Court</rs> ordered that every Justice in the county be summoned for <dateStruct><day type="name">Saturday</day></dateStruct> next, to consider the petition before them, and we have no doubt will make such an appeal to <persName n="Seddon,Secretary,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00235" reg="mostcommon:Seddon,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Secretary">Secretary</roleName> <surname>Seddon</surname></persName> as will ensure his cheerful acquiescence in their request. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="6"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Flour,</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="371"/> under the exhilarating manipulation of speculators in the life-blood of their country, has suddenly become very scarce in this market, and exceedingly high in prices.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="372"/>Within the past few days hundreds of barrels of this staff of life have been spirited off by railroads to secret hiding places elsewhere, there to remain till famine prices again brings it into market.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="373"/>Will the <rs>Government</rs> and people stand by and see the country overrun and rained by these vampires in trade, who care for nothing but gold and its equivalent?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="374"/>Has the <rs>Government</rs> no power to rid itself of these leaches?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="375"/>Are the people powerless, that they should stand with folded arms till speculators have deprived the army of subsistence and starved to death the wives, children, and widows, of our noble soldiers?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="376"/>Rather than submit to such fearful results, let every speculator in the necessaries of life be marched to the front and made to receive the bullets and bayonets of that hated foe whom they are striving to assist in crushing out the liberty and happiness of the <rs>South</rs>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="7"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Sick and disabled soldiers,</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="377"/> on furlough, or honorably discharged from the service, who are temporarily detained in <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, will be comfortably provided with food, quarters, and attention, free of charge, at the <rs type="place">Wayside Hospital</rs>, corner of <address><street n="19 Street">19th</street></address> and <address><street n="Franklin Street">Franklin streets</street></address>.--Similar hospitals have been established in <placeName reg="Petersburg, Petersburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7014404">Petersburg</placeName>, <placeName reg="Danville, Danville, Virginia" key="tgn,7014729">Danville</placeName>, <placeName key="tgn,7014170" n="1.000 62" reg="farmville, prince edward, virginia">Farmville</placeName>, <placeName reg="Lynchburg, Lynchburg, Virginia" key="tgn,7013981">Lynchburg</placeName>, <placeName key="tgn,7013585" n="1.000 66" reg="charlottesville, charlottesville, virginia">Charlottesville</placeName>, Liberty, and <placeName reg="Staunton, Staunton, Virginia" key="tgn,7014538">Staunton</placeName>, near the railroad depots, where sick and wounded soldiers will have the necessaries of life furnished them without expense.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="378"/>These hospitals are all attended by competent parties, and we are quite sure that they will prove pleasant resting places for those wearied patriots who have so nobly hazarded their lives for their suffering and blooding country. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="8"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">No charge.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="379"/> --<persName n="Willis,,Jacob,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00236" reg="default:Willis,Jacob,,,"><foreName>Jacob</foreName> <surname>Willis</surname></persName>, an invalid soldier, was sent under guard to the <rs type="place">Mayor's Court</rs> yesterday, from <placeName reg="Castle Thunder">Castle Thunder</placeName>, to be taken in charge of by the police; but as no accusation accompanied him he was returned.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="380"/><persName n="Willis,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00237" reg="nearbymention:Willis,Jacob,,,"><surname>Willis</surname></persName> stated that he had been taken from <placeName reg="Camp Winder">Camp Winder</placeName> to the <rs type="place">Castle</rs> for no cause that he knew of, and could not tell why he had been sent to the <rs>Mayor</rs>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="9"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Sent to his command.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="381"/> --<persName><foreName>John</foreName></persName> Q A Vaughan, charged with beating his mother and forcibly taking money from her, was before the <rs>Mayor</rs> yesterday; but as the witnesses failed to appear, be was handed over to the sergeant of the military company to which he is attached. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="10"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Fragments</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="382"/> of companies, many of them that never may be filled, are kept in camp and rendezvous about the city for weeks at a time.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="383"/>As <persName n="Lee,General,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00238" reg="nearbymention:Lee,Gen,,,"><roleName n="General">Gen.</roleName> <surname>Lee</surname></persName> needs forces at once, would it not be wise policy in the commandant of this district to turn these men over to companies already in the field, and thus enable them to do good service? </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="384"/> Bathing is essential to health when properly indulged in. If you wish to feel strong and vigorous through the day, rise early, and while the system is composed, the mind at case, and the blood at moderate heat, make your bath; but be sure not to remain in the water over <measure n="5minutes" type="date">five minutes</measure>. Bathing in the best of day is injurious, and may cause serious diseases. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="12"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Ripe fruits</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="385"/> and fresh, well served vegetables, are healthier food at this season of the year than meats; but green fruits and stale vegetable, badly cooked, are almost sure to produce diarrhea and other diseases that frequently prove fatal.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="386"/>Considering the number of produce have at this time, <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> is exceedingly healthy. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="13"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">The cage.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="387"/> --<persName n="McGary,,Patrick,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00239" reg="default:McGary,Patrick,,,"><foreName>Patrick</foreName> <surname>McGary</surname></persName> was last night assigned to the cage on the charge of being drunk and firing a pistol at <persName n="Henderson,,John,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00240" reg="default:Henderson,John,,,"><foreName>John</foreName> <surname>Henderson</surname></persName> in the street. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="14"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics">Distinguished arrival</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="388"/> --His <rs type="role2">Excellency</rs>, Z. H. <unclear></unclear> <rs type="role" reg="Governor">Governor</rs> of <placeName reg="North Carolina" key="tgn,7007709">North Carolina</placeName>, arrived in this city yesterday evening by the <rs>Southern Rode</rs>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="389"/>He is the <unclear></unclear> of <persName n="Hanson,Doctor,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00241" reg="mostcommon:Hanson,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Doctor">Dr.</roleName> <surname>Hanson</surname></persName>. </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="15"> 
<head type="nobreak" rend="italics"><placeName key="tgn,2100249" n="1.000 10" reg="Marble Hall, Hawkins, Tennessee">Marble Hall</placeName>,</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="390"/> it is said, is to be temporarily <unclear></unclear> to the use of the <rs>Mayor</rs> for his <unclear></unclear> Courts.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="391"/>The <placeName><placeName reg="City Hall">City Hall</placeName></placeName> room, now is <unclear></unclear> tobacconist as a <unclear></unclear> and then save the <unclear></unclear> ofd a <unclear></unclear> for that purpose. </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="2"/> 
<div2 type="telegraphic"> 
<head>Telegraphic.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>From the <rs>Southwest</rs>.</head> <opener> <dateline> Morton, Miss, <dateStruct value="-08-4"><month reg="08">Aug.</month> <day reg="4">4</day></dateStruct>. </dateline> </opener> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="392"/> --<num value="22">Twenty-two</num> transports, laden with troops, have passed <rs n="Natchez" type="nativeamerican">Natchez</rs>., going <hi rend="italics">down,</hi> up to <dateStruct><day type="name">Friday</day></dateStruct>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="393"/> A number of <persName n="Banks,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00243" reg="mostcommon:Banks,nomatch:0"><surname>Banks</surname></persName>'s and <orgName n="regiments"><persName n="Burnside,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00244" reg="nearbymention:Burnside,Gen,,,"><surname>Burnside</surname></persName>'s regiments</orgName> have been mustered out, their terms of service having expired. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="394"/> Transports loaded with negroes are sent up daily to <placeName reg="Island Number Ten, New Madrid, Missouri" key="tgn,2552260">Island No.10</placeName>, where a camp for the instruction of the blacks in the manual of arms has been established. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="395"/> <rs type="direction">East</rs> and <placeName reg="Louisiana" key="tgn,7007256"><rs type="direction">West</rs> Louisiana</placeName> have been stripped to form negro regiments. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="396"/> Rumor says <persName n="Sherman,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00245" reg="mostcommon:Sherman,nomatch:0"><surname>Sherman</surname></persName> is furloughing <num value="1">one</num> out of every company, and they leave daily for home. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="397"/> Pillaging parties are sent out daily from the garrisons at <rs n="Natchez" type="nativeamerican">Natchez</rs> and New Carthage, who strip the country of provisions and commit every species of vandalism. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="398"/> The weather is extremely warm &mdash; thermometer <num value="92">92</num> degrees. </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> 
<div1 type="notices"> 
<head></head> 
<div2 type="military"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="orders" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="399"/> <hi rend="smallcaps">The</hi> Army Committee of the <orgName n="Young Men's Christian Association" type="association">Young Men's Christian Association</orgName> acknowledges the receipt of the following contributions and supplies for the month of <dateStruct value="-07-"><month reg="07">July</month></dateStruct>, viz: </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="400"/> Buttermilk, received regularly by packet; <rs type="role">Mrs.</rs> E <persName n="Fontaine,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00246" reg="mostcommon:Fontaine,Cath,,,:1"><surname>Fontaine</surname></persName>, <placeName reg="Hanover, Hanover, Virginia" key="tgn,2112147">Hanover</placeName>, fans and old linen; <persName n="Fontaine,Miss,Cath,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00247" reg="default:Fontaine,Cath,,,"><roleName n="Miss">Miss</roleName> <foreName>Cath</foreName> <surname>Fontaine</surname></persName>, <persName n="Buckingham,Miss,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00248" reg="mostcommon:Buckingham,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Miss"></roleName><surname>Buckingham</surname></persName>, <num value="3">3</num> pairs socks; a lady, lint and bandages; cash per sundry persons, <measure n="60dollars" type="currency">$60</measure> <persName n="Kane,Mrs.,Jas,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00249" reg="default:Kane,Jas,,,"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <foreName>Jas</foreName> <surname>Kane</surname></persName>, <placeName reg="Louisa, Louisa, Virginia" key="tgn,2112748">Louisa</placeName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="401"/><measure n="20dollars" type="currency">$20</measure>; <persName n="Harris,,Henry,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00250" reg="default:Harris,Henry,,,"><foreName>Henry</foreName> <surname>Harris</surname></persName>, do, <measure n="20dollars" type="currency">$20</measure>; Sarah Harrie <unclear></unclear>, <measure n="5dollars" type="currency">$5</measure>; <persName n="Gordon,,Mary,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00251" reg="default:Gordon,Mary,,,"><foreName>Mary</foreName> <surname>Gordon</surname></persName> do, <measure n="5dollars" type="currency">$5</measure>; <persName><foreName>Hugh</foreName></persName> G <persName><foreName>Ellen</foreName></persName>, do, <measure n="10dollars" type="currency">$10</measure>; <rs type="role2">Miss</rs> A G McGahee, Alabama <measure n="35dollars" type="currency">$35</measure>; <rs type="role2">Capt</rs> R L <persName n="Marsh,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00252" reg="mostcommon:Marsh,nomatch:0"><surname>Marsh</surname></persName>, <measure n="50dollars" type="currency">$50</measure>, Charity, <measure n="10dollars" type="currency">$10</measure>; Wm W <persName n="Carrington,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00253" reg="mostcommon:Carrington,nomatch:0"><surname>Carrington</surname></persName> <measure n="50dollars" type="currency">$50</measure>; Children, per <rs type="role2">Mrs</rs>. R <persName n="Mayo,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00254" reg="mostcommon:Mayo,nomatch:0"><surname>Mayo</surname></persName>, <measure n="7dollars" type="currency">$7</measure> <num value="50">50</num>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="402"/> No special appear having been made the receipts for the month have been very light, There are quite a number of sick and wounded in the various hospitals in and around the city, with others arriving daily, and hospital supplies of all <unclear></unclear> are in demand.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="403"/>It will afford us pleasure to be the medium of distribution for any who may feel disposed to contribute to the comfort of our sick and wounded soldiers.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="404"/>Contributions in money or supplied may be forwarded to <persName n="Martin,,Roger,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00255" reg="default:Martin,Roger,,,"><foreName>Roger</foreName> <surname>Martin</surname></persName>, Sup't or to W P <persName n="Munford,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00256" reg="mostcommon:Munford,nomatch:0"><surname>Munford</surname></persName>, Chairman Army Committee Y M C A. </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="adverticements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="405"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="rent"> 
<head>For Rent and Sale.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="406"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="substitute"> 
<head>Substitute Notices.</head> 
<div3 type="orders" n="1"> 
<head>Substitute.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="407"/> --An employee for the last <measure n="2years" type="date">two years</measure> in the <orgName n="Confederate Government" type="org">Confederate Government</orgName>, aged <measure n="47years" type="date">47 years</measure>, and a native of <placeName reg="Canada, North and Central America, " key="tgn,7005685">Canada</placeName>, will go as a Substitute <measure n="5000dollars" type="currency">Price $5,000</measure>, if he has choice of company.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="408"/>Can give satisfactory recommendations as regards character and disposition of the money.--Address where an interview can be had. &#x0022;W S.,&#x0022; <orgName n="Dispatch office" type="office">Dispatch office</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="409"/> <term type="printrun">au 6--3*</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="2"> 
<head>Substitute wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="410"/> --<measure n="6000dollars" type="currency">$6,000</measure> will be paid for a reliable man over <measure n="45years" type="date">45 years</measure> of age. None but a citizen of the <placeName reg="United States" key="tgn,7012149">Confederate States</placeName> need apply <placeName reg="Virginia, United States, North and Central America" key="tgn,7007919">Virginia</placeName> preferred.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="411"/>Address &#x0022;J E,&#x0022; at J H <persName n="Blake,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00257" reg="mostcommon:Blake,nomatch:0"><surname>Blake</surname></persName>'s shop, on <address><street n="2 Street">2d street</street></address>, between <address><street n="Grace street">Grace</street></address> and <address><street n="Broad street">Broad</street></address> to-day, or at the <orgName n="Dispatch office" type="office">Dispatch office</orgName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="412"/> <term type="printrun">au 6--1t*</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="3"> 
<head>Substitute wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="413"/> --For mounted service.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="414"/>To a man over <measure n="45years" type="date">45 years</measure> of age a liberal price will be paid.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="415"/>Inquire in person for &#x0022;A B,&#x0022; at the <rs>Carriage Factory</rs> opposite the <rs type="place">Spotswood Hotel</rs> between the hours of <num value="9">9</num> A M. and <num value="3">3</num> P M. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="416"/> <term type="printrun">au 6--3t*</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="4"> 
<head>Substitute wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="417"/> --<num value="1">One</num> over <num value="45">45</num> of good character, and with good reference.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="418"/>Apply at <num value="135">No. 135</num> Broad at. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="419"/> <term type="printrun">au 6--3t*</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="5"> 
<head>Substitute wanted.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="420"/> --<num value="1">One</num> that can come well recommended will please apply to <persName n="Belvin,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00258" reg="mostcommon:Belvin,nomatch:0"><surname>Belvin</surname></persName> &#x0026; <persName n="Atkinson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00259" reg="mostcommon:Atkinson,nomatch:0"><surname>Atkinson</surname></persName>, on Governor, between <address><street n="Main street">Main</street></address> and <address><street n="Franklin street">Franklin streets</street></address>. <num value="1">One</num> over <measure n="45years" type="date">45 years</measure> preferred. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="421"/> <term type="printrun">au 3--5t*</term> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="422"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="3"/> 
<div2 type="announcements"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="death" n="1"> 
<head>Died.</head> 
<div4 type="obit" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="423"/> On the <dateStruct value="--5"><day reg="2">5th</day></dateStruct> inst, at <time value="1am">1 o'clock A. M.</time> <persName><foreName>Josephine</foreName></persName> only child of <persName><foreName>Eugene</foreName></persName> and <persName n="Callahan,,Bridget,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00260" reg="default:Callahan,Bridget,,,"><foreName>Bridget</foreName> <surname>Callahan</surname></persName>, aged <measure n="5months" type="date">5 months</measure> and <measure n="2weeks" type="date">2 weeks</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="424"/> The friends of the family are respectfully invited to attend her funeral from the residence of her parents, on <address><street n="5 Street">5th street</street></address>, between <address><street n="Byrd street">Byrd</street></address> and <address><street n="Arch street">Arch</street></address>, at <time value="3oclock">3 o'clock</time> this (<dateStruct><day type="name">Thursday</day></dateStruct>) evening without further invitation. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="425"/> After a short but painful illness of brain fever, on <dateStruct value="-07-14"><month reg="07">July</month> <day reg="14">14th</day></dateStruct>, little <persName><foreName>Jesse</foreName></persName> youngest <persName n="John,IsFather,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00261" reg="mostcommon:John,nomatch:0"><roleName n="IsFather">son of</roleName> <surname>John</surname></persName> R and <persName><foreName>Margaret</foreName></persName> S Trower, from <placeName reg="Norfolk, Norfolk, Virginia" key="tgn,7014231">Norfolk</placeName>, aged <measure n="2years" type="date">2 years</measure> and <measure n="7months" type="date">7 months</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="426"/>To the <name>Memory</name> of Litter <persName><foreName>Jesse</foreName></persName>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="427"/> <cit><q> <lg type="stanza"> <l>Dear little <persName><foreName>Jesse</foreName></persName>, thun bast left us, </l><l>Flown away to Heaven above; </l><l>There, among the dearest angels, </l><l>Where there is nothing but purity and love.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="428"/></l><l>No more shall we hear thy voice, </l><l>Nor thy little prattling tongue; </l><l>No more shall we hear those dear words, </l><l>Asking &#x0022;has my papa toms?&#x0022; </l><l>No more shall we ever hear </l><l>Thy little footsteps running around; </l><l>Prying in to every mischief, </l><l>But never doing any harm.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="429"/></l><l>Thy little chair at the table </l><l>Seems to say to all around-- </l><l>Our darling little baby </l><l>Has left me here all alone.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="430"/></l><l>Oh! how much we do miss thee, </l><l><placeName key="tgn,2295265" n="1.000 14" reg="drewry's bluff, chesterfield, virginia">Darling</placeName> sweetest little bud; </l><l>But reconciled we must be, </l><l>Not our will, but <name n="God" type="God">God's</name> be done, </l><l>Papa, mama, and little buddie, </l><l>Thy dear loss we deeply feel!; </l><l>But Its <name n="God" type="God">God</name> that hast bereft us, </l><l>He can all our sorrows heal, </l><l>Yet again we hope to meet thee, </l><l>Dear little angel, when life has fleed; </l><l>And again we hope to greet thee, </l><l>Where no parting tear is shed.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="431"/></l> </lg> </q><bibl></bibl></cit> </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> At <placeName reg="Ship Yard">Ship Yard</placeName>, in <placeName reg="James City, Virginia, United States" key="tgn,1002511">James City county</placeName>, the residence of his grandfather, <persName n="Goddin,Mister,Adolphus,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00262" reg="default:Goddin,Adolphus,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>Adolphus</foreName> <surname>Goddin</surname></persName>, on the <dateStruct value="1863-07-28"><day reg="28">28th</day> of <month reg="07">July</month>, <year>1863</year>,</dateStruct> of scarlet fever.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="432"/><persName n="Adolphus,,Gustavus,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00263" reg="default:Adolphus,Gustavus,,,"><foreName>Gustavus</foreName> <surname>Adolphus</surname></persName>, only <persName n="Wm,IsFather,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00264" reg="mostcommon:Wm,nomatch:0"><roleName n="IsFather">son of</roleName> <surname>Wm</surname></persName> B and <persName n="Addis,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00265" reg="mostcommon:Addis,nomatch:0"><surname>Addis</surname></persName> V <persName n="Haynes,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00266" reg="mostcommon:Haynes,nomatch:0"><surname>Haynes</surname></persName>, aged <measure n="7months" type="date">seven months</measure> and <measure n="12days" type="date">twelve days</measure>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="433"/> <cit><q> <lg type="stanza"> <l>Sleep on sweet babe, </l><l>And take thy rest; </l><l><name n="God" type="God">God</name> called thee home&#x0022; </l><l>[*] He thought it best.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="434"/>H* * * * * * </l> </lg> </q><bibl></bibl></cit> </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="435"/> At his residence, in this city, on <dateStruct value="1863-08-01"><day type="name">Saturday</day>, <month reg="08">August</month> <day reg="1">1st</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>, <persName n="William,Mister,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00267" reg="mostcommon:William,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <surname>William</surname></persName> S Ybiplett, aged <measure n="48years" type="date">48 years</measure>. </p> </div4> 
<div4 type="obit" n="5"> 
<head>Obituary.</head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="436"/> Died, at <placeName key="possibilities=41" n="1.000 10" reg=",">Oakwood</placeName>, <rs n="Powhatan" type="nativeamerican">Powhatan</rs> Co., at the residence of <persName n="Sublett,Mister,Wm,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00268" reg="default:Sublett,Wm,,,"><roleName n="Mister">Mr.</roleName> <foreName>Wm</foreName> <surname>Sublett</surname></persName>, on <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Wednesday</day></dateStruct> <time>evening</time>, <dateStruct value="-07-29"><month reg="07">July</month> <day reg="29">29th</day></dateStruct>, Mattis F, oldest daughter of <persName n="Mallids,Mrs.,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00269" reg="mostcommon:Mallids,nomatch:0"><roleName n="Mrs.">Mrs.</roleName> <surname>Mallids</surname></persName> F Danny, of this city. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="437"/> Sorrest will fail on many hearts outside of the family circle when the tidings of her death shall reach them.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="438"/>Gentle and unobtrusive in life, perhaps in death she would prefer a fond remembrance in the hearts of those who knew her to any enology of her virtues.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="439"/>A few weeks before her death she had gone to the country with the hope that the pure country air would restore her shattered constitution; but Death had marked the fair victim for his own, and after a protracted sickness of months, which she bore with great patience, she fell asleep in <persName><foreName>Jesus</foreName></persName>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="440"/>The Sabbath before the last which she spent on earth was the regular communion season in the church of which she was a member.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="441"/>She remembered it, and asked that a watch might be handed here, and as the hour approached when she supposed the people of <name n="God" type="God">God</name> were communing, she said to <num value="1">one</num> whom she tenderly loved, L &#x0022;Let us commune, too.&#x0022; She was consolers to within a few hours of her death, and on the morning of that day a Christan friend and minister had a most pleasant and satisfactory interview with her.--said he, &#x0022;Do you feel that you can commit yourself into the hands of your <name n="God" type="God">Heavenly Father</name> with perfect resignation to His will, whatever it may be?

<milestone unit="sentence" n="442"/>And apparently without knowing her end was so very near she replied, &#x0022;I think I can.&#x0022; </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="443"/> May He who can only comfort the broker hearted, gently heal the wound His own hand hath mane, enabling all who mourn her loss to say, &#x0022;Even so, Father, for to it seemed good to Thy <num value="8">eight</num>&#x0022; [*] </p> <closer> <signed>A Friend.</signed> </closer> </div4> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="amusements"> 
<head>Amusements.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="444"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="real estate"> 
<head><rs n="real estate" type="product">Real Estate</rs> for Sale.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="445"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="negroes"> 
<head>Negroes for Sale and Hire.</head> 
<div3 type="article" n="1"> 
<head>For Hire</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="446"/> --For the balance of the year, a good House Servant, Washer, and Ironer, For a good home the price will be reasonable. </p> <closer> <signed>Wm S <persName n="Royster,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00270" reg="mostcommon:Royster,nomatch:0"><surname>Royster</surname></persName>,</signed> <lb/> Corner <address><street n="Cary Street">Cary</street></address> and <address><street n="Virginia Street">Virginia</street></address> sts. <term type="printrun">au 6--2t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="2"> 
<head>For Sale</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="447"/> --To remain in or near the city of <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> a negro man, about <measure n="50years" type="date">50 years</measure> of age, who has worked most of his time in a tobacco factory.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="448"/>Apply at <address><street n="Cary street">Cary street</street></address> Jail, where he may be seen from <time value="9am">9 in the morning</time> until <time value="5pm">5 in the evening</time>. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="449"/> <term type="printrun">an 4--cod2t*</term> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="article" n="3"> 
<head>For Hire</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="450"/> --A servant Woman &mdash; a plain cook, washer and ironer.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="451"/>Apply to C Cookin, corner <address><street n="Clay Street">Clay</street></address> and <address><street n="Smith Street">Smith</street></address> sts, between <time value="9">9</time> and <time value="10oclock">10 o'clock</time> A M. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="452"/> <term type="printrun">an 4--2s*</term> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="advertisments"> 
<head></head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="453"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="4"/> 
<div2 type="special"> 
<head>Special Notices.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="454"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="lost"> 
<head>Lost, Strayed, &#x0026;c.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="455"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="13"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="14"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="15"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="16"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="17"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="18"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="19"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="20"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="5"/> 
<div2 type="auction"> 
<head><rs n="auction sales" type="product">Auction Sales</rs>--Future days</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="456"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="wants"> 
<head>Wants.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="457"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="13"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="14"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="15"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="16"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="17"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="18"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="19"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="20"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="6"/> 
<div2 type="auction"> 
<head><rs n="auction sales" type="product">Auction Sales</rs>--Future days.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="458"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="10"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="11"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="12"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="13"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="14"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="15"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> <milestone unit="column" n="7"/> 
<div2 type="auction"> 
<head><rs n="auction sales" type="product">Auction Sales</rs>--this day.</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="459"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="military"> 
<head>Military Notices.</head> 
<div3 type="orders" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="460"/>By the <name>Permission</name> of the <rs type="role" reg="Secretary of War">Secretary of War</rs>, I shall proceed immediately to maker and place in Camp the men already enlisted for my battalion. </p> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="461"/> All officers holding authority from me to recruit for this corps will report without delay with their master rolls. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Murford,,Wm,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00271" reg="default:Murford,Wm,,,"><foreName>Wm</foreName>  <surname>Murford</surname></persName></signed> <lb/> <placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName> <dateStruct value="1863-08-05"><month reg="08">August</month> <day reg="5">5</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct> <term type="printrun">au 6--1t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="2"> 
<head><hi rend="smallcaps">Headq're <num value="1" type="ordinal">1st</num> <unclear></unclear></hi><lb/><num value="2" type="ordinal">Second</num> <unclear></unclear><lb/><placeName reg="Richmond, Richmond, Virginia" key="tgn,7013964">Richmond</placeName>, <dateStruct value="1863-08-04"><month reg="08">Aug.</month> <day reg="4">4</day>, <year reg="1863">1863</year></dateStruct>.</head> 
<list type="ordered"> 
<head>Special orders--</head> 
<item n="1"> <num value="1">1</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="462"/>In obediences to General orders, of this date, this command will assemble on <address><street n="Broad Street">Broad st</street></address>, on <dateStruct><day type="name">Thursday</day></dateStruct>, <num value="6" type="ordinal">6th</num>, inst, at <time value="4:5pm">4&#x00BD; o'clock P. M.</time> completely armed and equipped for muster and inspection.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="463"/>The <unclear></unclear> and staff officers and appear mounted </item> 
<item n="2"> <num value="2">2</num>.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="464"/>All officers and nor-commissioned official are required to attend the preparatory drill <dateStruct value="---"><day type="name">Wednesday</day></dateStruct> <time>evening</time>, <num value="5" type="ordinal">5th</num> inst, at <time value="5oclock">5 o'clock</time>, at the <placeName reg="City Hall">City Hall</placeName>. </item> </list> <closer> By command of <lb/> <signed><rs type="role">Col.</rs> J B Dafforth</signed> <lb/> <signed>B W <persName n="Richardson,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00272" reg="mostcommon:Richardson,nomatch:0"><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>, 1djt.</signed> <term type="printrun">an 5--2t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="3"> 
<head>Attention.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="465"/>Marylanders</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="466"/> --<num value="15">Fifteen</num> men wanted to complete the organization of a company of Cavalry.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="467"/>Horses and equipments furnished and ready for the men. Apply at the <orgName>office of Capt</orgName> E B <persName n="Windes,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00273" reg="mostcommon:Windes,nomatch:0"><surname>Windes</surname></persName>, between are heart of <time value="9">9</time> and <time value="2oclock">2 o'clock</time>, corner <address><street n="9 Street">9th</street></address> and <address><street n="Back Street">Back streets</street></address>. </p> <closer> <signed>T Store's Davis,</signed> <lb/> <signed>Capt Commanding.</signed> <term type="printrun">au 3--6t*</term> </closer> </div3> 
<div3 type="orders" n="4"> 
<head>Military notice.</head> 
<p rend="nobreak">

<milestone unit="sentence" n="468"/> --We, the undersigned have authority from <rs type="role">Col.</rs> W H <persName n="Brown,,,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00274" reg="nearbymention:Brown,Thomas,M.,,"><surname>Brown</surname></persName> to organize a Company of Cavalry for local defence to be attached to his command.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="469"/>Arms, equipments and forage for horses furnished.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="470"/>This is a good opportunity for those having horses to join a good company, for local defence only as the <rs>Government</rs> propose to pay each man <measure n="12dollars" type="currency">$12</measure> per month and <unclear></unclear> forage for his horse.

<milestone unit="sentence" n="471"/>Those wishing <unclear></unclear> company can do so by calling at <unclear>killed</unclear> Brothar's, on <address><street n="13 Street">13th street</street></address>, between <address><street n="Main street">Main</street></address> and <address><street n="Cary street">Cary</street></address>. </p> <closer> <signed><persName n="Johns,,Parke,,," id="n-0001.0000.00000.00275" reg="expanded:Johns,"><foreName>Parke</foreName>  <surname>Johns</surname></persName></signed> <lb/> <signed>L M Miles.</signed> <term type="printrun">ly 27--1t</term> </closer> </div3> </div2> 
<div2 type="horses"> 
<head>Horses &#x0026;c., for Sale</head> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="1"> 
<head></head> 
<p>

<milestone unit="sentence" n="472"/> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="2"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="3"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="4"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="5"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="6"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="7"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="8"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> 
<div3 type="ad-blank" n="9"> 
<head></head> 
<p> <!-- &advertid; --> </p> </div3> </div2> </div1> </body> </text> </TEI.2>
 
